<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>English Archives | REVE Antivirus</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/lan/en/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 04:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Smishing? Why It’s A Potential Threat &amp; How To Stay Safe</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/what-is-smishing</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/what-is-smishing#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 03:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishing attacks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishing email]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[smishing]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8782</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Smishing attack has become a common term cybersecurity arena. Learn about smishing attacks, how to guard against it and more. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/what-is-smishing" data-wpel-link="internal">What Is Smishing? Why It&#8217;s A Potential Threat &#038; How To Stay Safe</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Phishing is a technique used by cyber terrorists frequently use to fool users and grab their confidential data. Normally this is done by sending fraudulent attachments or suspicious links (otherwise known as Phishing Links) via email or some kind of message. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The word Phishing is very common nowadays, almost everyone knows about this inimical method of stealing digital identity and assets. Due to its existence for a long period of time, almost everyone using the internet has </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/top-5-security-tactics-safeguard-business-phishing-attacks" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">developed some kind of a defense mechanism against it</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and are very cautious while opening a link sent through an email. To cope with the changed scenario, the bad guys have also adapted and are trying various newer methods. “<strong><em>Smishing</em></strong>” is one of those methods which have really caught the eyes of a lot of general users as well as experts.    </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is SMiShing</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8786" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/smishing-cover.jpg" alt="What is smishing?" width="1024" height="536" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When smartphones become the primary platform for the spreading of phishing links, that’s smishing. In simple terms, when hackers use mobile text messages to lure people falling into a digital trap, we categorize that as Smishing. Mobile text messages are popularly known as SMS or Short Message Service. That’s how SMiShing gets its name,</span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mobile-phone-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> phishing done via SMS</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or mobile phones. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How Is It Harming More</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As phishing is around for a long time, people are aware of this malicious mode of cyber crime in general. Moreover, there are built-in spam filters in all of the prominent email service providers. So a large chunk of phishing emails are actually filtered out before they are even opened. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, it’s not the same for Sms-phishing. As this is new, people are not that much aware yet, nor the filtering service for spam SMS is a prominent thing either. Many do not even take into consideration the fact that phishing through text messages is even a thing! In addition, everyone has a natural tendency to treat all text messages as innocuous and click any links or follow any instructions given there. As a result, smishing has a better success rate than phishing which is alarming.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another fact why Smishing is more damaging is, for email addresses, there are almost an infinite number of possibilities. However, a local cell phone number has only digits and usually consists of a certain amount of them. For example, any US phone number is 10 digits. So anyone could type 10 digits frivolously and could end up with a valid phone number. So a hacker can simply send text messages to any number.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8787" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/smishing.jpg" alt="Why Smishing is harmful" width="1024" height="536" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All these reasons combined make Smishing a very strong potential threat. A report by Gartner shows that as high as 98% of text messages are read and almost half of them get a response. When this is compared with 6% of total email responses, the scenario becomes clear.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different Kinds of Smishing</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like there are </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/phishing-email-scams" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">different types of email phishing scams</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there are different types of smishing as well. The primary method for Smishing is definitely the text messaging system. But, nowadays text messages are often replaced by different instant messaging apps. To name a few, Facebook messenger, WhatApp, and Viber are there. More often than not, a cell phone number is tagged along with all these instant messengers accounts. So, it becomes easy for a scammer to scam those apps too. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attackers also try to get into the victim’s mind in some specific ways. For instance, they might send a SMS saying the recipient has won a lottery and lure them to click a link. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8788" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Consumer-Blog-Images_800x400_phishing_5.png" alt="Lottery Smishing " width="800" height="400" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In another case, people are always waiting for a delivery from the courier service, so the scammers use some renowned brand name like DHL or FedEx and try to scam general people.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Probably the most common Smising frauds happen in the means banking channel. If not all then most of the people who use online banking services have a mobile phone. As people do not suspect their mobile to be a source of a phishing scam, scammers try to get hold of secret credentials and banking information via this. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8789" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/smishing-scam-behavioral-biometrics-02-1.jpg" alt="Smishing Banking Scam" width="800" height="350" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://www.irishtimes.com/business/financial-services/bank-of-ireland-does-u-turn-after-refusal-to-reimburse-smishing-victims-1.4326502" target="_blank" rel="noopener external noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Such an incident happened with the customers of Bank of Ireland</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> where as many as 300 customers fell victim of a Smishing scam and the bank had to compensate an amount around 800,000 Euros.        </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Stay Safe From Smishing</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Staying safe from Smishing is more of a habit than overnight success. Ensuring safety from these kinds of scams largely depends on the specific person’s consciousness and ability to identify a possible scam and ignore as well as report the message. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are some tips to identify and avoid a potential smishing scam</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All the potential scams have something in common, “If it is too good to be true, probably it is”! If the offer or claim in the message is unbelievable or unrealistic, you should better avoid it! </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As for any banks or financial institutions, they will never ask for your personal information like credit card no, ATM pin or OTPs. If any text message has the slightest hints of asking anything similar, simply report and block that sender. If you have any doubt if it is from your bank or not, contact them directly. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s better to completely ignore let alone responding to a number or account which is completely unknown to you.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Refrain yourself from clicking any link and submitting any personal info everywhere. Be sure to check thoroughly before doing any such things. </span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/what-is-smishing" data-wpel-link="internal">What Is Smishing? Why It&#8217;s A Potential Threat &#038; How To Stay Safe</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/what-is-smishing/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphone Cybersecurity – 5 Ways Malware Can Enter Your Mobile Device</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/smartphone-cybersecurity</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/smartphone-cybersecurity#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 09:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REVE antivirus]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8727</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Ensuring smartphone cybersecurity is essential for various different reasons. Check out 5 ways it can be compromised. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/smartphone-cybersecurity" data-wpel-link="internal">Smartphone Cybersecurity &#8211; 5 Ways Malware Can Enter Your Mobile Device</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8730" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/featured.jpg" alt="smartphone cybersecurity" width="600" height="400" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/featured.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/featured-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is the most sought after and used electronic device in the world today? That must be the smartphone. Chances are, you are reading this article on a smartphone as well. That being said, how aware are you of smartphone cybersecurity? The usage of portable mobile phones has skyrocketed in the last couple of decades. And it’s not difficult to guess that the threats regarding the security of these devices have increased too. More and more spywares and harmful malwares are built every day to steal data from your smartphone and possibly hold you hostage and rob you in one way or another. Here, let’s look at the 5 most common ways through which malware can get entry into your smartphone.  </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Through A Malicious Application</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most common way for any malware to get an entry into a mobile device is through a malicious software. Malware can come right from the source that a user uses to install an app to their mobile. So, if you think installing an app from the authorized play store or app store is safe then you have already compromised your smartphone cybersecurity. In the past, Google has discovered malicious apps which were available in their play store and later removed them and asked</span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/stay-safe-from-joker-malware" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> users to remove these apps from their devices </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">as well. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition, the attacks on smartphones are getting more sophisticated everyday. </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different malwares and spywares</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are surfacing with more harmful features. Now malwares that can read and send text messages,  intercept notifications and steal secret information like credit card data are found frequently.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Through Phishing Links</strong></h2>
<div style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8731 size-full" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/img1.jpg" alt="person holding a smartphone" width="600" height="400" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/img1.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/img1-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p class="wp-caption-text"></strong> <strong>Phishing links are behind most of the cyber attacks</strong></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though one of the oldest methods, phishing is still the most widely used method of cybercrimes. In fact, till this day more than ⅓ of data breaches happen due to phishing. Definitely, your smartphone cybersecurity can be compromised via phishing links. These links can easily be sent over an email, messaging apps or text messages. And all they require is a single click to infect your mobile phone with malware.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Due to Browser Vulnerabilities </strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The day internet browsers were introduced into mobile phones, a new era began. Users had an experience like never before and the whole smartphone scenario started to emerge. However, every coin has an opposite side to it, alongside this blessing, browsers have also become a mention worthy threat to smartphone cybersecurity. Because browser engine vulnerabilities are found regularly. App developers around the world are always on their toes to fix these problems and release a security patch. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, there lies a window between the discovery of a browser weakness and an update released for it which could be the perfect chance for malware to enter your mobile device. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Connecting to Unknown Wi-Fi </strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who doesn’t like free Wi-Fi? Restaurants, cafes, shopping malls, and free wi-fi connections are available in almost every busy public place. Loads and loads of PCs, as well as smartphones, are connected regularly to an open, public wi-fi. This could bring a potential cyber threat. Because wi-fi networks are built to send and receive data. Anyone connected in the same network can try to find a backdoor to access the data between your phone and server and if successful they can steal data or put malware inside your device. There are instances where cybercriminals set up their own wireless networks in a public place and just like we catch fish with baits, they draw a user into their trap with this wi-fi network! </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Exploiting Remote Access Tools</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">RATs or Remote Access Tools are not always malware. In fact, it has usage on legitimate,  noble causes too. Gaining complete access over a user’s device remotely is a feature on which mobile devices were built in the first place. However, this feature is often misused by cybercriminals and it can be a potential way through which harmful malware or spyware is inserted into your device.  </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are our top picks of how malware can enter your mobile device. Let us know of any queries in the comment section. For any cybersecurity related information or query visit </span><a href="http://www.reveantivirus.com" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">www.reveantivirus.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/smartphone-cybersecurity" data-wpel-link="internal">Smartphone Cybersecurity &#8211; 5 Ways Malware Can Enter Your Mobile Device</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/smartphone-cybersecurity/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Best Personal Cybersecurity Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/8-best-personal-cybersecurity-tips</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/8-best-personal-cybersecurity-tips#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 09:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8705</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p> [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/8-best-personal-cybersecurity-tips" data-wpel-link="internal">8 Best Personal Cybersecurity Tips</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-8707 size-full" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/stuck-940x470.jpg" alt="personal cybersecurity tips" width="1280" height="720" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/stuck-940x470.jpg 1280w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/stuck-940x470-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/stuck-940x470-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/stuck-940x470-1024x576.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity is an essential aspect to consider in today’s world. The internet has become a cumbersome space to roam due to the potential cyberthreats. </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different types of malwares </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">are on the rise and are always looking for the chance when a user lets his guard down for a moment. Only a single click in the wrong link can create such a mess that was unimaginable even a decade or two ago. Along with </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">organizational cybersecurity best practices</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it’s high time to embrace some personal habits to ensure cybersecurity. Here’s our pick for top personal cybersecurity tips in 2022. </span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passwords Must be Strong</span></h2>
<div id="attachment_8708" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8708" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8708" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/pass-300x300.jpg" alt="Strong password checklist" width="500" height="500" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/pass-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/pass-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/pass-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/pass.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8708" class="wp-caption-text">Strong password checklist</p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passwords are the first line of defense against personal or professional data security and cyberthreats. Yet, people have an affinity towards choosing the most common and widely used username/passwords combinations. So, using a strong password is mandatory. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does a strong password consist of? While the length of the password itself is an important one, experts suggest the combination of different types of letters and characters is essential. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, while creating a password do not forget to include a least </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Capital letter</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A small letter</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A number (i.e. 0,1,3)</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A special character (i.e. !, @, #, %) </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To make life difficult for the cybercriminals as well as bolster personal cybersecurity, never use the most used passwords like birthdays, family member’s names. Also, refrain from using the same password over and over again in multiple places.</span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"></h2>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beware of Phishing and Other Scams</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Phishing links and emails cause the most amount of cyberattacks. In fact, more than 33% of data breaches are a direct result of phishing. The intruder will pose someone or some link familiar to the recipient and trick them to open a malicious link.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The way to tackle this potential cyber threat is not only increasing cybersecurity through softwares and services, but also to imply organizational awareness among the employees and users. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s easy to click, but once trapped, it’s almost impossible to get yourself out of a phishing scam. So, maintaining personal online hygiene is a must. Suspecting and inspecting each and every link and making sure they are from a  trusted, safe source helps to stay safe from the 3 billion fake emails sent globally every day!</span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be Intelligent Using Social Media</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s no denying the fact that social media has become a new part and parcel of our everyday life. As much as social media has made our life easy and more engaging, it has also increased vulnerability against different cyber threats. Hackers can now use social engineering to gain access to systems and information available openly on social media. It’s possible to leak valuable personal data through social media. As a result, being cautious and intelligent while using social media must be on the top of the list of personal cybersecurity tips. </span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Updates are Mandatory</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ransomware attacks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> often cause the most damage for both businesses and consumers. And one of the most essential cybersecurity tips is to patch old and outdated services with updates. Software patches are issued mostly to mitigate a vulnerability or recently discovered security flaw. Updating OS as well as other softwares to their latest versions with security patches is the way of moving forward.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, it’s suggested to turn on automatic system updates for all devices along with the web browsers. An interesting fact is, many people find it annoying to update patches at a regular interval. However, updates keep you safe against the risks of </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">different types of malware</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and other harmful computer infections. </span></p>
<h2>Rely on Two-factor Authentication</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-8709" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2fa.jpg" alt="2 factor authentication are essential " width="500" height="500" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2fa.jpg 800w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2fa-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2fa-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/2fa-768x768.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></p>
<p>2FA or 2-factor authentication is another very important and widely prescribed in personal cybersecurity tips. It helps you to keep your account secure even if somehow the username &amp; passwords are compromised.</p>
<p>How it works is, when a user provides a username &amp; password, another OTP (one-time password) is generated in a previously authenticated device / app. This OTP is required to log into the associated account. It’s completely random which in return helps to strengthen the overall security of an account.</p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protect Your PII</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personally Identifiable Information or shortly called PII is anything that can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Starting from your fingerprints, name, home address, date of birth, phone number anything can be your PII. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the era which is dominated by social media and online communication, new and new things are adding to the above list. Hence,  any personal cybersecurity tips will say that you keep your digital footprint minimal and be protective about your PII. </span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set up Firewall and Use Antivirus</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All the firewalls and cybersecurity products work as the main line of defense against any cybersecurity threat. Antivirus and endpoint cloud plays a vital role in blocking and eradicating all malicious attacks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s essential that you use a </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">modern antivirus</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or anti-malware solution to protect your personal data, and set up all the necessary firewalls as well.</span></p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overconfidence Hurts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I am smart, I never visit any harmful sites or links”, “This will never happen to me”, “No one can intrigue me to click a phishing link!” &#8211; these are the most detrimental thoughts ever. It’s better to remember, everyone thinks they are safe before the unimaginable happens. The criminals always find a newer and better way to attack. So it’s better to be safe than sorry. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are our top picks for personal cybersecurity tips everyone should follow. Do you agree with our list? What steps do you take to ensure your digital security? Let us know in the comment section! </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/8-best-personal-cybersecurity-tips" data-wpel-link="internal">8 Best Personal Cybersecurity Tips</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/8-best-personal-cybersecurity-tips/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tips On Preventing Cyber Attacks In Organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/organizational-safety-against-cybersecurity-attacks</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/organizational-safety-against-cybersecurity-attacks#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 09:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8722</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p> [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/organizational-safety-against-cybersecurity-attacks" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 5 Tips On Preventing Cyber Attacks In Organizations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-7456 size-large" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Cyber-Security-Attacks-1024x536.jpg" alt="cyber security attacks" width="1024" height="536" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Cyber-Security-Attacks-1024x536.jpg 1024w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Cyber-Security-Attacks-300x157.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Cyber-Security-Attacks-768x402.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Cyber-Security-Attacks.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The internet has turned out to be extremely beneficial for almost everyone in all aspects. Unfortunately, access to a vast amount of information has enabled an increased number of cybercrimes. Today, cybersecurity attacks not only target the large corporations, but startups or smaller organizations are also easily being targeted. Without top-notch focus on cybersecurity, you are leaving your business open to cyberattacks, as well as vulnerable to data theft.  For every business organization from large to small,  it’s one of the major concerns. The threats are not only for the business itself but also their customers and employees. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, taking appropriate steps to better your business&#8217;s cybersecurity is essential. But how to do that? How to save your organization from cybersecurity attacks? Below some helpful tips are listed.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Train Your Employees Against Cybersecurity Attacks</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the quickest and easiest ways to improve the</span> <a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/cyber-security-tips-business" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cybersecurity of your business</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">is to properly train and educate your office employees. Everyone in your organization should have a good knowledge of the company’s security policies and understand why its importance. Therefore, you should invest in cybersecurity training for every staff member. Hold each employee of your company accountable to the organization’s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cyber security policies and procedures. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Get a continuity plan. Doing this is important because most security breaches or </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ransomware attacks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> occur when an employee accidentally clicks on a link or attachment that allows a hacker to access your company’s network.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Modern Antivirus Protection</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You cannot overstate the value and importance of an antivirus for business cybersecurity. </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/product/antivirus" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Professional grade antivirus protection</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">is a must to keep your sensitive business data (that often includes personal details about clients, customers, and employees) out of the harmful hands. Check if all systems or machines used by your employees have the latest versions of security software and OS. In case they are not upgraded to the latest versions, force them to do it now.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lock Down The Wi-fi Network</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wi-Fi is one of the most important necessities that every business organization needs to survive in this competitive industry. However, unsecured wifi connection can become a weak point when it comes to the cybersecurity of an organization. So, if you have a Wi-Fi network, check to make sure it’s hidden. If you have customers, clients and others visiting your place, add an added layer of protection and set up a separate guest network for them. Wi-Fi networks are designed to both send and receive data and protection for Wi-Fi networks are essential for safety against cybersecurity attacks.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implement A Smart Mobile Device Policy</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Simple things can reduce the risk of cyber dangers, such as introducing and implementing strong mobile device policy and making sure that all the devices are protected. Majority of employees use work email on their personal mobile devices. This creates security challenges and opens the door to various cyber threats, especially if the devices hold sensitive data or can access business networks off the premises. The cyber criminals always have eyes on the user&#8217;s weaknesses and vulnerabilities. To prevent this, a smart smartphone security policy is required. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Backup Your Data</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you haven&#8217;t already, it&#8217;s time to think about regular</span> <a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/data-backup" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data backups</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">to add some extra layer of  cybersecurity in your organization. With a restorable backup system in place, if security threats such as malware, viruses, spyware etc lurk on your devices, you will still have your data saved in a secured place, waiting for recovery. In several cases, backup files are stored offsite so that in case of cybersecurity attacks or natural disaster, they can be restored later. So, check to make sure that your valuable data is backed up and stored in a separate location.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is your business prepared to manage a cybersecurity attack? Do you need to improve your organization’s cyber security?  Share your valuable thoughts with us in the comment section! For any cybersecurity related query do not hesitate to </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reach us</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">!</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/organizational-safety-against-cybersecurity-attacks" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 5 Tips On Preventing Cyber Attacks In Organizations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/organizational-safety-against-cybersecurity-attacks/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Different Types of Malwares And How To Stay Safe From Them</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 09:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REVE antivirus]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8694</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p> [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware" data-wpel-link="internal">7 Different Types of Malwares And How To Stay Safe From Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8696" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Featured.png" alt="Types of malware" width="600" height="450" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Featured.png 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Featured-300x225.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malwares are the public enemy of the modern digital era. Approximately there were almost 5 billion malware attacks in the year 2021. Let’s know about what malware is, different types of malware and how to keep your personal computer or organization safe from malware attacks in this article. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is Malware</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malware is a shortened form of malicious software. It denotes any harmful computer program that is created to do harm to a computer system. They are unwanted software intentionally designed to unsettle the normal behavior of a computer, server, client, network etc and steal or leak sensitive information, data or even access in various forms. . </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different Types of Malware</span></h2>
<div id="attachment_8701" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8701" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8701 size-full" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Types-of-malware.jpg" alt="Types of malware" width="600" height="300" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Types-of-malware.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Types-of-malware-300x150.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8701" class="wp-caption-text">Types of malware</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">These harmful programs come in different forms with different targets and approaches. Let’s look at some very common malware</span></p>
<table style="height: 283px;" width="911">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Malware Name</b></td>
<td><b>Malware Function</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Ransomware</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Block the system and demand ransom for encryption key</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Spyware</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collects sensitive user information by spying on device</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Adware</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shows unwanted advertisements and collects user data without consent</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Trojan Horse</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disguises or hides behind other software, can take control of victim’s system</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Worm</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spreads throughout networks via replicating itself</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Keyloggers</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maps and stores user’s keystrokes</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Fileless Malware</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Makes changes to native OS files</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ransomware:</span></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8380" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/sfew.jpg" alt="Ransomware red screen" width="600" height="314" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/sfew.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/sfew-300x157.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In today’s world, <a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal">ransomware</a> is probably the most threatening and dangerous malware. Once it gets entry to a system it encrypts files, folders or even the whole OS and demands ransom in an untraceable mode of payment for the decryption key. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Worldwide<a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/mitigate-ransomware-attack" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"> ransomware attacks </a>are on the up, in 2021 alone almost 500 million ransomware attacks were estimated. It is also predicted that, by 2021 the expense for ransomware victims will reach 6 trillion dollars annually!</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spyware:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spyware is another dangerous type of malware. It can work on the background and steal sensitive information like passwords, pins, payment information etc. What’s more frightening is, spyware is not only functional in desktop or browser, it can also affect smartphones as well. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adware:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who willingly wants to see an advertisement? None right? Well, an adware just forces you to do so! It displays pop-up ads that often have no relevance or acceptance to you. Not only is it annoying but also it takes up resources and slows the machine down. Furthermore, adware’s activities are often not limited to displaying forced ads. Collecting personal data, redirecting to other advertising sites, even changing internet browser settings, default browser and search settings as well as homepages can also be done by more advanced malicious adwares.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trojan Horse:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the name suggests, when a trojan horse, or simply “Trojan” is disguised in such a way that it looks like a normal, harmless file or program. This file is designed to trick a user into downloading and installing malware inadvertently into their system.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, as soon as a Trojan is installed, cyber criminals get a free pass to the system and are ready to exploit it. It is possible to steal data, install more malware, modify files, monitor user activity, destroy data, steal financial information, conduct denial of service (DoS) attacks on targeted web addresses, and more using the Trojan horse malware. In a worse case scenario, if it is combined with a worm, the damage can be extreme.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Worm:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like a worm in nature, a computer malware named as worm can replicate itself over and over. It targets vulnerabilities in operating systems to install themselves into networks. They can also be spread via phishing attacks. Once a worm has got access to a machine, it not only can infect the machine, but in some cases it can affect the whole network as well. They are capable of infecting large numbers of computers and consume bandwidth overloading the web servers in the way. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keyloggers:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keyloggers can be referred to as a special type of spyware which can record the keys struck in a keyboard without the knowledge of the user. This assists the hacker to steal passwords, banking information or other sensitive information. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fileless Malware:</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are different types of malware which are very well disguised and do not install or change anything initially. However, they are capable of making changes directly to the files like PowerShell that are native to the OS. What makes it so dangerous is, as these files are considered as a legitimate file, fileless attacks are often not caught by a cybersecurity software!</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How Does Malware Get Entry?</span></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8697" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/inside.jpg" alt="Stay safe from malwares" width="600" height="337" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/inside.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/inside-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A malware can get entry in various ways. However, most common sources of malware spread include email attachments, malicious websites, torrents, and shared networks. Here are some examples</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>Phishing:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Phishing links containing emails are probably the most common way of malware entry. These mails come from frauds and try to snatch sensitive user data. Nowadays, not only email but also sms or in instant messaging apps are also used for the purpose as well.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>Torrents:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Though file sharing via torrent is already banned in many countries in the world but for some less technologically advanced countries, people are still using different torrent clients. These files are always suspected and considered as a way of malwares to get entry to a new machine. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>Flash drives:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Connecting a public flash drive which is used in public networks without scanning it for malwares contains a high chance for malware spread. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Stay Safe From Malwares</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malwares can wreak havoc to any personal or organizational network. Enough cybersecurity awareness is a must for the safeguard. To win the fight against malwares, support of </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a modern and advanced cybersecurity product</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is necessary. An antivirus software which can detect any kind of malware threats and take prompt action to restrict any kind of loss. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware" data-wpel-link="internal">7 Different Types of Malwares And How To Stay Safe From Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/types-of-malware/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Cybersecurity Layers An Entrepreneur Should Maintain</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/cybersecurity-layers-an-entrepreneur-should-focus</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/cybersecurity-layers-an-entrepreneur-should-focus#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 09:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[endpoint security solutions]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8509</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p> [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/cybersecurity-layers-an-entrepreneur-should-focus" data-wpel-link="internal">7 Cybersecurity Layers An Entrepreneur Should Maintain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8514" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8514" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-8514" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized.jpg" alt="cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus" width="600" height="400" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8514" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus</strong></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s start this with an incident with Mr. <em>John Owen Brennan</em>, former Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). One fine morning in 2015, Mr. Brennan discovered that his personal email account has been hacked and a Tweet containing sensitive personal information of more than 20 CIA Personnel is openly available on the internet. The information was published on Wikileaks as well.  What’s more interesting is, the hacker who did all this social engineering to do something of this scale, claimed himself to be only a high school student! </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, as an entrepreneur, you may wonder if the personal email of the CIA chief is not safe, what are the stakes that your would be? Well, information security is not something you should play a gamble with. Sad as it may sound, </span><b>cybersecurity is still something most of us take casually even in this digital era</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, maintaining minimum safety on this could provide you with maximum benefits. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, let’s look at some very common security layers every entrepreneur or decision maker should understand and </span><b>cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus on to strengthen the entire cybersecurity of an organization</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. These practices are easy to deploy but have a huge impact on overall cybersecurity. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">7 Cybersecurity Layers An Entrepreneur Should Focus</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let&#8217;s take a glance at the top seven cybersecurity layers at first, followed by detailed discussions. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passwords</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two-factor Authentication</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Backup And Access Management</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Physical Property Security</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wireless Security</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email Security</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment in Cybersecurity Software</span></li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passwords</span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first layer of all the cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus on should definitely be the passwords. The thing with passwords is simple, update them regularly, keep them confidential and never ever share them with even the person you trust the most!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to passwords, using a different combination of uppercase, lowercase letters, numbers and symbols creates the strongest one. Also, a password should never be cross-used, different accounts must have different passwords. Passwords containing name, organization name, email etc should also be avoided. All in all, regular awareness programs on choosing and updating strong passwords should be taken among employees to bolster the layer of cybersecurity. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two-factor Authentication</span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">After passwords, the most important layer to implement and focus on should be the two-factor authentication or the 2FA service. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even the strongest of passwords are crackable. So it’s always great to have an extra layer of protection, here in the form of 2FA. This process ensures an account is not accessible with only a single password but requires multiple authentications before the user is let through. In this method after the password is given, another authentication is needed. This second authentication might be via an email, text message to an employee’s registered number, small authenticator device or application like </span><a href="https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/1066447" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google Authenticator</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So, even with a compromised password, the intruder can do no harm unless the second authentication method is compromised also, which is highly unlikely. In addition, advanced authentication methods like facial recognition, fingerprint, ultrasonic sound etc are also improving rapidly over time. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Backup And Access Management</span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this digital world data is the most precious thing for any individual or organization. </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/bd/product/endpoint-cloud" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensuring the safeguard of data </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">results in the prevention of critical data loss. And baking up sensitive data in multiple places, if possible both on physical drive and cloud is among the top cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus on.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With data security comes the topic of access management. There will be different types of employees in an organization with different responsibilities. Surely, all do not require the same level of access to company data. Failing to manage this access level may result in unwanted data leaks from unwanted sources. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Physical Property Security </span></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_8513" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8513" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-8513" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-3.jpg" alt="premises security" width="600" height="337" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-3.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-3-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8513" class="wp-caption-text">Do you spend enough recourses to ensure premises security?</p></div></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Staying over-focused on digital security often catches many business owners off guard with their physical properties security. However, it’s a very important layer of cybersecurity to consider the protection of physical properties as well. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An old hard drive or flash drive might not be properly dumped and data might leak from there, an official laptop with a weak or no password might be stolen from a coffee shop or snatched from the road. Even when inside the office, it only takes a moment for an intruder to do harm to an unprotected, unattended pc.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To ensure this cybersecurity layer, employee training is essential, they should be made aware of all possible scenarios and losses. They should be extremely wary of using official devices, especially off-premises. Before dumping any old hard drives or flash drives, they should be completely wiped off. Also, the drives which are currently in use should be encrypted so that even if it’s on the wrong hand, no harm can be done. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wireless Security</span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The wireless internet your company uses to do all the business could also be a cybersecurity threat if left unchecked. As the wifi signal isn’t limited to the office premises, a wireless network with weak security could easily be breached and a hacker can connect to it from far away. A wireless network is an ideal channel to send and receive data. Once the wireless security is breached, it often is child’s play for a hacker to steal sensitive official information and harm the organization. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email Security</span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there is only one cybersecurity layer an entrepreneur decides to focus on, it should better be Email security. Email accounts should be protected at all costs. Because if the email account is compromised, then it’s not a very difficult task to take control of all the associated profiles linked to a certain email address. Because the hacker can simply request a reset password link and set a new password via the compromised email. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To stay safe, employee awareness is a must. They should be trained to identify and refrain from clicking suspicious links which may contain phishing links or viruses. Also, a </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/bd/product/internet-security" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">modern cybersecurity product with Email security</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> could prove vital on this topic. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Software</span></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_8515" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8515" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8515 size-full" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-2.jpg" alt="Investment on cybersecurity" width="600" height="375" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-2.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/small-sized-2-300x188.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8515" class="wp-caption-text">Make investment on cybersecurity before any unfortunate incident</p></div></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every business has different kinds of expenses and operating costs. To ensure a cybersecurity environment, there could be no better investment than investing in a modern cybersecurity solution. Most antivirus software can help keep email accounts and other sensitive information safe. But modern cyber security software brings more features like blacklists and whitelists, employee monitoring, mobile security, internet security etc. For that, </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">REVE Antivirus</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> could be an excellent choice. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We live in such an era where any business can be hacked, data can be stolen. And without maintaining the proper security layers, it’s not a question of how but when. These are our pics for the top 7 cybersecurity layers an entrepreneur should focus on to bolster company cybersecurity. Let us know your thoughts in the comment section. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/cybersecurity-layers-an-entrepreneur-should-focus" data-wpel-link="internal">7 Cybersecurity Layers An Entrepreneur Should Maintain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/cybersecurity-layers-an-entrepreneur-should-focus/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joker Malware Is Back – Remove These Apps From Your Android Device Instantly!</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/stay-safe-from-joker-malware</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/stay-safe-from-joker-malware#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[computer virus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet security software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware check]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8491</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p> [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/stay-safe-from-joker-malware" data-wpel-link="internal">Joker Malware Is Back &#8211; Remove These Apps From Your Android Device Instantly!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-8492 alignnone" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pexels-pixabay-38275-1024x684.jpg" alt="Malware is here" width="1024" height="684" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The infamous malware called “Joker” first came into attention back in 2017 when android users discovered all of a sudden that not only their sensitive information is stolen but also they have a big amount due on their credit card in the form of monthly subscriptions fees that they had no idea about. As soon as it came into Google’s attention they mitigated the situation by removing the suspicious apps from play stores and alerting users worldwide. However this Joker Malware seems like a persistent one and keeps finding a backdoor or another to enter android devices and do pernicious activities.  </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Recent News</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Joker malware was kind of dormant for a few months. However, back in August this year, authorities from the </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/gadgets-news/belgian-police-warns-smartphone-users-the-joker-virus-is-back-with-these-8-android-apps/articleshow/85590074.cms" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Belgian police department warned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the harmful malware is back again and given a list of 8 applications that might cause unwanted situations. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">And very recently, a </span><a href="https://twitter.com/sh1shk0va/status/1458795768022720520" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Russian malware analyst warned with a Tweet</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the Joker Malware is in fact active again and stealing user data via malicious applications. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">List of Flagged Applications</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a list of android applications that is surely compromised and flagged as harmful. Take a look at them and check if your device has any one of those installed. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Easy PDF Scanner</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Super-Click VPN</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Battery Charging Animation Bubble Effects</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Battery Charging Animation Wallpaper</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now QRCode Scan</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Volume Boosting Hearing Aid</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Volume Booster Louder Sound Equalizer</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Classic Emoji Keyboard</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dazzling Keyboard</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EmojiOne Keyboard</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Smart TV Remote</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Flashlight Flash Alert on Call</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Halloween Coloring</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Super Hero-Effect</span></li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why You Should Be Afraid Of Joker Malware</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All malware are deleterious in their own way but this Joker Malware is one that raised some big questions to android security. Android OS has some security and vetting checks of its own. What Joker Malware can do is by tweaking some codes it can bypass the security check and make its way into the OS. <img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8494" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pandasecurity-sbg-1024x768.jpg" alt="malware hacker" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pandasecurity-sbg-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pandasecurity-sbg-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pandasecurity-sbg-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/pandasecurity-sbg.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the malware is inside the system it can sit behind and steal user data including SMS, contact lists and device info. <strong>The problem with an unauthorized app having access to SMSs is, it can also get hold of any OTPs coming into the device</strong>. And Joker Malware takes this advantage to the fullest and is accused of doing even online transactions without the consent or knowing of the concerned person. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Victims said they were subscribed to many premium services which they had no knowledge of. They only get to know with a surprising amount of monthly subscription fees at the end of the month. This malware can also work in the background and create clicking events on various advertisements. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Should You Do Instantly</span></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the list there are applications with just a few downloads but also applications which have thousands of downloads. Even if these are taken down from google play store however APK file of these are available on the internet. Additionally, <strong>if any of the applications are already installed on your device, you should waste no time removing it then install a </strong></span><strong><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/bd" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer">modern antivirus</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which is equipped with</span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/bd/mobile-security/android" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> mobile security feature</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and do a proper scan of your device to check if there are any more threats to your device. Also, <strong>check and double check to the monthly subscriptions you are currently enrolled</strong> to and if you find anywhere you meant not to be, contact them asap and stop the subscription before the next cycle! </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/stay-safe-from-joker-malware" data-wpel-link="internal">Joker Malware Is Back &#8211; Remove These Apps From Your Android Device Instantly!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/bd/stay-safe-from-joker-malware/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 4 Reasons Businesses Should Invest In Cybersecurity Right Now</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/invest-in-cybersecurity</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/invest-in-cybersecurity#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SME Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8466</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>What’s at stake if you leave your cybersecurity unchecked? Why businesses should invest in cybersecurity right now? Find out here.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/invest-in-cybersecurity" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 4 Reasons Businesses Should Invest In Cybersecurity Right Now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8457" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8457" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-8457" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/many-pcs.jpg" alt="Choose the cyber security solution best suits you" width="600" height="314" /><p id="caption-attachment-8457" class="wp-caption-text">Choose the cyber security solution best suits you</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s discernible to everyone that more and more people are now connected to the internet today. The cyber-world is becoming a new reality for this generation. Generally, in a society, if the population increases, the rate of crimes see an increment too. It’s evident that, with a huge number of users, the rate of cybercrime and cyber attacks are skyrocketing to the top. In fact, the cyber security threat to each individual as well as an institution is more at present than at any other time in the past. This info alone should suffice the necessity for any cybersecurity investments. However, let’s dig deeper and find out some more reasons to decide </span><b>why businesses should invest in cybersecurity right now</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Why Organizations Should Invest in Cybersecurity?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55811165" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A report</span> from BBC</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> says the rate of cybercrimes has reached such a level that </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/mitigate-ransomware-attack" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ransomware payments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are claimed by insurers and insurance companies cover them! The decision to invest in cybersecurity is backed up by a lot of reasons, let’s take a look at a few.</span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Data is The New King, The Security of King Comes First</b></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2018/05/23/10-charts-that-will-change-your-perspective-of-big-datas-growth/?sh=1adc98bb2926" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">article by Forbes magazine</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it was estimated that the big data market will jump from $42B in 2018 to $103 in 2027. Even though the physical security of an establishment is taken seriously most of the time, the issue of cybersecurity is often overlooked. So, it doesn’t come as a surprise when 9 out of 10 global businesses admit that they have suffered some kind of security breach. These breaches are often to steal valuable data. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, a massive cyberattack at T-Mobile has resulted in a leak of personal information for more than 40 million customers. The </span><a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/network/cyberattack-against-tmobile-and-our-customers" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO of T-Mobile had to write and explain </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">to the customers to appease the situation. From giant organizations to SMBs, data is the new king. And if data breaches can occur in giants like Facebook or T-Mobile, who’s ensuring the data security for your enterprise? Taking a decision to invest in cybersecurity today will benefit the safety of this precious data in the future for sure.   </span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>To Increase Profit</b></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lot of the small and medium-sized businesses have no or negligible amount of investments in cybersecurity. They are in the situation mostly because they have a tight budget the adjustments are made in the cybersecurity sector. However, experts argue that if an organization can invest in cybersecurity in a calculative and timely manner, it increases their profit and productivity to a large extent!  </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If businesses invest in Cybersecurity tools today, they could now avoid a potential large scale cyber attack in the future which might catch them off-guard and make them pay a fortune in retributions after an attack. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s how an investment in cybersecurity could in fact result in profit, even though at first glance it might look like an expense. </span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>To Increase Productivity</b></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Believe it or not, cybersecurity is directly related to productivity. Mostly because we are in an era where every type of business is now dependent on the internet in one way or another. Now, in case of a cyberattack, the natural flow of business is surely interrupted. In case of a data breach, until the whole situation is assessed regular workflow simply can not be resumed. If the scenario is worse and there is a </span><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ransomware attack</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, surely all the PCs affected by it will be locked and unusable. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, the cost of business income disruption and lost productivity due to a lack of cybersecurity is clearly visible. And the solution clearly is to invest in cybersecurity.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, investing in your employees, helping them bolster their cyber knowledge by attending online and offline cybersecurity courses help boost overall productivity. It&#8217;s undeniably true that when workers feel like their range of abilities is being upgraded and the business is putting resources into their learning, they feel more leaned to improve at their positions. </span></p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Brand Recognition and Customer Trust</b></h3>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Step into the shoes of a customer and ask yourself, for if there is more than one choice for a certain product or service, which one would you choose? The one which had previous incidents of cybersecurity-related issues or the one which is clear of any such incident? Companies spend millions of dollars just to create brand awareness and customer trust.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When clients realize that a business site is secure and it has a history of ensuring client information with determination, they are inclined to make purchases from it. Today, more and more people are getting extremely mindful and wary with regard to their information protection and security. Therefore, organizations that have incorporated strong network protection and IT support arrangements into their environments, are bound to improve sales in the long run as customers feel safer to make transactions there. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are our top-pick to answer the question that why businesses should invest in cybersecurity. Can you think of any other reasons? Do let us know in the comment section. We regularly post cybersecurity updates and articles on our blog site, subscribe to get early notifications. Keep connected on our </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/reveantivirus/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/reve-antivirus/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">LinkedIn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> page for continuous updates as well.   </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/invest-in-cybersecurity" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 4 Reasons Businesses Should Invest In Cybersecurity Right Now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/invest-in-cybersecurity/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint Security and Stand-alone Antivirus Software: How do they work? Which One Do You Need?</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/endpoint-security-and-antivirus-differences</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/endpoint-security-and-antivirus-differences#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SME Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[antivirus software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[endpoint security solutions]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[enterprise security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REVE antivirus]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8451</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Endpoint security and Antivirus, two terms are from the same industry and have many fundamental things in common in between them. However, these two similar yet technically different software are often confusing to a lot of decision-makers, let alone the mass. Differentiating and choosing the right fit for your need [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/endpoint-security-and-antivirus-differences" data-wpel-link="internal">Endpoint Security and Stand-alone Antivirus Software: How do they work? Which One Do You Need?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8456" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8456" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8456" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/featureed-1024x536.jpg" alt="mac and typewriter comparison" width="600" height="314" /><p id="caption-attachment-8456" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Choose the best protection for your pc</strong></p></div>
<p><b>Endpoint security and Antivirus</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, two terms are from the same industry and have many fundamental things in common in between them. However, these two similar yet technically different software are often confusing to a lot of decision-makers, let alone the mass. Differentiating and choosing the right fit for your need can often be baffling. So, today, you will get to know more about these two similar yet different software which will help you decide to pick the one better suited for your convenience.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Current Scenario of SMBs Cyber Security</span></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before jumping into the technical details and all, let’s look at some data regarding cybersecurity in small and medium-sized businesses. In mid-2019, global communication giant </span><a href="https://enterprise.verizon.com/resources/reports/2019/2019-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verizon published a DBIR</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Data Breach Investigations Report ) which indicates, 71% of data breaches are motivated to gain some kind of a financial benefit and 43% of total data breach victims are indeed small businesses.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, a </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2020/03/02/one-in-five-smbs-dont-use-any-cybersecurity-heres-what-theyre-putting-at-risk/?sh=5e8246137b95" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">survey conducted by famous Forbes magazine</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> showed more than half of the SMBs believe that they are not a lucrative figure on the radar of the cybercriminals even though one in five of all the small business owners reported some sort of a cyber attack on their organization.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems like, small and medium businesses consider other risk factors like a fire incident or even a robbery and take precautions against them. When, in reality, a cyber attack can wreak havoc and prove to be disastrous for an initiative.</span><b> Therefore, the investment in cybersecurity should be one of the primary focuses for every SMB</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Keeping that in mind, let’s take a look at the options for an enterprise cyber security solution. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Endpoint Protection / Security</span></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><b>What is an Endpoint?</b> <span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For ease of understanding, let’s think of a personal computer device. This pc is owned by the organization but given to a certain employee for his official purpose usage. When working for the office, this pc is connected to a broad official network. Here, the PC we are talking about is an endpoint for that network.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, we can say,</span><b> any device </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">(that can be a laptop, desktop, tablet, mobile phone etc.) </span><b>sitting at the end of a communication network can be considered as an endpoint. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding about endpoint is important because every endpoint is a probable vulnerability that can be a target for cybercrime.</span> Intruders usually take an entry from a single endpoint and gradually infect more machines connected to the network. Today, more and more endpoints are adding continuously from external locations by the means of new device log in to a network parameter and working as an IoT or Internet of Things.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><b>How Does An Endpoint Security Function?</b><b><br />
</b><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/en/product/endpoint-security-solutions" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An endpoint security software</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ensures cyber security for all the endpoints connected to the network. This may include email protection, web protection, creating a firewall, intrusion detection or even an antivirus! </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Endpoint security solution like this is centrally managed so that any administrator can authenticate logins, support remote software deployment and updates from a central console. This is more suited for business or commercial use where a large number of pcs are connected in a single network may be under a single roof or connected from home.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Standalone Antivirus Software</span></h2>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><b>What is an Antivirus?</b></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When compared between endpoint solution / endpoint protection/ endpoint security and antivirus, usually antivirus is a term more used and well known to the mass. But, how does it work? In simpler words, this is a software that is able to protect a pc from malware by detecting and removing it before it does any harm. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The question might arise as </span><b>what is malware</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">? Well, a malware is a broad term used to define all types of malicious and unwanted code that can harm a computer. A computer virus, worm, trojan, keylogger or </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ransomware</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> all are different forms of malware. And, an antivirus’s job is to detect and restrict any type of function of the malware on the pc it’s giving protection to.   </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><b>How Does A Stand-alone Antivirus Software work?</b></p>
<div id="attachment_8458" style="width: 611px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8458" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-8458" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/imgpsh_fullsize_anim.png" alt="Signature update of antivirus software" width="601" height="286" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/imgpsh_fullsize_anim.png 601w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/imgpsh_fullsize_anim-300x143.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /><p id="caption-attachment-8458" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Signature update of antivirus software</strong></p></div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The work process of an antivirus is computer virus definition and signature-based. There is a database for the antivirus software to look for where numerous virus definitions and signatures are written. What the antivirus software does is, it keeps running in the background of the machine (PC, tablet, mobile, servers etc) it’s installed in, and continuously scans files &amp; directories. At the same time, it taps the database and cross-match the definitions of viruses and if it happens to find a match, it blocks or quarantines that file right away thus protects the machine from a probable attack.</span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the reason, signature update of an antivirus is essential. For every new malware created, there need to be a signature update and antivirus provider companies constantly update their existing databases accordingly. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antivirus is usually available as a stand-alone product, however, it often comes as one component of an endpoint protection solution as well. So, endpoint security and antivirus comes hand in hand in some cases</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing Between An Endpoint Security And Antivirus, Which One Do You Need?</span></h2>
<div id="attachment_8457" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8457" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-8457" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/many-pcs.jpg" alt="multiple screens" width="600" height="314" /><p id="caption-attachment-8457" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Choose the cyber security solution best suits you</strong></p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, after knowing all these, it’s decision-making time, which is a better plan for you? Well, it mostly depends on the size and the type of your organization. Antivirus software is more of a one-to-one solution. This software is targeted to find and remove malicious codes and apps but on a personal level. As the name indicates, this software is dedicated to providing you protection against computer viruses. </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.reveantivirus.com/en" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some modern and advanced antivirus</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> also provides a safety net against worms, trojans, or ransomware. However, there is no central control for a stand-alone service like this.</span></p>
<p><b>You should choose a stand-alone antivirus software for your cyber security if </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">you only require real-time, manual scanning for threat identification and elimination on a personal level. For micro-sized start-ups or small teams working under the same roof, this might be convenient. An antivirus software should also provide you web protection and alerts &amp; notification for any threats.  Do keep in mind to turn on the automatic update option else it will continue to rely on old virus definitions which might be dangerous for your cyber safety. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the contrary, endpoint security provides a more holistic protection for each machine connected to the network. The idea of an endpoint security product is to take a bunch of computers under a single network and provide cyber safety to each of them. So centralized management console is a fundamental feature here. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, to ensure cybersecurity ask yourself specific questions, does your organization have a lot of inter-connected PCs? Is the Internet of Things (IoT) in rapid growth in your environment? Does it require network-independent, real-time monitoring? Are there remote workers in your company? Or does it have a “bring your own device” policy in effect? </span><b>If all or most of the answers are yes, then you need to invest in an endpoint security solution</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With all the discussions above, we hope you now have a precise idea on which one to choose between endpoint security and antivirus. For any confusion or consultation, feel free to leave a comment here on the comment box below or contact us anytime at </span><a href="mailto:support@reveantivirus.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">support@reveantivirus.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Follow us on </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/reveantivirus/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/reve-antivirus/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">LinkedIn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for recent cyber security trends, updates and information. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/endpoint-security-and-antivirus-differences" data-wpel-link="internal">Endpoint Security and Stand-alone Antivirus Software: How do they work? Which One Do You Need?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/endpoint-security-and-antivirus-differences/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Cybersecurity Practices Every Small Business Should Follow</title>
      <link>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment</link>
      <comments>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shahriar Rahman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 09:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[BD English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cyber Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security awareness tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware attacks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/?p=8438</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cyber attacks are the new talk of the town and small businesses are the latest victims of the scam. Let’s look at the top 6 best practices that every small organization should follow for a better cyber secured, safer environment.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 6 Cybersecurity Practices Every Small Business Should Follow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-8439" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Internet-11-de-octubre-e1539202498192-1280x720-1024x576.jpg" alt="best practices for a cyber secured environment" width="600" height="338" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Internet-11-de-octubre-e1539202498192-1280x720-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Internet-11-de-octubre-e1539202498192-1280x720-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Internet-11-de-octubre-e1539202498192-1280x720-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Internet-11-de-octubre-e1539202498192-1280x720-e1635739442719.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every giant organization we look at today probably was a start-up or small-scale operation in the past. Understanding the trend and taking the right decision at the right time has helped them to reach the pinnacle they are today. As the resources are always scarce and there are endless needs to be fulfilled, a small business has to prioritize its needs before addressing them. Sad as it may sound, the priority of cybersecurity is seldom found in such priority lists, let alone near the top. Keeping the fact in mind that a cyber-attack can wreak havoc to any organization independent of its size or presence, all of them should turn their focus to cybersecurity. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>This post addresses some best practices for a cyber secured environment that every small business should follow</strong>. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Back it up, Always!</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-7752" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/offpage_AV_5-min-1024x536.jpg" alt="data backup" width="600" height="314" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/offpage_AV_5-min-1024x536.jpg 1024w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/offpage_AV_5-min-300x157.jpg 300w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/offpage_AV_5-min-768x402.jpg 768w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/offpage_AV_5-min.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everybody has an Achilles hill, and the vulnerability is often found only after an incident. On an occasion where precious data is somehow lost or encrypted by a </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/mitigate-ransomware-attack-loss" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ransomware attack</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, your best friend would be, you guessed it right, the data you backed up earlier! </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So best practices for a cyber secured environment include the practice of regular data backup. Ransomware attacks are on the rise, companies are still getting locked out of their information because they did not back it up properly in the past. A study predicted that </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7575251/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">in 2021 there will be a new ransomware victim every 11 seconds</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">! Therefore, Make sure your small business does not fall into the same trap, make sure to make data back up your habit! Data backup should be performed on all the computers. Experts now suggest moving to cloud storage for data backup as it’s modern and more secured.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Employee Awareness On Cybersecurity Is Vital</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to the cybersecurity of an organization, no matter small or big, often it comes down to how aware all the employees are. Nowadays all of the organizational pcs are connected to one another which makes each of the employee’s pc an endpoint. So, a great cybersecurity threat is, an attack can come from any one of these. As a result, employee awareness is a vital point of best practices for a cyber secured environment. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a small business, a precise internet use and network sharing guideline should not only be established but also strictly followed. In addition, regular training on cybersecurity and monitoring on how the employees are following the company cybersecurity protocols should be maintained. Basic security practices such as using a strong password, using different passwords for different accounts, using multi-factor authentication etc should be implemented and encouraged. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Put Your Cyber Readiness To Test</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best way to determine the current cybersecurity of your small business is to put cyber readiness to the test. Just like a fire drill, one way to do this is by simulating an actual cyber crisis. Maybe a large portion of the employees are reluctant on changing their password to a strong one, maybe others are not updating their cybersecurity solution’s security update, or in the worse case, their firewall is simply turned off. Some may fall victim to a very simple phishing scam. All of these are better to be exposed on a drill than an original attack which is why a tabletop exercise is a beneficial way to find and patch up the weaknesses. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Control Data Flow From Your Organization, Internet Security Firewall And Wi-Fi Networks</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Controlling data flow is another step towards ensuring best practices for a cyber secured environment. Setting up a firewall that prevents any outsider from accessing data on a private network would be your friend here. On a personal level, all unauthorized access to business computers should be prevented. Administrative access should be made as scarce as possible and only the trusted, experienced key personnel should have it. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to this, the source of the incoming data should also be monitored. Organizational Wi-Fi networks should be set up in such a way that it does not broadcast the SSID (Service Set Identifier) and it’s encrypted, hidden and secured. Finally, regularly check the employee access to data and information. Each employee should have access to the exact amount of data they need, not more not less. The protection of sensitive data should be configured accordingly as well. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Hackers Will Value Your Small Business Even if You Don’t</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-8256 size-full" src="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Untitled-1.jpg" alt="5 Key Cybersecurity Concerns during Covid-19 Pandemic" width="600" height="314" srcset="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Untitled-1.jpg 600w, https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Untitled-1-300x157.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small scale businesses are often under the delusion that their operation is too small to attract the intruders therefore a full-scale cybersecurity solution is probably not necessary for them. However, the true scenario is the opposite, no matter the size of the organization, if a cybercriminal can gain access to the data it’s his gain. Moreover, as the day progresses the cyberattacks are becoming more and more convoluted. Often the hackers use data stolen from a company to initiate an attack on another entity.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bottom line, as a small business owner, don’t fool yourself thinking you do not need any cybersecurity, everyone does! Even if you devalue your company, a potential opportunity-seeking hacker won’t.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Invest In A Modern Cybersecurity Solution Before It’s Too Late</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small businesses are often high-value targets for hackers. Fortunately, there are </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/en" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">modern professional complete cybersecurity tools</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that can build up a defensive wall against any potential cyber threats. Relying on these automated tools to take care of your vulnerability is a great idea. There are many forms of security layers, vulnerability scanners, internet security, </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/en/product/endpoint-security-solutions" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">endpoint security</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> etc. Prevention is better than cure, a wise man would invest in his organizational cybersecurity today instead of paying the ransom some time into the future. So, best practices of a cyber secured environment include a fixed amount of allocation for every small business.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>We</strong> are already into the cyber era. The more things are getting digital, threats for a full-scale cyber attack are creeping up as well. So, a small business without a focus on cybersecurity is just sitting ducks for the cybercriminals. As prevention is always better than cure and it is high time to turn the focus of organizations into cybersecurity, especially the small businesses. As </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/en/cyber-security-for-remote-workers" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="internal"><span style="font-weight: 400;">work from home is becoming a new norm</span></a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, if your organization has employees working from home, the task might become a bit arduous. However, the same protocols should be implemented and followed by them as well for the well-being of the entire organization.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment" data-wpel-link="internal">Top 6 Cybersecurity Practices Every Small Business Should Follow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal">REVE Antivirus</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.reveantivirus.com/blog/blog/best-practices-for-a-cyber-secured-environment/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>