<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Safety Detectives</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:23:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Interview With Boris Gorin – Canonic Security</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/interview-boris-gorin-canonic-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Aviva Zacks]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=92405</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CANONIC-300x196.png" alt=""></p>With many thanks to Boris Gorin, Canonic Security&#8217;s CEO and Co-Founder, Aviva Zacks of Safety Detectives found out why his company focuses on SaaS with its AppTotal. Safety Detectives: What motivated you to start Canonic Security? Boris Gorin: From my significant background in SaaS security, I started to see gaps in security and recognized that [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CANONIC-300x196.png" alt=""></p><p><strong><em>With many thanks to Boris Gorin, Canonic Security&#8217;s CEO and Co-Founder, Aviva Zacks of Safety Detectives found out why his company focuses on SaaS with its AppTotal.</em></strong></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><b>Safety Detectives: What motivated you to start Canonic Security?</b><b></b></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><strong>Boris Gorin:</strong> From my significant background in SaaS security, I started to see gaps in security and recognized that while SaaS adoption continued to exponentially grow, our industry was not addressing the security challenges that came along with the modernized digitally transformed SaaS-native security platforms. Traditional security solutions were not designed to protect SaaS-native security platforms and because of this, vulnerabilities were increasing for those infrastructures not paying close attention to the interactions between processes, platform integrations, and API calls. It became clear that our industry needed more visibility into data so that security and governance teams could have a complete view of any vulnerabilities in their infrastructure among thousands of dynamically changing apps.</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><b>SD: What do you love about working in cybersecurity?</b><b></b></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><strong>BG:</strong> Cybersecurity has always been driven by a tightly-knit community of innovators. Inevitably, the nature of innovation pushes our community to create a home-grown toolset to get the job done. I tend to focus on helping the cybersecurity community do the best job that we can together. In the context of <a href="https://www.canonic.security/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">Canonic Security</a>, SaaS app security is a case in point. We believe that is where the low-hanging fruit lies—for the attackers first and foremost. I’ve been in cybersecurity long enough to understand that any attack vector interesting to actual attackers and white hat Red Teams will trickle down throughout the enterprise. We see that dynamic playing out in the domain of SaaS security as well.</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><b>SD: What is Canonic Security’s flagship product?</b><b></b></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><strong>BG:</strong> AppTotal is the industry’s first publicly available community offering that automatically assesses the risks involved with OAuth apps. It essentially builds on Canonic Security’s app sandboxing technology, and dynamically scans SaaS add-ons for vulnerabilities and suspicious or malicious behavior.</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">AppTotal lets organizations profile third-party apps&#8217; permissions and access, posture, and behavior before connecting them to IT-approved applications. It is the first independent and continuously updated SaaS add-ons and integrations index, starting with Google Workspace, Microsoft 365/Azure, and Slack, with Atlassian, Salesforce, and others coming soon.</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">With AppTotal, anyone can:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">Assess the risks involved with third-party apps before granting them access to your environment</li>
<li class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">Uncover the app and publisher behind any OAuth client ID</li>
<li class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">Analyze the behavior of third-party apps within your SaaS platform</li>
</ul>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal">It’s also a community tool, and we’d love to get reader feedback!</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><b>SD: How does Canonic Security stay competitive in a world filled with cybersecurity companies?</b><b></b></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><strong>BG:</strong> Business continuity will continue to heavily rely on SaaS apps and low code automation as companies continue to integrate third-party APIs on top of subscription based platforms. While businesses are taking full advantage of the ease and access of interconnected apps, the resulting productivity benefits increase the risks associated with a growing attack surface. Canonic Security’s app governance platform provides full visibility over apps and API integrations with access intelligence, vulnerability insight, and the industry’s first free community application security sandbox. Canonic is redefining SaaS application security with this unique sandbox environment that provides users with quick access to simulate and vet third-party integrations—a very valuable resource for companies as they grow increasingly more dependent on interconnected SaaS apps.</p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><b>SD: How is the pandemic changing cybersecurity for the future?</b><b></b></p>
<p class="yiv8552167496MsoNormal"><strong>BG:</strong> As organizations continue to adopt remote working regardless of health risks, employees are driven to use cloud services to get the job done. That means taking a closer look at how third-party platforms share sensitive data and present new risks for companies that are not necessarily SaaS-borne. It is imperative for enterprises immersed in technological innovation driving a shift in business culture to rethink SaaS application governance so that the required checks and balances are in place when it comes to data, system, and account access. Unfortunately, many companies are just starting to realize that SaaS environments are uniquely exposed to attackers and easy to miss vulnerabilities. Accelerated by the adoption of more cloud platforms, security teams and business decision-makers alike are reimagining how to approach SaaS security in general and third-party app governance in particular.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magniber Ransomware Targets Users While Posing as Windows 10 Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/magniber-ransomware-targets-users-while-posing-as-windows-10-updates/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 06:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=92383</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Windows-300x225.png" alt=""></p>A new ransomware campaign, called Magniber, is targeting Windows users that download pirated content. This campaign reportedly began late last month. Since April 27, an increasing number of victims have shared their stories on the BleepingComputer forum in search of a solution. According to reports from the publication, the ransomware disguises itself as Windows 10 updates and [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Windows-300x225.png" alt=""></p><p><strong>A new ransomware campaign, called Magniber, is targeting Windows users that download pirated content. This campaign reportedly began late last month.</strong></p>
<p>Since April 27, an increasing number of victims have <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/forums/t/771427/magniber-2022-ransomware-cyvpbwzfv-lpdyefulm-yyqiidt-support-topic/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">shared their stories</a> on the <i>BleepingComputer</i> forum in search of a solution. <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fake-windows-10-updates-infect-you-with-magniber-ransomware/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">According to reports from the publication</a>, the ransomware disguises itself as Windows 10 updates and gets distributed through fraudulent warez and crack sites.</p>
<p>The ransomware then deletes shadow volume copies and encrypts files after being run, attaching a random 8-character extension.</p>
<p>Afterward, victims are sent a ransomware note which instructs them to install the Tor browser and access a custom url address for their specific individual case.</p>
<p>The Magniber payment site instructs victims on how to negotiate and pay for their ransom payment in Bitcoin. Victims are also allowed to decrypt one file for free, in order to demonstrate the validity of Magniber’s claims.</p>
<p>“The only 1 way to decrypt your files is to receive the private key and decryption program,” the ransom note reads. “Any attempts to restore your files with the third party software will be fatal for your files!”</p>
<p><strong>Reportedly, most ransom demands have been for approximately 0.068 bitcoin (or $2,500).</strong></p>
<p>Since Magniber is considered secure, there are no weaknesses on its website that can be exploited in order to recover users’ files free of charge.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Senators Call on Zelle to Fight Money Transfer Scams and Protect Consumers</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/us-senators-call-on-zelle-to-fight-money-transfer-scams-and-protect-consumers/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=92074</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/US-Senate-300x204.jpg" alt=""></p>US Senators Bob Menendez, D-N.J. and Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass. have called on the company behind Zelle to do more to protect consumers from money transfer scams and help get money back into their accounts. “This widespread fraud on money transfer apps has affected nearly 18 million Americans,” the lawmakers wrote in a letter on Tuesday to [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/US-Senate-300x204.jpg" alt=""></p><p><strong>US Senators Bob Menendez, D-N.J. and Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass. have called on the company behind Zelle to do more to protect consumers from money transfer scams and help get money back into their accounts.</strong></p>
<p>“This widespread fraud on money transfer apps has affected nearly 18 million Americans,” the lawmakers <a href="https://www.menendez.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/menendez_letter_to_zelle_on_scams_and_fraud.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">wrote</a> in a letter on Tuesday to Zelle’s parent company, Early Warning Systems. “Given the rise of increasingly sophisticated scams on your platform and the widely documented difficulties consumers have faced in seeking relief from banks, we seek to understand the extent to which Zelle allows fraud to flourish and the steps your company is taking to increase consumer protection and help users recover lost funds.”</p>
<p>Early Warning Systems, LLC. is owned by seven of the U.S.’s largest banks, including Bank of America, Wells Fargo, J.P. Morgan Chase, Capital One, PNC, Truist, and U.S. Bank.</p>
<p>Early Warning Systems told reporters that it has received the letter and “will provide a response in due course.”</p>
<p><strong>The senators said that Zelle has handled more than $490 billion in transactions in 2021, doubling its nearest competitor Venmo.</strong></p>
<p>“Alarmingly, both your company and the big banks who both own and partner with the platform have abdicated responsibility for fraudulent transactions, leaving consumers with no way to get back their funds,” the lawmakers said. “Zelle’s biggest draw — the immediacy of its transfers — also makes scams more effective and a favorite of fraudsters, as consumers have no option to cancel a transaction even moments after authorizing it.”</p>
<p>“And banks have chosen to let consumers suffer, blaming them for authorizing fraudulent transactions,” they added.</p>
<p>The senators said the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) and the FDIC previously clarified that <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/boarddocs/supmanual/cch/efta.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">Regulation E</a> of the <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/boarddocs/caletters/2008/0807/08-07_attachment.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">Electronic Fund Transfer Act</a> protected victims of fraudulent money transfers, including those who were induced into transferring the money themselves. They also cited an FDIC <a href="https://www.fdic.gov/regulations/examinations/consumer-compliance-supervisory-highlights/documents/ccs-highlights-march2022.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">report</a> from March “finding that the banks and the platform were both responsible for fraudulent electronic transfers through this regulation.”</p>
<p><strong>In one case, a man <a href="https://www.nj.com/news/2022/02/man-loses-2800-after-fraudster-impersonates-his-bank-heres-how-it-happened.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">lost $2,800</a> after being deceived into making a Zelle transfer after he received a text saying there were fraudulent transactions on his Wells Fargo account.</strong></p>
<p>“Hindsight being 20/20, I see how stupid this sounds now but I was following the directions from the verified bank employee and felt confident that she had my best interest in mind,” he said. “Obviously that was false.”</p>
<p>Wells Fargo ended up refunding the money, but that usually doesn’t happen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Offers $10M Reward for Information About Russian Hackers Behind NotPetya Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/us-offers-10m-reward-for-information-about-russian-hackers-behind-notpetya-attack/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 06:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=92065</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Russia-Blocks-Tor-300x167.jpg" alt=""></p>The United States has offered $10 million to anyone who has information regarding the Russian military hackers who orchestrated the notorious NotPeyta cyberattack. NotPetya first appeared in June 2017 and was spread via a poisoned update to a Ukrainian accounts program widely used by businesses in the country. Victims found their data scrambled by the [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Russia-Blocks-Tor-300x167.jpg" alt=""></p><p><strong>The United States has offered $10 million to anyone who has information regarding the Russian military hackers who orchestrated the notorious NotPeyta cyberattack.</strong></p>
<p>NotPetya first appeared in June 2017 and was spread via a poisoned update to a Ukrainian accounts program widely used by businesses in the country.</p>
<p>Victims found their data scrambled by the ransomware as a result of this attack. One high-profile victim was Pavlo Rozenko, who at the time was the deputy prime minister of Ukraine. He <a href="https://twitter.com/RozenkoPavlo/status/879677026256510976" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">posted</a> on Twitter a photo of his PC, which was in the process of being encrypted by NotPetya.</p>
<p>However, victims of the attack were not limited to Ukraine. NotPetya targeted power plants, airports, and government computers in dozens of countries. Victims included pharmaceutical firm Merck, law firm DLA Piper, container ship operator Maersk, and British advertising company WPP.</p>
<p><strong>In its <a href="https://www.state.gov/rewards-for-justice-reward-offer-for-information-on-russian-military-intelligence-officers-conducting-malicious-activity-against-u-s-critical-infrastructure/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">announcement</a> on Tuesday about the reward, US authorities revealed that NotPetya had cost American organizations around $1 billion in losses.</strong></p>
<p>“These cyber intrusions damaged the computers of hospitals and other medical facilities in the Heritage Valley Health System (Heritage Valley) in western Pennsylvania, a large U.S. pharmaceutical manufacturer, and other US private sector entities,” US State Department said.</p>
<p>The six men named by the US authorities are GRU officers Yuriy Sergeyevich Andrienko, Sergey Vladimirovich Detistov, Pavel Valeryevich Frolov, Anatoliy Sergeyevich Kovalev, Artem Valeryevich Ochichenko, and Petr Nikolayevich Pliskin.</p>
<p>A federal grand jury <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/six-russian-gru-officers-charged-connection-worldwide-deployment-destructive-malware-and" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">indicted</a> the six Russian officers in October 2020 on counts of conspiracy to conduct computer fraud and abuse, conspiracy to commit wire fraud, wire fraud, damaging protected computers, and aggravated identity theft.</p>
<p>The Russian military hacking group associated with the men has also been implicated in a series of cyber attacks against Ukrainian critical infrastructure and government departments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stormous Ransomware Gang Claims to Have Hacked Coca-Cola</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/stormous-ransomware-gang-claims-to-have-hacked-coca-cola/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=92022</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Coca-Cola-300x169.jpg" alt=""></p>Russian-linked ransomware gang Stormous claimed to breach the servers of US soft drink giant Coca-Cola in April. Stormous said in a post to its website on Monday that it took 161 GBs worth of data, including financial information, credentials, and other sensitive information from Coca-Cola’s servers on April 24. The threat actor is now trying to [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Coca-Cola-300x169.jpg" alt=""></p><p><strong>Russian-linked <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/blog/can-antivirus-prevent-ransomware/" target="_blank">ransomware</a> gang Stormous claimed to breach the servers of US soft drink giant Coca-Cola in April.</strong></p>
<p>Stormous said in a post to its website on Monday that it took 161 GBs worth of data, including financial information, credentials, and other sensitive information from Coca-Cola’s servers on April 24. The threat actor is now trying to sell the collection of stolen data for a little over 1.6 Bitcoin ($64,000).</p>
<p><strong>The attack on Coca-Cola appears to have been orchestrated after Stormous took a poll on Telegram, asking followers to help choose their next victim.</strong></p>
<p>In an announcement last month, the ransomware group also pledged its full support for the Russian government after it invaded Ukraine.</p>
<p>“The STORMOUS team has officially announced its support for the Russian governments,” the group <a href="https://twitter.com/darktracer_int/status/1498644747316981762" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">said</a> in a message in March. “And if any party in different parts of the world decides to organize a cyberattack or cyberattacks against Russia, we will be in the right direction and will make all our efforts to abandon the supplication of the West, especially the infrastructure.”</p>
<p>The soft drink giant has not yet confirmed if the alleged ransomware attack has taken place. Although, Coca-Cola said that it is working with law enforcement and forensic teams to check out Stormous’ claims.</p>
<p>“We are aware of this matter and are investigating to determine the validity of the claim,” Coca-Cola communications vice president Scott Leith <a href="https://therecord.media/coca-cola-investigating-claims-of-hack-after-ransomware-group-hawks-stolen-data/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">commented</a> for The Record.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/breastcancer-leak-report/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[SafetyDetectives Cybersecurity Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=89144</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/US-Charity-Exposed-Users-300x158.png" alt=""></p>Intro Breastcancer.org, a world-renowned breast cancer charity, has suffered a data exposure affecting users of the organization’s website. The SafetyDetectives cybersecurity team found an Amazon S3 bucket owned by Breastcancer.org that was misconfigured, left publicly available without any authentication controls in place. Breastcancer.org’s misconfigured bucket has therefore exposed hundreds of thousands of files containing sensitive [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/US-Charity-Exposed-Users-300x158.png" alt=""></p><h2>Intro</h2>
<p>Breastcancer.org, a world-renowned breast cancer charity, has suffered a data exposure affecting users of the organization’s website.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/" target="_blank">SafetyDetectives</a> cybersecurity team found an Amazon S3 bucket owned by Breastcancer.org that was misconfigured, left publicly available without any authentication controls in place.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org’s misconfigured bucket has therefore exposed hundreds of thousands of files containing <strong>sensitive images</strong> belonging to the <strong>website’s users. </strong>In particular, a portion of these images contained detailed <strong>EXIF data</strong>, which could potentially be used to locate and harass users.</p>
<p>This exposure points toward the variety of information that can be recovered from the images we post online.</p>
<h2>Who is Breastcancer.org?</h2>
<p>Founded in 2000, Breastcancer.org is a non-profit organization with a commitment to provide the latest scientifically-backed research on breast cancer and breast health for free through its website.</p>
<p>The organization hopes to empower women to make the right decisions in life, with content that simplifies a vast corpus of complex and confusing medical information.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org’s published resources are fact-checked by a team of 70+ practicing medical professionals. Outside of the site’s guidance articles, visitors can also find medical news resources, videos, podcasts, webinars, peer-to-peer discussion boards, personalized content recommendations, and Spanish-language resources.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org is based in Ardmore, Pennsylvania, in the United States, and receives over 28 million web visitors every year according to its website. Throughout its history, Breastcancer.org has reached 220,000 registered members and 174 million people across the world.</p>
<h2>What was Exposed?</h2>
<p>Breastcancer.org’s unsecured bucket exposed over 350,000 files, totaling around 150 GB of data. The bucket exposed the <strong>sensitive images </strong>of Breastcancer.org’s <strong>website users.</strong></p>
<p>There were two separate datasets exposed on Breastcancer.org’s bucket:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>User avatars</strong></li>
<li><strong>Post images</strong></li>
</ul>
<h3>User Avatars</h3>
<p><strong>User avatars </strong>are profile pictures taken from the accounts of Breastcancer.org users. The bucket contained <strong>over 50,000 user avatars</strong>. Many of the avatars featured <strong>images of registered users.</strong></p>
<p>While this is publicly available information, user avatars could be used in conjunction with EXIF data to identify vulnerable users.</p>
<p>You can see examples of user avatars in the following images.</p>
<div id="attachment_89146" style="width: 599px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-89146" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-89146 size-full" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1.jpeg" alt="US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images" width="589" height="395" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1.jpeg 589w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-300x201.jpeg 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-150x101.jpeg 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-65x44.jpeg 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-280x188.jpeg 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-560x376.jpeg 560w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-220x148.jpeg 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-1-440x295.jpeg 440w" sizes="(max-width: 589px) 100vw, 589px" /><p id="caption-attachment-89146" class="wp-caption-text">A couple pictured in one user avatar</p></div>

<div id="attachment_89147" style="width: 599px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-89147" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-89147 size-full" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2.jpeg" alt="US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images" width="589" height="784" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2.jpeg 589w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-225x300.jpeg 225w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-128x170.jpeg 128w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-65x87.jpeg 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-280x373.jpeg 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-560x745.jpeg 560w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-300x399.jpeg 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-150x200.jpeg 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-220x293.jpeg 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-2-440x586.jpeg 440w" sizes="(max-width: 589px) 100vw, 589px" /><p id="caption-attachment-89147" class="wp-caption-text">A man pictured in another user avatar</p></div>

<h3>Post Images</h3>
<p><strong>Post images </strong>were uploaded to Breastcancer.org by its users. The bucket contained<strong> over 300,000</strong> post images and <strong>EXIF data </strong>was attached to each post image. EXIF data exposes numerous details about the format of an image and the context in which it was captured.</p>
<p>EXIF data in post images included:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Device details, </strong>i.e. brand and model of the camera used.</li>
<li><strong>GPS location</strong> of the captured image.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some post images featured <strong>sensitive content </strong>that felt as though it was intended for private viewing. For example, there were results from medical tests and images of nudity (most likely taken for medical purposes) included among the files — contents that a user would not typically post publicly.</p>
<p>We decided to test whether post images were uploaded from public posts or private messages. We created two breastcancer.org accounts and sent an image from one account to the other. The image we sent later appeared in the bucket, confirming our suspicion that private images were exposed.</p>
<p>You can see evidence of post images below.</p>
<div id="attachment_89148" style="width: 599px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-89148" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-89148 size-full" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3.jpeg" alt="US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images" width="589" height="332" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3.jpeg 589w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-150x85.jpeg 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-65x37.jpeg 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-280x158.jpeg 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-560x316.jpeg 560w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-220x124.jpeg 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-3-440x248.jpeg 440w" sizes="(max-width: 589px) 100vw, 589px" /><p id="caption-attachment-89148" class="wp-caption-text">A picture of a nude woman on the bucket</p></div>

<div id="attachment_89149" style="width: 498px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-89149" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-89149 size-full" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4.jpeg" alt="US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images" width="488" height="867" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4.jpeg 488w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-169x300.jpeg 169w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-96x170.jpeg 96w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-65x115.jpeg 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-280x497.jpeg 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-300x533.jpeg 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-150x266.jpeg 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-220x391.jpeg 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-4-440x782.jpeg 440w" sizes="(max-width: 488px) 100vw, 488px" /><p id="caption-attachment-89149" class="wp-caption-text">One user’s ultrasound results</p></div>

<div id="attachment_89150" style="width: 765px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-89150" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-89150 size-full" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5.png" alt="US Charity Exposed Users’ Sensitive Images" width="755" height="870" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5.png 755w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-260x300.png 260w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-148x170.png 148w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-65x75.png 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-280x323.png 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-560x645.png 560w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-300x346.png 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-600x691.png 600w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-672x774.png 672w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-150x173.png 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-220x254.png 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/us-charity-exposed-users-sensitive-images-5-440x507.png 440w" sizes="(max-width: 755px) 100vw, 755px" /><p id="caption-attachment-89150" class="wp-caption-text">EXIF data exposed a range of info specific to each image</p></div>

<p>Breastcancer.org’s open bucket was live and being updated at the time of discovery.</p>
<p>It is important to note that Amazon doesn’t manage Breastcancer.org’s bucket and this misconfiguration is not Amazon’s responsibility.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org reaches users around the world and we’d expect there are a significant number of American and European users with images on the bucket.</p>
<p>The Breastcancer.org website suggests it has over 200,000 registered users, though, it seems unlikely that all of these users are exposed based on the bucket’s files. There are over 50,000 user avatars on the bucket, so 50,000 should stand as a minimum estimate of the number of users exposed.</p>
<p>The number of exposed people could be higher, however, considering that users could be exposed in post images even if their user avatar is not included on the bucket.</p>
<p>You can see a full breakdown of Breastcancer.org’s data exposure in the table below.</p>
<table class="no-header">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of files exposed</td>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">350,000+</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of affected users</td>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">50,000+</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Size of breach</td>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Around 150 GB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">Company location</td>
<td colspan="1" rowspan="1">USA</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>We discovered Breastcancer.org’s unsecured bucket on November 11th, 2021. It contained files dating back to April 2017, though, filenames suggest some of these images date back to 2014 and were migrated to the bucket in 2017. We saw recent files on the bucket, too, dated mid-November 2021. This suggests the bucket was still in use when we found it.</p>
<p>On November 17th, 2021, we messaged breastcancer.org regarding its data exposure. We sent another message to both newly-found and previously-contacted people from the organization on November 21st, 2021. We didn’t receive a reply and on December 14th, 2021, we sent further messages to AWS, the US Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT), and additional breastcancer.org employees regarding this data exposure.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org and its users could experience various impacts as a result of this incident.</p>
<h2>Data Exposure Impact</h2>
<p>We cannot and do not know whether malicious actors accessed the content of Breastcancer.org’s S3 bucket. With no security controls in place, hackers and cybercriminals could have read or downloaded the bucket’s images. This data could be used to subject users to criminal activities.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org may also face legal implications for the status of its AWS S3 bucket.</p>
<h3>Impact on Users</h3>
<p>Exposed Breastcancer.org users could experience forms of<strong> harassment </strong>if hackers accessed the bucket’s data.</p>
<p>There are no contact details belonging to users exposed on the open bucket. However, cybercriminals could target EXIF data to identify users. A picture of a person’s house, for example, could be used to locate that person if geolocation data is attached.</p>
<p>Malicious actors could identify vulnerable users to launch vicious and spiteful attacks against them. Hackers could reference a person’s medical condition or nude images to berate them with hurtful comments. With GPS locations exposed on the server, online harassment could spill over into the real world.</p>
<h3>Impact on Breastcancer.org</h3>
<p>Breastcancer.org may be investigated by data protection authorities in several jurisdictions for exposing users’ data. It’s more than likely Breastcancer.org has users from nations around the world exposed on the bucket. However, we won’t check the location data of exposed photos for ethical reasons.</p>
<p>Breastcancer.org could come under the scrutiny of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) if the organization has mishandled the data of US citizens. The FTC protects consumers from unfair or deceptive business acts or practices. Any breach of the FTC Act could land Breastcancer.org with a maximum penalty of US$100 million or the imprisonment of guilty individuals in severe cases.</p>
<h2>Preventing Data Exposure</h2>
<p>What steps can users take to mitigate the risk of data exposure and cybercrime?</p>
<p>Here are a few tips to prevent data exposure:</p>
<ul>
<li>Only provide your personal information to companies, organizations, and entities that you trust 100%.</li>
<li>Only visit websites with a secure domain name (i.e. websites that have a “https” and/or closed lock symbol at the beginning of their name).</li>
<li>Be especially vigilant when providing your most sensitive forms of data, such as your social security number.</li>
<li>Create super-strong passwords that use a mix of letters, numbers, and symbols, and update these passwords regularly.</li>
<li>Don’t click a link online unless you’re certain the source is legitimate. This includes links in emails, messages, or phishing websites that are masquerading as a legitimate domain.</li>
<li>Edit your privacy settings on social media sites. Your social media accounts should only display content to friends and trusted users.</li>
<li>Avoid displaying or typing important and highly-sensitive forms of data (such as credit card numbers or passwords) when connected to a public or unsecured WiFi network.</li>
<li>Educate yourself about cybercrime, data protection, and the methods that reduce your chances of falling victim to phishing attacks and malware.</li>
</ul>
<h2>About Us</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/" target="_blank">SafetyDetectives.com</a> is the world’s largest antivirus review website.</p>
<p>The SafetyDetectives research lab is a pro bono service that aims to help the online community defend itself against cyber threats while educating organizations on how to protect their users’ data. The overarching purpose of our web mapping project is to help make the internet a safer place for all users.</p>
<p>Our previous reports have brought multiple high-profile vulnerabilities and data leaks to light, including 2.6 million users exposed by an <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/blog/igblade-leak-report/" target="_blank">American social analytics platform IGBlade</a>, as well as a breach at a <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/blog/hariexpress-leak-report/" target="_blank">Brazilian Marketplace Integrator platform Hariexpress.com.br</a> that leaked more than 610 GB of data.</p>
<p>For a full review of SafetyDetectives cybersecurity reporting over the past 3 years, follow <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/author/sdteam/" target="_blank">SafetyDetectives Cybersecurity Team</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram Hacker Steals Approximately $3 Million Worth of Bored Ape Yacht Club NFTs</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/instagram-hacker-steals-approximately-3-million-worth-of-bored-ape-yacht-club-nfts/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 06:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=91806</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Bored-Ape-Yacht-Club-NFTs-300x200.jpg" alt=""></p>Yuga Labs’ Instagram account, the creators of the popular series of NFT ape profile pictures collectively called the Bored Ape Yacht Club (BAYC), was attacked by hackers on Monday. According to Yuga Labs, a hacker took over the official Instagram account and lured members with fraudulent messages claiming they would receive free tokens if they connected [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Bored-Ape-Yacht-Club-NFTs-300x200.jpg" alt=""></p><p><strong>Yuga Labs’ Instagram account, the creators of the popular series of <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/blog/how-to-stay-safe-when-buying-and-selling-nfts/" target="_blank">NFT</a> ape profile pictures collectively called the Bored Ape Yacht Club (BAYC), was attacked by hackers on Monday.</strong></p>
<p>According to Yuga Labs, a hacker took over the official Instagram account and lured members with fraudulent messages claiming they would receive free tokens if they connected their MetaMask wallets to a site linked through the post.</p>
<p>“This morning, the official BAYC Instagram account was hacked. The hacker posted a fraudulent link to a copycat of the BAYC website with a fake Airdrop, where users were prompted to sign a ‘safeTransferFrom’ transaction,” BAYC <a href="https://twitter.com/BoredApeYC/status/1518637579633053701" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">said</a> in a tweet on Monday. “This transferred their assets to the scammer&#8217;s wallet.”</p>
<p><strong>While BAYC immediately alerted its community, removed the fraudulent links, and regained control of the accounts, the scammer still took off with approximately $3 million worth of NFTs through the hacked Instagram account.</strong></p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.theblockcrypto.com/post/143328/bored-ape-instagram-account-hacked-nfts-worth-2-8-million-stolen" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">reports</a>, Four Bored Apes, six Mutant Apes, and three Bored Ape Kennel Club NFTs were stolen by the hackers, along with other items from upcoming collections.</p>
<p>“You need to contact us first – anybody contacting you first is not us, BAYC warned,” the developers said. “We will not reach out to anyone over email first, and we will NEVER ask for your seed phrase.”</p>
<p>Yuga Labs is still currently investigating the hack and alerted its community to remain vigilant and only seek information from its official web pages.</p>
<p>“We will also NEVER announce mints on the BAYC or Otherside Instagram accounts first, ever,” the BAYC added. “Only obtain information from our official Twitter accounts: @BoredApeYC, @yugalabs, and @OthersideMeta. These will be crossposted on the #announcement channel of BAYC Discord.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview With Max Azarov – Novakid</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/interview-with-max-azarov-novakid/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Aviva Zacks]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 09:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=91709</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/NovaKid-300x196.png" alt=""></p>Aviva Zacks of Safety Detectives interviewed Max Azarov, co-founder and CEO of Novakid. She asked him how his company protects the safety of its primary users—children. Safety Detectives: What motivated you to start your company? Max Azarov: Novakid came about because of a trip that Dmitry (co-founder of Novakid) and I took to the Mobile [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/NovaKid-300x196.png" alt=""></p><p><em><strong>Aviva Zacks of Safety Detectives interviewed Max Azarov, co-founder and CEO of Novakid. She asked him how his company protects the safety of its primary users—children.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Safety Detectives: What motivated you to start your company?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Max Azarov: </strong><a href="https://www.novakidschool.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">Novakid</a> came about because of a trip that Dmitry (co-founder of Novakid) and I took to the Mobile World Congress in June 2017 to promote Cloudike, our first start-up business. In the local subway, we saw huge banners advertising a company called VIP Kid. This took us by surprise, as it made us realize that this type of business is obviously in demand if this is how it is advertised.</p>
<p>I had struggled to find an English teacher for my children. I understood that this was an opportunity because of the issues I had experienced. Offline centers tended to be taught by students and most online services focused on adults.</p>
<p>Dmitry and I both wanted to create a business that was useful and solved a problem. Before the trip to Shanghai, we often discussed the idea of creating a &#8220;box for learning languages&#8221; – a device with a voice bot that would communicate with the user in the format of lessons and adjust the presentation of the material for the user. But this idea wasn’t successful, so we looked at ways to build a platform that incorporated gamification and story-based learning. The result is Novakid!</p>
<p><strong>SD: Tell me about your services.</strong></p>
<p><strong>MA: </strong>Novakid is an online EdTech platform that offers English language learning for children between the ages of 4 and 12 years old. Our mission is to revolutionize English learning through full language immersion, a personalized teaching approach, and the advantages of artificial intelligence (AI) and augmented reality (AR) technologies.</p>
<p>The business was established in 2017 and has grown exponentially since then. We have over 500,000 clients across 49 countries, 70,000 of which are active users. Over 2,4 million classes were delivered by Novakid teachers in 2021, more than double the total lessons are given in 2020. In March 2022, we delivered a record number of lessons in one month – 513,546 completed lessons! In 2021, Novakid was recognized as the number one online English school for children in Europe by J&#8217;son &amp; Partners.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Novakid program develops the main language skills &#8211; speaking, reading, and listening comprehension</li>
<li>We offer an affordable ESL education for families – Novakid operates in the mid-range price category</li>
<li>Our platform operates on a robust IT platform, leveraging AI, AR, and gamification to provide an interactive and engaging learning format for students, as well as a unique machine-learning-based methodology for evaluating student progress. The platform uses over 1,500 parameters, A/B testing, and other data-driven approaches to assess student progress.</li>
<li>We have experienced teaching staff who go through a careful selection and training process to instruct on the Novakid platform.</li>
<li>Lessons are delivered exclusively in English and are only 25 minutes in length.</li>
<li>Edutainment/game-based lessons</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-91717" src="https://www.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses.png" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses.png 1920w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-300x169.png 300w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-1024x576.png 1024w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-768x432.png 768w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-1536x864.png 1536w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-150x84.png 150w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-65x37.png 65w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-280x158.png 280w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-560x315.png 560w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-600x338.png 600w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-672x378.png 672w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-800x450.png 800w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-220x124.png 220w, https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Novakid-Courses-440x248.png 440w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></p>
<p><strong>SD: What makes your company unique?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MA:</strong> Novakid is a game-changer because it makes learning English fun, interactive, and engaging by meeting the needs and challenges of each individual student. Our online education platform emphasizes personalization and uses AI-assisted data extraction and analysis to cater to the unique needs of our students. Importantly, we incorporate gamification into the curriculum to make lessons fun, interactive, and challenging for learners. Using a data-driven curriculum, the platform can gather detailed data on each student’s level of achievement and learning styles to create individualized curriculums that are far more effective than standard, one-size-fits-all-type teaching methods.</p>
<p><strong>SD: How does your company deal with cybersecurity?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MA:</strong> Safety and privacy are essential components of positive and kid-friendly content. The privacy of a child is a paramount consideration for Novakid.</p>
<p>We implement industry best practices where it concerns data management and access control. All our data is encrypted in transit and at rest and we leverage AWS and Google Cloud services to ensure secure storage and processing. We also work with world-class partners such as Intercom and Stripe who have a strong reputation in the security of their services.</p>
<p>Novakid strictly protects the student data (attendance rate, grades, records of the lessons) as well as students’ and their parents’ personal information.</p>
<p>Taking into consideration the age range and child development abilities, Novakid opted for creating separate accounts for a student and for their parents: Kid’s Area and Parent Area. The Kid’s Area is a gamified learning environment for students where they can access the English lesson with their teacher, do homework, play games, get rewards, choose an avatar, and even watch animated comic stories. An important feature to consider is that the Kid’s Area at Novakid is completely free from any commercial elements.</p>
<p>Access to all the information is limited to the Novakid teacher and the student’s parents/guardians. As children’s personal data is processed by Novakid’s teachers as well, Novakid concludes a data processing contract with them to prevent fraudulent or inappropriate activities.</p>
<p>The privacy policies are developed and implemented in accordance with the United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 as well as the Council of Europe’s Recommendation CM/Rec (2018)7 of the Committee of Ministers to member States on Guidelines to respect, protect and fulfill the rights of the child in the digital environment.</p>
<p>Children cannot use the Novakid platform until their parents or guardians approve of that usage. Novakid gives its clients the right to withdraw the consent of Novakid collecting further personal information from a child. This right is stated in the GTC (General Terms and Conditions).</p>
<p>We have also designed a special Privacy Policy for children, where the difficult terms are explained in a simple and colorful way.</p>
<p><strong>SD: How is the pandemic affecting your industry?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MA:</strong> When the first lockdown started, we had to scale up very quickly due to the increased demand for our services. We are pleased to say that we were able to maintain our services and customer satisfaction levels throughout this time, even though our client base grew so fast which increased the demands on the platform’s technologies. It’s important to remember that no technology can replace a teacher. Instead, technology is elevating the role of teachers: from imparting knowledge towards co-creation of knowledge. We feel this contributed to our success during the pandemic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French Hospital Group Disconnects from the Internet After Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/french-hospital-group-disconnects-from-the-internet-after-cyberattack/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 07:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=91681</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Hospital-300x200.jpg" alt=""></p>The GHT Coeur Grand Est. Hospitals and Health Care group disconnected all incoming and outgoing Internet connections after falling victim to a cyberattack that resulted in the theft of sensitive administrative and patient data. GHT is a hospital network located in Northeast France with nine locations, 6,000 employees, and around 3,370 beds. The attack occurred [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Hospital-300x200.jpg" alt=""></p><p><strong>The GHT Coeur Grand Est. Hospitals and Health Care group disconnected all incoming and outgoing Internet connections after falling victim to a cyberattack that resulted in the theft of sensitive administrative and patient data.</strong></p>
<p>GHT is a hospital network located in Northeast France with nine locations, 6,000 employees, and around 3,370 beds.</p>
<p>The attack occurred on April 19 and impacted the systems of Vitry-le-François and Saint-Dizier, causing GHT to disconnect Internet connections to the hospitals to prevent the attack&#8217;s spread along with additional data theft.</p>
<p>“The GHT Cœur Grand Est has cut all incoming and outgoing internet connections from its establishments in order to protect and secure information systems and data,” <a rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">said</a> a translated statement from GHT.</p>
<p>“This computer containment will continue until the risk of a new attack exploiting the flaw created is completely circumscribed. To this end, some online services are temporarily unavailable (making appointments, etc.),” GHT added.</p>
<p>The hospital network said that the attackers also managed to copy administrative computer data stored in the establishment&#8217;s systems and warned that other threat actors may publish and use the data.</p>
<p>Patient care hasn’t been interrupted since the software used in the hospitals has not been affected by this cyberattack. However, online services still remain impacted while investigating the flaw that allowed the threat actors access to their network.</p>
<p>Additionally, due to this data breach, the risk of social engineering attacks and scams against patients or hospital employees has dramatically increased.</p>
<p>To alleviate this risk, GHT urged all parties to stay vigilant and report any suspicious online requests to law enforcement authorities.</p>
<h2>Additional Breaches</h2>
<p><strong>At the end of March, the Hospital de Castelluccio in Corsica was <a href="https://twitter.com/ARSCORSE1/status/1508799466220011531?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1508799466220011531%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bleepingcomputer.com%2Fnews%2Fsecurity%2Ffrench-hospital-group-disconnects-internet-after-hackers-steal-data%2F" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">attacked</a> by hackers, who also managed to steal sensitive patient data and other documents during the incident.</strong></p>
<p>The incident was <a href="https://www.ch-castelluccio.fr/actualites/57" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">disclosed</a> to the public immediately and had negative consequences on the operation of radiotherapy in the hospital’s oncology unit.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, stolen data marketplace Vice Society published the stolen documents allegedly originating from the attack on the Castelluccio hospital and made them available for purchase.</p>
<p>These documents included employee correspondence, HR information, patient records, identities, social security coverage details, and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FBI Warns of Increased Ransomware Attacks Against US Agriculture Sector</title>
      <link>https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/fbi-warns-of-increased-ransomware-attacks-against-us-agriculture-sector/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Thierry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.safetydetectives.com/?post_type=news&amp;p=91493</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Agriculture-Sector-300x225.jpeg" alt=""></p>The US Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) warned Food and Agriculture (FA) sector organizations on Wednesday of an increased risk of ransomware attacks during the harvest and planting seasons. Although ransomware groups regularly target the US agriculture sector, the FBI noted that the quantity of attacks against these entities during critical seasons is concerning. The FBI revealed [&#8230;]]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://static.safetydetectives.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Agriculture-Sector-300x225.jpeg" alt=""></p><p><strong>The US Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/News/2022/220420-2.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-btn-name="Affiliate Link">warned</a> Food and Agriculture (FA) sector organizations on Wednesday of an increased risk of <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/blog/ransomware-statistics/" target="_blank">ransomware</a> attacks during the harvest and planting seasons.</strong></p>
<p>Although ransomware groups regularly target the US agriculture sector, the FBI noted that the quantity of attacks against these entities during critical seasons is concerning.</p>
<p>The FBI revealed this information during a joint flash alert released in coordination with the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (DHS/CISA).</p>
<p>“Ransomware attacks during these seasons against six grain cooperatives during the fall 2021 harvest and two attacks in early 2022 that could impact the planting season by disrupting the supply of seeds and fertilizer,” the FBI said.</p>
<p>“Cyber actors may perceive cooperatives as lucrative targets with a willingness to pay due to the time-sensitive role they play in agricultural production,” the agency added.</p>
<p>In its statement on Wednesday, the FBI also highlighted several ransomware attacks against US agricultural cooperatives that led to financial losses and impacted production.</p>
<h2>Ransomware Attacks on Critical US Infrastructure</h2>
<p><strong>In a February joint advisory, the FBI, CISA, and the NSA also <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/cybersecurity-authorities-issue-advisory-on-significant-increase-in-ransomware-attacks/" target="_blank">warned</a> of an increase in ransomware attacks impacting 14 of the 16 US critical infrastructure sectors, including Food and Agriculture.</strong></p>
<p>Since the start of 2022, the FBI issued flash alerts highlighting how several ransomware gangs (including <a href="https://www.safetydetectives.com/news/fbi-blackbyte-ransomware-attacks-breached-critical-us-infrastructure/" target="_blank">BlackByte</a>, Ragnar Locker, and Avoslocker) have breached dozens of critical US infrastructure.</p>
<p>Attackers use a variety of methods to gain access to victims&#8217; networks, including phishing, stealing Remote Desktop Protocols (RDP) credentials, and exploiting unpatched vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>Ransomware groups also utilize cybercriminal services-for-hire to negotiate ransom payments, help victims make payments, and mediate payment disputes with other cybercriminals.</p>
<p>“If the ransomware criminal business model continues to yield financial returns for ransomware actors, ransomware incidents will become more frequent,” the advisory said. “Every time a ransom is paid, it confirms the viability and financial attractiveness of the ransomware criminal business model.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>