<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/" xmlns:blogger="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <atom:id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386</atom:id>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 21:39:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Comparison</category>
    <category>Ai</category>
    <category>Blockchain</category>
    <category>Chrome Extension</category>
    <category>Email Marketing</category>
    <category>NFTs</category>
    <category>PLR</category>
    <category>Tool</category>
    <category>Wordpress</category>
    <category>review</category>
    <title>Crunch Hype</title>
    <description>CrunchHype is a free Digital Marketing Site. The main goal of this site is to provide quality tutorials, tips, courses, tools and other resources that allows anyone to work online and master digital marketing based on real case study and deep research.</description>
    <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/</link>
    <managingEditor>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</managingEditor>
    <generator>Blogger</generator>
    <openSearch:totalResults>13</openSearch:totalResults>
    <openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex>
    <openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" />
    <feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="techcrunch" />
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">Techcrunch</feedburner:emailServiceId>
    <feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">https://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-2614342552940509599</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 05:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-04-19T13:00:08.550+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Blockchain</category>
      <title>What is Blockchain: Everything You Need to Know (2022)</title>
      <description>&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img alt="What is Blockchain" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGSmMnm7rS8T3FdymStVEU4Vzq6neAfiH-HWZEh_NyxTReup8XF0S0N2hYBTI4xHAyV1-mWUv2CI-7PohYUMPpCIzoUm7GloDeFVR_-cquCFWMPp8vGgnG7TSsy6XPf9Gs-lG1lAWskhHGhc_2x7I5Y-psklBHqgNZQOPkcwqTNio0SXAUX5-hyRopZg/s16000/Most%20Frequently%20Asked%20Questions%20About%20Email%20Marketing.png" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Blockchain" /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGSmMnm7rS8T3FdymStVEU4Vzq6neAfiH-HWZEh_NyxTReup8XF0S0N2hYBTI4xHAyV1-mWUv2CI-7PohYUMPpCIzoUm7GloDeFVR_-cquCFWMPp8vGgnG7TSsy6XPf9Gs-lG1lAWskhHGhc_2x7I5Y-psklBHqgNZQOPkcwqTNio0SXAUX5-hyRopZg/s1920/Most%20Frequently%20Asked%20Questions%20About%20Email%20Marketing.png" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to pay online, you need to register an account and provide credit card information. If you don't have a credit card, you can pay with bank transfer. With the rise of cryptocurrencies, these methods may become old.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Imagine a world in which you can do transactions and many other things without having to give your personal information. A world in which you don’t need to rely on banks or governments anymore. Sounds amazing, right? That’s exactly what blockchain technology allows us to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;It’s like your computer’s hard drive. blockchain is a technology that lets you store data in digital blocks, which are connected together like links in a chain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain technology was originally invented in 1991 by two mathematicians, Stuart Haber and W. Scot Stornetta. They first proposed the system to ensure that timestamps could not be tampered with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;A few years later, in 1998, software developer Nick Szabo proposed using a similar kind of technology to secure a digital payments system he called “Bit Gold.” However, this innovation was not adopted until Satoshi Nakamoto claimed to have invented the first Blockchain and Bitcoin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;So, What is Blockchain?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;A blockchain is a distributed database shared between the nodes of a computer network. It saves information in digital format. Many people first heard of blockchain technology when they started to look up information about bitcoin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain is used in cryptocurrency systems to ensure secure, decentralized records of transactions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain allowed people to guarantee the fidelity and security of a record of data without the need for a third party to ensure accuracy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;To understand how a blockchain works, Consider these basic steps:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain collects information in “blocks”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;A block has a storage capacity, and once it's used up, it can be closed and linked to a previously served block.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blocks form chains, which are called “Blockchains.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;More information will be added to the block with the most content until its capacity is full. The process repeats itself.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Each block in the chain has an exact timestamp and can't be changed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Let’s get to know more about the blockchain.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;How does blockchain work?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain records digital information and distributes it across the network without changing it. The information is distributed among many users and stored in an immutable, permanent ledger that can't be changed or destroyed. That's why blockchain is also called "Distributed Ledger Technology" or DLT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Someone or a computer will transacts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The transaction is transmitted throughout the network.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;A network of computers can confirm the transaction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;When it is confirmed a transaction is added to a block&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The blocks are linked together to create a history.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;And that’s the beauty of it! The process may seem complicated, but it’s done in minutes with modern technology. And because technology is advancing rapidly, I expect things to move even more quickly than ever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;A new transaction is added to the system. It is then relayed to a network of computers located around the world. The computers then solve equations to ensure the authenticity of the transaction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Once a transaction is confirmed, it is placed in a block after the confirmation. All of the blocks are chained together to create a permanent history of every transaction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;How are Blockchains used?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Even though blockchain is integral to cryptocurrency, it has other applications. For example, blockchain can be used for storing reliable data about transactions. Many people confuse blockchain with cryptocurrencies like bitcoin and ethereum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain already being adopted by some big-name companies, such as Walmart, AIG, Siemens, Pfizer, and Unilever. For example, IBM's Food Trust uses blockchain to track food's journey before reaching its final destination.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Although some of you may consider this practice excessive, food suppliers and manufacturers adhere to the policy of tracing their products because bacteria such as E. coli and Salmonella have been found in packaged foods. In addition, there have been isolated cases where dangerous allergens such as peanuts have accidentally been introduced into certain products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Tracing and identifying the sources of an outbreak is a challenging task that can take months or years. Thanks to the Blockchain, however, companies now know exactly where their food has been—so they can trace its location and prevent future outbreaks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain technology allows systems to react much faster in the event of a hazard. It also has many other uses in the modern world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is Blockchain Decentralization?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain technology is safe, even if it’s public. People can access the technology using an internet connection.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Have you ever been in a situation where you had all your data stored at one place and that one secure place got compromised? Wouldn't it be great if there was a way to prevent your data from leaking out even when the security of your storage systems is compromised?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain technology provides a way of avoiding this situation by using multiple computers at different locations to store information about transactions. If one computer experiences problems with a transaction, it will not affect the other nodes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Instead, other nodes will use the correct information to cross-reference your incorrect node. This is called “Decentralization,” meaning all the information is stored in multiple places.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain guarantees your data's authenticity—not just its accuracy, but also its irreversibility. It can also be used to store data that are difficult to register, like legal contracts, state identifications, or a company's product inventory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Pros and Cons of Blockchain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain has many advantages and disadvantages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Accuracy is increased because there is no human involvement in the verification process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;One of the great things about decentralization is that it makes information harder to tamper with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Safe, private, and easy transactions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Provides a banking alternative and safe storage of personal information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Data storage has limits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The regulations are always changing, as they differ from place to place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;It has a risk of being used for illicit activities&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Frequently Asked Questions About Blockchain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;I’ll answer the most frequently asked questions about blockchain in this section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Is Blockchain a cryptocurrency?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain is not a cryptocurrency but a technology that makes cryptocurrencies possible. It's a digital ledger that records every transaction seamlessly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Is it possible for Blockchain to be hacked?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Yes, blockchain can be theoretically hacked, but it is a complicated task to be achieved. A network of users constantly reviews it, which makes hacking the blockchain difficult.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is the most prominent blockchain company?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Coinbase Global is currently the biggest blockchain company in the world. The company runs a commendable infrastructure, services, and technology for the digital currency economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Who owns Blockchain?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain is a decentralized technology. It’s a chain of distributed ledgers connected with nodes. Each node can be any electronic device. Thus, one owns blockhain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is the difference between Bitcoin and Blockchain technology?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Bitcoin is a cryptocurrency, which is powered by Blockchain technology while Blockchain is a distributed ledger of cryptocurrency&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is the difference between Blockchain and a Database?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Generally a database is a collection of data which can be stored and organized using a database management system. The people who have access to the database can view or edit the information stored there. The client-server network architecture is used to implement databases. whereas a blockchain is a growing list of records, called blocks, stored in a distributed system. Each block contains a cryptographic hash of the previous block, timestamp and transaction information. Modification of data is not allowed due to the design of the blockchain. The technology allows decentralized control and eliminates risks of data modification by other parties.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Final Saying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Blockchain has a wide spectrum of applications and, over the next 5-10 years, we will likely see it being integrated into all sorts of industries. From finance to healthcare, blockchain could revolutionize the way we store and share data. Although there is some hesitation to adopt blockchain systems right now, that won't be the case in 2022-2023 (and even less so in 2026). Once people become more comfortable with the technology and understand how it can work for them, owners, CEOs and entrepreneurs alike will be quick to leverage blockchain technology for their own gain. Hope you like this article if you have any question let me know in the comments section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #2b00fe; font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;FOLLOW US ON TWITTER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" data-show-count="false" href="https://twitter.com/AdilAhmad_c?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;Follow @AdilAhmad_c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async="" charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/04/what-is-blockchain-everything-you-need.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhGSmMnm7rS8T3FdymStVEU4Vzq6neAfiH-HWZEh_NyxTReup8XF0S0N2hYBTI4xHAyV1-mWUv2CI-7PohYUMPpCIzoUm7GloDeFVR_-cquCFWMPp8vGgnG7TSsy6XPf9Gs-lG1lAWskhHGhc_2x7I5Y-psklBHqgNZQOPkcwqTNio0SXAUX5-hyRopZg/s72-c/Most%20Frequently%20Asked%20Questions%20About%20Email%20Marketing.png" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>3</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-4109465143659836541</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:20:06.206+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Comparison</category>
      <title>ProWritingAid VS Grammarly: Which Grammar Checker is Better in (2022) ?</title>
      <description>&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjF7I9iAp1Tfc6kFmKNOYqqI2V1NjZ1ltfemNKGCo1nvQlCy0DWGe_hNag4uruW_SW6tMwc0M8sa4O7ca4zQ6Hiiu6TDi4VAohA3aTPmU4KuRqBC2KQpg3PB_55tjbwwO9ko2xAW-9QQdfpph0xVKiCDiMRKkrL8clOk90wa1arfXGW0VKIO182Qb31vw=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Grammarly vs prowritingaid" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjF7I9iAp1Tfc6kFmKNOYqqI2V1NjZ1ltfemNKGCo1nvQlCy0DWGe_hNag4uruW_SW6tMwc0M8sa4O7ca4zQ6Hiiu6TDi4VAohA3aTPmU4KuRqBC2KQpg3PB_55tjbwwO9ko2xAW-9QQdfpph0xVKiCDiMRKkrL8clOk90wa1arfXGW0VKIO182Qb31vw=w640-h360" title="Grammarly vs prowritingaid" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ProWritingAid VS Grammarly:&lt;span style="color: #3c4043;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white; font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #3c4043; font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;When it comes to English grammar, there are two Big Players that everyone knows of: the Grammarly and ProWritingAid. but you are wondering which one to choose so here we write a detail article which will help you to choose the best one for you so Let's start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is Grammarly?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly is a tool that checks for grammatical errors, spelling, and punctuation.it gives you comprehensive feedback on your writing. You can use this tool to proofread and edit articles, blog posts, emails, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly also detects all types of mistakes, including sentence structure issues and misused words. It also gives you suggestions on style changes, punctuation, spelling, and grammar all are in real-time. The free version covers the basics like identifying grammar and spelling mistakes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;whereas the Premium version offers a lot more functionality, it detects plagiarism in your content, suggests word choice, or adds fluency to it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Features of Grammarly&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spelling and Word Suggestion:&lt;/b&gt; Grammarly detects basic to advance grammatical errors and also help you why this is an error and suggest to you how you can improve it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Create a Personal Dictionary:&lt;/b&gt; The Grammarly app allows you to add words to your personal dictionary so that the same mistake isn't highlighted every time you run Grammarly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Different English Style&lt;/b&gt;: Check to spell for American, British, Canadian, and Australian English.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plagiarism:&lt;/b&gt; This feature helps you detect if a text has been plagiarized by comparing it with over eight billion web pages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wordiness:&lt;/b&gt; This tool will help you check your writing for long and hard-to-read sentences. It also shows you how to shorten sentences so that they are more concise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/b&gt; The program also notifies users when passive voice is used too frequently in a document.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Punctuations:&lt;/b&gt; This feature flags all incorrect and missing punctuation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Repetition:&lt;/b&gt; The tool provides recommendations for replacing the repeated word.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Proposition:&lt;/b&gt; Grammarly identifies misplaced and confused prepositions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plugins:&lt;/b&gt; It offers Microsoft Word, Microsoft Outlook, and Google Chrome plugins.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is ProWritingAid?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid is a style and grammar checker for content creators and writers. It helps to optimize word choice, punctuation errors, and common grammar mistakes, providing detailed reports to help you improve your writing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid can be used as an add-on to WordPress, Gmail, and Google Docs. The software also offers helpful articles, videos, quizzes, and explanations to help improve your writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Features of ProWriting Aid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Here are some key features of ProWriting Aid:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammar checker and spell checker:&lt;/b&gt; This tool helps you to find all grammatical and spelling errors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Find repeated words:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; The tool also allows you to search for repeated words and phrases in your content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Context-sensitive style suggestions:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; You can find the exact style of writing you intend and suggest if it flows well in your writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Check the readability of your content:&lt;/b&gt; Pro Writing Aid helps you identify the strengths and weaknesses of your article by pointing out difficult sentences and paragraphs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sentence Length: &lt;/b&gt;It also indicates the length of your sentences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Check Grammatical error:&lt;/b&gt; It also checks your work for any grammatical errors or typos, as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Overused words:&lt;/b&gt; As a writer, you might find yourself using the same word repeatedly. ProWritingAid's overused words checker helps you avoid this lazy writing mistake.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Consistency:&lt;/b&gt; Check your work for inconsistent usage of open and closed quotation marks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Echoes:&lt;/b&gt; Check your writing for uniformly repetitive words and phrases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Difference between Grammarly and Pro-Writing Aid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; are well-known grammar-checking software. However, if you're like most people who can't decide which to use, here are some different points that may be helpful in your decision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly vs ProWritingAid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly &lt;/b&gt;is a writing enhancement tool that offers suggestions for grammar, vocabulary, and syntax whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; offers world-class grammar and style checking, as well as advanced reports to help you strengthen your writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; provides Android and IOS apps whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; doesn't have a mobile or IOS app.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; offers important suggestions about mistakes you've made whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; shows more suggestions than Grammarly but all recommendations are not accurate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; has a more friendly UI/UX whereas the ProWritingAid interface is not friendly as Grammarly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; is an accurate grammar checker for non-fiction writing whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; is an accurate grammar checker for fiction writers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; finds grammar and punctuation mistakes, whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; identifies run-on sentences and fragments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; provides 24/7 support via submitting a ticket and sending emails. &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid’s&lt;/b&gt; support team is available via email, though the response time is approximately 48 hours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; offers many features in its free plan, whereas&lt;b&gt; ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; offers some basic features in the free plan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly &lt;/b&gt;does not offer much feedback on big picture writing; &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; offers complete feedback on big picture writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grammarly&lt;/b&gt; is a better option for accuracy, whereas &lt;b&gt;ProWritingAid&lt;/b&gt; is better for handling fragmented sentences and dialogue. It can be quite useful for fiction writers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid VS Grammarly: Pricing Difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid comes with three pricing structures. The full-year cost of ProWritingAid is $79, while its lifetime plans cost $339. You also can opt for a monthly plan of $20.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly offers a Premium subscription for $30/month for a monthly plan&amp;nbsp; $20/month for quarterly and $12/month for an annual subscription.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The Business plan costs $12.50 per month for each member of your company.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid vs Grammarly – Pros and Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;It allows you to fix common mistakes like grammar and spelling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Offers most features in the free plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Allows you to edit a document without affecting the formatting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Active and passive voice checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Personal dictionary&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Plagiarism checker (paid version)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Proofread your writing and correct all punctuation, grammar, and spelling errors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Allows you to make changes to a document without altering its formatting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Helps users improve vocabulary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;User-friendly interface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Browser extensions and MS word add-ons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Available on all major devices and platforms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly will also offer suggestions to improve your style.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Enhance the readability of your sentence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Free mobile apps&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Offers&amp;nbsp; free version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Supports only English&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Customer support only via email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Limits to 150,000 words&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Subscription plans can be a bit pricey&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Plagiarism checker is only available in a premium plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Doesn’t offer a free trial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;No refund policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The free version is ideal for basic spelling and grammatical mistakes, but it does not correct advanced writing issues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Some features are not available for Mac.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProwritingAid Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;It offers more than 20 different reports to help you improve your writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Less expensive than other grammar checkers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;This tool helps you strengthen your writing style as it offers big-picture feedback.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid has a life plan with no further payments required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Compatible with Google Docs!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Prowritingaid works on both Windows and Mac.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;They offer more integrations than most tools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Editing can be a little more time-consuming when you add larger passages of text.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid currently offers no mobile app for Android or iOS devices.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Plagiarism checker is only available in premium plans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;All recommendations are not accurate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Summarizing the Ginger VS Grammarly: My Recommendation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;As both writing assistants are great in their own way, you need to choose the one that suits you best.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;For example, go for Grammarly&amp;nbsp; if you are a non-fiction writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Go for ProWritingAid if you are a fiction writer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid is better at catching errors found in long-form content. However, Grammarly is more suited to short blog posts and other similar tasks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;ProWritingAid helps you clean up your writing by checking for style, structure, and content while Grammarly focuses on grammar and punctuation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Grammarly has a more friendly UI/UX whereas; ProWritingAid offers complete feedback on big picture writing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Both ProWritingAid and Grammarly are awesome writing tools, without a doubt. but as per my experience, Grammarly is a winner here because Grammarly helps you to review and edit your content. Grammarly highlights all the mistakes in your writing within seconds of copying and pasting the content into Grammarly’s editor or using the software’s native feature in other text editors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Not only does it identify tiny grammatical and spelling errors, it tells you when you overlook punctuations where they are needed. And, beyond its plagiarism-checking capabilities, Grammarly helps you proofread your content. Even better, the software offers a free plan that gives you access to some of its features.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/03/prowritingaid-vs-grammarly-which.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjF7I9iAp1Tfc6kFmKNOYqqI2V1NjZ1ltfemNKGCo1nvQlCy0DWGe_hNag4uruW_SW6tMwc0M8sa4O7ca4zQ6Hiiu6TDi4VAohA3aTPmU4KuRqBC2KQpg3PB_55tjbwwO9ko2xAW-9QQdfpph0xVKiCDiMRKkrL8clOk90wa1arfXGW0VKIO182Qb31vw=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>12</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-5204433722330471234</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:21:10.148+05:00</atom:updated>
      <title>Sellfy Review 2022: How Good Is This Ecommerce Platform?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjbDTd3znkB-FhGnQL-V8kUsAXIlJaksqIPyM9X0IoE1Yq0zomkIHOZNIXFw83utgtxHLJaBoC_cQnAgR8w-xLkzmkSs5JbWBrCyFzNva6va-yu_T1v224t7i-8JZ6hybYjhw2oCHnqrmeN07VxMpMQ2GuXb7KHbn8ocHU20WyiD_CK3BQXUIxGSCQS2A=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sellfy" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjbDTd3znkB-FhGnQL-V8kUsAXIlJaksqIPyM9X0IoE1Yq0zomkIHOZNIXFw83utgtxHLJaBoC_cQnAgR8w-xLkzmkSs5JbWBrCyFzNva6va-yu_T1v224t7i-8JZ6hybYjhw2oCHnqrmeN07VxMpMQ2GuXb7KHbn8ocHU20WyiD_CK3BQXUIxGSCQS2A=w640-h360" title="Sellfy" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Are you searching for an ecomerce platform to help you build an online store and sell products?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;In this Sellfy review, we'll talk about how this eCommerce platform can let you sell digital products while keeping full control of your marketing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;And the best part? Starting your business can be done in just five minutes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Let us then talk about the Sellfy platform and all the benefits it can bring to your business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;What is Sellfy?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Sellfy &lt;/a&gt;is an eCommerce solution that allows digital content creators, including writers, illustrators, designers, musicians, and filmmakers, to sell their products online. Sellfy provides a customizable storefront where users can display their digital products and embed "Buy Now" buttons on their website or blog. Sellfy product pages enable users to showcase their products from different angles with multiple images and previews from Soundcloud, Vimeo, and YouTube. Files of up to 2GB can be uploaded to Sellfy, and the company offers unlimited bandwidth and secure file storage. Users can also embed their entire store or individual project widgets in their site, with the ability to preview how widgets will appear before they are displayed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa; font-weight: normal;"&gt;Sellfy includes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Online Store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Sellfy &lt;/a&gt;is a powerful e-commerce platform that helps you personalize your online storefront. You can add your logo, change colors, revise navigation, and edit the layout of your store. Sellfy also allows you to create a full shopping cart so customers can purchase multiple items. And Sellfy gives you the ability to set your language or let customers see a translated version of your store based on their location.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Sellfy &lt;/a&gt;gives you the option to host your store directly on its platform, add a custom domain to your store, and use it as an embedded storefront on your website. Sellfy also optimizes its store offerings for mobile devices, allowing for a seamless checkout experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Product hosting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Sellfy &lt;/a&gt;allows creators to host all their products and sell all of their digital products on one platform. Sellfy also does not place storage limits on your store but recommends that files be no larger than 5GB. Creators can sell both standard and subscription-based products in any file format that is supported by the online marketplace. Customers can purchase products instantly after making a purchase – there is no waiting period.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;You can organize your store by creating your product categories, sorting by any characteristic you choose. Your title, description, and the image will be included on each product page. In this way, customers can immediately evaluate all of your products. You can offer different pricing options for all of your products, including "pay what you want," in which the price is entirely up to the customer. This option allows you to give customers control over the cost of individual items (without a minimum price) or to set pricing minimums—a good option if you're in a competitive market or when you have higher-end products. You can also offer set prices per product as well as free products to help build your store's popularity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy is ideal for selling digital content, such as ebooks. But it does not allow you to copyrighted material (that you don't have rights to distribute).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Embed options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy offers several ways to share your store, enabling you to promote your business on different platforms. Sellfy lets you integrate it with your existing website using "buy now" buttons, embed your entire storefront, or embed certain products so you can reach more people. Sellfy also enables you to connect with your Facebook page and YouTube channel, maximizing your visibility.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Payments and security&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy is a simple online platform that allows customers to buy your products directly through your store. Sellfy has two payment processing options: PayPal and Stripe. You will receive instant payments with both of these processors, and your customer data is protected by Sellfy's secure (PCI-compliant) payment security measures. In addition to payment security, Sellfy provides anti-fraud tools to help protect your products including PDF stamping, unique download links, and limited download attempts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Marketing and analytics tools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The Sellfy platform includes marketing and analytics tools to help you manage your online store. You can send email product updates and collect newsletter subscribers through the platform. With Sellfy, you can also offer discount codes and product upsells, as well as create and track Facebook and Twitter ads for your store. The software's analytics dashboard will help you track your best-performing products, generated revenue, traffic channels, top locations, and overall store performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Integrations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;To expand functionality and make your e-commerce store run more efficiently, Sellfy offers several integrations. Google Analytics and Webhooks, as well as integrations with Patreon and Facebook Live Chat, are just a few of the options available. Sellfy allows you to connect to Zapier, which gives you access to hundreds of third-party apps, including tools like Mailchimp, Trello, Salesforce, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Pricing and Premium Plan Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Get &lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Sellfy &lt;/a&gt;14 day free trail from &lt;a href="https://get.sellfy.com/crunchhype" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Free Plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Price: $0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The free plan comes with:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Up to 10 products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Print-on-demand products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Physical products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Starter Plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Price: $19/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Starter plan comes with:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Everything is Free, plus:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Unlimited products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Digital products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Subscription products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Connect your domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;2,000 email credits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Business Plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Price: $49/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The business plan comes with:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Everything in Starter, plus:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Remove "Sellfy" branding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Store design migration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Cart abandonment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Product upselling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;10,000 email credits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Premium Plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Price: $99/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The premium plan comes with:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Everything in Business, plus:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Product migration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Priority support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;50,000 email credits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy Review: Pros and Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy has its benefits and downsides, but fortunately, the pros outweigh the cons.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;It takes only a few minutes to set up an online store and begin selling products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;You can sell your products on a single storefront, even if you are selling multiple product types.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy supports selling a variety of product types, including physical items, digital goods, subscriptions, and print-on-demand products.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy offers a free plan for those who want to test out the features before committing to a paid plan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;You get paid the same day you make a sale. Sellfy doesn't delay your funds as some other payment processors do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Print-on-demand services are available directly from your store, so you can sell merchandise to fans without setting up an integration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;You can conduct all store-related activities via the mobile app and all online stores have mobile responsive designs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Everything you need to make your website is included, including a custom domain name hosting, security for your files, and the ability to customize your store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The file security features can help you protect your digital property by allowing you to put PDF stamps, set download limits, and SSL encryption.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy provides unlimited support.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy provides simple and intuitive tax and VAT configuration settings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Marketing strategies include coupons, email marketing, upselling, tracking pixels, and cart abandonment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Although the free plan is helpful, but it limits you to only 10 products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Payment plans often require an upgrade if you exceed a certain sales amount per year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The storefront designs are clean, but they're not unique templates for creating a completely different brand image.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Sellfy's branding is removed from your hosted product when you upgrade to the $49 per month Business plan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;The free plan does not allow for selling digital or subscription products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;In this article, we have taken a look at some of the biggest benefits associated with using sellfy for eCommerce. Once you compare these benefits to what you get with other platforms such as Shopify, you should find that it is worth your time to consider sellfy for your business. After reading this article all of your questions will be solved but if you have still some questions let me know in the comment section below, I will be happy to answer your questions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Comfortaa;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style="background-color: white; box-sizing: inherit; font-size: 16px; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"&gt;This article contains affiliate links which means we make a small commission if you buy sellfy premium plan from our link.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/03/sellfy-review-2022-how-good-is-this.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjbDTd3znkB-FhGnQL-V8kUsAXIlJaksqIPyM9X0IoE1Yq0zomkIHOZNIXFw83utgtxHLJaBoC_cQnAgR8w-xLkzmkSs5JbWBrCyFzNva6va-yu_T1v224t7i-8JZ6hybYjhw2oCHnqrmeN07VxMpMQ2GuXb7KHbn8ocHU20WyiD_CK3BQXUIxGSCQS2A=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>1</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-3560174651575689239</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-19T15:02:30.604+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Comparison</category>
      <title>Ahrefs vs SEMrush: Which SEO Tool Should You Use?</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgjp-Lwdt6oYlgGQ0HWI9cLSBOiniI0CKOWnRWuiQTe2uBJIenevsoZKESvI4-Uo-4r6VU1RjQZUtLtpA1vJyAZhg0fEFn-wOintkjZnNkYcZjS0XIs3XQ2dPgOwKfZZw4YubtvjfJRsVyRBc4tCckB7yip4A-9W1yMbv7bBk3zEGElqHhzHxBdoQAOCg=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="semrush vs ahrefs" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgjp-Lwdt6oYlgGQ0HWI9cLSBOiniI0CKOWnRWuiQTe2uBJIenevsoZKESvI4-Uo-4r6VU1RjQZUtLtpA1vJyAZhg0fEFn-wOintkjZnNkYcZjS0XIs3XQ2dPgOwKfZZw4YubtvjfJRsVyRBc4tCckB7yip4A-9W1yMbv7bBk3zEGElqHhzHxBdoQAOCg=w640-h360" title="semrush vs ahrefs" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush and Ahrefs are among the most popular tools in the SEO industry. Both companies have been in business for years and have thousands of customers per month.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you're a professional SEO or trying to do digital marketing on your own, at some point you'll likely consider using a tool to help with your efforts. Ahrefs and SEMrush are two names that will likely appear on your shortlist.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In this guide, I'm going to help you learn more about these SEO tools and how to choose the one that's best for your purposes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is SEMrush?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj19XUpt9Fx6nM7Ny-YihiwJWB3uGFI9tHee_lrhQeIenb_r1q2oBe1dISx7oQMgmqyySFMeVYw5s6BuI5UArx4xk-yedJTPno9GEckbtENs6soBmpzX4VduRbH8V0oZnRFSM-pWh8bHtur90-lgI69vlx5khN1QiHmy1m5SCfSeWjOg2S9szWoIz16Gw=s1660" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="semrush" border="0" data-original-height="910" data-original-width="1660" height="350" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj19XUpt9Fx6nM7Ny-YihiwJWB3uGFI9tHee_lrhQeIenb_r1q2oBe1dISx7oQMgmqyySFMeVYw5s6BuI5UArx4xk-yedJTPno9GEckbtENs6soBmpzX4VduRbH8V0oZnRFSM-pWh8bHtur90-lgI69vlx5khN1QiHmy1m5SCfSeWjOg2S9szWoIz16Gw=w640-h350" title="senrush" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush is a popular SEO tool with a wide range of features—it's the leading competitor research service for online marketers. SEMrush's SEO Keyword Magic tool offers over 20 billion Google-approved keywords, which are constantly updated and it's the largest keyword database.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The program was developed in 2007 as SeoQuake is a small Firefox extension&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Most accurate keyword data:&lt;/b&gt; Accurate keyword search volume data is crucial for SEO and PPC campaigns by allowing you to identify what keywords are most likely to bring in big sales from ad clicks. SEMrush constantly updates its databases and provides the most accurate data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Largest Keyword database:&lt;/b&gt; SEMrush's Keyword Magic Tool now features 20-billion keywords, providing marketers and SEO professionals the largest database of keywords.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;All SEMrush users receive daily ranking data, mobile volume information, and the option to buy additional keywords by default with no additional payment or add-ons needed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Most accurate position tracking tool: &lt;/b&gt;This tool provides all subscribers with basic tracking capabilities, making it suitable for SEO professionals. Plus, the Position Tracking tool provides local-level data to everyone who uses the tool.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;SEO Data Management: &lt;/b&gt;SEMrush makes managing your online data easy by allowing you to create visually appealing custom PDF reports, including Branded and White Label reports, report scheduling, and integration with GA, GMB, and GSC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Toxic link monitoring and penalty recovery: &lt;/b&gt;With SEMrush, you can make a detailed analysis of toxic backlinks, toxic scores, toxic markers, and outreach to those sites.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Content Optimization and Creation Tools: &lt;/b&gt;SEMrush offers content optimization and creation tools that let you create SEO-friendly content. Some features include the SEO Writing Assistant, On-Page SEO Check, er/SEO Content Template, Content Audit, Post Tracking, Brand Monitoring.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;             &lt;h2 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiFPt6nHmthnZI41Oon-MIy17GEkHvEbLK9v0wD4O6LeObZYb7CJtZjqHTtcjbIYFUX_97R049GK6a7rCS9LfObFMUIchs0V2iFLEs5QJdsj6dtuktGWOV2i4TE69JTj2-HSE5U9Qdgo78OSsCjHsA0Ho9KlNt-odFsCmALTxdCf0B9Rp58lq53mnTYog=s1664" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="ahrefs" border="0" data-original-height="820" data-original-width="1664" height="316" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiFPt6nHmthnZI41Oon-MIy17GEkHvEbLK9v0wD4O6LeObZYb7CJtZjqHTtcjbIYFUX_97R049GK6a7rCS9LfObFMUIchs0V2iFLEs5QJdsj6dtuktGWOV2i4TE69JTj2-HSE5U9Qdgo78OSsCjHsA0Ho9KlNt-odFsCmALTxdCf0B9Rp58lq53mnTYog=w640-h316" title="ahrefs" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs is a leading SEO platform that offers a set of tools to grow your search traffic, research your competitors, and monitor your niche. The company was founded in 2010, and it has become a popular choice among SEO tools. Ahrefs has a keyword index of over 10.3 billion keywords and offers accurate and extensive backlink data updated every 15-30 minutes and it is the world's most extensive backlink index database.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Backlink alerts data and new keywords&lt;/b&gt;: Get an alert when your site is linked to or discussed in blogs, forums, comments, or when new keywords are added to a blog posting about you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Intuitive interface: &lt;/b&gt;The intuitive design of the widget helps you see the overall health of your website and search engine ranking at a glance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Site Explorer: &lt;/b&gt;The Site Explorer will give you an in-depth look at your site's search traffic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Domain Comparison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Reports with charts and graphs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;JavaScript rendering and a site audit can identify SEO issues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A question explorer that provides well-crafted topic suggestions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;             &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Direct Comparisons: Ahrefs vs SEMrush&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Now that you know a little more about each tool, let's take a look at how they compare. I'll analyze each tool to see how they differ in interfaces, keyword research resources, rank tracking, and competitor analysis.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;User Interface&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs and SEMrush both offer comprehensive information and quick metrics regarding your website's SEO performance. However, Ahrefs takes a bit more of a hands-on approach to getting your account fully set up, whereas SEMrush's simpler dashboard can give you access to the data you need quickly.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In this section, we provide a brief overview of the elements found on each dashboard and highlight the ease with which you can complete tasks.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;AHREFS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhk3VNx-XZQai3cSSRUZ1EnAPaJfaBIpsLoApcbaYpea06OuGUuNtK87c3vMzo3GW557VsH1Pjafx4WhwJOwFxFQ47gVIiXj7cnEMj9bBsnUztsLE4amuvbAbqG8DhWjTVlv3sEN-YIYzp46pZA7uVzzetGe6BNZTSgwtCePCEqd31bmt8HcoVt44HAJA=s742" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="ahrefs interface" border="0" data-original-height="413" data-original-width="742" height="356" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhk3VNx-XZQai3cSSRUZ1EnAPaJfaBIpsLoApcbaYpea06OuGUuNtK87c3vMzo3GW557VsH1Pjafx4WhwJOwFxFQ47gVIiXj7cnEMj9bBsnUztsLE4amuvbAbqG8DhWjTVlv3sEN-YIYzp46pZA7uVzzetGe6BNZTSgwtCePCEqd31bmt8HcoVt44HAJA=w640-h356" title="ahrefs interface" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Ahrefs dashboard is less cluttered than that of SEMrush, and its primary menu is at the very top of the page, with a search bar designed only for entering URLs.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Additional features of the Ahrefs platform include:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can see analytics from the dashboard, including search engine rankings to domain ratings, referring domains, and backlink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Jumping from one tool to another is easy. You can use the Keyword Explorer to find a keyword to target and then directly track your ranking with one click.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The website offers a tooltip helper tool that allows you to hover your mouse over something that isn't clear and get an in-depth explanation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;SEMRUSH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEja9R_j5CeaUWEwdfV8efIiouyrgLKBhy0e4iE4469LObloNet5cUUFz3NdoHbfe7esbgJc-8XoKKjKOB3bscOK31TzJ_EYwF6PdX7Qpmw3RNuJFmViPOG6nuyfWIVPIDwVA0lbdK-8ygQRvhuCanSLXCaHEU0XrKRp9-HhsXf8E7Rs27GvyNzVxztvGw=s1668" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="semrush domain overview" border="0" data-original-height="908" data-original-width="1668" height="348" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEja9R_j5CeaUWEwdfV8efIiouyrgLKBhy0e4iE4469LObloNet5cUUFz3NdoHbfe7esbgJc-8XoKKjKOB3bscOK31TzJ_EYwF6PdX7Qpmw3RNuJFmViPOG6nuyfWIVPIDwVA0lbdK-8ygQRvhuCanSLXCaHEU0XrKRp9-HhsXf8E7Rs27GvyNzVxztvGw=w640-h348" title="semrush domain overview" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you log into the SEMrush Tool, you will find four main modules. These include information about your domains, organic keyword analysis, ad keyword, and site traffic.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You'll also find some other options like&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A search bar allows you to enter a domain, keyword, or anything else you wish to explore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A menu on the left side of the page provides quick links to relevant information, including marketing insights, projects, keyword analytics, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The customer support resources located directly within the dashboard can be used to communicate with the support team or to learn about other resources such as webinars and blogs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Detailed descriptions of every resource offered. This detail is beneficial for new marketers, who are just starting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;       &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;WHO WINS?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Both Ahrefs and SEMrush have user-friendly dashboards, but Ahrefs is less cluttered and easier to navigate. On the other hand, SEMrush offers dozens of extra tools, including access to customer support resources.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When deciding on which dashboard to use, consider what you value in the user interface, and test out both.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 14.05pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 14.05pt; margin: 14.05pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext"&gt;Rank Tracking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you're looking to track your website's search engine ranking, rank tracking features can help. You can also use them to monitor your competitors.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Let's take a look at Ahrefs vs. SEMrush to see which tool does a better job.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiwI2EsnhOaR8PPGn03_vC7Rnhyl6hbADM_ilA7IukOAIz0A7SFJDh0Gkj85yqIOJv4gBiiBdfcd_0hy3b7gTYPZhUKQ4eyWLi60IxDA_w-tXRSQ3QkogvhxI1lgvgM59SpOnj8Z6rj9mC_EEBV8k60_c3P4ywhjUD5DKgpM73Vei7qqC7sHIIyVyYXxA=s623" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="ahrefs rank tracking" border="0" data-original-height="492" data-original-width="623" height="506" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiwI2EsnhOaR8PPGn03_vC7Rnhyl6hbADM_ilA7IukOAIz0A7SFJDh0Gkj85yqIOJv4gBiiBdfcd_0hy3b7gTYPZhUKQ4eyWLi60IxDA_w-tXRSQ3QkogvhxI1lgvgM59SpOnj8Z6rj9mC_EEBV8k60_c3P4ywhjUD5DKgpM73Vei7qqC7sHIIyVyYXxA=w640-h506" title="ahrefs rank tracking" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Ahrefs Rank Tracker is simpler to use. Just type in the domain name and keywords you want to analyze, and it spits out a report showing you the search engine results page (SERP) ranking for each keyword you enter.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Rank Tracker looks at the ranking performance of keywords and compares them with the top rankings for those keywords. Ahrefs also offers:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You'll see metrics that help you understand your visibility, traffic, average position, and keyword difficulty.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It gives you an idea of whether a keyword would be profitable to target or not.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;SEMRUSH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhcPjF5Xp0f_j3LEzL1aOppWxoqdWtxA7kwRMnWHbiSk-_coyrMwWl6kjy3t_sT0TULSm0C6CzC2-xxgTzz_Gp7zDB5uotawo722P-uBuk_Wm1LXyj3W2zKSGIPRazUBmHLGaFWXskZcQGSezKY5yQF07pKF3QYdWIqXyDoNuSvG9Iv8bnR3-fB29VRSA=s352" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="semrush position tracking" border="0" data-original-height="143" data-original-width="352" height="260" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhcPjF5Xp0f_j3LEzL1aOppWxoqdWtxA7kwRMnWHbiSk-_coyrMwWl6kjy3t_sT0TULSm0C6CzC2-xxgTzz_Gp7zDB5uotawo722P-uBuk_Wm1LXyj3W2zKSGIPRazUBmHLGaFWXskZcQGSezKY5yQF07pKF3QYdWIqXyDoNuSvG9Iv8bnR3-fB29VRSA=w640-h260" title="semrush position tracking" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMRush offers a tool called Position Tracking. This tool is a project tool—you must set it up as a new project. Below are a few of the most popular features of the SEMrush Position Tracking tool:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;All subscribers are given regular data updates and mobile search rankings upon subscribing&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The platform provides opportunities to track several SERP features, including Local tracking.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Intuitive reports allow you to track statistics for the pages on your website, as well as the keywords used in those pages.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Identify pages that may be competing with each other using the Cannibalization report.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;WHO WINS?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs is a more user-friendly option. It takes seconds to enter a domain name and keywords. From there, you can quickly decide whether to proceed with that keyword or figure out how to rank better for other keywords.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush allows you to check your mobile rankings and ranking updates daily, which is something Ahrefs does not offer. SEMrush also offers social media rankings, a tool you won't find within the Ahrefs platform. Both are good which one do you like let me know in the comment.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Keyword research is closely related to rank tracking, but it's used for deciding which keywords you plan on using for future content rather than those you use now.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When it comes to SEO, keyword research is the most important thing to consider when comparing the two platforms.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;AHREFS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjVlN7ZilFvyQeMJ6PPTwdkbIonTi5Vk1tHik9vLCGaS90ncQ9lfBz3d0k3UphJlRjfSdolO7lDrP9ucXQ89rg3L3nMhnZMcgD9INDfxElxUfTYCZVtTX7Jtg3A7EW1sgQKGGLJ1IoGZC_VnvNTLVrkRvGmaUDlQmoQycMCXEaNGcuV0tHeqxBPhs00BA=s824" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="372" data-original-width="824" height="288" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjVlN7ZilFvyQeMJ6PPTwdkbIonTi5Vk1tHik9vLCGaS90ncQ9lfBz3d0k3UphJlRjfSdolO7lDrP9ucXQ89rg3L3nMhnZMcgD9INDfxElxUfTYCZVtTX7Jtg3A7EW1sgQKGGLJ1IoGZC_VnvNTLVrkRvGmaUDlQmoQycMCXEaNGcuV0tHeqxBPhs00BA=w640-h288" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Ahrefs Keyword Explorer provides you with thousands of keyword ideas and filters search results based on the chosen search engine.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs supports several features, including:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It can search multiple keywords in a single search and analyze them together. At SEMrush, you also have this feature in Keyword Overview.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs has a variety of keywords for different search engines, including Google, YouTube, Amazon, Bing, Yahoo, Yandex, and other search engines.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you click on a keyword, you can see its search volume and keyword difficulty, but also other keywords related to it, which you didn't use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;h2 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMRUSH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjiBVN83kj79tj3MmwHM5ELWsU9oAx5bZ7Y7znUE1zevmfGZNcshIh-7WzAWu7StXVuAG7wcLTgAzfLSn5wZ-8ur9EQtkjlMb0Tz22Qitnl1iKHq7iSfq3oNr281qY_3jamHUjaSWx2Yl4Q-47dZmgjLyvO9l9LooPjxRLN2eZTZIT0u8awK8ImaZsaoQ=s1672" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="904" data-original-width="1672" height="346" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjiBVN83kj79tj3MmwHM5ELWsU9oAx5bZ7Y7znUE1zevmfGZNcshIh-7WzAWu7StXVuAG7wcLTgAzfLSn5wZ-8ur9EQtkjlMb0Tz22Qitnl1iKHq7iSfq3oNr281qY_3jamHUjaSWx2Yl4Q-47dZmgjLyvO9l9LooPjxRLN2eZTZIT0u8awK8ImaZsaoQ=w640-h346" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush's Keyword Magic Tool has over 20 billion keywords for Google. You can type in any keyword you want, and a list of suggested keywords will appear.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Keyword Magic Tool also lets you to:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Show performance metrics by keyword&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Search results are based on both broad and exact keyword matches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Show data like search volume, trends, keyword difficulty, and CPC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Show the first 100 Google search results for any keyword.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Identify SERP Features and Questions related to each keyword&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush has released a new Keyword Gap Tool that uncovers potentially useful keyword opportunities for you, including both paid and organic keywords.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;           &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;WHO WINS?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Both of these tools offer keyword research features and allow users to break down complicated tasks into something that can be understood by beginners and advanced users alike.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you're interested in keyword suggestions, SEMrush appears to have more keyword suggestions than Ahrefs does. It also continues to add new features, like the Keyword Gap tool and SERP Questions recommendations.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 14.05pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 14.05pt; margin: 14.05pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext"&gt;Competitor Analysis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Both platforms offer competitor analysis tools, eliminating the need to come up with keywords off the top of your head. Each tool is useful for finding keywords that will be useful for your competition so you know they will be valuable to you.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;AHREFS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhPVWMffMoYqUU3U1PvQqmOTRNlQmKNSOfvhQ9CU4iIbeICqhQnDrk54c2B_bv_ceqp8JvCdeZ_mhVhMIZM243qpMPJzn1qrFhPmAYs1RQ2U-4jdm5Wml5ByEDhfJSxkqXo2nHegAvrGStAfrx1kADwNhiqzh_ctgmDhaVUrbzu2tvU_9W1rc09LZv-Dw=s768" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="368" data-original-width="768" height="306" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhPVWMffMoYqUU3U1PvQqmOTRNlQmKNSOfvhQ9CU4iIbeICqhQnDrk54c2B_bv_ceqp8JvCdeZ_mhVhMIZM243qpMPJzn1qrFhPmAYs1RQ2U-4jdm5Wml5ByEDhfJSxkqXo2nHegAvrGStAfrx1kADwNhiqzh_ctgmDhaVUrbzu2tvU_9W1rc09LZv-Dw=w640-h306" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ahrefs' domain comparison tool lets you compare up to five websites (your website and four competitors) side-by-side.it also shows you&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;how your site is ranked against others with metrics such as backlinks, domain ratings, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Use the Competing Domains section to see a list of your most direct competitors, and explore how many keywords matches your competitors have.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To find more information about your competitor, you can look at the Site Explorer and Content Explorer tools and type in their URL instead of yours.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;SEMRUSH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjFfBJXtpt_AgR1qT00BIOsWz_HhUEeTLPUsO_FjMCnR4fFAjD2O-_ba6oQoYl3T4Y-PmPD31ZIVieQJTn5r_uX0PQASI6yYAvPBpm7n7YM4wJ9fsBlQ69mU9npFUYxs5-1zJJvZ2--QDrJAvTpIEstcxsyE6sZ3zz36rd35qp6loVAEAvOxmjqZu06rg=s1620" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="639" data-original-width="1620" height="252" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjFfBJXtpt_AgR1qT00BIOsWz_HhUEeTLPUsO_FjMCnR4fFAjD2O-_ba6oQoYl3T4Y-PmPD31ZIVieQJTn5r_uX0PQASI6yYAvPBpm7n7YM4wJ9fsBlQ69mU9npFUYxs5-1zJJvZ2--QDrJAvTpIEstcxsyE6sZ3zz36rd35qp6loVAEAvOxmjqZu06rg=w640-h252" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush provides a variety of insights into your competitors' marketing tactics. The platform enables you to research your competitors effectively. It also offers several resources for competitor analysis including:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Traffic Analytics helps you identify where your audience comes from, how they engage with your site, what devices visitors use to view your site, and how your audiences overlap with other websites.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush's Organic Research examines your website's major competitors and shows their organic search rankings, keywords they are ranking for, and even if they are ranking for any (SERP) features and more.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Market Explorer search field allows you to type in a domain and lists websites or articles similar to what you entered. Market Explorer also allows users to perform in-depth data analytics on These companies and markets.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 15.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 15.95pt; margin: 15.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext" style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;WHO WINS?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMrush wins here because it has more tools dedicated to competitor analysis than Ahrefs. However, Ahrefs offers a lot of functionality in this area, too. It takes a combination of both tools to gain an advantage over your competition.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;h3 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ahrefs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lite Monthly: $99/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Standard Monthly: $179/month &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Annually Lite: $990/year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Annually Standard: $1790/year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;       &lt;h3 style="margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;SEMRUSH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pro Plan: $119.95/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Guru Plan:$229.95/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Business Plan: $449.95/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;h2 style="break-after: auto; margin-bottom: 14.95pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 14.95pt; margin: 14.95pt 0in; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; page-break-after: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span color="windowtext"&gt;Which SEO tool should you choose for digital marketing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When it comes to keyword data research, you will become confused about which one to choose.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Consider choosing Ahrefs if you&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Like friendly and clean interface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Searching for simple keyword suggestions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Want to get more keywords for different search engines like Amazon, Bing, Yahoo, Yandex, Baidu, and more &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Consider SEMrush if you:&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Want more marketing and SEO features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Need competitor analysis tool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Need to keep your backlinks profile clean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Looking for more keyword suggestions for Google&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in; text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Both tools are great. Choose the one which meets your requirements and if you have any experience using either Ahrefs or SEMrush let me know in the comment section which works well for you.&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 12.0pt; margin-left: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 12.0pt; margin: 12pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/03/ahrefs-vs-semrush-which-seo-tool-should.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgjp-Lwdt6oYlgGQ0HWI9cLSBOiniI0CKOWnRWuiQTe2uBJIenevsoZKESvI4-Uo-4r6VU1RjQZUtLtpA1vJyAZhg0fEFn-wOintkjZnNkYcZjS0XIs3XQ2dPgOwKfZZw4YubtvjfJRsVyRBc4tCckB7yip4A-9W1yMbv7bBk3zEGElqHhzHxBdoQAOCg=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>10</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-2465929187257267845</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-19T15:03:39.694+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">PLR</category>
      <title>Top 10 Best PLR(Private Label Rights)  Websites | Which One You Should Join in 2022?</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgpTleC7nbtAf6ZqNeNw3zr0CpxWqvP175ArBM_TBOd_D2XjD_CGwF2TM9OsWbwU_-C1BEOe2OXJ_oSgpXDk-KKLqU3hWGz4nlEFbfUnDMGrG7CVmSbU0R4RKilCKTgdnIenYfcsdZn_Bf-KJ9hQoWMgrys1mzk-DC1KFkpsA4ojFe549aXM2QF58xHfQ=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="PLR" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgpTleC7nbtAf6ZqNeNw3zr0CpxWqvP175ArBM_TBOd_D2XjD_CGwF2TM9OsWbwU_-C1BEOe2OXJ_oSgpXDk-KKLqU3hWGz4nlEFbfUnDMGrG7CVmSbU0R4RKilCKTgdnIenYfcsdZn_Bf-KJ9hQoWMgrys1mzk-DC1KFkpsA4ojFe549aXM2QF58xHfQ=w640-h360" title="PLR" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Content creation is one of the biggest struggles for many marketers and business owners. It often requires both time and financial resources, especially if you plan to hire a writer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Today, we have a fantastic opportunity to use other people's products by purchasing Private Label Rights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To find a good PLR website, first, determine the type of products you want to acquire. One way to do this is to choose among membership sites or PLR product stores. Following are 10 great sites that offer products in both categories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;What are PLR websites?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Private Label Rights (PLR) products are digital products that can be in the form of an ebook, software, online course videos, value-packed articles, etc. You can use these products with some adjustments to sell as your own under your own brand and keep all the money and profit yourself without wasting your time on product creation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The truth is that locating the best website for PLR materials can be a time-consuming and expensive exercise. That’s why we have researched, analyzed, and ranked the best 10 websites:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1. PLR.me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;PLR.me is of the best places to get PLR content in 2021-2022. It offers a content marketing system that comes with courses, brandable tools, and more. It is the most trusted PLR website, among other PLR sites. The PLR.me platform features smart digital caching PLR tools for health and wellness professionals. The PLR.me platform, which was built on advanced caching technology, has been well-received by big brands such as Toronto Sun and Entrepreneur. The best thing about this website is its content marketing automation tools.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pay-as-you-go Plan – $22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;100 Monthly Plan – $99/month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;400 Annual Plan – $379/year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;800 Annual Plan – $579/year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2500 Annual Plan – $990/year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Access over 15,940+ ready-to-use PLR coaching resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Content marketing and sliding tools are provided by the site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can create courses, products, webinars, emails, and nearly anything else you can dream of.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can cancel your subscription anytime.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Compared to other top PLR sites, this one is a bit more expensive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2. InDigitalWorks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;InDigitalWorks is a leading private label rights membership website established in 2008. As of now, it has more than 100,000 members from around the globe have joined the platform. The site offers thousands of ready-to-be-sold digital products for online businesses in every single niche possible. InDigitalWorks features hundreds of electronic books, software applications, templates, graphics, videos that you can sell right away.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3 Months Plan – $39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1 Year Plan – $69&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lifetime Plan – $79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;IndigitalWorks promotes new authors by providing them with 200 free products for download.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Largest and most reputable private label rights membership site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;20000+ digital products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;137 training videos provided by experts to help beginners set up and grow their online presence for free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10 GB of web hosting will be available on a reliable server.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Fewer people are experiencing the frustration of not getting the help they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3. BuyQualityPLR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;BuyQualityPLR’s website is a Top PLR of 2021-2022! It's a source for major Internet Marketing Products and Resources. Whether you’re an Affiliate Marketer, Product Creator, Course Seller,&amp;nbsp; BuyQualityPLR can assist you in the right direction. You will find several eBooks and digital products related to the Health and Fitness niche, along with a series of Security-based products. If you search for digital products, Resell Rights Products, Private Label Rights Products, or Internet Marketing Products, BuyQualityPLR is among the best websites for your needs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free PLR articles packs, ebooks, and other digital products are available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Price ranges from 3.99$ to 99.9$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Everything on this site is written by professionals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The quick download features available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Doesn't provide membership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Offers thousand of PLR content in many niches&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Valuable courses available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can't buy all content because it doesn't provide membership&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4. IDPLR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The IDPLR website has helped thousands of internet marketers since 2008. This website follows a membership approach and allows you to gain access to thousands of PLR products in different niches. The best thing about this site is the quality of the products, which is extremely impressive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;This is the best PLR website of 2021-2022, offering over 200k+ high-quality articles. It also gives you graphics, templates, ebooks, and audio.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3 Months ACCESS: $39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1 YEAR ACCESS: $69&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;LIFETIME ACCESS: $79&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You will have access to over 12,590 PLR products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You will get access to training tutorials and Courses in a Gold membership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10 GB of web hosting will be available on a reliable server.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You will receive 3D eCover Software&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It offers an unlimited download limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Most important, you will get a 30 day money-back guarantee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A few products are available for free membership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. PLRMines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;PLRmines is a leading digital product library for private label rights products. The site provides useful information on products that you can use to grow your business, as well as licenses for reselling the content. You can either purchase a membership or get access through a free trial, and you can find unlimited high-quality resources via the site's paid or free membership. Overall, the site is an excellent resource for finding outstanding private label rights content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lifetime membership:&amp;nbsp; $97&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4000+ ebooks from top categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Members have access to more than 660 instructional videos covering all kinds of topics in a membership area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You will receive outstanding graphics that are ready to use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;They also offer a variety of helpful resources and tools, such as PLR blogs, WordPress themes, and plugins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The free membership won't give you much value.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6. Super-Resell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Super-Resell is another remarkable provider of PLR material. The platform was established in 2009 and offers valuable PLR content to users. Currently, the platform offers standard lifetime memberships and monthly plans at an affordable price. Interested users can purchase up to 10,000 products with digital rights or rights of re-sale. Super-Resell offers a wide range of products such as readymade websites, article packs, videos, ebooks, software, templates, and graphics, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6 Months Membership: $49.90&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lifetime membership: $129&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It offers you products that come with sales pages and those without sales pages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;You'll find thousands of digital products that will help your business grow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Daily News update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The company has set up an automatic renewal system. This can result in costs for you even though you are not using the service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7. Unstoppable PLR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;UnStoppablePLR was launched in 2006 by Aurelius Tjin, an internet marketer. Over the last 15 years, UnStoppablePLR has provided massive value to users by offering high-quality PLR content. The site is one of the best PLR sites because of its affordability and flexibility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Regular Price: $29/Month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You’ll get 30 PLR articles in various niches for free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;100% money-back guarantee.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Members get access to community&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It gives you access to professionally designed graphics and much more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;People often complain that not enough PLR products are released each month.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;8. Resell Rights Weekly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Resell Rights Weekly, a private label rights (PLR) website, provides exceptional PLR content. It is among the top free PLR websites that provide free membership. You will get 728+ PLR products completely free and new products every single week. The Resell Rights Weekly gives you free instant access to all products and downloads the ones you require.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Gold Membership: $19.95/Month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lots of products available free of cost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free access to the&amp;nbsp; members forum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The prices for the products at this PLR site are very low quality compared to other websites that sell the same items.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;9. MasterResellRights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;MasterResellRights was established in 2006, and it has helped many successful entrepreneurs. Once you join MasterResellRights, you will get access to more than 10,000 products and services from other members. It is one of the top PLR sites that provide high-quality PLR products to members across the globe. You will be able to access a lot of other membership privileges at no extra price. The website also provides PLR, MRR, and RR license products.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;One Month Membership: $19.97&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;Three Month Membership: $47.00&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;Access more than 10,000 high-quality,&amp;nbsp; PLR articles in different niches.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;Get daily fresh new updates&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;Users get 8 GB of hosting space&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;You can pay using PayPal&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;⦁&lt;span style="white-space: pre;"&gt;	&lt;/span&gt;Only members have access to the features of this site.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10. BigProductStore&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;BigProductStore is a popular private label rights website that offers tens of thousands of digital products. These include software, videos, video courses, eBooks, and many others that you can resell, use as you want, or sell and keep 100% of the profit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The PLR website updates its product list daily. It currently offers over 10,000 products.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The site offers original content for almost every niche and when you register as a member, you can access the exclusive products section where you can download a variety of high-quality, unique, and exclusive products.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Monthly Plan: $19.90/Month 27% off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;One-Time-Payment: $98.50&amp;nbsp; 50% off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Monthly Ultimate: $29.90/Month 36% off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;One-Time-Payment Ultimate: $198.50 50% off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can use PLR products to generate profits, give them as bonuses for your affiliate promotion campaign, or rebrand them and create new unique products.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Lifetime memberships for PLR products can save you money if you’re looking for a long-term solution to bulk goods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The website is updated regularly with fresh, quality content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Product descriptions may not provide much detail, so it can be difficult to know just what you’re downloading.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Some product categories such as WP Themes and articles are outdated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/02/top-10-best-plrprivate-label-rights.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgpTleC7nbtAf6ZqNeNw3zr0CpxWqvP175ArBM_TBOd_D2XjD_CGwF2TM9OsWbwU_-C1BEOe2OXJ_oSgpXDk-KKLqU3hWGz4nlEFbfUnDMGrG7CVmSbU0R4RKilCKTgdnIenYfcsdZn_Bf-KJ9hQoWMgrys1mzk-DC1KFkpsA4ojFe549aXM2QF58xHfQ=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>5</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-841924673597300262</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-22T16:04:57.615+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">review</category>
      <title>Canva Review 2022: Details, Pricing &amp; Features</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiljHs4qU-lZzbi0TWFIn9ZuZKsIqXppAn9S2OA4I8hviC-oeROUJF6PF5KTjPEWQ2irXcq0ZnCIPMK0pBNstNrtYIDtMsqgNkw7owWNq3iv6svrjwvE0qzmQPxWCqb8zFpAZp2h-nbXAycwtkBxLBXR29g8zffX5fJPYtV5_Tblkbm-0MC19hOMYHYcA=s1366" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="768" data-original-width="1366" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiljHs4qU-lZzbi0TWFIn9ZuZKsIqXppAn9S2OA4I8hviC-oeROUJF6PF5KTjPEWQ2irXcq0ZnCIPMK0pBNstNrtYIDtMsqgNkw7owWNq3iv6svrjwvE0qzmQPxWCqb8zFpAZp2h-nbXAycwtkBxLBXR29g8zffX5fJPYtV5_Tblkbm-0MC19hOMYHYcA=w640-h360" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Are you looking for a new graphic design tool? Would you like to read a detailed review of Canva? As it's one of the tools I love using. I am also writing my first ebook using canva and publish it soon on my site you can download it is free.&amp;nbsp; Let's start the review.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva has a web version and also a mobile app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;What is &lt;a href="https://partner.canva.com/c/3290703/1278208/10068" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Canva&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://partner.canva.com/c/3290703/1278208/10068" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Canva &lt;/a&gt;is a free graphic design web application that allows you to create invitations, business cards, flyers, lesson plans, banners, and more using professionally designed templates. You can upload your own photos from your computer or from Google Drive, and add them to Canva's templates using a simple drag-and-drop interface. It's like having a basic version of Photoshop that doesn't require Graphic designing knowledge to use. It’s best for nongraphic designers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Who is Canva best suited for?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://partner.canva.com/c/3290703/1278208/10068" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Canva &lt;/a&gt;is a great tool for small business owners, online entrepreneurs, and marketers who don’t have the time and want to edit quickly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To create sophisticated graphics, a tool such as Photoshop can is ideal. To use it, you’ll need to learn its hundreds of features, get familiar with the software, and it’s best to have a good background in design, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Also running the latest version of Photoshop you need a high-end computer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;So here&amp;nbsp; Canva takes place, with Canva you can do all that with drag-and-drop feature. It’s also easier to use and free. Also an even-more-affordable paid version is available for $12.95 per month.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free vs Pro vs Enterprise Pricing plan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The product is available in three plans: Free, Pro ($12.99/month per user or&amp;nbsp; $119.99/year for up to 5 people), and Enterprise ($30 per user per month, minimum 25 people).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free plan Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;250,000+ free templates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;100+ design types (social media posts, presentations, letters, and more)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Hundreds of thousands of free photos and graphics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Invite members to your team&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Collaborate and comment in real-time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5GB of cloud storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: red; font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Try &lt;a href="https://partner.canva.com/c/3290703/1278208/10068" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Canva Pro&lt;/a&gt; for free for 30 days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pro Plan Features&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Everything Free, has plus:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;100+ million premium and&amp;nbsp; stock photos, videos, audio, and graphics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;610,000+ premium and free templates with new designs daily&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Access to Background Remover and Magic Resize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Create a library of your brand or campaign's colors, logos, and fonts with up to 100 Brand Kits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Remove image backgrounds instantly with background remover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Resize designs infinitely with Magic Resize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Save designs as templates for your team to use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;100GB of cloud storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Schedule social media content to 8 platforms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Enterprise Plan Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Everything Pro has plus:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Establish your brand's visual identity with logos, colors and fonts across multiple Brand Kits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Control your team's access to apps, graphics, logos, colors and fonts with brand controls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Built-in workflows to get approval on your designs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Set which elements your team can edit and stay on brand with template locking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Unlimited Storage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Log in with single-sign on (SSO) and have access to 24/7 Enterprise-level support.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;How to Use Canva?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To get started on Canva, you will need to create an account by providing your email address, Google, Facebook or Apple credentials. You will then choose your account type between student, teacher, small business, large company, non-profit, or personal. Based on your choice of account type, templates will be recommended to you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can sign up for a free trial of Canva Pro, or you can start with the free version to get a sense of whether it’s the right graphic design tool for your needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="1278208"&gt;&lt;a href="https://partner.canva.com/c/3290703/1278208/10068"&gt;Canva Sign Up &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img height="0" width="0" src="https://imp.pxf.io/i/3290703/1278208/10068" style="position:absolute;visibility:hidden;" border="0" /&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Designing with Canva&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgM7YZbpEWXuX7McOKgqVQgrWlabYMSo3a4U9zch0MoomYWl4xBhgZrVjiZKA9hMBEkEL-5IkdFFkw7rotiewBPKDjunpoe6eBXwmG_rk7Ntkw0l4h-bdBMY5LJtS_QFWWkauczX7J4wI5aMMPmHD3nKre-xTEzdLvVVgx5IC5lEAbNpIgSB6kEMRO-iw=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="canva" border="0" data-original-height="870" data-original-width="1280" height="436" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgM7YZbpEWXuX7McOKgqVQgrWlabYMSo3a4U9zch0MoomYWl4xBhgZrVjiZKA9hMBEkEL-5IkdFFkw7rotiewBPKDjunpoe6eBXwmG_rk7Ntkw0l4h-bdBMY5LJtS_QFWWkauczX7J4wI5aMMPmHD3nKre-xTEzdLvVVgx5IC5lEAbNpIgSB6kEMRO-iw=w640-h436" title="canva" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you sign up for an account, Canva will suggest different post types to choose from. Based on the type of account you set up&amp;nbsp; you'll be able to see templates categorized by the following categories: social media posts, documents, presentations, marketing, events, ads, launch your business, build your online brand, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Start by choosing a template for your post or searching for something more specific. Search by social network name to see a list of post types on each network.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Templates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEimJ6jOhTnmaFvrB_VTjmU4f5D4AqXjy65hqYROJW4_z_-EN0phhYBAoCpgD5iq2ICEF19CE6CS1o41joiTQDR12n-trPkotc4gGOggwyf2qpLR5G8pHkXd6DszzjsvJ_OtRZFE5vAUw81Gvv3kr_gdmA_JhhBjSpMDkj1lBWJb1uJeVbPsqwUKgLgMoQ=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="canva templates" border="0" data-original-height="882" data-original-width="1280" height="442" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEimJ6jOhTnmaFvrB_VTjmU4f5D4AqXjy65hqYROJW4_z_-EN0phhYBAoCpgD5iq2ICEF19CE6CS1o41joiTQDR12n-trPkotc4gGOggwyf2qpLR5G8pHkXd6DszzjsvJ_OtRZFE5vAUw81Gvv3kr_gdmA_JhhBjSpMDkj1lBWJb1uJeVbPsqwUKgLgMoQ=w640-h442" title="canva templates" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Next, you can choose a template. Choose from hundreds of templates that are ready to go, with customizable photos, text, and other elements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can start your design by choosing from a variety of ready-made templates, searching for a template matching your needs, or working with a blank template.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Canva has a lot to choose from, so start with a specific search.if you want to create business card just search for it and you will see alot of templates to choose from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Elements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Inside the Canva designer, the Elements tab gives you access to lines and shapes, graphics, photos, videos, audio, charts, photo frames, and photo grids.The search box on the Elements tab lets you search everything on Canva.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiMPph53bq8js4qlIL55ERQwzAxyL406RSoDJ10bhJ8iO_mlKHtuaQBKAVr4iLEbJh4xEQW7QOfDXOqV1sbYv3qRdMssBchVFWWFqfANHdeX0461ZaBsX_bsLwrB-ad4OyJFfAu03Jyok1fCMvpR5IiBnFjOxVIYbP9AQe7Zs6NIHKwspoD8hl3unL3Dw=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="canva elements" border="0" data-original-height="882" data-original-width="1280" height="442" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiMPph53bq8js4qlIL55ERQwzAxyL406RSoDJ10bhJ8iO_mlKHtuaQBKAVr4iLEbJh4xEQW7QOfDXOqV1sbYv3qRdMssBchVFWWFqfANHdeX0461ZaBsX_bsLwrB-ad4OyJFfAu03Jyok1fCMvpR5IiBnFjOxVIYbP9AQe7Zs6NIHKwspoD8hl3unL3Dw=w640-h442" title="canva elements" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To begin with, Canva has a large library of elements to choose from. To find them, be specific in your search query. You may also want to search in the following tabs to see various elements separately:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Photos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Photos tab lets you search for and choose from millions of professional stock photos for your templates.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can replace the photos in our templates to create a new look. This can also make the template more suited to your industry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can find photos on other stock photography sites like pexel, pixabay and many more or simply upload your own photos.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhKT6RizHZUEKqQQAV8rZZUDBHG_7b8oD-2jNuEUsf4q2RYa7Nx_QDTVSL7vBWvdi8NWBEyV2sKMtE4MtIFgc5O6ggDlunJMNa8ilfAFIWG3xMWQiqY0BKZFHRxn0151lEbOj-6QykEt28OY8e_0F_WyloPPKbiXLH-h68degeJZzyHZddkSO0Ge-zamA=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="canva photos" border="0" data-original-height="884" data-original-width="1280" height="442" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhKT6RizHZUEKqQQAV8rZZUDBHG_7b8oD-2jNuEUsf4q2RYa7Nx_QDTVSL7vBWvdi8NWBEyV2sKMtE4MtIFgc5O6ggDlunJMNa8ilfAFIWG3xMWQiqY0BKZFHRxn0151lEbOj-6QykEt28OY8e_0F_WyloPPKbiXLH-h68degeJZzyHZddkSO0Ge-zamA=w640-h442" title="canva photos" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you choose an image, Canva’s photo editing features let you adjust the photo’s settings (brightness, contrast, saturation, etc.), crop, or animate it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;When you subscribe to Canva Pro, you get access to a number of premium features, including the Background Remover. This feature allows you to remove the background from any stock photo in&amp;nbsp; library or any image you upload.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Text tab lets you add headings, normal text, and graphical text to your design.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you click on&amp;nbsp; text, you'll see options to adjust the font, font size, color, format, spacing, and text effects (like shadows).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Pro subscribers can choose from a large library of fonts on the Brand Kit or the Styles tab. Enterprise-level controls ensure that visual content remains on-brand, no matter how many people are working on it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Audio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Create an animated image or video by adding audio to capture user’s attention in social news feeds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you want to use audio from another stock site or your own audio tracks, you can upload them in the Uploads tab or from the more option.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Video&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Want to create your own videos? Choose from thousands of stock video clips. You’ll find videos that range upto 2 minutes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can upload your own videos as well as videos from other stock sites in the Uploads tab.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Once you have chosen a video, you can use the editing features in Canva to trim the video, flip it, and adjust its transparency.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Backgrounds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;On the Background tab, you’ll find free stock photos to serve as backgrounds on your designs. Change out the background on a template to give it a more personal touch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Styles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhBQW4BOkq3UutI4TFJiQlwAkDWDeE_48rdkRxCrVrRMkhw6cDGtZKFruHN-Q54dF9446S6j9Wp-9n914SAde1veZqvCo8ATKX2UuSx-TMYq--zNtB2wkFXdtAOS4q6_1EBVCVz8kfJfo2HT2CA-ModbPaq3a86gMezGir-Vqmvz61ic-tJMfxNmblZMA=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="880" data-original-width="1280" height="440" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhBQW4BOkq3UutI4TFJiQlwAkDWDeE_48rdkRxCrVrRMkhw6cDGtZKFruHN-Q54dF9446S6j9Wp-9n914SAde1veZqvCo8ATKX2UuSx-TMYq--zNtB2wkFXdtAOS4q6_1EBVCVz8kfJfo2HT2CA-ModbPaq3a86gMezGir-Vqmvz61ic-tJMfxNmblZMA=w640-h440" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Styles tab lets you quickly change the look and feel of your template with just a click. And if you have a Canva Pro subscription, you can upload your brand’s custom colors and fonts to ensure designs stay on brand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Logos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you have a Canva Pro subscription, you’ll have a Logos tab. Here, you can upload variations of your brand logo to use throughout your designs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;With Canva, you can also create your own logos. Note that you cannot trademark a logo with stock content in it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Publishing with Canva&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;With Canva, free users can download and share designs to multiple platforms including Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Slack and Tumblr.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Pro subscribers can create multiple post formats from one design. For example, you can start by designing an Instagram post, and Canva's Magic Resizer can resize it for other networks, Stories, Reels, and other formats.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Pro subscribers can also use Canva’s Content Planner to post content on eight different accounts on Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Slack, and Tumblr.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Team&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Pro allows you to work with your team on visual content. Designs can be created inside Canva, and then sent to your team members for approval. Everyone can make comments, edits, revisions, and keep track via the version history.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When it comes to printing your designs, Canva has you covered. With an extensive selection of printing options, they can turn your designs into anything from banners and wall art to mugs and t-shirts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Print is perfect for any business seeking to make a lasting impression. Create inspiring designs people will want to wear, keep, and share. Hand out custom business cards that leave a lasting impression on customers' minds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Apps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The Canva app is available on the Apple App Store and Google Play. The Canva app has earned a 4.9 out of five star rating from over 946.3K Apple users and a 4.5 out of five star rating from over 6,996,708 Google users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In addition to mobile apps, you can use Canva’s integration with other Internet services to add images and text from sources like Google Maps, Emojis, photos from Google Drive and Dropbox, YouTube videos, Flickr photos, Bitmojis, and other popular visual content elements.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva Pros and Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pros:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A user-friendly interface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva is a great tool for people who want to create professional graphics but don’t have graphic design skills.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Hundreds of templates, so you'll never have to start from scratch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Wide variety of templates to fit multiple uses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Branding kits to keep your team consistent with the brand colors and fonts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Creating visual content on the go&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can find royalty free images, audio, and video without having to subscribe to another service.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cons:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Some professional templates are available for Pro user only&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Advanced photo editing features like blurring or erasing a specific area are missing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Some elements that fall outside of a design are tricky to retrieve.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features (like Canva presentations) could use some improvement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you are a regular user of Adobe products, you might find Canva's features limited.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Prefers to work with vectors. Especially logos.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Expensive enterprise pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In general, Canva is an excellent tool for those who need simple images for projects. If you are a graphic designer with experience, you will find Canva’s platform lacking in customization and advanced features – particularly vectors. But if you have little design experience, you will find Canva easier to use than advanced graphic design tools like Adobe Photoshop or Illustrator for most projects. If you have any queries let me know in the comments section.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/02/canva-review-2022-details-pricing.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiljHs4qU-lZzbi0TWFIn9ZuZKsIqXppAn9S2OA4I8hviC-oeROUJF6PF5KTjPEWQ2irXcq0ZnCIPMK0pBNstNrtYIDtMsqgNkw7owWNq3iv6svrjwvE0qzmQPxWCqb8zFpAZp2h-nbXAycwtkBxLBXR29g8zffX5fJPYtV5_Tblkbm-0MC19hOMYHYcA=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>1</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-1806810620236281419</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:22:49.686+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Wordpress</category>
      <title>Top 7 Best Wordpress Plugin Of All Time</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh83RF5KAieFKbr8sc_oPwJu-O9cNT4jJC_X80CRTLCtAzm-P2Cmve2aQCJ34ry4Dve9p9APjCwN1Nk8y8pzGRmxo4ZNGtVp0wZx88vviNUwX3n7OWWR7Vl6tVSY_xUULmVFMNMGR6R4t1GVsvEHP_xn5MM-9bxj91J4EAEwN1XYVZD8C82fz64bjmLoA=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh83RF5KAieFKbr8sc_oPwJu-O9cNT4jJC_X80CRTLCtAzm-P2Cmve2aQCJ34ry4Dve9p9APjCwN1Nk8y8pzGRmxo4ZNGtVp0wZx88vviNUwX3n7OWWR7Vl6tVSY_xUULmVFMNMGR6R4t1GVsvEHP_xn5MM-9bxj91J4EAEwN1XYVZD8C82fz64bjmLoA=w640-h360" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you are looking for the best wordpress plugins, then you are at the right place. Here is the list of best wordpress plugins that you should use in your blog to boost SEO, strong your security and know every aspects of your blog . Although creating a good content is one factor but there are many wordpress plugins that perform different actions and add on to your success. So let's&amp;nbsp; start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1.Yoast SEO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Those users who are serious about SEO, Yoast SEO will do the work for them to reach their goals. All they need to do is select a keyword, and the plugin will then optimize your page according to the specified keyword&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Yoast offers many popular SEO WordPress plugin functions. It gives you real-time page analysis to optimize your content, images, meta descriptions, titles, and kewords. Yoast also checks the length of your sentences and paragraphs, whether you’re using enough transition words or subheadings, how often you use passive voice, and so on. Yoast tells Google whether or not to index a page or a set of pages too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Let me summarize these points in bullets:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Enhance the readability of your article to reduce bounce rate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Optimize your articles with targetted keywords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Let Google know who you are and what your site is about&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Improve your on-page SEO with advanced, real-time guidance and advice on keyword usage, linking, and external linking.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Keep your focus keywords consistent to help rank better on&amp;nbsp; Google.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Preview how your page would appear in the search engine results page (SERP)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Crawl your site daily to ensure Google indexes it as quickly as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Rate your article informing you of any mistakes you might have made so that you can fix them before publishing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Stay up-to-date with Google’s latest algorithm changes and adapt your on-page SEO as needed with smartsuggestionss from the Yoast SEO plugin. This plugin is always up-to-date.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free Version is available&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Premium version=$89/year that comes with extra functions, allowing you to optimize your content up to five keywords, among other benefits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2. WP Rocket&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A website running WordPress can put a lot of strain on a server, which increases the chances that the website will crash and harm your business. To avoid such an unfortunate situation and ensure that all your pages load quickly, you need a caching plugin like WP Rocket.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;WP Rocket plugin designed to increases your website speed. Instead of waiting for pages to be saved to cache, WP Rocket turns on desired caching settings, like page cache and gzip compression. The plugin also activates other features, such as CDN support and llazy image loadding, to enhance your site speed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features in bullets:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Browser Catching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Preloading the cache of pages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Reducing the number of HTTP requests allows websites to load more quickly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Decreasing bandwidth usage with GZIP compression&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Apply optimal browser caching headers (expires)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Minifying and combining JavaScript and CSS files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Remove Unused CSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Deferred loading of images (LazyLoad)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;WebP compatibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Deferred loading of JavaScript files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Delay JavaScript Execution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Critical Path CSS generation and deferred loading of CSS files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Database optimization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;WordPress Heartbeat API control&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;DNS prefetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;CDN integration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cloudflare integration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Sucuri integration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Easy import/export of settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Easy roll back to a previous version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Single License =$49/year for one website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Plus License =$99/year for 3 websites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Infinite License =$249/year for unlimited websites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3.Wordfence Security&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Wordfence Security is a WordPress firewall and security scanner that keeps your site safe from malicious hackers, spam, and other online threats. This Plugin comes with a web application firewall (WAF) called tthread Defence&amp;nbsp; Feed&amp;nbsp; that helps to prevents brute force attacks by ensuring you set stronger passwords and limiting login attempts. It searches for malware and compares code, theme, and plugin files with the records in the WordPress.org repository to verify their integrity and reports changes to you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Wordfence security scanner provides you with actionable insights into your website's security status and will alert you to any potential threats, keeping it safe and secure. It also includes login security features that let you activate reCAPTCHA and two-factor authentication for your website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features in Bullets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Scans your site for vulnerabilities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Alerts you by email when new threats are detected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Supports advanced login security measures.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;IP addresses may be blocked automatically if suspicious activity is detected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Premium Plan= $99/Year that comes with extra security features like the real time IP backlist and country blocking option and also support from highly qualified experts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4. Akismet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Akismet can help prevent spam from appearing on your site. Every day, it automatically checks every comment against a global database of spam to block malicious content. With Akismet, you also won’t have to worry about innocent comments being caught by the filter or false positives. You can simply tell Akismet about those and it will get better over time. It also checks your contact form submissions against its global spam database and weed out unnecessary fake information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features in Bullets:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The program automatically checks comments and filters out spam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Hidden or misleading links are often revealed in the comment body.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Akismet tracks the status of each comment, allowing you to see which ones were caught by Akismet and which ones were cleared by a moderator.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A spam-blocking feature that saves disk space and makes your site run faster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Moderators can view a list of comments approved by each user.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free to use for personal blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. Contact Form 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Contact Form 7 is a plug-in that allows you to create contact forms that make it easy for your users to send messages to your site. The plug-in was developed by Takayuki Miyoshi and lets you create multiple contact forms on the same site; it also integrates Akismet spam filtering and lets you customize the styling and fields that you want to use in the form. The plug-in provides CAPTCHA and Ajax submitting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features in bullets:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Create and manage multiple contact forms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Easily customize form fields&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Use simple markup to alter mail content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Add Lots of third-party extensions for additional functionality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Shortcode offers a way to insert content into pages or posts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Akismet spam filtering, Ajax-powered submitting, and CAPTCHA are all features of this plugin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free to use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6. Monster Insights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you’re looking for an easy way to manage your Google Analytics-related web tracking services, Monster Insights can help. You can add, customize, and integrate Google Analytics data with ease so you’ll be able to see how every webpage performs, which online campaigns bring in the most traffic, and which content readers engage with the most. It’s same as Google Analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It is a powerful tool to keep track of your traffic stats. With it, you can view stats for your active sessions, conversions, and bounce rates. You’ll also be able to see your total revenue, the products you sell, and how your site is performing when it comes to referrals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;MonsterInsights offers a free plan that includes basic Google Analytics integration, data insights, and user activity metrics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features in bullets:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Demographics and interest reports:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Anonymize the&amp;nbsp; IPs of visitor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;See the results of how far visitors Scroll down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Show the insights of multiple links to the same page and show you which links get more clicks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;See sessions of two related sites as a single session&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Google AdSense tracking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Send you weekly analytics report of your blog you can download it as pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Premium plan= $99.50/year that comes with extra features like page and post tracking, Adsense tracking,&amp;nbsp; custom tracking and reports.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7. Pretty Links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pretty Links is a powerful WordPress plugin that enables you to easily cloak affiliate links on your websiteIt even allows you to easily redirect visitors based on a specific request, including permanent 301 and temporary 302/307 redirects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pretty links also helps you to automatically shorten your url for your post and pages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can also enable auto-linking feature to automatically add affiliate links for certain keywords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Create clean, easy-to-remember URLs on your website (301, 302, and 307 redirects only)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Random-generator or custom URL slugs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Track the number of clicks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Easy to understand reports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;View click details including ip address, remote host, browser, operating system, and referring site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can pass custom parameters to your scripts when using pretty permalinks, and still have full tracking capability.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Exclude IP Addresses from Stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cookie-based system to track your activity across clicks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Create nofollow/noindex links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Toggle tracking on / off on each link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pretty Link Bookmarklet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Update redirected links easily to new URLs!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pricing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Beginner Plan=$79/year that can be used on 1 site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Marketer Plan: $99/year – that can be used on upto 2 sites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Super Affiliate Plan: $149/year – that can be use on upto 5 sites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;We hope you’ve found this article useful. We appreciate you reading and welcome your feedback if you have it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/02/top-7-best-wordpress-plugin-of-all-time.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh83RF5KAieFKbr8sc_oPwJu-O9cNT4jJC_X80CRTLCtAzm-P2Cmve2aQCJ34ry4Dve9p9APjCwN1Nk8y8pzGRmxo4ZNGtVp0wZx88vviNUwX3n7OWWR7Vl6tVSY_xUULmVFMNMGR6R4t1GVsvEHP_xn5MM-9bxj91J4EAEwN1XYVZD8C82fz64bjmLoA=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>5</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-6302203471093077113</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-19T15:06:10.280+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Comparison</category>
      <title>Ginger VS Grammarly: Which Grammar Checker is Better in (2022) ?</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiw55GbmTyuJuYD43yqA61hrsY7bBgb5BwMzkO1sOgHcRFh3PK4ApQtQgGeXfZWLhT-2zxAxo_RB16tyEXwqBx4h__IKoEb9OIpWD9NqRI-9DU1uhH47E3QMQqFx0uSAjjk-aRD0hEZJkahQCdC_uQIZEVJUnVkyQfeqg8nJZxtgLCxZcLX0af06pu5WQ=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Grammarly vs Ginger" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiw55GbmTyuJuYD43yqA61hrsY7bBgb5BwMzkO1sOgHcRFh3PK4ApQtQgGeXfZWLhT-2zxAxo_RB16tyEXwqBx4h__IKoEb9OIpWD9NqRI-9DU1uhH47E3QMQqFx0uSAjjk-aRD0hEZJkahQCdC_uQIZEVJUnVkyQfeqg8nJZxtgLCxZcLX0af06pu5WQ=w640-h360" title="Grammrly Vs Ginger" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ginger VS Grammarly:&lt;/b&gt; When it comes to grammar checkers, Ginger and Grammarly are two of the most popular choices on the market. This article aims to highlight the specifics of each one so that you can make a more informed decision about the one you'll use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;What is Grammarly?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you are a writer, you must have heard of&amp;nbsp; Grammarly before. Grammarly has over 10M users across the globe, it's probably the most popular AI writing enhancement tool, without a doubt. That's why there's a high chance that you already know about Grammarly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;But today we are going to do a comparison between Ginger and Grammarly, So let's define Grammarly here. Like Ginger, Grammarly is an AI writing assistant that checks for grammatical errors, spellings, and punctuation. The free version covers the basics like identifying grammar and spelling mistakes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;While the Premium version offers a lot more functionality, it detects plagiarism in your content, suggests word choice, or adds fluency to it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features of Grammarly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly detects basic to advance grammatical errors and also help you why this is an error and suggest to you how you can improve it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Create a personal dictionary&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Check to spell for American, British, Canadian, and Australian English.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Understand inconsistencies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Detect unclear structure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Detect Plagiarism.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Explore overuse of words and wordiness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Get to know about the improper tones.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Discover the insensitive language aligns with your intent, audience, style, emotion, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;What is Ginger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ginger is a writing enhancement tool that not only catches typos and grammatical mistakes but also suggests content improvements. As you type, it picks up on errors then shows you what’s wrong, and suggests a fix. It also provides you with synonyms and definitions of words and allows you to translate your text into dozens of languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger Software: Features &amp;amp; Benefits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger's software helps you identify and correct common grammatical mistakes, such as consecutive nouns, or contextual spelling correction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The sentence rephrasing feature can help you convey your meaning perfectly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger acts like a personal coach that helps you practice certain exercises based on your mistakes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The dictionary feature helps users understand the meanings of words.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In addition, the program provides a text reader, so you can gauge your writing’s conversational tone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger vs Grammarly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly and Ginger are two popular grammar checker software brands that help you to become a better writer. But if you’re undecided about which software to use, consider these differences:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly only supports the English language while Ginger supports 40+ languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly offers a wordiness feature while Ginger lacks a Wordiness feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly shows an accuracy score while Ginger lacks an accuracy score feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly has a plagiarism checker while ginger doesn't have such a feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly can recognize an incorrect use of numbers while Ginger can’t recognize an incorrect use of numbers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly and Ginger both have mobile apps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger and Grammarly offer monthly, quarterly, and annual plans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly allows you to check uploaded documents. while Ginger doesn't check uploaded documents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly Offers a tone suggestion feature while Ginger doesn't offer a tone suggestion feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger helps to translate documents into 40+ languages while Grammarly doesn't have a translation feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger Offers text to speech features while Grammarly doesn't have such features.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly Score: 7/10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger:4/10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;So Grammarly&amp;nbsp; wins here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger VS Grammarly: Pricing Difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger offers a Premium subscription for 13.99$/month. it comes at $11.19/month for quarterly and $7.49/month for an annual subscription with 40$ off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;On the other hand,&amp;nbsp; Grammarly offers a Premium subscription for $30/month for a monthly plan&amp;nbsp; $20/month for quarterly, and $12/month for an annual subscription.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;For companies with three or more employees, the Business plan costs $12.50/month for each member of your team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger Wins Here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger vs Grammarly – Pros and Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Offers&amp;nbsp; free version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;All-in-one tool (grammar checker + spell checker + punctuation checker)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Allows you to edit a document without affecting the formatting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Style checker (paid version)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Active and passive voice checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Personal dictionary&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Plagiarism checker (paid version)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Available on all major devices and platforms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Free mobile apps&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;User-friendly interface&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Browser extensions and MS word add-ons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Can upload and download documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Supports only English&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Customer support only via email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Limits to 150,000 words&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Subscription plans can be a bit pricey&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Doesn’t offer a free trial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;No refund policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger Pros&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Offers free version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;All-in-one tool (grammar checker + spell checker + punctuation checker)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Affordable Subscription plans (Additionals discounts are available)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Active and passive voice changer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Translates documents in 40+ languages&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Personal dictionary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Browser extension available&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Personal trainers help clients develop their knowledge of grammar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Text-to-speech feature reads work out loud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Get a full refund within 7 days&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger Cons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Mobile apps aren't free&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Limited monthly corrections for free users&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;No style checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;No plagiarism checker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Not as user-friendly as Grammarly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You are unable to upload or download documents; however, you may copy and paste files as needed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Doesn't offer a free trial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Summarizing the Ginger VS Grammarly: My Recommendation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;While both writing assistants are fantastic in their ways, you need to choose the one you want.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;For example, go for Grammarly if you want a plagiarism tool included.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Choose Ginger if you want to write in languages other than English. I will to the differences for you in order to make the distinctions clearer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly offers a plagiarism checking tool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger provides text to speech tool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly helps you check uploaded documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ginger supports over 40 languages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly has a more friendly UI/UX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Both Ginger and Grammarly are awesome writing tools, without a doubt. Depending on your needs, you might want to use Ginger over Grammarly. As per my experience, I found Grammarly easier to use than Ginger.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Which one you like let me know in the comments section also give your opinions in the comments section below.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/02/ginger-vs-grammarly-which-grammar.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiw55GbmTyuJuYD43yqA61hrsY7bBgb5BwMzkO1sOgHcRFh3PK4ApQtQgGeXfZWLhT-2zxAxo_RB16tyEXwqBx4h__IKoEb9OIpWD9NqRI-9DU1uhH47E3QMQqFx0uSAjjk-aRD0hEZJkahQCdC_uQIZEVJUnVkyQfeqg8nJZxtgLCxZcLX0af06pu5WQ=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>10</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-5077419905984021446</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-19T15:06:50.851+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">NFTs</category>
      <title>Most Frequently Asked Questions About NFTs(Non-Fungible Tokens)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhQ__o2Bk7fjBlzcWaYTiBTTZ95DOPWpTIDWtMzAr9krA18i_9rwyAg6cHLKxIeFHR5Y194Rk7Xl8hXQYUME-yYDOGmLnm6LMvHEIRKdgBqcKD7348U3UE5l2a2T0s1xRm0id0LQOUoKvgeXl-QGtgUTwIyYeCR22MVLenD6zzunb9BG_Vhca6cJm3bAg=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="NFTs" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhQ__o2Bk7fjBlzcWaYTiBTTZ95DOPWpTIDWtMzAr9krA18i_9rwyAg6cHLKxIeFHR5Y194Rk7Xl8hXQYUME-yYDOGmLnm6LMvHEIRKdgBqcKD7348U3UE5l2a2T0s1xRm0id0LQOUoKvgeXl-QGtgUTwIyYeCR22MVLenD6zzunb9BG_Vhca6cJm3bAg=w640-h360" title="NFTs" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Non-fungible tokens (NFTs) are the most popular digital assets today, capturing the attention of cryptocurrency investors, whales and people from around the world. People find it amazing that some users spend thousands or millions of dollars on a single NFT-based image of a monkey or other token, but you can simply take a screenshot for free. So here we share some freuently asked question about NFTs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1) What is an NFT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;NFT stands for non-fungible&amp;nbsp; token, which is a cryptographic token on a blockchain with unique identification codes that distinguish it from other tokens. NFTs are unique and not interchangeable, which means no two NFTs are the same. NFTs can be a unique artwork, GIF, Images, videos, Audio album. in-game items, collectibles etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2) What is Blockchain?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A blockchain is a distributed digital ledger that allows for the secure storage of data. By recording any kind of information—such as bank account transactions, the ownership of Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), or Decentralized Finance (DeFi) smart contracts—in one place, and distributing it to many different computers, blockchains ensure that data can’t be manipulated without everyone in the system being aware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3) What makes an NFT valuable?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The value of an NFT comes from its ability to be traded freely and securely on the blockchain, which is not possible with other current digital ownership solutionsThe NFT points to its location on the blockchain, but doesn’t necessarily contain the digital property. For example, if you replace one bitcoin with another, you will still have the same thing. If you buy a non-fungible item, such as a movie ticket, it is impossible to replace it with any other movie ticket because each ticket is unique to a specific time and place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4) How do NFTs work?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;One of the unique characteristics of non-fungible tokens (NFTs) is that they can be tokenised to create a digital certificate of ownership that can be bought, sold and traded on the blockchain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;As with crypto-currency, records of who owns what are stored on a ledger that is maintained by thousands of computers around the world. These records can’t be forged because the whole system operates on an open-source network.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;NFTs also contain smart contracts—small computer programs that run on the blockchain—that give the artist, for example, a cut of any future sale of the token.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5) What’s the connection between NFTs and cryptocurrency?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Non-fungible tokens (NFTs) aren't cryptocurrencies, but they do use blockchain technology. Many NFTs are based on Ethereum, where the blockchain serves as a ledger for all the transactions related to said NFT and the properties it represents.5) How to make an NFT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Anyone can create an NFT. All you need is a digital wallet, some ethereum tokens and a connection to an NFT marketplace where you’ll be able to upload and sell your creations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6) How to validate the authencity of an NFT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you purchase a stock in NFT, that purchase is recorded on the blockchain—the bitcoin ledger of transactions—and that entry acts as your proof of ownership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7) How is an NFT valued? What are the most expensive NFTs?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The value of an NFT varies a lot based on the digital asset up for grabs. People use NFTs to trade and sell digital art, so when creating an NFT, you should consider the popularity of your digital artwork along with historical statistics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;In the year 2021, a digital artist called Pak created an artwork called The Merge. It was sold on the Nifty Gateway NFT market for $91.8 million.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;8) Can NFTs be used as an investment?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Non-fungible tokens can be used in investment opportunities. One can purchase an NFT and resell it at a profit. Certain NFT marketplaces let sellers of NFTs keep a percentage of the profits from sales of the assets they create.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;9) Will NFTs be the future of art and collectibles?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Many people want to buy NFTs because it lets them support the arts and own something cool from their favorite musicians, brands, and celebrities. NFTs also give artists an opportunity to program in continual royalties if someone buys their work. Galleries see this as a way to reach new buyers interested in art.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10) How do we buy an NFTs?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;There are many places to buy digital assets, like opensea and their policies vary. On top shot, for instance, you sign up for a waitlist that can be thousands of people long. When a digital asset goes on sale, you are occasionally chosen to purchase it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;11) Can i mint NFT for free?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;To mint an NFT token, you must pay some amount of gas fee to process the transaction on the Etherum blockchain, but you can mint your NFT on a different blockchain called Polygon to avoid paying gas fees. This option is available on OpenSea and this simply denotes that your NFT will only be able to trade using Polygon's blockchain and not Etherum's blockchain. Mintable allows you to mint NFTs for free without paying any gas fees.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;12) Do i own an NFT if i screenshot it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The answer is no. Non-Fungible Tokens are minted on the blockchain using cryptocurrencies such as Etherum, Solana, Polygon, and so on. Once a Non-Fungible Token is minted, the transaction is recorded on the blockchain and the contract or license is awarded to whoever has that Non-Fungible Token in their wallet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;12) Why are people investing so much in NFT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Non-fungible tokens have gained the hearts of people around the world, and they have given digital creators the recognition they deserve. One of the remarkable things about non-fungible tokens is that you can take a screenshot of one, but you don’t own it. This is because when a non-fungible token is created, then the transaction is stored on the blockchain, and the license or contract to hold such a token is awarded to the person owning the token in their digital wallet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can sell your work and creations by attaching a license to it on the blockchain, where its ownership can be transferred. This lets you get exposure without losing full ownership of your work. Some of the most successful projects include Cryptopunks, Bored Ape Yatch Club NFTs, SandBox, World of Women and so on. These NFT projects have gained popularity globally and are owned by celebrities and other successful entrepreneurs. Owning one of these NFTs gives you an automatic ticket to exclusive business meetings and life-changing connections.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Final Saying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;That’s a wrap. Hope you guys found this article enlightening. I just answer some question with my limited knowledge about NFTs. If you have any questions or suggestions, feel free to drop them in the comment section below. Also &lt;span style="color: red;"&gt;I have a question for you, Is bitcoin an NFTs?&lt;/span&gt; let me know in The comment section below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/02/most-frequently-asked-questions-about.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhQ__o2Bk7fjBlzcWaYTiBTTZ95DOPWpTIDWtMzAr9krA18i_9rwyAg6cHLKxIeFHR5Y194Rk7Xl8hXQYUME-yYDOGmLnm6LMvHEIRKdgBqcKD7348U3UE5l2a2T0s1xRm0id0LQOUoKvgeXl-QGtgUTwIyYeCR22MVLenD6zzunb9BG_Vhca6cJm3bAg=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>5</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-8563727018976767958</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:24:08.374+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Chrome Extension</category>
      <title>10 Best Chrome Extensions That Are Perfect for Everyone</title>
      <description>&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjIzhhoRuo6JR-7_6kymWhyoZ8V6Yy_kR8A9sDUaVi-v0DJz2XLla9Um5TcMYfJX_zRoRLA5fnnZ9hSsLZnNn2wwHGvXJ5Ik0hdJETjCsMefCkiOGtrnFLRoEFSHR9sdc-1ySgpBNZTep6Q4eRLvWFrXNvW7IfQR-Sd2O-Sgnd_H0vdyDstTOHy_NSA8A=s1920" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Are you a great Chrome user? That’s nice to hear. But first, consider whether or not there are any essential Chrome extensions you are currently missing from your browsing life, so here we're going to share with you10 Best Chrome Extensions That Are Perfect for Everyone" border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjIzhhoRuo6JR-7_6kymWhyoZ8V6Yy_kR8A9sDUaVi-v0DJz2XLla9Um5TcMYfJX_zRoRLA5fnnZ9hSsLZnNn2wwHGvXJ5Ik0hdJETjCsMefCkiOGtrnFLRoEFSHR9sdc-1ySgpBNZTep6Q4eRLvWFrXNvW7IfQR-Sd2O-Sgnd_H0vdyDstTOHy_NSA8A=w640-h360" title="Are you a great Chrome user? That’s nice to hear. But first, consider whether or not there are any essential Chrome extensions you are currently missing from your browsing life, so here we're going to share with you10 Best Chrome Extensions That Are Perfect for Everyone" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre; font-weight: normal;"&gt;Are you a great Chrome user? That’s nice to hear. But first, consider whether or not there are any essential Chrome extensions you are currently missing from your browsing life, so here we're going to share with you 10 Best Chrome Extensions That Are Perfect for Everyone. So Let's Start.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1. LastPass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;When you have too several passwords to remember, LastPass remembers them for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;This chrome extension is an easy way to save you time and increase security. It’s a single password manager that will log you into all of your accounts. you simply ought to bear in mind one word: your LastPass password to log in to all or any your accounts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Save usernames and passwords and LastPasswill&amp;nbsp; log you&amp;nbsp; in&amp;nbsp; automatically.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Fill the forms quickly to save your addresses, credit card numbers and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2. MozBar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;MozBar is an SEO toolbar extension that makes it easy for you to analyze your web pages' SEO while you surf. You can customize your search so that you see data for a particular region or for all regions. You get data such as website and domain authority and link profile. The status column tells you whether there are any no-followed links to the page.You can also compare link metrics. There is a pro version of MozBar, too.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3. Grammerly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Grammarly is a real-time grammar checking and spelling&amp;nbsp; tool for online writing. It checks spelling, grammar, and punctuation as you type, and has a dictionary feature that suggests related words. if you use mobile phones for writing than&amp;nbsp; Grammerly also have a mobile keyboard app.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4. VidlQ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;VidIQ is a SaaS product and Chrome Extension that makes it easier to manage and optimize your YouTube channels. It keeps you informed about your channel's performance with real-time analytics and powerful insights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Learn more about insights and statistics beyond YouTube Analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Find great videos with the Trending tab.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;You can check out any video’s YouTube rankings and see how your own video is doing on the charts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Keep track&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; history of the keyword to determine when a keyword is rising or down&amp;nbsp; in popularity over time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Quickly find out which videos are performing the best on YouTube right now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Let this tool suggest keywords for you to use in your title, description and tags.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. ColorZilla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;ColorZilla is a browser extension that allows you to find out the exact color of any object in your web browser. This is especially useful when you want to match elements on your page to the color of an image.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Advanced Color Picker (similar to Photoshop's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Ultimate CSS Gradient Generator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The "Webpage Color Analyzer" site helps you determine the palette of colors used in a particular website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Palette Viewer with 7 pre-installed palettes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Eyedropper - sample the color of any pixel on the page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Color History of recently picked colors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Displays some info about the element, including the tag name, class, id and size.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Auto copy picked colors to clipboard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Get colors of dynamic hover elements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pick colors from Flash objects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pick colors at any zoom level&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6. Honey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Honey is a chrome extension with which you&amp;nbsp; save each product from the website and notify it when it is available at&amp;nbsp; low price it's one among the highest extensions for Chrome that finds coupon codes whenever you look online.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Best for finding exclusive prices on Amazon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;A free reward program called Honey Gold.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Searches and filters the simplest value fitting your demand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Instant notifications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7. GMass: Powerful Chrome Extension for Gmail Marketers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;GMass (or Gmail Mass) permits users to compose and send mass emails using Gmail. it is a great tool as a result of you'll use it as a replacement for a third-party email sending platform. you will love GMass to spice up your emailing functionality on the platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;8. Notion Web Clipper: Chrome Extension for Geeks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It's a Chrome extension for geeks that enables you to highlight and save what you see on the web.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It's been designed by Notion, that could be a Google space different that helps groups craft higher ideas and collaborate effectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Save anything online with just one click&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Use it on any device&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Organize your saved clips quickly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Tag, share and comment on the clips&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you are someone who works online, you need to surf the internet to get your business done. And often there is no time to read or analyze something. But it's important that you&amp;nbsp; do it. Notion Web Clipper will help you with that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;9. WhatFont: Chrome Extension for identifying Any Site Fonts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;WhatFont is a Chrome extension that allows web designers to easily identify and compare different fonts on a page. The first time you use it on any page, WhatFont will copy the selected page.It&amp;nbsp; Uses this page to find out what fonts are present and generate an image that shows all those fonts in different sizes. Besides the apparent websites like Google or Amazon,&amp;nbsp; you'll conjointly use it on sites wherever embedded fonts ar used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10. SimilarWeb: Traffic Rank &amp;amp; Website Analysis Extension&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Similar Web is an SEO add on for both Chrome and Firefox.It allows you&amp;nbsp; to check web site traffic and key metrics for any web site, as well as engagement rate, traffic ranking, keyword ranking, and traffic source. this is often a good tool if you are looking to seek out new and effective SEO ways similarly as analyze trends across the web.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Discover keyword trends&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Know fresh keywords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Get benefit from the real traffic insights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Analyze engagement metrics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Explore unique visitors data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Analyze your industry's category&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Use month to date data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;How to Install chrome Extension in Android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;I know everyone knows how to install extension in pc but most of people don't know how to install it in android phone so i will show you how to install it in android&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1. Download Kiwi browser from Play Store and then Open it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;center&gt;Advertisement&lt;/center&gt;&lt;iframe src="//assertedclosureseaman.com/watchnew?key=7b9b5cf011593acf83910a92a9fd246a" width="300" height="250" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;center&gt; Continue reading below&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEi25LTllzVk0iORktl91fiAhmVUCofdIFVEKVisVw1f4GXHXw2cXbRNa7L1dAhBw564yzzbx55-BShU4_-NWtadHbiPKlwaLbK_3ys29eZP4asIH-34TsZMzFhqeSQFA8122wkOQyrmTshAmxymlSAnJ6bhEyC2OdxMExCsL6CuSoK7HpS9SP-s-K6Tww=s1280" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1280" data-original-width="561" height="308" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEi25LTllzVk0iORktl91fiAhmVUCofdIFVEKVisVw1f4GXHXw2cXbRNa7L1dAhBw564yzzbx55-BShU4_-NWtadHbiPKlwaLbK_3ys29eZP4asIH-34TsZMzFhqeSQFA8122wkOQyrmTshAmxymlSAnJ6bhEyC2OdxMExCsL6CuSoK7HpS9SP-s-K6Tww=w151-h308" width="151" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;2. Tap the three dots at the top right corner and select Extension.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj1XG9VeulJFtoXSNBLzqUbE4YTnhaQrId9flQApaXlnPwmLIBVkudzU0JvrCqz6LuN4dMD9g3VkdhRE_U4AQSk0Ee_UfbTAYid6RxwRMjv_4kJdJ1vJyDgz5S2O5GgpzaF0TVDJ93DYQx8c-tABkJzoVgsxZlqsB6h6rDSD0M5tiV6QzsK2Y5D3s2gsw=s1280" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1280" data-original-width="561" height="255" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj1XG9VeulJFtoXSNBLzqUbE4YTnhaQrId9flQApaXlnPwmLIBVkudzU0JvrCqz6LuN4dMD9g3VkdhRE_U4AQSk0Ee_UfbTAYid6RxwRMjv_4kJdJ1vJyDgz5S2O5GgpzaF0TVDJ93DYQx8c-tABkJzoVgsxZlqsB6h6rDSD0M5tiV6QzsK2Y5D3s2gsw=w140-h255" width="140" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3. Click on (+From Store) to access chrome web store or simple search chrome web store and access it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgq7DjHt61IOEU5rrWvUcVSbatsb0GDTGri43l8qgHkbwoVPFYEAk7nWW9MpOm2Wr4AudzqPtQ9pOaGs9xyAR0-TR0HbsuJa8u_DOFYVIdowCsepPSGzoIvui2MArLLY10gnECpwodysbAMIL9LXXWPYguJLyEMCs9A6OegMeW4But4-AuOuMAN110plA=s1280" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1280" data-original-width="561" height="289" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgq7DjHt61IOEU5rrWvUcVSbatsb0GDTGri43l8qgHkbwoVPFYEAk7nWW9MpOm2Wr4AudzqPtQ9pOaGs9xyAR0-TR0HbsuJa8u_DOFYVIdowCsepPSGzoIvui2MArLLY10gnECpwodysbAMIL9LXXWPYguJLyEMCs9A6OegMeW4But4-AuOuMAN110plA=w140-h289" width="140" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4. Once you found an extension click on add to chrome a message will pop-up&amp;nbsp; asking if you wish to confirm your choice. Hit OK to install the extension in the Kiwi browser.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjR1Au8lENnJDcBpf-vv28GffoBSEsK-i_LXN-CljyWPtSN01514RI_K3CqK0ClH3HC0kI86wi5AvQHgWt1Vis6t2gOsZtVtIFsB58ORG0HPsJo02U5K_Ae5M6LWqe6aZS7i8b-vWzyQKHra2yyk0Fg2zZ4OM-eAllebtKTTuWgivWlI1vNWYvu8rsEQQ=s854" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="854" data-original-width="480" height="296" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjR1Au8lENnJDcBpf-vv28GffoBSEsK-i_LXN-CljyWPtSN01514RI_K3CqK0ClH3HC0kI86wi5AvQHgWt1Vis6t2gOsZtVtIFsB58ORG0HPsJo02U5K_Ae5M6LWqe6aZS7i8b-vWzyQKHra2yyk0Fg2zZ4OM-eAllebtKTTuWgivWlI1vNWYvu8rsEQQ=w180-h296" width="180" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. To manage&amp;nbsp; extensions on the browser, tap the three dots in the upper right corner. Then select Extensions to access a catalog of installed extensions that you can disable, update or remove with just a few clicks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Your Chrome extensions should install on Android, but there’s no guarantee all of them will work. Because Google Chrome Extensions are not optimized for Android devices.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Final Saying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;We hope this list of 10 best chrome extensions that is perfect for everyone will help you in picking the right Chrome Extensions. We have selected the extensions after matching their features to the needs of different categories of people. Also which extension you like the most let me know in the comment section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/01/10-best-chrome-extensions-that-are.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjIzhhoRuo6JR-7_6kymWhyoZ8V6Yy_kR8A9sDUaVi-v0DJz2XLla9Um5TcMYfJX_zRoRLA5fnnZ9hSsLZnNn2wwHGvXJ5Ik0hdJETjCsMefCkiOGtrnFLRoEFSHR9sdc-1ySgpBNZTep6Q4eRLvWFrXNvW7IfQR-Sd2O-Sgnd_H0vdyDstTOHy_NSA8A=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>8</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-4705741174433838580</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:25:01.918+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Email Marketing</category>
      <title>Most Frequently Asked Questions About  Email Marketing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgD5ya1-4Tnsum7tKBC7maSYhkX2x5tHg2-_ihpar1PmlsT7MKPH0419APpBlmOXCVkxaozFrSnC23BdOQy6AnChsLoBEDG2qt34GukCtnGjPXwGHpa9AicdbP0EjCMyxbTGYGUPz24NvoC6Ph3zCxOJ1ZhqxeAua4kx-SzwkbngPsWo9dciHSozTstJA=s1920" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="1920" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgD5ya1-4Tnsum7tKBC7maSYhkX2x5tHg2-_ihpar1PmlsT7MKPH0419APpBlmOXCVkxaozFrSnC23BdOQy6AnChsLoBEDG2qt34GukCtnGjPXwGHpa9AicdbP0EjCMyxbTGYGUPz24NvoC6Ph3zCxOJ1ZhqxeAua4kx-SzwkbngPsWo9dciHSozTstJA=w640-h360" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Frank Ruhl Libre&amp;quot;;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;1. Why is email marketing important?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Email is the marketing tool that helps you&amp;nbsp; create a seamless, connected, frictionless buyer journey. More importantly, email marketing allows you to build relationships with prospects, customers, and past customers. It's your chance to speak&amp;nbsp; to them right in their inbox, at a time that suits them. Along with the right message, email can become one of your most powerful marketing channels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Frank Ruhl Libre&amp;quot;;"&gt;2. What is benefits of email marketing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Email marketing is best way for creating long term relationship with your clients, and increasing sales in our company.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Benefits of email marketing for bussiness:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Better brand recognition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Statistics of what works best&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;More sales&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Targeted audience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;More traffic to your products/services/newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Build credibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Most&amp;nbsp; bussinesses are using email marketing and making tons of money with email marketing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3. What is the simplest day and time to send my marketing emails?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Again, the answer to this question varies from company to company. And again, testing is the way to find out what works best. Typically, weekends and mornings seem to be&amp;nbsp; times when multiple emails are opened, but since your audience may have different habits, it's best to experiment and then use your&amp;nbsp; data to decide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;4. Which metrics should I be looking at?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The two most important metrics for email marketing are&amp;nbsp; open rate and click-through rate. If your emails aren't opened, subscribers will never see your full marketing message, and if they open them but don't click through to your site, your emails won't convert.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. How do I write a decent subject line?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The best subject lines are short and to the point, accurately describing&amp;nbsp; the content of the email, but also catchy and intriguing, so the reader wants to know more. Once Again, this is the perfect place for&amp;nbsp; A/B testing, to see what types of subject lines work best with your audience. Your call to action should be clear and&amp;nbsp; simple. It should be somewhere at the top of your email for those who haven't finished reading the entire email,&amp;nbsp; then repeated&amp;nbsp; at the end for those reading all the way through. It should state exactly what you want subscribers to do, for example "Click here to download the premium theme for free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;6. Is email marketing still effective?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Email marketing is one of the most effective ways for a business to reach its customers directly. Think about it. You don't post something on your site&amp;nbsp; hoping people will visit it. You don't even post something on a social media page and hope fans&amp;nbsp; see it. You're sending something straight to each person's inbox, where they'll definitely&amp;nbsp; see it! Even if they don't open it, they'll still see your subject line and business name every time you send an email, so you're still communicating directly with your audience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7. However do I grow my email subscribers list? Should i buy an email list or build it myself?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Buying an email list is&amp;nbsp; waste of time &amp;amp; money. These email accounts are unverified and not interested in your brand. The mailing list is useless if your subscribers do not open your emails. There are different ways to grow your mailing list.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Give them a free ebook and host it on a landing page where they have to enter the email to download the file and also create a forum page on your website, asks your visitors what questions they might have about your business, and collects email addresses to follow up with them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;8. How do I prevent audience from unsubscribing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If the&amp;nbsp; subject line of the email is irrelevant to&amp;nbsp; customers, they will ignore it multiple times. But, if it keeps repeating, they are intercepted and unsubscribed from your emails. So, send relevant emails for the benefit of the customer. Don't send emails that often only focus&amp;nbsp; on sales, offers and discounts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Submit information about your business and offers so you can connect with customers. You can also update them on recent trends in your industry. The basic role of an email is first and foremost to&amp;nbsp; connect with customers, get the most out of this tool.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;9. What is the difference between a cold email and a spam email?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Cold emails are mostly sales emails that are sent with content align to the needs of the recipient. It is usually personalized and includes a business perspective. However, it is still an unsolicited email. And all unsolicited emails are marked as SPAM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Regularly receiving this type of unsolicited email in your users' inboxes, chances are&amp;nbsp; your emails will soon be diverted to&amp;nbsp; spam or junk folders. The most important thing to prevent this from happening is to respect your recipients' choice to opt-out of receiving emails from you. You can add the links to easily unsubscribe. You must be familiar with the CAN-SPAM Act and its regulations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;10. Where can I find email template?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Almost all email campaign tools provide you with ready-made templates. Whether you use MailChimp or Pardot, you'll get several email templates ready to use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;However, if you want to create a template from scratch, you can do so.Most of email campaign tools have option to paste the HTML code of your own design.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;11. What email marketing trend will help marketers succeed in 2022?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Is it a trend to listen to&amp;nbsp; and get to know your customers? I think people realize how bad it feels for a brand or a company to obsess over themselves without knowing their customers personal needs. People who listen empathetically and then provide value based on what they learn will win.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Final Saying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;You can approach email marketing in different ways. We have compiled a list of most frequently asked questions to help you understand how to get started, what constraints you need to keep in mind, and what future development you will need, we don’t have 100% answers to every situation and there’s always a chance you will have something new and different to deal with as you market your own business.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/01/most-frequently-asked-questions-about.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgD5ya1-4Tnsum7tKBC7maSYhkX2x5tHg2-_ihpar1PmlsT7MKPH0419APpBlmOXCVkxaozFrSnC23BdOQy6AnChsLoBEDG2qt34GukCtnGjPXwGHpa9AicdbP0EjCMyxbTGYGUPz24NvoC6Ph3zCxOJ1ZhqxeAua4kx-SzwkbngPsWo9dciHSozTstJA=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>2</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-7535332462149609558</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-20T10:26:53.650+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Tool</category>
      <title>7 Free Websites Every Content Creator Needs to Know</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjwH3GmjDmHcu86RboQutNZeTWtfl93FX1CXyb3v9r45OyLZAAwlhaOy0qm5SrXo8QN5MuzUWOQqJ5QZg-4aVQOdMGG4HZkQ65y_kyrOUqZhhVMMWlqYUG7MrCIMp4hGVK79ILv7nU7EYAGcyE_HTap6A74fr9L9ui86KozuV2G6niNgmGyEWgf3O2Aag=s1366" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="768" data-original-width="1366" height="360" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjwH3GmjDmHcu86RboQutNZeTWtfl93FX1CXyb3v9r45OyLZAAwlhaOy0qm5SrXo8QN5MuzUWOQqJ5QZg-4aVQOdMGG4HZkQ65y_kyrOUqZhhVMMWlqYUG7MrCIMp4hGVK79ILv7nU7EYAGcyE_HTap6A74fr9L9ui86KozuV2G6niNgmGyEWgf3O2Aag=w640-h360" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Do you have the desire to become a content creator, but not have the money to start? Here are 7 free websites every content creator needs to know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;1.Exploding Topics (Trending Topics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhNzJJ96Kzlld-aqoaqvMFnBOdDbQ-1CspYnUvKKGHIsbmqt5aZpgowp3SsxV8Od_xs2iL3ygNfuRQlchGRE2vmIEAFMDjQ2lF-He48S8ZzFQPVtITAul06thnaYe1wJapgOpBDKBiGlQ9A54K6vNkl-ln16Ky5kKzraB9yvYntYfF5-WH4bIQpW0W6Kg=s1200" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Exploding Topics" border="0" data-original-height="627" data-original-width="1200" height="334" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhNzJJ96Kzlld-aqoaqvMFnBOdDbQ-1CspYnUvKKGHIsbmqt5aZpgowp3SsxV8Od_xs2iL3ygNfuRQlchGRE2vmIEAFMDjQ2lF-He48S8ZzFQPVtITAul06thnaYe1wJapgOpBDKBiGlQ9A54K6vNkl-ln16Ky5kKzraB9yvYntYfF5-WH4bIQpW0W6Kg=w640-h334" title="Exploding Topics" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:- Exploding Topics)&lt;span&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;If you're a content creator, you might be wondering what better way to find new topic ideas than to see what people are searching for? This tool gives you this data without anyone else's explanation. It provides related hashtags and tips on how to use them effectively in your posts. It's a great tool for anyone who wants to keep up to date with what's most relevant in their niche. You can also see the most popular hashtags by country, making it easier to understand cross-border and demographic trends. This site makes your search for content easier than ever! There are countless ways to use explosive topics to your advantage as a content creator.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Some examples can be:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Use the most popular hashtags and keywords to get inspiration for ideas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Find out what people are talking about in real-time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Find new audiences you may not have known were interested in your topic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;There’s no excuse not to try this website — it’s free and easy to use!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://explodingtopics.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Visit Exploding Topics From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;2. Headline Studio (Headline Grader)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEg_BImtXlDG4mY8E1M-s7N9jOu5mCNj4xpeck4f4BjnbBk28ufqx8PrbIGztTVFEjJyPgGYSb1c5Lot3i2FFvoTf9hceIdMZ0q0UlzHwIAgekKDQzenRCFDXjjmCDRGVWcweACwx4TWJNkTkLP3qY4MVhAhzHV_NvX827iVC4Isi_5PY1APma3Q86sKqg=s660" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Headline Studio" border="0" data-original-height="526" data-original-width="660" height="510" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEg_BImtXlDG4mY8E1M-s7N9jOu5mCNj4xpeck4f4BjnbBk28ufqx8PrbIGztTVFEjJyPgGYSb1c5Lot3i2FFvoTf9hceIdMZ0q0UlzHwIAgekKDQzenRCFDXjjmCDRGVWcweACwx4TWJNkTkLP3qY4MVhAhzHV_NvX827iVC4Isi_5PY1APma3Q86sKqg=w640-h510" title="Headline Studio" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:-Headline Studio)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Headline Studio allows you to create catchy headlines for your content.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;After writing a title there is data on how often people view articles with similar titles and why they are involved with them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;This is a valuable tool when creating new blog posts because it generates catchy headlines for your blog post to catch a reader’s attention.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://coschedule.com/headline-studio" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Visit Headline Studio From Here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;3. Answer the public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhDhwDpmPqs-AfaJNuQH-ZI-fg5MSl8TFMFUQLd0-yFurLMLy_1v49EHto_y9A4sI-vfmW5vmIiGnBC2-LKgXOZDXthDwXBGCrRUkwpEHLI42IjYf7tO35yZH4Ru2EUnAeE_FNLbKeqsUEsFFElGZ1ZfxVH5SyD0VFFstvvN8xUms5oG55piVEgGQ7Zgw=s665" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Answer The Public" border="0" data-original-height="657" data-original-width="665" height="632" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhDhwDpmPqs-AfaJNuQH-ZI-fg5MSl8TFMFUQLd0-yFurLMLy_1v49EHto_y9A4sI-vfmW5vmIiGnBC2-LKgXOZDXthDwXBGCrRUkwpEHLI42IjYf7tO35yZH4Ru2EUnAeE_FNLbKeqsUEsFFElGZ1ZfxVH5SyD0VFFstvvN8xUms5oG55piVEgGQ7Zgw=w640-h632" title="Answer The Public" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:- Answer The Public)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Answer The public is an excellent tool for content creators. It gives you insight into what people are asking on social media sites and communities and lets you guess about topics that matter to your audience. Answer the public allows you to enter a keyword or topic related to your niche and it will show results with popular questions and keywords related to your topic. It's an amazing way to get insights into what people are searching online and allows you to identify topics driven by new blog posts or social media content on platforms like Facebook, Instagram, Youtube, and Twitter as well as the types of questions they ask and&amp;nbsp; also want answers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://answerthepublic.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;Answer The Public From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;4. Surfer Seo (SEO Ranking)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjOUhpQP2O68T9_tM27QAv_umu2RIQxnCSRfjJ9hK0w04j-LEkhxd-7wEhtVKUqTXyCEJZ7agOQFq9A5KBjzwN0g8zyPXwrDMh0RUgUBXjVqKKsSzY_4DleJcS2UA5HeKfev_o7cqESm3Ax0bejSQ48B-889nuJbde7jiVRZ8eTvuf8TrELwgGdjseCZw=s640" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Surfer Seo" border="0" data-original-height="400" data-original-width="640" height="400" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjOUhpQP2O68T9_tM27QAv_umu2RIQxnCSRfjJ9hK0w04j-LEkhxd-7wEhtVKUqTXyCEJZ7agOQFq9A5KBjzwN0g8zyPXwrDMh0RUgUBXjVqKKsSzY_4DleJcS2UA5HeKfev_o7cqESm3Ax0bejSQ48B-889nuJbde7jiVRZ8eTvuf8TrELwgGdjseCZw=w640-h400" title="Surfer Seo" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:-Surfer Seo)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;With this tool, content creators can quickly and easily check the ranking of their websites and those of other competitors. This tool allows you to see how your website compares to others in different categories, including:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Rank Potential&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Organic Search Ranking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Surfer Seo is free and the interface is very friendly. It's a great tool for anyone who wants to do quick competitor research or check their site's rankings at any time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://surferseo.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Visit SurferSeo From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;5. Canva (Templates/Graphics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjHx5hbdU0ZIHY4IGh8jRKSfmbrXldgc6KgR2KC7qI4Hti-fZmxcJqSB4WsQ9xSMc_lAlvczySNLl1aYHA02zu7wzHrAB81ZggyIApoJt3Y3n7-uDMC4-2xmH7X0kzhuMoGwDGhtpAxbuxbB2fWpWrSPsJ1ybyrJaCMbZHADcWkrfGuVuTJkhEzzvx9qQ=s676" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Canva" border="0" data-original-height="417" data-original-width="676" height="394" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjHx5hbdU0ZIHY4IGh8jRKSfmbrXldgc6KgR2KC7qI4Hti-fZmxcJqSB4WsQ9xSMc_lAlvczySNLl1aYHA02zu7wzHrAB81ZggyIApoJt3Y3n7-uDMC4-2xmH7X0kzhuMoGwDGhtpAxbuxbB2fWpWrSPsJ1ybyrJaCMbZHADcWkrfGuVuTJkhEzzvx9qQ=w640-h394" title="Canva" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:- Canva)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva is a free graphic design platform that makes it easy to create invitations, business cards, mobile videos, Instagram posts, Instagram stories, flyers, and more with professionally designed templates. You can even upload your photos and drag and drop them into Canva templates. It's like having a basic version of Photoshop. You can also remove background from images with one click.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Canva offers thousands of free, professionally designed templates that can be customized with just a few clicks. Simply upload your photos to Canva, drag them into the template of your choice, and save the file to your computer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;It is free to use for basic use but if you want access to different fonts or more features, then you need to buy a premium plan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.canva.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Visit Canva From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;6. Facebook Audience Insights (Audience Research)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgre3_JAZazKoa9DtY-qK4RXgJKSWBtYWJfbdaNNhmoIpBGFa-n_Ol5ffuL_w6ohklcjWX8zaOnW3PzuB5LnkEsOALNRb1ZyedPDUuqL7zCxJIDmHndfAf3EGkP643w49XMe-QEiDvzvQdPgx0x8Cr7qOTtdNBn9RcH1HdDBll-qEe1dH773lrqW-wNVg=s617" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Facebook Audience Insights" border="0" data-original-height="292" data-original-width="617" height="302" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgre3_JAZazKoa9DtY-qK4RXgJKSWBtYWJfbdaNNhmoIpBGFa-n_Ol5ffuL_w6ohklcjWX8zaOnW3PzuB5LnkEsOALNRb1ZyedPDUuqL7zCxJIDmHndfAf3EGkP643w49XMe-QEiDvzvQdPgx0x8Cr7qOTtdNBn9RcH1HdDBll-qEe1dH773lrqW-wNVg=w640-h302" title="Facebook Audience Insights" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit:- Facebook Audience Insights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Facebook Audience Insights is a powerful tool for content creators when researching their target market. This can help you understand the demographics, interests, and behaviors of your target audience. This information helps determine the direction of your content so that it resonates with them. The most important tools to consider in Facebook Audience Insights are Demographics and Behavior. These two sections provide you with valuable information about your target market, such as their age and from where they belong, how much time they spend on social media per day, what devices they use to access it, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;There is another section of Facebook Audits that is very helpful. This will let you know the interests, hobbies, and activities that people in your target market are most interested in. You can use this information to create content for them about things they will be about as opposed to topics they may not be so keen on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=Facebook+Audience+Insights&amp;amp;oq=Facebook+Audience+Insights&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i176j69i58.244j0j4&amp;amp;client=ms-android-transsion-infinix-rev1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome-mobile&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Facebook Audience Insights From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;7. Pexels (Images)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEi-CJjqBxkWOZXBVZ7JUGZvxLYWU-icCh0iuL8VWuOoXrCgRuoC59Di9LKh7vCuxm-cCUhQ3FF2nBODoY9vsOX5NgRtKymDp00cXFXYRMc1QyxwMAtsWsmaQiFOAp-d8xZ1VDR3JDaznWbXNSAx2mny3Ti1yM0gngRZta1asKxPK-qB4B7BLCYt0WI1gQ=s1200" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pexel" border="0" data-original-height="822" data-original-width="1200" height="438" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEi-CJjqBxkWOZXBVZ7JUGZvxLYWU-icCh0iuL8VWuOoXrCgRuoC59Di9LKh7vCuxm-cCUhQ3FF2nBODoY9vsOX5NgRtKymDp00cXFXYRMc1QyxwMAtsWsmaQiFOAp-d8xZ1VDR3JDaznWbXNSAx2mny3Ti1yM0gngRZta1asKxPK-qB4B7BLCYt0WI1gQ=w640-h438" title="Pexel" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;(Photo Credit: Pixel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;Pexels is a warehouse for any content creator with millions of free royalty images who wants to find high-quality images that can be used freely without having to worry about permissions or licensing so you are free to use the photos in your content and also there is no watermark on photos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;The only cons are that some photos contain people, and Pexels doesn't allow you to remove people from photos. Search your keyword and download as many as you want!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Visit Pexel From Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: red; font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;So there you have it. We hope that these specially curated websites will come in handy for content creators and small businesses alike. If you've got a site that should be on this list, let us know! And if you're looking for more content creator resources, then let us know in the comments section below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Frank Ruhl Libre;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/01/7-free-websites-every-content-creator.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjwH3GmjDmHcu86RboQutNZeTWtfl93FX1CXyb3v9r45OyLZAAwlhaOy0qm5SrXo8QN5MuzUWOQqJ5QZg-4aVQOdMGG4HZkQ65y_kyrOUqZhhVMMWlqYUG7MrCIMp4hGVK79ILv7nU7EYAGcyE_HTap6A74fr9L9ui86KozuV2G6niNgmGyEWgf3O2Aag=s72-w640-h360-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>8</thr:total>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2525761963252134386.post-3540326599808924672</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-03-19T15:11:38.237+05:00</atom:updated>
      <category domain="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">Ai</category>
      <title>Top 9 Free AI Tools That Make Your Life Easier</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.copy.ai/?via=adil"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Copy.ai&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh3XRgDXB0VsEgf272YBOXlxHdjxzyTuKQQd2OmNi4rBNKfPOBeYxyAeiDLR7v_w5U6umenSX8HHZ1A_jPQ4lLnjfQmT9oi6u2hjJx1AOoJUtuXguddjjTCqTOUbR_lrh_RGLGpLnPZxBPZvEV4m7TsWmJLVVMrpYzDqvYJdZs6JcbeeFu-J4kQ_RbhBw=s753" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="584" data-original-width="753" height="481" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh3XRgDXB0VsEgf272YBOXlxHdjxzyTuKQQd2OmNi4rBNKfPOBeYxyAeiDLR7v_w5U6umenSX8HHZ1A_jPQ4lLnjfQmT9oi6u2hjJx1AOoJUtuXguddjjTCqTOUbR_lrh_RGLGpLnPZxBPZvEV4m7TsWmJLVVMrpYzDqvYJdZs6JcbeeFu-J4kQ_RbhBw=w640-h481" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Photo:- Copy.ai&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;First one on the list is copy.ai. It is an AI based copy writer tool. Basically&amp;nbsp; what a copywriter tool does is, it gives you content that you can post on your blog or video&amp;nbsp; when you give it a few descriptions about the topic you want content on.So copy ai can help you write instagram captions gives you blog idea, product descriptions,&amp;nbsp; facebook content, startup ideas, viral ideas, a lot of things it can do, you just make an account&amp;nbsp; in this website, then select a tool and fill in&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;the necessary description and the AI will generate&amp;nbsp; content on what you ask for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;For tutorials go to their official &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCiS3VZF1BkmqIA_jcf9o9rA" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Youtube&amp;nbsp; channel&lt;/a&gt; .An awesome tool that is going to be really handy in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://Hotpot.ai"&gt;Hotpot.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEipWkFTGX6rePdieHOF3zv4KHcSuYRFuSxYojumHuN1M8mm170guemQDJ1--Zrs0TFI5Q9RVjF76w7slz5KvuPx2rSAy4-R_ssyjjO_qqdos2o7-vw0KyDpt46Edzll4uUwQ4vfAxYwosXIu6R5ZJJgVPcUwW_7V3VYzF81U2qaaBxyYyWZHhNIKSQeHA=s1261" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="811" data-original-width="1261" height="412" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEipWkFTGX6rePdieHOF3zv4KHcSuYRFuSxYojumHuN1M8mm170guemQDJ1--Zrs0TFI5Q9RVjF76w7slz5KvuPx2rSAy4-R_ssyjjO_qqdos2o7-vw0KyDpt46Edzll4uUwQ4vfAxYwosXIu6R5ZJJgVPcUwW_7V3VYzF81U2qaaBxyYyWZHhNIKSQeHA=w640-h412" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Hotpot.ai offers a collection of&amp;nbsp; AI tools for designers, as well as for anyone,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;it has an “AI picture restorer” which removes&amp;nbsp; scratches ,and basically restores your old photo&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;into amazing pictures and makes it look brand new.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ai picture colorizer , turns your black and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;white photo into color. And there is a background&amp;nbsp; remover tool, picture enlarger and a lot more for designers, check it out,and explore all the tools.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.myheritage.com/deep-nostalgia" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Deep-nostalgia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgiDXvewlK0J3hZL6pife8wxOfyy8d4Z_SWCouF1jy0tsFTVSkDXJy_fWhQqf10DlV_24tZVFjWyA-gvhlRSOdiwFC3jrDBfqx6EAaV2ntzGGVW3YPPOpDyOebPUxrdbO8kQ9yRBgVoCwfSoT10Grf_gvkLqjx6MoQLwIMDVANfGqp9UKgIwPehcyZGLA=s1264" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="846" data-original-width="1264" height="428" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEgiDXvewlK0J3hZL6pife8wxOfyy8d4Z_SWCouF1jy0tsFTVSkDXJy_fWhQqf10DlV_24tZVFjWyA-gvhlRSOdiwFC3jrDBfqx6EAaV2ntzGGVW3YPPOpDyOebPUxrdbO8kQ9yRBgVoCwfSoT10Grf_gvkLqjx6MoQLwIMDVANfGqp9UKgIwPehcyZGLA=w640-h428" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Deep-nostalgia became&amp;nbsp; very popular on the internet when people started&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;making reaction videos of their parents reacting&amp;nbsp; to animated pictures of their grandparents. So&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;deep - nostalgia is a very cool app, that will&amp;nbsp; animate any photo of a person.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;So what makes it&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;really cool is that fact that you can upload an&amp;nbsp; old photo of your family and see them animate&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;and living. Which is pretty cool and creepy at&amp;nbsp; the same time if they are dead already.. Really&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;amazing service from myheritage, I created a&amp;nbsp; lot of cool animations with my old photos as&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;well as with the photos of my grandparents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://Pfpmaker.com"&gt;Pfpmaker.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjGLD1qxoL2_EONUnccNODXhwDW8ISI2r7QVMECb5axA0kjjSu0rrxZKpTfrYs3AQtH25mXAnPblBbqnRZnhuPPqZyiS2Iczhg1x-ncwhHirMsjoLQon7V7aiDxzXkHnaHzEM-KmhChbjoGVeHQmlYVzgDc8XmQe6DvKA6lfTuRhUP5kIP8EdrUQ02FhA=s1225" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="839" data-original-width="1225" height="438" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEjGLD1qxoL2_EONUnccNODXhwDW8ISI2r7QVMECb5axA0kjjSu0rrxZKpTfrYs3AQtH25mXAnPblBbqnRZnhuPPqZyiS2Iczhg1x-ncwhHirMsjoLQon7V7aiDxzXkHnaHzEM-KmhChbjoGVeHQmlYVzgDc8XmQe6DvKA6lfTuRhUP5kIP8EdrUQ02FhA=w640-h438" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name='more'&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Having a nice&amp;nbsp; looking profile picture is really important if you want that professional feel in your socials.&amp;nbsp; Whether in linkedin or twitter having a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;distinct and catchy profile picture can make&amp;nbsp; all the difference. So that's where pfpmaker&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;comes in. it a free online tool to create amazing professional profile pictures that fits&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;you. It generates a lot of profile pictures&amp;nbsp; and you can also make small changes to already&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;created profile pictures if you want to,as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://Brandmark.io"&gt;Brandmark.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj3a_-DytTTUCcST6afi9raDxAN1DFNI-F0OZr1DfTQytNMtF1eUXNTKFQaH0MRphNzaz_r6JCCZhXGeFKQtPfeq79caY84h4E3ALtIuE58XLprnwi5XSXD-QyMf-wNuCXmWCCxudfEZS1REs9em312z9LMavy7Ho6a3WqdA17bmofK-ozArKOymSlnGg=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="810" data-original-width="1280" height="406" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEj3a_-DytTTUCcST6afi9raDxAN1DFNI-F0OZr1DfTQytNMtF1eUXNTKFQaH0MRphNzaz_r6JCCZhXGeFKQtPfeq79caY84h4E3ALtIuE58XLprnwi5XSXD-QyMf-wNuCXmWCCxudfEZS1REs9em312z9LMavy7Ho6a3WqdA17bmofK-ozArKOymSlnGg=w640-h406" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Speaking of brands, getting a&amp;nbsp; good logo for your brand is the most frustrating&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;thing ever, so brandmark.io makes it super easy.&amp;nbsp; It will create a logo for your brand within&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;2 clicks. So you goto this website. Type in your brand name and slogan if you have any, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;give BRAND KEYWORDS that relate to your brand,&amp;nbsp; then pick a color style and done, the ai will&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;generate amazing logos for you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;You can also make&amp;nbsp; minor edits to the suggested logos to better fit your needs as well. But to get that png you need&amp;nbsp; to pay a hefty price, but if you are looking for some logo ideas, this is a great place to start.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://deep-image.ai"&gt;Deep-image.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEibQccLFuu9WhMieW2HbcLKjTnGD-dvimUt7QnDhPCUMTnS68CbVeVuEKSt_inYVfgKEIjlkvZMphRPyJcyN2CgFhryxo8sfLESl8v4Bl7TE4F3xrekHLP51FfARcjOR7oncz8dSBZ7WFr2vAKIF9RMCzkVwEyGqwVNoLpCL-QYadYCNh0omVZKkdzz8w=s1280" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="832" data-original-width="1280" height="416" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEibQccLFuu9WhMieW2HbcLKjTnGD-dvimUt7QnDhPCUMTnS68CbVeVuEKSt_inYVfgKEIjlkvZMphRPyJcyN2CgFhryxo8sfLESl8v4Bl7TE4F3xrekHLP51FfARcjOR7oncz8dSBZ7WFr2vAKIF9RMCzkVwEyGqwVNoLpCL-QYadYCNh0omVZKkdzz8w=w640-h416" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Even in the previous websites, some&amp;nbsp; had picture enlarger tools. This deep-image.ai is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;a dedicated image enlarger, which supports upto 4x&amp;nbsp; enlargement for free. The UI is pretty good and the tool is pretty fast with amazing results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bigjpg.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Bigjpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhmjYfji2J-uwt5tc66XXJ6MwjShL_RrSFTVgtj3drQ7hSG97xLwdAhkVEC32YalC6RnPb7Iq4Doj7MCdlhGLv5mO_b8yOnoQ6XIzgNHOaOXiCb8JYq1x4ZlrLDISf81iDnd2GdCrYDrttna3RKQA4_ZqV8E7nmPDqoayGuZSbdQPInxQ74cnwj0Z3j_w=s2000" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="1600" data-original-width="2000" height="506" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEhmjYfji2J-uwt5tc66XXJ6MwjShL_RrSFTVgtj3drQ7hSG97xLwdAhkVEC32YalC6RnPb7Iq4Doj7MCdlhGLv5mO_b8yOnoQ6XIzgNHOaOXiCb8JYq1x4ZlrLDISf81iDnd2GdCrYDrttna3RKQA4_ZqV8E7nmPDqoayGuZSbdQPInxQ74cnwj0Z3j_w=w640-h506" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Bigjpg does the same as&amp;nbsp; deep-image.ai , but this service offers a little bit more options like if your photo is an artwork&amp;nbsp; it scales image differently than normal photos and it supports upto 4x enlargement for free&amp;nbsp; and you can also set noise reduction options. Very good tool,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://lumen5.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Lumen5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiDhlMkUGhu9RuUmXB0Rj7Im9FPts-RE9ZmT4SXcseA75C9odxcoD6AA0dIV6fOA1AfOL3uzbx3Rr4pTzo4zXbsakxXzIVGTWxzI_xZVdNnBkRi6hUAust9NUHTIRM0p9XeBFsQLgHB3-1xslkc3-VH8KDN6PEMJI_-h9v0fUuwcuFrBS4kbpBFIQyIIA=s1256" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="832" data-original-width="1256" height="424" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEiDhlMkUGhu9RuUmXB0Rj7Im9FPts-RE9ZmT4SXcseA75C9odxcoD6AA0dIV6fOA1AfOL3uzbx3Rr4pTzo4zXbsakxXzIVGTWxzI_xZVdNnBkRi6hUAust9NUHTIRM0p9XeBFsQLgHB3-1xslkc3-VH8KDN6PEMJI_-h9v0fUuwcuFrBS4kbpBFIQyIIA=w640-h424" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Lumen5 is an&amp;nbsp; online marketing video maker that makes it really easy to create branding or informational videos&amp;nbsp; within a couple of clicks. They have really great templates and various aspect ratios for various&amp;nbsp; social media platforms.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;You can also edit each element of the video if you don't like the preset,&amp;nbsp; and the best part is, they have a ton of , I mean a ton of free stock photos and videos.You can also&amp;nbsp; upload your own videos or any type of media. Definitely a good tool if you don't know how&amp;nbsp; to work with complex tools like after effects, but want to create a sick video for your brand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://namelix.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Namelix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh7VU8lm3tSbUpOBxVtMYQ2Uai0CaKaGUJipaMWZdKiQYeXK6L4MDFN1mEOT-f4RRiwMx_OKvDTrN24kv8VUgtUgPr3a_jHFfQwJFd9j__j_Sh5nepM40YK7mT0iUd8Oko5t-zV7bbWI4Umoi6Kyhya7G-pjKDTRtj64a_v0I1ZZHFxxH7HpHsdEjmnOA=s1264" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="832" data-original-width="1264" height="422" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh7VU8lm3tSbUpOBxVtMYQ2Uai0CaKaGUJipaMWZdKiQYeXK6L4MDFN1mEOT-f4RRiwMx_OKvDTrN24kv8VUgtUgPr3a_jHFfQwJFd9j__j_Sh5nepM40YK7mT0iUd8Oko5t-zV7bbWI4Umoi6Kyhya7G-pjKDTRtj64a_v0I1ZZHFxxH7HpHsdEjmnOA=w640-h422" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;If you are struggling to find&amp;nbsp; good names for your brand or youtube channel, give&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;namelix a try. It's an ai based name generator&amp;nbsp; that will suggest good names for your brand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Sawarabi Mincho&amp;quot;;"&gt;depending on the keyword that you give..&amp;nbsp; Also logo for your brand. Pretty cool and an amazing piece of tool. So that's been it , those are my favourite free AI based tools that you can use right now,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Sawarabi Mincho;"&gt;Which one You like the most Let me know in the Comments below.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchhype.com/2022/01/top-9-free-ai-tools-that-make-your-life.html</link>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (Unknown)</author>
      <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/a/AVvXsEh3XRgDXB0VsEgf272YBOXlxHdjxzyTuKQQd2OmNi4rBNKfPOBeYxyAeiDLR7v_w5U6umenSX8HHZ1A_jPQ4lLnjfQmT9oi6u2hjJx1AOoJUtuXguddjjTCqTOUbR_lrh_RGLGpLnPZxBPZvEV4m7TsWmJLVVMrpYzDqvYJdZs6JcbeeFu-J4kQ_RbhBw=s72-w640-h481-c" height="72" width="72" />
      <thr:total>8</thr:total>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>