<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Net Security</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com</link>
    <description>Daily information security news with a focus on enterprise security.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:24:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://img.helpnetsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/09093400/cropped-hns2-32x32.png</url>
      <title>Help Net Security</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Aryaka partners with Carnegie Mellon University CyLab to develop new threat mitigation techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/aryaka-carnegie-mellon-university-cylab/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Aryaka]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Carnegie Mellon University]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227434</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Aryaka announced it has formed a strategic partnership with CyLab, Carnegie Mellon University’s (CMU’s) Security and Privacy Institute, to research new threat mitigation techniques and innovate solutions for enterprise networking and security. Founded in 2003, CyLab is Carnegie Mellon University’s public/private collaborative computer security and privacy research institute. With more than 100 core and affiliated faculty and 100 graduate students, it is one of the largest cyber security research centers in the United States. Aryaka’s &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/aryaka-carnegie-mellon-university-cylab/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/aryaka-carnegie-mellon-university-cylab/">Aryaka partners with Carnegie Mellon University CyLab to develop new threat mitigation techniques</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parfin selects Anjuna Security to protect MPC custody assets against risk and misuse</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/anjuna-security-parfin/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Anjuna Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Parfin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227395</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Anjuna Security and Parfin announced that the Anjuna Confidential Cloud Software solution now enables Parfin’s MPC Custody platform to utilize the highly secure hardware protection of AWS Nitro Enclaves without any changes to applications or processes. The added layer of hardware security locks out cloud provider employees, third-party insiders or compromised software components from access to Multi-Party Computation (MPC) cryptographic keys, digital assets or proprietary custodial applications. In the digital asset custody market, trust, risk &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/anjuna-security-parfin/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/anjuna-security-parfin/">Parfin selects Anjuna Security to protect MPC custody assets against risk and misuse</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StorONE and Seagate join forces to solve important storage-related challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/storone-seagate/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Seagate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[StorONE]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227463</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>StorONE announced a new solution with Seagate that promises to extend the hybrid storage use case while lowering the cost of production, archive and backup storage. The new solution combines updated versions of StorONE and Seagate’s successful hybrid storage solutions based on StorONE’s Enterprise Storage Platform software and Seagate’s Next-Gen Application Platform (AP), the Exos AP BV-1. The Seagate Exos AP BV-1 is the 2nd GEN AMD EPYC server module. It supports Seagate’s existing family &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/storone-seagate/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/storone-seagate/">StorONE and Seagate join forces to solve important storage-related challenges</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WEBGAP partners with Intel to accelerate the adoption of remote browser isolation cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/webgap-intel/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[WEBGAP]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227376</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Remote browser isolation (RBI) cybersecurity vendor WEBGAP announced that they have partnered with Intel to integrate their technology into Intel’s Secure Access Service Edge (SASE) architecture in order to accelerate RBI adoption globally. WEBGAP is part of the Intel Network Builders Ecosystem, working with engineers from Intel’s Enterprise and Cloud Networking Division to integrate their market leading RBI technology into Intel’s Smart Edge Open Platform for deployment to Intel’s global customer base. WEBGAP founder Guise &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/webgap-intel/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/webgap-intel/">WEBGAP partners with Intel to accelerate the adoption of remote browser isolation cybersecurity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sandbox AQ and Deloitte help organizations protect operations during the quantum transformation</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/sandbox-aq-deloitte/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Deloitte]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sandbox AQ]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227387</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Sandbox AQ announced a strategic alliance with Deloitte. As one of Sandbox AQ&#8217;s two Platinum Global Systems Integrators, Deloitte will provide services related to Sandbox&#8217;s quantum-readiness solutions to organizations looking to prepare for disruptions caused by maturing quantum technologies – both potential benefits and security threats. Initial use cases will focus on upgrading the cybersecurity infrastructure of joint customers including the transition to quantum-resistant cryptographic algorithms. Additional use cases include leveraging AI and quantum, for &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/sandbox-aq-deloitte/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/sandbox-aq-deloitte/">Sandbox AQ and Deloitte help organizations protect operations during the quantum transformation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabanci acquires Radiflow to boost its cybersecurity offerings across various industrial sectors</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/radiflow-sabanci-group/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Radiflow]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227417</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Radiflow announced that it is being acquired in a two-phase process by Sabanci Group, market leaders in the financial services, energy, and industrial sectors. The initial phase entails a $45 million primary and secondary investment in several installments to reach a majority stake in Radiflow. In the second phase, Sabanci intends to acquire a 100% stake in Radiflow by 2025. A recent increase in demand for comprehensive OT cybersecurity solutions has allowed for Radiflow to &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/radiflow-sabanci-group/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/radiflow-sabanci-group/">Sabanci acquires Radiflow to boost its cybersecurity offerings across various industrial sectors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Perception raises $13 million to address the OT network cybersecurity needs of critical industries</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/network-perception-financing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Network Perception]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227432</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Network Perception announced that it has raised $13 million in Series A financing. The funding round was led by The Westly Group with participation from Energy Impact Partners and other existing investors, including Serra Ventures, Okapi Venture Capital, Energy Foundry and SaaS Venture Capital. The Series A funding brings Network Perception’s total funding to $15.73 million. Network Perception solutions proactively and continuously assure the security of critical OT assets using intuitive network segmentation verification and &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/network-perception-financing/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/network-perception-financing/">Network Perception raises $13 million to address the OT network cybersecurity needs of critical industries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShiftLeft raises $29 million to expand coverage of cloud native application architectures and languages</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/shiftleft-funding/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 22:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ShiftLeft]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227469</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>ShiftLeft announced an additional $29 million in funding from cybersecurity-focused investor SYN Ventures and Blackstone Innovations Investments with participation from existing investors. The funding will be applied to accelerate product development, marketing and sales efforts. As part of the expansion capital funding, SYN Managing Partner Jay Leek will join the ShiftLeft Board of Directors. The expansion capital comes at a period of unprecedented growth for the company while earning a Gross Retention Rate of 97% &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/shiftleft-funding/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/shiftleft-funding/">ShiftLeft raises $29 million to expand coverage of cloud native application architectures and languages</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doug McNitt joins Calix as EVP and General Counsel</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/calix-doug-mcnitt/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 22:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Calix]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227467</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Calix announced that Doug McNitt, a legal expert with deep experience leading teams across the artificial intelligence, cloud, and cybersecurity Industries, has joined the company as executive vice president and general counsel, effective now. Doug is responsible for driving the legal strategy and operations and developing the future generation of legal talent at Calix. As Calix advances its All-platform strategy to deliver unique value to its customers and generate rapid growth, Doug’s expertise in security, &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/calix-doug-mcnitt/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/calix-doug-mcnitt/">Doug McNitt joins Calix as EVP and General Counsel</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepwatch hires John Lionato as EVP of Security Operation</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/deepwatch-john-lionato/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 22:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[deepwatch]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227372</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Deepwatch announced that John Lionato has joined the company as Executive Vice President of Security Operations. Lionato brings decades of cybersecurity and technology experience to the role, where he will be responsible for the delivery and service quality of Deepwatch’s managed security services. Lionato joins from Accenture, where as Managing Director for Managed Detection and Response he led the company’s acquisition of Symantec’s Cyber Security Services and expanded Accenture’s global extended detection and response (XDR) &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/deepwatch-john-lionato/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/04/deepwatch-john-lionato/">Deepwatch hires John Lionato as EVP of Security Operation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>