<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>TIME</title>
    <atom:link href="https://time.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://time.com</link>
    <description>Current &amp; Breaking News | National &amp; World Updates</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:11:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">162509141</site>
    <item>
      <title>These States Are Set to Ban Abortion if Roe v. Wade is Overturned</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173196/abortion-trigger-laws-bans-roe-v-wade/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Abigail Abrams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 23:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173196</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[There is no federal law protecting abortion, so rolling back Roe would create a starker patchwork of legality and access across the country]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173196"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173196/abortion-trigger-laws-bans-roe-v-wade/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the Supreme Court overturns </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the 1973 ruling that established a constitutional right to abortion in America, it would reshape women&#8217;s reproductive rights across the country.</span></p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="Abortion across the U.S. if Roe v. Wade  is overturned" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/sWOOn/5/#?secret=f7QonAyh1N" data-secret="f7QonAyh1N" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="551"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A leaked draft of a Supreme Court ruling in <i>Dobbs v. Jackson Women&rsquo;s Health Organization</i>, first </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reported by Politico</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Monday evening, would overturn <em>Roe</em> and return decisions about the legality of abortion to the states. Many states are considering or have passed so-called trigger laws, and other measures, that would rapidly curtail or outlaw abortion in the wake of such a ruling. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Court is expected to issue its final ruling in <em>Dobbs</em> by the end of June, but the publication of the draft, and Politico&#8217;s reporting that a majority of Supreme Court justices support overturning <em>Roe</em>, has focused attention on where abortion rights are most likely to be rolled back.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;We hold that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Casey</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> must be overruled,&rdquo; Justice Samuel Alito writes in the draft document. In addition to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the 1992 case of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planned Parenthood v. Casey</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has upheld the constitutional right to abortion, and together they prohibited states from banning abortion before about 24 weeks, when a fetus is viable outside the womb. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Supreme Court confirmed on Tuesday that the leaked draft opinion is authentic, but noted that the Court&#8217;s decision in the case, which was argued Dec. 1, is not final and could still change before the justices ultimately issue their ruling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Politicians and activists on both sides of the abortion debate reacted quickly to the leak, launching intense preparations for a likely new era of abortion in the U.S. There is no federal law protecting abortion, so rolling back </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">would create a starker patchwork of legality and access across the country. Some conservative-led states would quickly ban abortion, while others would push to restrict abortion in various ways and other, liberal-led states would protect abortion rights. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the Supreme Court does overturn </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, abortion would be outlawed in about half of the states. Most of this would happen through &ldquo;trigger laws,&rdquo; which are designed to take effect shortly after the Court strikes down </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Other states have laws on the books that were passed before 1973 that they could try to bring back, while still others have passed abortion restrictions in recent years that were blocked by courts, but which they could try to implement once </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is no longer the law of the land. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because of the varied state laws at play, there are several different forecasts of how many states will ban abortion. The Guttmacher Institute, a research firm that tracks abortion policy and supports reproductive rights, has estimated that </span><a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/article/2021/10/26-states-are-certain-or-likely-ban-abortion-without-roe-heres-which-ones-and-why"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">27 states</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are likely to ban abortion once </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is gone. These include: Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Iowa, Kentucky, Louisiana, Michigan, Mississippi, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, West Virginia, Wisconsin and Wyoming.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Center for Reproductive Rights, a legal group that fights abortion restrictions and tracks state laws, </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/what-if-roe-fell/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">counts 25 states</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as likely to ban abortion. It includes Pennsylvania but not Florida, Iowa or Montana. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the Court issues its final ruling, changes could start happening quickly. Of the 13 states with trigger laws, those in Kentucky, Louisiana and South Dakota appear set to take effect immediately. In Arkansas, Mississippi, Missouri, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Utah and Wyoming, state attorneys general or other officials must take action to put the bans in effect. In Idaho, Tennessee and Texas, the laws would take effect 30 days after the Court strikes down </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The leaked opinion draft could speed this process, says Elizabeth Nash, who tracks state abortion policy for Guttmacher. Though the leaked opinion is not final, it allows states to line up their legal arguments in favor of implementing other abortion restrictions. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;Everyone was expecting that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> would be substantially damaged, perhaps overturned. Now we see where the court is going, which means that there&rsquo;s now a roadmap for how attorneys general are going to respond in these conservative states,&rdquo; Nash says. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Six states have bans on abortion that were passed before 1973 and have not been repealed. And a number of others have passed laws in the last few years that courts have blocked because they were in violation of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If that precedent goes away, the states can try to bring those laws back into effect. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, states like California, Colorado and Connecticut have passed laws protecting abortion in their state laws, and the glimpse at the Supreme Court&rsquo;s draft decision could encourage more liberal states to add extra protections.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173196</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Most ‘Pro-Life’ Nations Offer a Grim Preview of America’s Future</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173258/pro-life-countries-roe-v-wade-future/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jill Filipovic]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[nationpod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173258</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A few years ago, in a small home off an uneven road in Honduras, I got a little peek into what life is like when abortion is illegal. There, I met a woman in her early 20s, who for privacy I&#8217;ll call Alma. She lived with her family and a smattering of extremely cute animals&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173258"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173258/pro-life-countries-roe-v-wade-future/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>A few years ago, in a small home off an uneven road in Honduras, I got a little peek into what life is like when abortion is illegal.</p>
<p>There, I met a woman in her early 20s, who for privacy I&rsquo;ll call Alma. She lived with her family and a smattering of extremely cute animals &ndash; there were a few little dogs, a kitten or two, a hen and her chicks. Months earlier, Alma had had stillbirth &ndash; she hadn&rsquo;t even known she was pregnant, she told me. Doctors, though, suspected that she had taken medication to induce an abortion. They called the police. When I met Alma, she was awaiting trial.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>In Honduras, <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/06/07/domestic-violence-immigration-asylum-caravan-honduras-central-america-227086/"  target="_blank">abortion is outlawed</a>, along with emergency contraception. Sexual violence is commonplace, and women are barred from a basic tool to prevent pregnancy after rape, and then potentially jailed if they end an unwanted one. Through both abortion restrictions and endemic violence, women hear one message: Your body isn&rsquo;t yours.</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6116072/mississippi-abortion-supreme-court-jackson-womens-health/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inside Mississippi&rsquo;s Last Abortion Clinic&mdash;and the Biggest Fight for Abortion Rights in a Generation</span></i></a></p>
<p>Alma was far from the only woman I&rsquo;ve met whose body has borne the weight of abortion bans. There was a girl I called <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/06/07/domestic-violence-immigration-asylum-caravan-honduras-central-america-227086/"  target="_blank">Sofia</a> when I wrote about her, also in Honduras, forced to have a child as a 12-year-old rape victim. There was <a href="https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2021/06/16/how-us-abortion-politics-distorts-womens-lives-in-conflict-zones/"  target="_blank">Anita</a>, the pseudonym for a woman who fled war in South Sudan and was forced into sex by her husband even after a doctor told them another pregnancy too soon could kill her; she self-induced an abortion and nearly paid with her life. There was <a href="https://jill.substack.com/p/the-stories-you-never-forget?s=w"  target="_blank">Silvana</a>, raped as a child during Colombia&rsquo;s civil war, who starved herself into a miscarriage. There was a woman whose name I don&rsquo;t know, but whose story I heard again and again in a Bangladeshi camp full of Rohingya Muslim refugees from Myanmar &ndash; to end an unwanted pregnancy, she put a red-hot brick on her stomach, searing off her flesh.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://time.com/6173019/supreme-court-leak-roe-v-wade-abortion/" >leaked draft of a Supreme Court opinion</a> suggests that the Court is poised to overturn <em><a href="https://time.com/5793643/jane-roe-100-women-of-the-year/" >Roe v. Wade</a></em>, the 1973 case that legalized abortion for American women. Those of us who have followed the long arc of reproductive-rights law in the U.S. aren&rsquo;t surprised, although many of us are devastated and angry. Those of us who have reported on abortion rights and access, and women&rsquo;s rights more broadly, know just how high the stakes are.</p>
<p>The reality is that abortion access, and the procedure itself, has changed quite a bit since the bad old days of pre-<em>Roe</em> America. Now, a combination of <a href="https://time.com/5954429/fda-biden-abortion-pills/" >misoprostol and mifepristone</a>, taken orally, can effectively and safely induce an abortion without the potentially fertility- or even life-ending complications of older methods that required something be inserted into the cervix. <a href="https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2022/01/11/choice-by-mail/"  target="_blank">Activists have worked hard</a> to make these medications are available to women in places where abortion is illegal or hard to get<a href="https://www.plancpills.org/"  target="_blank">, including in the United States</a>. If<em> Roe</em> goes, these activist networks will undoubtedly expand. Abortion won&rsquo;t end, and activists will try to make sure that as many women as possible can access safe abortion-inducing medications. Again, the pro-choice movement will save women&rsquo;s lives.</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6160143/anti-abortion-roe-wade-supreme-court/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Battle Over the Future of the Anti-Abortion Movement if the Supreme Court Overturns Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p>But activists working to deliver safe abortions in a hostile legal environment simply cannot reach every woman in need. Even now, with Roe still standing, a great number of American women cannot get the abortions they want. And the women who are best able to access safe abortions will be those with greater resources: Money, to be sure, but also the education, connections, and internet literacy to know where to find help, and how to tell charlatans and scammers from safe providers. Women who are already vulnerable &ndash; who are poor, who are young, who live in rural areas, who don&rsquo;t speak English well or at all, who are the least able to take on a child they haven&rsquo;t planned for &ndash; are the most likely to fall through the cracks.</p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="Supreme Court police officers set up barricades during a protest" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1100,734 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=560,374 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=809,540 809w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1619,1080 1619w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1680,1121 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1499,1000 1499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1200,801 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1520,1014 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=46,31 46w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=2024,1350 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=479,320 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=767,512 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=800,534 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/pro-life-nations-02.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Al Drago&mdash;Bloomberg/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >U.S. Supreme Court police officers set up barricades during a protest outside of the U.S. Supreme Court in Washington, D.C., U.S., on Tuesday, May 3, 2022.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The criminalization of abortion will in and of itself discourage some women from pursuing abortion procedures, and those women will carry pregnancies to term against their wishes, making them more likely to be stuck in poverty and tied to abusive men. Some of those women will die because of that lack of choice. One <a href="https://theconversation.com/study-shows-an-abortion-ban-may-lead-to-a-21-increase-in-pregnancy-related-deaths-167610"  target="_blank">estimate</a> suggests that maternal mortality might increase by as much as 21% if abortion is outlawed nationwide.</p>
<p>Other women, fearful of the law but desperate to not be pregnant and too scared or ashamed to ask for help, will take matters into their own hands. Others won&rsquo;t know how to find help or where to look. Some will be fine. Some may not be.</p>
<p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://time.com/6172950/roe-alabama-abortion-clinic-prepares/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">If Roe v. Wade Is Overturned, Our Clinic Will Stop Providing Abortions Immediately. But We Won&#8217;t Shut Down</span></i></a></p>
<p>Overzealous prosecutors in the U.S. have already jailed women over suspected abortions. If abortion is outlawed, every indication is that more women, and certainly more doctors, will wind up behind bars.</p>
<p>The world&rsquo;s most &ldquo;pro-life&rdquo; nations show us what could be in store. In countries with <a href="https://time.com/6173229/countries-abortion-illegal-restrictions/" >the strictest anti-abortion laws</a>, women face <a href="https://www.thedialogue.org/blogs/2018/09/abortion-access-and-violence-against-women-in-latin-america/"  target="_blank">pervasive violence</a> from men. That isn&rsquo;t to say that anti-abortion laws cause violence. It is to say that violence against women, like restrictions on what women can do with their reproductive lives, is a tool of misogynist dominance. It stems from the urge to force women to do your bidding, and the belief that women&rsquo;s bodies and women&rsquo;s lives should be under male control. It&rsquo;s not a coincidence that <a href="https://www.globalcitizen.org/en/content/best-worst-countries-for-women-gender-equality/"  target="_blank">the countries where women do the best</a> &ndash; where they are the most economically prosperous, the safest, have the highest levels of education and employment, are the most supported in parenthood, and are the freest &ndash; are also countries where abortion is legal and contraception is easily accessible.</p>
<p>By curtailing abortion access, the U.S. is again making itself an outlier on women&rsquo;s rights, and joining a small number of nations &ndash; <a href="https://time.com/5905885/poland-abortion-ban-protest/" >Poland,</a> Hungary, Brazil, Russia, China &ndash; that are moving ever rightward toward authoritarianism. While many countries have liberalized their abortion laws as they have become more democratic, just a handful have restricted reproductive rights &ndash; and those restrictions have gone hand-in-hand with <a href="https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2021/10/21/supreme-court-abortion-dobbs-texas-martha-f-davis-fiona-de-londras"  target="_blank">shifts away</a> from democratic traditions and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/09/world/abortion-rights-us.html"  target="_blank">toward autocracy</a>.</p>
<p>According to the U.N., nearly <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2016/09/541212-repealing-anti-abortion-laws-would-save-lives-nearly-50000-women-year-un"  target="_blank">50,000 women&rsquo;s lives could be saved</a> each year simply by repealing anti-abortion laws. The U.S. has instead restricted abortion even further. <a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" >Overturning <span style="font-style: normal !msorm;"><em>Roe </em></span></a>would be the biggest blow in nearly 50 years to abortion rights in the U.S., and just the first step in a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2022/05/02/abortion-ban-roe-supreme-court-mississippi/"  target="_blank">broader conservative effort</a> to make abortion totally illegal &ndash; and if anti-abortion activists get their way, a national abortion law would have <a href="https://www.npr.org/2019/05/22/725634053/anti-abortion-rights-groups-push-gop-to-rethink-rape-and-incest-exceptions"  target="_blank">no exceptions</a> for rape, incest, health, or <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2022/04/28/the-new-abortion-restriction-no-one-is-talking-about-00028171"  target="_blank">the pregnant woman&rsquo;s life</a>.</p>
<p>These are the stakes if this draft opinion becomes law: Some women&rsquo;s lives, many women&rsquo;s futures, and all of our freedoms.</p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="GnWkCFcw" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173258</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Gas Prices Are Pushing Electric Car Sales to a Tipping Point</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173178/high-gas-prices-electric-vehicles/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[biztech2030]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173178</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[When Eric Dirksen received his first electric car in December&#8212;a new Tesla Model Y&#8212;he didn&#8217;t know gas prices would spike a few months after. But with fuel costing about $4.20 per gallon on average this week, he&#8217;s happy with the decision. &#8220;Very fortunate at the timing,&#8221; he says. Dirksen spent $62 on charging in the&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173178"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173178/high-gas-prices-electric-vehicles/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When Eric Dirksen received his first electric car in December&mdash;a new Tesla Model Y&mdash;he didn&rsquo;t know gas prices would spike a few months after. But with fuel costing about $4.20 per gallon on average this week, he&rsquo;s happy with the decision. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;Very fortunate at the timing,&rdquo; he says. Dirksen spent $62 on charging in the last month, roughly the same amount as 15 gallons of gas. &ldquo;I wanted to be more intentional with ensuring I was doing what I could to ensure a sustainable future for my daughter. It was the obvious choice,&rdquo; Dirksen says of his purchase. &ldquo;The savings are still mind blowing to me.&#8221;</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With gas prices painfully high for the third straight month, more Americans like Dirksen have been turning to fuel-efficient vehicle alternatives as a way to save money, new data shows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An unreleased report from CarGurus, an automotive research and shopping firm, shows that 53% of active shoppers say they are considering a more fuel-efficient vehicle in response to high gas prices. The data, shared with TIME, looks at consumer sentiment toward electric vehicles based on an online survey of 2,176 U.S. automobile owners at various points this year. It finds that 40% of Americans now expect to own an electric car in the next five years, up from 32% in February and 30% last year.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x aligncenter "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?w=560&w=560" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png 1688w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=768,500 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=600,390 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1536,999 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=550,358 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1100,716 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=280,182 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=560,364 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=415,270 415w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=838,545 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=830,540 830w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1660,1080 1660w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=407,265 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=814,529 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1537,1000 1537w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=190,124 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=380,247 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=263,171 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=526,342 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=61,40 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1200,781 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=640,416 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=760,494 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1520,989 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=700,455 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1000,650 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=48,31 48w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=840,546 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1680,1093 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1012,658 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=320,208 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=730,475 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=192,125 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=384,250 384w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=479,312 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=958,623 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=767,499 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1534,998 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=800,520 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-04-29-at-3.45.05-PM.png?resize=1600,1041 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >CarGurus</span><span class="caption" >The data, shared with TIME, looks at consumer sentiment toward electric vehicles based on an online survey of 2,176 U.S. automobile owners at various points this year.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;Gas prices have really pushed shoppers to consider EVs that otherwise wouldn&#8217;t have sooner,&rdquo; says Ali Chapman, a senior customer insights analyst at CarGurus. &ldquo;And it&rsquo;s led to increased activity in EVs on our site.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google searches for electric cars have also been boosted by the gas prices, reaching a record high in March. And the results are being felt all across the auto industry. Companies that manufacture electric vehicles have reported blockbuster sales in recent months, exceeding even the most optimistic Wall Street expectations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tesla, the largest electric vehicle manufacturer, generated a record profit of $3.32 billion in the first three months of 2022, with sales of its vehicles jumping roughly 80% from last year. German automakers Volkswagen and Mercedes also reported a bump in sales for their electric vehicle fleet, up 65% and 37%, respectively. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But despite the increase in sales and activity, data from CarGurus reveals consumer buying habits are a little more complex. In a survey of respondents last year, 56% said they&rsquo;d be much more likely to consider an electric vehicle if gas prices reached $5/gallon. Today, that figure drops to a more realistic 27%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;The initial shock of paying $5/gallon really kind of gets people looking,&rdquo; says Kevin Roberts, director of industry insights and analytics at CarGurus. &ldquo;But then as that awareness grows, interest slips out.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That interest in EVs is also impacted by supply chain problems, particularly shortages of items like lithium-ion batteries and semiconductors, which are making it difficult for consumers to ride home in a new electric vehicle. For almost a year, long wait lists for electric vehicles have been common, and the war in Ukraine has further disrupted production.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s made finding an electric vehicle take a little bit of luck&mdash;and a little more from your wallet. At many dealerships, only a small handful of EVs&mdash;if any&mdash;are available. Ordering one could take over a year to arrive, and some dealers only have pre-owned electric inventory on their lots. The problem isn&rsquo;t just the chip shortage, but that demand is significantly outpacing production.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On April 20, Ford shut down orders for the rest of the year on the Mach-E, its signature electric crossover, dubbed Car and Driver&rsquo;s electric vehicle of the year, meaning anyone who wants to buy one will have to pay a premium price. &ldquo;Most people come in here to ask about the Mach-E,&rdquo; one Ford salesman said last week, citing higher than normal gas prices as the reason for increased interest. &ldquo;If we had more of them they would sell the fastest.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But although carmakers are raising their prices, consumers still appear to want electric vehicles. &ldquo;Two-thirds of people say that they agree EVs are the way of the future,&rdquo; Chapman says. &ldquo;They seem somewhat inevitable.&rdquo; Experts say it will take time, as less than 1% of the 250 million cars on the road today are electric, but high gas prices could be one way to encourage switching.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;EV interest is going to continue to grow organically over time,&rdquo; Roberts says. &ldquo;Gas prices just kind of accelerate that.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, experts are looking back on the 2008 financial crisis as a potential example of what could happen in the electric vehicle industry. As gas prices spiked that year, consumers drastically shifted their driving habits and the kinds of vehicles they wanted, particularly as more electric vehicles were being introduced, Roberts says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;But then when those gas prices went back down, people went back immediately to what their previous practices were before.&rdquo; </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173178</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Abortion Rights Around the World</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173229/countries-abortion-illegal-restrictions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eloise Barry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Explainer]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173229</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The rollback of abortion rights in the U.S. has been mirrored in many other nations, but in others, women's rights activists have succeeded in broadening abortion access]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173229"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173229/countries-abortion-illegal-restrictions/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Supreme Court is </span><a href="https://time.com/6172868/roe-wade-supreme-court/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> considering overturning the landmark </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ruling on abortion rights, according to a leaked </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">draft opinion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If carried out, abortion will no longer be considered a constitutional right in the U.S., and each state will be free to determine the legality of the procedure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 1973, </span><a href="https://time.com/3669867/roe-v-wade-history/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> gave women in the U.S. an absolute right to an abortion in the first three months of pregnancy, and limited rights beyond then. While abortion is legal in some form in every state under </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">abortion access has been eroded over the years in more than a dozen states. </span><a href="https://time.com/6099921/texas-self-managed-abortions/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Texas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for example, passed a law in 2021 allowing residents to sue clinics and doctors for carrying out an abortion after six weeks. In Mississippi&mdash;the state at the center of the Supreme Court case&mdash;most abortions are banned after 15 weeks.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6173019/supreme-court-leak-roe-v-wade-abortion/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What to Know About the Leaked Roe v. Wade Supreme Court Draft Opinion</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rollback of abortion rights in the U.S. has been mirrored in many other nations globally, where the rise of pro-life movements have coincided with radical political or cultural shifts. In other countries, abortion rights activists have succeeded in pushing for less restrictive laws as part of a broader fight for women&rsquo;s rights.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here is a look at countries where abortion is banned, restricted, or has recently been legalized.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries where abortion is illegal</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?category[1348]=1348"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Center for Reproductive Rights</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a global legal advocacy organization, there are 24 countries in the world where abortion is completely prohibited. These include Andorra and Malta in Europe, El Salvador and Honduras in Central America, Senegal and Egypt in Africa, and the Philippines and Laos in Asia. Some </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?category[1348]=1348"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">90 million (5%) women</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">of reproductive age live in countries that prohibit abortion altogether.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Activists and campaigners in many of these countries continue to fight to ease abortion restrictions. The hardline laws in El Salvador, which were introduced in 1998 after campaigning from conservative sectors of the Catholic Church, have led to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">dozens of women being found guilty of &#8220;aggravated homicide,&#8221; even in cases of miscarriage. In March, thousands of Salvadoran women </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-60646938"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">marched</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to demand that the ban be eased to allow abortions in cases of rape, when the fetus is not viable, or if the woman&#8217;s life is at risk.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries with significant restrictions to abortion access</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than 50 countries and regions permit abortions only when the woman&rsquo;s health is at risk. (Some refer only to physical health, while others include mental health.) These include Libya, Iran, Indonesia, Venezuela and Nigeria. Others have exceptions for cases of rape, incest, or fetal abnormality.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Brazil, for example, abortion is illegal except in cases of rape, risks to the life of the mother, or when the fetus has anencephaly&mdash;missing part of the brain or skull. In these cases, the woman needs approval from a doctor and at least three other</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> clinical experts.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In August 2020, under President Bolsonaro&rsquo;s far-right government, a </span><a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2020/09/21/brazil-revoke-regulation-curtailing-abortion-access"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Health Ministry regulation</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">was introduced that requires medical professionals to collect evidence and report to the police anyone who seeks legal termination of a pregnancy after rape&mdash;which Human Rights Watch </span><a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2020/09/21/brazil-revoke-regulation-curtailing-abortion-access"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">suggests</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is to dissuade rape survivors.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="Protests Continue Against Abortion Ruling In Poland" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg 1024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=550,366 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=280,186 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=811,540 811w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=840,559 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=526,350 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=640,426 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=760,506 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=700,466 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=1000,666 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=1012,674 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=958,638 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=800,533 800w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Omar Marques/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >A woman holds a European Union flag at a protest against the Constitutional Court ruling on tightening abortion laws on Oct. 30, 2020 in Warsaw, Poland. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In January 2021, a </span><a href="https://time.com/5905885/poland-abortion-ban-protest/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">near-total ban on abortion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was introduced in Poland, only allowing the procedure in cases of rape, incest, or when the mother&rsquo;s life is at risk. The ban removed the exception for an abortion </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in cases of severe and irreversible fetal abnormalities&mdash;the grounds for which 98% of abortions in Poland were carried out in 2019.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Mass demonstrations broke out in Poland in November 2021 following the </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-59206683"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">death of a woman</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at 22 weeks pregnant from sepsis, after her family said that life-saving treatment was delayed because of the ban. This month, the first pro-abortion activist to be charged under the new law </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2022/mar/28/polish-woman-is-first-to-face-trial-for-violating-strict-abortion-law"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">went on trial</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for providing a pregnant woman with tablets to induce a miscarriage.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries with broader access to abortion </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Center for Reproductive Rights</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in countries from Japan to India to Canada, as well as most of Europe and the U.S., more than </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">half of women of reproductive age </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?country=JPN&amp;category[1351]=1351"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">can safely access</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> abortion either on request or based on broad social or economic grounds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seventy-two countries, including France and Germany, allow for abortion subject to gestational time limits&mdash;the most common being 12 weeks. Even in these countries, there are often a variety of exceptions that allow abortions to take place later. In the U.K. for example, there is a 24-week limit on abortion, but if the fetus has a disability such as </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/sep/23/woman-with-downs-syndrome-loses-uk-abortion-law-case"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Down&rsquo;s Syndrome</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the pregnancy can be terminated right up until birth.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Enormous Consequences of Overturning Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While pro-life movements in countries like Poland and the U.S. have successfully lobbied for rollbacks in reproductive rights, other nations are making strides towards greater freedoms. In the past 18 months, Colombia, Argentina, and Mexico&mdash;traditionally conservative Catholic countries in Latin America&mdash;decriminalized abortions following waves of protests and campaigning by women&rsquo;s rights and pro-choice groups. The most recent, Colombia, </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2022/feb/22/colombia-legalises-abortion-in-move-celebrated-as-historic-victory-by-campaigners"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">set the legal gestational limit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at 24 weeks of pregnancy in February.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The changes have inspired other pro-choice movements in the region&mdash;dubbed the </span><a href="https://time.com/5358823/argentina-abortion-vote-latin-america/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;green wave&rdquo;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the colors worn by campaigners. Chile could become the </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/chile-abortion-debate-gets-key-place-constitution-redraft-2022-03-16/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">first Latin American country</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to have the right to abortion enshrined in the country&rsquo;s constitution, pending the results of a vote later this year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And in Europe, Ireland drew worldwide attention after a May 2018 popular referendum that led to abortion being legalized up to 12 weeks, and limited circumstances beyond then. Before the change, thousands of Irish women would typically travel to nearby England fo</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">r the procedure every year, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the Belfast-based journalism project </span><a href="https://www.thedetail.tv/articles/abortion-exported-women-travelling-for-terminations"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Detail Data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2020, New Zealand </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-51955148"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">decriminalized</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> abortion and extended the legal period to 20 weeks of pregnancy. Prior to that, two doctors were required to approve an abortion&mdash;and they would only do so if there was a &ldquo;serious danger&rdquo; to the woman&rsquo;s health. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173229</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Original Roe v. Wade Supreme Court Leak, 49 Years Before the Alito Bombshell</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173058/supreme-court-leak-history-david-beckwith/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia B. Waxman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[nationpod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Second click]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173058</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In 1973, TIME got a scoop on the news of the Roe v. Wade decision. Here's what the reporter behind the story, David C. Beckwith, remembers]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173058"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173058/supreme-court-leak-history-david-beckwith/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>The leak <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank">to Politico on Monday</a> of a draft of an opinion by a majority of U.S. Supreme Court Justices that would overturn <em>Roe </em>v. <em>Wade</em> has been called &#8220;unprecedented&#8221; in the modern history of the Court&mdash;but it&#8217;s not the first time a Supreme Court decision has been made public before its official release. This week&#8217;s leak comes 49 years after TIME first published the news of the original <em>Roe v. Wade</em> decision, which ruled that a woman&#8217;s constitutional right to privacy included decisions about <a href="https://time.com/6116072/mississippi-abortion-supreme-court-jackson-womens-health/" >whether to terminate a pregnancy</a>.</p>
<p>TIME called up the reporter behind the 1973 story, David C. Beckwith, who is now retired and living in Austin. He landed the scoop about a year into working at TIME, covering legal affairs and the Department of Justice. He says he talked to about 15 people for the story, including a clerk for Justice Lewis F. Powell Jr. named <a href="https://www.legacy.com/us/obituaries/azcentral/name/larry-hammond-obituary?id=2122832"  target="_blank">Larry Hammond</a>, and that he had no problem getting people to talk to him about the case, though he did find people were &#8220;nervous&#8221; at first.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>&#8220;I talked to a lot of people&mdash;some on the court, some clerks, some friends of people that were either clerks or court members,&#8221; says Beckwith, now 79.</p>
<p><em><strong>Read more: </strong></em><a href="https://time.com/5110210/roe-v-wade-anniversary-abortion/" >Roe v. Wade<em> Lawyer &#8216;Amazed&#8217; Americans Still Fighting Over Abortion</em></a></p>
<p>The resulting article, headlined &#8220;Abortion on Demand,&#8221; ran in the Jan. 29, 1973, issue, in the section &#8220;The Sexes.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Last week TIME learned that the Supreme Court has decided to strike down nearly every anti-abortion law in the land,&#8221; the article <a href="https://time.com/vault/issue/1973-01-29/page/50/" >reported</a>. &#8220;Such laws, a majority of the Justices believe, represent an unconstitutional invasion of privacy that interferes with a woman&#8217;s right to control her own body.&#8221;</p>
<p>As <a href="https://time.com/vault/issue/1973-01-29/page/50/" >TIME explained the significance of the decision</a> back then:</p>
<blockquote><p>The historic ruling, upholding a challenge to Georgia&#8217;s restrictive abortion statute, will permit states to impose only minimal curbs on the right to abortion at will. These might include consent of a physician, licensing of abortion facilities and a ban on late termination of pregnancy. Beyond that, a woman&#8217;s freedom to end her pregnancy will not be significantly abridged. No decision in the court&#8217;s history, not even those outlawing public school segregation and capital punishment, has evoked the intensity of emotion that will surely follow this ruling. The pronouncement, ending 13 months of wrangling among the Justices, is certain to be met with passionate resistance by abortion opponents and to stir new controversy across the nation.</p></blockquote>
<p>The magazine&#8217;s story was supposed to come out after the decision came down, but the decision was delayed, so the issue ended up <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2022/05/02/leak-time-magazine-roe-wade/"  target="_blank">hitting newsstands a few hours before the ruling was announced</a> on Jan. 22, 1973.</p>
<p>Beckwith remembers getting some pushback to the article shortly after it came out; Chief Justice Warren E. Burger showed up at TIME&#8217;s Washington Bureau. Editors flew down from the New York headquarters in a private plane, and Beckwith escorted them in a limo to a dinner meeting with Burger.</p>
<p>&#8220;Burger showed up at the TIME offices a month or two after the decision was announced [and] he had a loose-leaf binder, three inches thick, detailing all the reporting I&#8217;d done,&#8221; Beckwith says. &#8220;He feared that the integrity of the court was being jeopardized, and he wanted me to be fired or to be ordered not to spy on the court. He thought [the story] was the equivalent of espionage. His position was this sort of espionage on the court was damaging to the court and to the country and that [he] couldn&#8217;t have a situation where this sort of thing happened again&mdash;it could affect the stock market, it could affect all sorts of things. And he tried to get some sort of promise, and he couldn&#8217;t believe that the TIME editors didn&#8217;t see it his way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nearly five decades later, the court is again concerned about the integrity of the institution: having <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/03/us/roe-wade-abortion-supreme-court"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> the authenticity of the latest leaked draft, written by Justice Samuel Alito, the court has launched an investigation into the identity of the leaker. The opinion is not the final draft, and the content could still change, but Beckwith, for one, agrees with what he&#8217;s seen. (Some legal scholars, <a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" >on the other hand</a>, have read the Alito draft as a dangerous break with precedent.)</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m kind of old school&#8230;I found, from my reading of the Alito decision, that it&#8217;s a tour de force,&#8221; Beckwith says he believes. &#8220;It&#8217;s really hard to argue with much of what he says, from a constitutional law standpoint. We all have our political opinions that divide us, these days especially, but if you believe that the Constitution should be the lodestar for our jurisprudence, Alito is hitting all the right notes, and I just don&#8217;t see much that can be argued with it.&#8221;</p>
<p>After TIME, Beckwith worked in Republican politics for Dan Quayle, Kay Bailey Hutchison, and John Cornyn.</p>
<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6122144/supreme-court-roe-v-wade-mississippi-abortion/" >A Case That Could Overturn <em>Roe v. Wade</em> Goes Before the Supreme Court</a></p>
<p>Beckwith also understands why the 2022 leak is making a much greater splash than his own work made in 1973.</p>
<p>&#8220;The impact of my story was much less, much less, because while it was seen as a technical leak from the court, it was immediately overtaken by the actual decision itself within a day,&#8221; says Beckwith.</p>
<p>The decision came out on Jan. 22, 1973, two days after Inauguration Day, and there was a reason for that, Beckwith says. &#8220;According to the rumor I got,&#8221; he says, &#8220;Burger didn&#8217;t want to face [President Richard] Nixon on the inauguration stand with that decision having just come out.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://time.com/vault/issue/1973-01-29/page/50/" ><em>Read TIME&#8217;s 1973 story on the</em> Roe v. Wade <em>decision in the TIME Vault</em></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173058</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Leaked Supreme Court Draft Threatens to Make Every Race About Abortion</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173203/supreme-court-roe-midterms/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Elliott]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The D.C. Brief]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173203</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[This article is part of The D.C. Brief, TIME&#8217;s politics newsletter. Sign up here to get stories like this sent to your inbox. Bombshell is a word that gets thrown around Washington a lot, but the report published Monday evening by Politico merits its use. The leaking of a draft of a ruling that would&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173203"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173203/supreme-court-roe-midterms/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article is part of The D.C. Brief, TIME&rsquo;s politics newsletter. Sign up </span></i><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to get stories like this sent to your inbox.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bombshell</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a word that gets thrown around Washington a lot, but the </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> published Monday evening by Politico merits its use.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The leaking of a draft of a ruling that would overturn two landmark cases that in effect made access to abortion a constitutional right in the United States landed like a grenade, blowing up both the ongoing midterm elections and the agendas of both parties in Washington. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The initial 98-page ruling leaves little room for nuance: &#8220;We hold that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Casey</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> must be overruled,&rdquo; Justice Samuel Alito wrote of the nearly 50-year-old ruling and its follow-up. Assuming </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Politico</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has its leak dead-to-rights that a majority of the justices is willing to rip a Band-Aid from the skin of American politics, such a ruling would do more than lead to the outright banning of abortion in more than a dozen states. It could also upend the broader landscape of individual rights, </span><a href="https://www.advocate.com/law/2022/5/02/supreme-court-poised-overturn-roe-v-wade-other-rights-risk"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">potentially</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> leading to changes in the national rules around contraception, marriage, and private sexual activity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That is, all of that would happen if the ruling is where the court is actually headed. Chief Justice John Roberts on Tuesday </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/05/03/supreme-court-leak-investigation-abortion-roe-wade/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">confirmed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the authenticity of the draft, a move that spoke volumes to just how much the leak has rocked Washington. But he added that it did not represent the court&rsquo;s final decision. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In that ambiguity and with a sliding abacus of nuance, both political parties wrestled with their responses to the fallout and calculations about the impact this would have on the electorate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Democrats immediately rushed to cast Republicans as the party of anti-abortion extremists. Their outrage machine rightly kicked into overdrive and fundraising emails flooded the inboxes of activists and donors. Strategists who had been worried about anemic interest in a cycle without a presidential race on the ballot saw opportunities to engage unreliable voters and perhaps stave off the anticipated Democratic losses. But the Democrats lacked a unified answer to a post-</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> world, lacking 60 votes in the Senate to codify protections for abortion rights and seemingly unwilling to change the rules so they could govern with just a majority of 51 votes in the Senate. Even then, Democratic Sen. Joe Manchin has been open about his opposition to abortion and could still drag his party on the topic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Republicans, meanwhile, looked to balance their latent glee with the risks of contending with a newly animated Democratic opposition. The GOP has fully embraced a return to the culture wars as a way to poke their own base, fanning discontent over what schools are teaching children and laying the foundation for anti-LGBTQ policies and narrower crackdowns on abortion access. But a full-blown reversal of a federal protection for abortion rights may be a swing too far for some and provoke a reactionary spasm. For every hardcore anti-abortion activist, there are two moderate moms who have long assumed their reproductive rights were walled-off from the outrage churn over critical race theory.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Admittedly, both parties were bracing for a potentially seismic shift in the election season whenever the court&rsquo;s ruling on the Mississippi abortion law came down this summer. But Politico&rsquo;s leak shocked many into action earlier than expected. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first test case may be playing out in real time in Ohio, where Republicans </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/02/us/ohio-senate-republican-primary.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">face</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a fierce primary contest on Tuesday to decide the nominee in a race to follow retiring Sen. Rob Portman, a member of the Republican establishment. Almost $70 million has been spent on ads in the GOP primary alone, making it the most expensive race so far this year. Former President Donald Trump&rsquo;s endorsement buoyed support for author and investor J.D. Vance and seemed to deflate the hopes of rivals Josh Mandel, Mike Gibbons, and Jane Timken. The state&rsquo;s powerful Ohio Right to Life </span><a href="https://www.theblaze.com/news/jd-vance-receives-endorsement-from-ohio-right-to-life-in-the-crowded-primary-race"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">lined-up</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with Vance but also offered praise for the other three candidates who each scored a 100% rating on the group&rsquo;s scorecard. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But those candidates are also contending with a late insurgent rise of Matt Dolan, a state senator whose family owns the Cleveland Guardians, and who has openly questioned the GOP&rsquo;s fealty to Trump. Dolan&rsquo;s relative moderation on abortion rights &mdash; he sided with Republican Gov. John Kasich&rsquo;s veto of a bill that could have banned abortion as early as eight weeks &mdash; may play a stronger-than-expected role in the Republican primary&rsquo;s final hours. (Kasich, however, </span><a href="https://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/politics/2018/12/21/ohio-gov-john-kasich-signs-one-nations-most-restrictive-abortion-bans-vetoes-heartbeat-bill/2366674002/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">signed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a </span><a href="https://www.cleveland.com/metro/2017/05/ohio_bill_would_ban_most_abort.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">law</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that banned most abortions as early as 12 weeks and had no exception for rape or incest. A federal judge </span><a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/u-s-judge-blocks-part-of-ohio-ban-on-abortion-procedure"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">struck</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> part of that law down and abortion is </span><a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/fact-sheet/state-facts-about-abortion-ohio"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">now</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> legal in Ohio up until roughly the 20th week of pregnancy.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Focus groups for years have consistently told pollsters that abortion is an animating factor for a relatively small sliver of both parties. The intensity gap is one that has allowed both parties to offer up predictable rhetoric without any real consequences. (The notable exceptions, of course, come when candidates stray beyond the staid mainline postures, as was the case in 2012, when Republicans candidates like </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/decision2012/gops-akin-mourdock-lose-senate-elections/2012/11/07/2b48954c-27b3-11e2-b2a0-ae18d6159439_story.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rep. Todd Akin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> drew widespread scorn for rhetoric on &ldquo;legitimate rape&rdquo; and pregnancy.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By a roughly 2-to-1 margin, Americans want to see </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> upheld, according to an ABC News-Washington </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> poll last week, and a majority broadly support abortion rights. Roughly seven in 10 Americans say the decision should be made by the pregnant person and doctors, with only one in four saying the law should regulate that decision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the partisan divide remains pronounced in the poll, with 75% of Democrats telling ABC-</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> pollsters that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">should stand and 44% of Republicans saying it should be overturned. But among the biggest bloc of voters &mdash; the 40% who identify as independents &mdash; 53% say </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> should be left in place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Gallup </span><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/244709/pro-choice-pro-life-2018-demographic-tables.aspx"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">polling</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, moderate voters who describe themselves as &ldquo;pro-choice&rdquo; enjoy an 18-point advantage over those who say they&rsquo;re &ldquo;pro-life.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The numbers, by and large, have remained </span><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/350804/americans-opposed-overturning-roe-wade.aspx"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">consistent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> over the years. It&rsquo;s not as if voters are just now discovering the medical and ethical issues embedded in the conversation around abortion. But, perhaps instructively, American opinion on same-sex marriage </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2015-pace-of-social-change/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">swung</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rapidly and wildly when the Supreme Court legalized such unions &mdash; and could find a corresponding shift if a long-assumed right to abortion was suddenly stripped.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Supreme Court has traditionally finished its docket by late June or early July. An overturned </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> could energize abortion foes, who have been clamoring for this moment since the 1970s. But it also could spark widespread liberal outrage &mdash; not only among those who view abortion access as a leading issue, but a broader group of voters wary of what could come next from the 6-3 conservative court. And in the suburbs, where the margins for party control often lie, many voters could be alienated by such a raw return to the culture wars. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The debate, meanwhile, would not simply end in Washington. The end of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> would </span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/meet-the-press/america-ready-post-roe-politics-n1285149"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">force</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> every state to work out far more granular positions on abortion rights for their constituents, which could take the conversation from one largely seen as defined by Washington and turn it into a fight in every voter&rsquo;s backyard. Without the sense of distance, everyone from local elected officials to governors may suddenly be </span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/11/29/abortion-supreme-court-roe-v-wade-unity/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">forced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into defining exactly when pregnant individuals can have access to abortion and under what circumstances. It could turn the nation&rsquo;s politics into chaos. Which is why even local and state parties should note the teed-up Supreme Court draft.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make sense of what matters in Washington. </span></i><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sign up for the D.C. Brief newsletter</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173203</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Draft Decision Ending Roe v. Wade Emboldens Activists on Both Sides of the Abortion Debate</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6172995/supreme-court-roe-v-wade-abortion-activists/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Abigail Abrams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6172995</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Both pro-abortion rights and anti-abortion activists spent most of Tuesday scrambling to respond to a leaked draft of a Supreme Court decision that would overturn Roe v. Wade. While the draft, first reported by Politico, is neither final nor legally binding, its release fundamentally upends the debate over abortion nationwide, experts say. The news encourages&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6172995"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6172995/supreme-court-roe-v-wade-abortion-activists/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both pro-abortion rights and anti-abortion activists spent most of Tuesday scrambling to respond to a leaked draft of a Supreme Court decision that would overturn <em>Roe v. Wade</em>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the draft, first <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank">reported by Politico</a>, is neither final nor legally binding, its release fundamentally upends the debate over abortion nationwide, experts say. The news encourages conservative legislators to further restrict abortion at the state level and injects a new cloud of confusion over would-be patients, potentially discouraging people from accessing abortions that are still legal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planned Parenthood and NARAL Pro-Choice America, as well as <a href="https://time.com/5916746/abortion-clinics-covid-19/" >independent abortion clinics</a> and other reproductive rights groups, say a top priority now is reminding people that abortion remains legal for the time being. Meanwhile conservative lawmakers are now considering proposing new legislation&mdash;or reconvening legislative sessions&mdash;in light of the leaked decision. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chief Justice John Roberts confirmed the authenticity of the leaked draft on Tuesday, but a spokesperson emphasized that the opinion, which would explicitly overturn the 1973 decision that established the national right to abortion, may change. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Until the Court hands down a final decision saying otherwise, <em>Roe v. Wade</em> remains in effect.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6173019/supreme-court-leak-roe-v-wade-abortion/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What to Know About the Leaked Roe v. Wade Supreme Court Draft Opinion</span></i></a></p>
<h2>Mass confusion over current abortion rights</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elizabeth Nash, who tracks state abortion policy for the Guttmacher Institute, a research firm that supports reproductive rights, says many people are likely confused about their current reproductive rights. &ldquo;Most certainly some people will think abortion is banned,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;And that&rsquo;s why we&#8217;re seeing abortion providers and patient groups working doubly hard to remind people that abortion remains legal.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abortion providers and abortion funds said they&#8217;ve received a volley of calls on Tuesday asking whether abortion is still legal, and are currently working to help patients access care. &ldquo;No matter what a court decides, no matter what law is passed or overturned, people have always needed and will continue to need access to safe abortion,&rdquo; Dr. Bhavik Kumar, medical director of Planned Parenthood Gulf Coast told reporters on Tuesday. &ldquo;Unfortunately, people of color, poor and low income people, young folks, undocumented people and those living in rural areas are suffering the most from these abortion bans.&rdquo; </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Kumar is in Texas providing abortion services to patients this week. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Already, 13 states have laws known as &ldquo;trigger bans&rdquo; that would outlaw abortion if </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is overturned, and six more have abortion bans that pre-date </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> but could also go into effect. When the Court heard <a href="https://time.com/6124416/supreme-court-abortion-oral-arguments-mississippi/" >oral arguments for </a></span><a href="https://time.com/6116072/mississippi-abortion-supreme-court-jackson-womens-health/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dobbs v. Jackson Women&rsquo;s Health</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in December, advocates and experts on both sides came away expecting the justices would significantly roll back or overturn the 1973 decision.</span></p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="Abortion across the U.S. if Roe v. Wade  is overturned" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/sWOOn/5/#?secret=i4XxxI1Ljv" data-secret="i4XxxI1Ljv" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="551"></iframe></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6160143/anti-abortion-roe-wade-supreme-court/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Battle Over the Future of the Anti-Abortion Movement if the Supreme Court Overturns Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since then, abortion opponents have jumped into action pushing more aggressive restrictions on abortion in anticipation of the high Court&rsquo;s ruling. Between Jan. 1 and April 14, Republican-led states introduced 536 abortion restrictions in 42 states, according to </span><a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/article/2022/03/2022-state-legislative-sessions-abortion-bans-and-restrictions-medication-abortion"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Guttmacher</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Last year, Texas passed its <a href="https://time.com/6093905/texas-abortion-ban-abortion-rights/" >six-week abortion ban</a> with a private enforcement mechanism that has since inspired other states to follow suit. Florida and Arizona passed 15-week abortion bans this year. Idaho passed a law modeled on Texas&#8217; six-week ban. Kentucky passed a law imposing a host of new abortion restrictions that temporarily shut down the state&rsquo;s abortion providers until a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/abortion-business-health-kentucky-legislature-eda1b6c68c636e753be8032c715bde45"  target="_blank">judge blocked the law</a>. Oklahoma passed a law outlawing all abortions and is close to enacting two others that use Texas&rsquo; civil enforcement process. </span></p>
<h2>Further state-level restrictions</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While some state legislative sessions have now ended for the year, others like Missouri, Louisiana and Ohio are ongoing, and lawmakers could introduce new legislation or advance other bills in light of the leaked decision. &ldquo;This leak has also energized abortion opponents, and so they are gearing up for the day when Roe falls,&rdquo; Nash says.</span></p>
<p>Special sessions are common in state legislatures, and conservatives in several states have already said they want to reconvene lawmakers now that they expect the Supreme Court to overturn <em>Roe</em>.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">South Dakota Gov. Kristi Noem </span><a href="https://twitter.com/govkristinoem/status/1521303498545061889"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tweeted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Monday that if the Politico report was true, she would &ldquo;immediately call for a special session to save lives and guarantee that every unborn child has a right to life in South Dakota.&rdquo; Republican lawmakers in <a href="https://twitter.com/bluestein/status/1521450124303646720"  target="_blank">Georgia</a> and <a href="https://www.wlky.com/article/indiana-lawmakers-sign-onto-letter-requesting-possible-special-session-on-abortion/39387483"  target="_blank">Indiana</a> have called for their governors to convene special sessions once the Supreme Court rules, and Arkansas Gov. Asa Hutchinson said last month he was considering doing so too. And Florida Voice for the Unborn, a leading anti-abortion group in the Sunshine State, sent a letter to Gov. Ron DeSantis on Tuesday morning urging a special session there in light of the leaked Supreme Court draft. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, abortion rights supporters are also hoping the leak will embolden liberal lawmakers and voters to turn out in the midterm elections. Planned Parenthood Action Fund, NARAL and EMILY&rsquo;s List recently announced they plan to spend $150 million ahead of the 2022 midterms, and abortion rights leaders noted on Tuesday that they had been inundated with calls and text messages from people asking how they can show up to help.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6143345/15-week-abortion-ban-supreme-court/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Red States Aren&#8217;t Waiting for the Supreme Court&#8217;s Roe Decision to Push New Abortion Bans</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;We have been warning for decades about what is happening in this country in terms of abortion access,&rdquo; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fatima Goss Graves, president and CEO of National Women&rsquo;s Law Center told reporters on Tuesday. &ldquo;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think this draft opinion leaked last night is making it real for people.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mini Timmaraju, president of NARAL, similarly called the leak a &ldquo;wake up call&rdquo; for groups across the progressive spectrum. &ldquo;This week has given us a perfect opportunity to close the believability gap and really let people understand what&#8217;s at stake in this,&rdquo; she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abortion funds, the grassroots groups that help pay for and provide material support to people seeking abortions, are also expecting to see an influx of donations this week. Access Reproductive Care (ARC)-Southeast, a fund that serves six states across the South, received $5,000 just through its fundraising platform from Monday night until Tuesday morning, co-founder and executive director Oriaku Njoku said. While Njoku said that amount might not sound like a lot for national organizations, it is a huge amount for the group to raise in under 24 hours.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;What we&#8217;re telling patients, what has been our commitment to our community from the very beginning, is that we will do whatever we need to do to make sure that folks get access to the abortion care that they want and they need, that we&rsquo;re doing our part to eliminate those barriers to abortion access by providing abortion funding and logistical support,&rdquo; Njoku said. &ldquo;And that is not going to change depending on what the laws are.&rdquo;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6172995</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democrats Vow to Protect Reproductive Rights But Can’t Actually Do Much</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173091/democrats-roe-v-wade-codify-abortion-unlikely/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Abby Vesoulis and Eric Cortellessa]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173091</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Democrats in Congress were in a fighting mood on Tuesday. Just hours after Politico published a draft opinion by a Supreme Court majority that would strike down Roe v. Wade, senators issued fiery promises about what Congress must do next to safeguard legal access to abortions. &#8220;I am angry. Angry and upset and determined,&#8221; Sen.&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173091"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173091/democrats-roe-v-wade-codify-abortion-unlikely/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>Democrats in Congress were in a fighting mood on Tuesday. Just hours after <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank">Politico published</a> a draft opinion by a Supreme Court majority that would strike down <em>Roe v. Wade, </em>senators issued fiery promises about what Congress must do next to safeguard legal access to abortions.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I am angry. Angry and upset and determined,&rdquo; Sen. Elizabeth Warren of Massachusetts declared outside the Court. &#8220;The United States Congress can keep <em>Roe v. Wade</em> the law of the land. They just need to do it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>It just wasn&#8217;t clear how. Many Democrats have long pursued two legislative avenues to safeguard the right to a legal abortion nationwide. &ldquo;Congress must pass legislation that codifies Roe v. Wade as the law of the land in this country NOW,&rdquo; Sen. <a href="https://twitter.com/SenSanders/status/1521303260933541890"  target="_blank">Bernie Sanders tweeted</a>. &ldquo;And if there aren&rsquo;t 60 votes in the Senate to do it, and there are not, we must end the filibuster to pass it with 50 votes.&rdquo;<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>Yet in a 50-50 Senate, any effort to pass a law codifying abortion access nationwide would require 60 votes, which Democrats are extremely unlikely to win. And any attempt to end-run that 60-vote limit would require overturning the filibuster&mdash;an equally unlikely scenario.</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6173019/supreme-court-leak-roe-v-wade-abortion/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What to Know About the Leaked Roe v. Wade Supreme Court Draft Opinion</span></i></a></p>
<p>That much was clear in February, when Republican Senators, joined by Democratic Sen. Joe Manchin, blocked a bill known as the Women&rsquo;s Health Protection Act, which was designed to enshrine the right to abortions in federal law. The measure passed the Democratic-controlled House last September, but never stood a chance of gaining the support of 60 senators.</p>
<p>Democrats in the Capitol acknowledged Tuesday that little has changed, even though the explosive leak from the Court has ratcheted up the urgency.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&rsquo;ll put a vote on the floor to make clear where the senators stand,&#8221; says Democratic Sen. Chris Murphy of Connecticut. &#8220;It&#8217;s no secret that we don&#8217;t have the votes right now to change the rules of the Senate to ensconce <em>Roe v. Wade</em> into law.&rdquo;</p>
<p>At a lunch meeting of Senate Democrats hours after the <em>Roe </em>draft opinion leaked, no one even brought up the filibuster issue, according to Democratic Sen. Bob Menendez of New Jersey. That may be because Manchin and Democratic Sen. Kyrsten Sinema remain opposed to killing it. &#8220;The filibuster is the only protection we have of democracy right now,&rdquo; Manchin told reporters Tuesday. Sinema said in a statement that not eliminating the filibuster is &ldquo;safeguarding against the erosion of women&#8217;s access to health care.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&#8220;The people who don&rsquo;t want to change the filibuster haven&rsquo;t changed their minds,&#8221; says a Senate Democratic aide. &#8220;There will be a push to enact legislative changes, but we simply don&rsquo;t have the votes.&rdquo;</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Enormous Consequences of Overturning Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p>In the absence of them, Democrats vowed to put the issue at the center of the midterm elections. &#8220;You can be sure in 2022, this will be an issue all throughout the country,&rdquo; Senate Democratic leader Chuck Schumer told reporters. &#8220;We&#8217;ve got to go out and make the case to voters to elect more Democrats,&#8221; Murphy says.</p>
<p>Democratic lawmakers emphasized a SCOTUS ruling would make real what has long been an abstract fear. &#8220;There&rsquo;s a big difference between threatening to take away women&rsquo;s reproductive rights and actually doing it,&#8221; says Democratic Sen. Chris Van Hollen. &ldquo;This is a clarifying moment. This has been part of the right-wing movement for a very long time. Now the American people are waking up to seeing that what was implicit is now explicit.&rdquo;</p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="Abortion across the U.S. if Roe v. Wade  is overturned" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/sWOOn/5/#?secret=7SRJKFP98e" data-secret="7SRJKFP98e" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="551"></iframe></p>
<p>Sen. Amy Klobuchar inveighed against the draft opinion, calling it contrary to the will of the American people. &#8220;The Supreme Court has been stacked with ultra conservative justices who are literally reversing 50 years of precedent,&rdquo; Klobuchar intoned in the Senate basement. &ldquo;They are taking Neanderthal views, pushing America backwards.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But privately, Democrats on the Hill admitted that in a split Senate, there was little the legislative branch could do at the moment to change the situation.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll have another vote to codify Roe into law,&rdquo; according to a senior House staffer, &ldquo;but that&rsquo;s just meaningless because of the Senate.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173091</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The FDA Is Moving Forward with a Menthol Cigarette Ban. Here’s What the Science Says</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173070/menthol-cigarette-ban-studies/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jamie Ducharme]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 18:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Addiction]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173070</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[They're already in place in Canada and the U.K.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173070"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173070/menthol-cigarette-ban-studies/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is moving forward with <a href="https://time.com/6007509/fda-menthol-cigarette-ban/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener">plans to ban menthol cigarettes</a> and all flavored cigars&mdash;policies that agency officials say could help prevent some of the roughly 500,000 U.S. deaths linked to tobacco each year.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The actions we are proposing can help significantly reduce youth initiation and increase the chances that current smokers quit,&rdquo; FDA Commissioner Dr. Robert Califf <a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-proposes-rules-prohibiting-menthol-cigarettes-and-flavored-cigars-prevent-youth-initiation"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">said in a statement</a>. &ldquo;It is clear that these efforts will help save lives.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But whether the proposed menthol ban will work as intended is a matter of active debate.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><a href="https://ash.org/mentholban-support/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Many influential public-health groups support the policy</a>. Menthol adds a minty flavor and cooling feeling to cigarettes, masking their harshness. As a result, menthol cigarettes are thought to be both more appealing to new smokers and harder for current smokers to quit, which justifies their prohibition, according to many public health experts. (<a href="https://academic.oup.com/jnci/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/jnci/djac070/6571153?redirectedFrom=fulltext"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">A new study</a>, however, calls into question whether menthols are actually harder to quit than regular cigarettes.)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/disparities/african-americans/index.htm"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Black Americans are disproportionately likely to smoke menthols</a>, in large part due to decades of targeted marketing from tobacco companies. Supporters of a menthol ban, <a href="https://naacp.org/articles/naacp-statement-fda-plan-ban-sale-menthol-and-e-cigarettes"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">including the NAACP</a>, argue that the move would improve the health of Black Americans, while critics argue it is a racial justice issue and could result in discriminatory policing by criminalizing a product disproportionately used by people of color. In <a href="https://www.aclu.org/letter/coalition-letter-concern-hhs-menthol-cigarette-ban"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a joint letter</a> sent to the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services secretary last year, the ACLU and other signatories wrote that a menthol ban would &ldquo;prioritize criminalization over public health and harm reduction&rdquo; and could create an illicit market for menthol products. (The FDA has said it would enforce penalties against retailers and manufacturers that violate the ban, not individuals.)</p>
<p>Others who don&rsquo;t support the ban argue that it will simply push menthol smokers to use unflavored tobacco products.</p>
<p>After San Francisco in 2018 banned all flavored tobacco products, including menthols and e-cigarettes, fewer young adults used vaping products but more smoked cigarettes, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7186365/#b0300"  target="_blank">one small 2020 study found</a>. While other societal factors may explain that shift&mdash;including <a href="https://time.com/5753947/vaping-lung-disease-outbreak-peak/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener">an outbreak of vaping-related lung disease</a> beginning months after San Francisco&rsquo;s policy went into full effect&mdash;the authors concluded that flavor bans could lead to more traditional cigarette smoking.</p>
<p>Still, a number of recent real-world studies suggest that menthol bans do have positive effects on public health.</p>
<p>In 2020, menthol cigarettes were banned in the U.K. <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.10029?utm_source=For_The_Media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_term=050322"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">A paper</a> published in <em>JAMA Network Open </em>on May 3 examined how the regulation affected teenage menthol smoking, using national surveys conducted before and after it took effect. Before the policy went into place, roughly 12% of teenage smokers in the U.K. said they used menthol-flavored products. After it took effect, that number dropped to 3%&mdash;a clear sign that the ban led to a drop in youth menthol use, the authors write. (The 3% who said they continued to smoke menthols may have purchased them illegally or used products like sprays and filter tips that add a minty flavor.)</p>
<p>That finding, though intuitive, could strengthen support for menthol bans, since public-health authorities including the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/data_statistics/evidence/pdfs/Scientific-Evidence-Brief-Flavored-Tobacco-Products-Including-Menthol-508.pdf"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">argue that use of flavored tobacco products can lure young people</a> into a lifetime of addiction. However, the <em>JAMA Network Open</em> study didn&rsquo;t look into whether former teen menthol users quit smoking altogether or simply switched to another type of tobacco product.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The ban in England seems to have worked in reducing [teenage] menthol smoking, so by extension we would hope it would work in the U.S., although there are obviously big market differences,&rdquo; says co-author Katherine East, an academic fellow at King&rsquo;s College London&rsquo;s Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology, and Neuroscience. Cigarette smoking is rare among U.S. teenagers, with only about 2% of high school students using them regularly, according to the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/71/ss/ss7105a1.htm?s_cid=ss7105a1_w"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">latest federal data</a>. But among that small group, menthols are common: about 38% of teenage smokers in the U.S. use them, compared to about 12% in the U.K. before the ban.</p>
<p>Geoffrey Fong, chief principal investigator of the International Tobacco Control Policy Evaluation Project, has <a href="https://tobaccocontrol.bmj.com/content/early/2021/03/31/tobaccocontrol-2020-056259"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">studied menthol bans in Canada</a>, where provinces began outlawing menthol cigarettes in 2015 and a national ban followed in 2017. In <a href="https://tobaccocontrol.bmj.com/content/early/2022/04/27/tobaccocontrol-2021-057227"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a paper published in April</a>, Fong and his colleagues found that Canada&rsquo;s regulations did, indeed, prompt many menthol users to quit smoking altogether.</p>
<p>By comparing national tobacco-use surveys from pre- and post-ban, they found that 22% of Canadian adults who used menthols went on to quit, compared to about 15% of non-menthol smokers. Of course, that means almost 80% of menthol users <em>hadn&rsquo;t </em>quit, and had instead either switched to another tobacco product or found a way to keep smoking menthols, such as by purchasing them through a First Nations reservation exempt from the ban. (<a href="https://time.com/5778534/juul-native-american-tribes/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reservations in the U.S. are also exempt</a> from many federal tobacco regulations.) But Fong calls the seven-percentage-point difference in quit rates between menthol and non-menthol smokers &ldquo;huge,&rdquo; especially considering how difficult it is to kick a nicotine addiction of any kind.</p>
<p>Relatively few Canadians smoked menthols even before the ban. But Fong and his co-authors wanted to know how similar policies might affect population health in the U.S., where more people use these products. Using their Canadian findings, they estimated that more than 1.3 million U.S. smokers would quit in the wake of a menthol ban, including more than 380,000 Black smokers.</p>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s extremely strong public-health benefits from this,&rdquo; Fong says. &ldquo;From our research, we can expect significant positive effects, and greater proportional benefits for the public health of the Black community.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Another research review, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7346606/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" target="_blank">published in 2020</a>, found that up to 30% of U.S. menthol smokers would consider switching to e-cigarettes if menthols were banned. While <a href="https://time.com/5680988/juul-vaping-health-crisis/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener">e-cigarettes aren&rsquo;t harmless</a>, experts widely consider them to be less dangerous than traditional cigarettes&mdash;so even without total nicotine cessation, most experts would consider that a net positive for public health.</p>
<p>Ultimately, though, researchers won&rsquo;t know what effect a menthol ban could have on U.S. smokers until years after one is implemented. Since the rule faces a long bureaucratic road and likely won&rsquo;t take effect until at least 2024, that means solid conclusions are a ways off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173070</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amber Heard Has PTSD From Johnny Depp, Psychologist Testifies</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173134/johnny-depp-accountant-lost-money-trial/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Melissa Locker]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 17:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[celebrities]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[culturepod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173134</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Johnny Depp’s counsel today rested its case in the ongoing defamation against Amber Heard.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173134"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173134/johnny-depp-accountant-lost-money-trial/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Johnny Depp&rsquo;s counsel today rested its case in the <a href="https://time.com/6171006/johnny-depp-amber-heard-trial/" >ongoing defamation suit</a> the actor brought against his ex-wife Amber Heard in March 2019. This is the second lawsuit stemming from the former relationship between Depp and Heard, following a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">trial in the U.K.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2020.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depp&rsquo;s legal team spent the last 13 days attempting to prove to a jury that Depp was defamed by an op-ed Heard published in the Washington </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Post</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2018. In it, Heard discussed the treatment of women in sexual assault cases and referred to herself as a &ldquo;public figure representing domestic abuse.&rdquo;</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Heard did not mention Depp by name in the op-ed, Depp argues that the op-ed not only defamed him, but cost him work. Yesterday, Depp&rsquo;s agent, Jack Whigham, testified that <a href="https://time.com/6172789/johnny-depp-agent-testimony-trial/" >the op-ed was &ldquo;catastrophic&rdquo; for Depp&rsquo;s career.</a> Whigham also claimed that a reported &ldquo;$22.5 million verbal deal&rdquo; that Depp had secured with Disney for a sixth installment in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pirates of the Caribbean </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">franchise was scuttled after Heard&rsquo;s op-ed was published.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Forensic accountant Mike Spindler&rsquo;s testimony</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Tuesday, forensic accountant Mike Spindler testified that he had analyzed Depp&rsquo;s earnings following the 2018 op-ed. &#8220;I concluded that Mr. Depp suffered lost earnings of approximately $40 million,&#8221; Spindler said.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6172174/johnny-depp-tiktok-defenders/" ><em>Why You&#8217;re Seeing So Many Johnny Depp Defenders on TikTok</em></a></p>
<h2><strong>Forensic psychologist Dawn Hughes&rsquo;s testimony</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8203;&#8203;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first witness to take the stand in Heard&rsquo;s defense was Dawn Hughes, a clinical and forensic psychologist who specializes in abusive relationships. Hughes, whose professional testimony helped convict</span> <a href="https://time.com/5568135/nxivm-allison-mack-raniere/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">NXIVM leader Keith Raniere</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of charges including sex trafficking and forced labor conspiracy, testified that the actress suffers from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) stemming from her relationship with Depp</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="https://people.com/movies/amber-heard-has-ptsd-from-johnny-depp-abuse-forensic-psychologist-says/"  target="_blank"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">People</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> reported</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Hughes made that assessment after talking with Heard multiple times, reading her case files, and interviewing some of Heard&rsquo;s physicians, as well as her mother.<br />
</span></p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="xS0AP92v" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This testimony comes one week after Dr. Shannon Curry, the forensic psychologist hired by Depp&rsquo;s team, </span><a href="https://time.com/6170866/johnny-depp-amber-heard-trial-borderline-personality-disorder/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">testified that Heard</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> showed no signs of PTSD.</span></p>
<h2><strong>What happens next</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the last two weeks, Depp&rsquo;s legal team called more than two dozen witnesses, including Depp himself. Many witnesses, including Depp&rsquo;s bodyguard, attested to witnessing volatile behavior from both Heard and Depp.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, as Depp&rsquo;s case wrapped, Heard&rsquo;s legal team moved to dismiss the entire case, arguing that Depp&rsquo;s team did not prove their case. It was an expected legal maneuver that could help them on appeal, if Heard loses her case in the lower court.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presiding judge Penny Azcarate partially denied the motion based on two arguments, </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/01/entertainment/johnny-depp-amber-heard-defamation-trial-week-3/index.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">per CNN</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, saying that Depp&rsquo;s team had shown sufficient evidence of defamation to allow the case to continue. As </span><a href="https://deadline.com/2022/05/judge-rejects-amber-heards-motion-to-toss-out-johnny-depps-defamation-case-1235015325/"  target="_blank"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deadline </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">noted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Azcarate said that &ldquo;if there is a scintilla of evidence that a reasonable juror could weigh, then the matter survives a motion to strike.&rdquo; However, the judge left the door open to one other argument for dismissal, if Heard&rsquo;s team presents sufficient evidence while making its case.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heard&rsquo;s case is expected to kick off with psychologist Dawn Hughes, an expert in abusive relationships, as her first witness. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The trial is set to last six weeks.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173134</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>