<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
    <description>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</description>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rawstory.com/feeds/world.rss" rel="self">
    </atom:link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:08:25 -0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNDk4MDQwMC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTcwODk2ODc0NH0.CAuDKCrYnLogkIrRCoHwZj7vOQ_5oq7DyFBijbdG0dE/image.jpg?width=210</url>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
      <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Canada leaders affirm right to choose after leak of draft U.S. ruling overturning abortion rights</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/canada-leaders-affirm-right-to-choose-after-leak-of-draft-u-s-ruling-overturning-abortion-rights/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29756006&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="0deb6803434bbff265a7209e2129aa47" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="58d7f" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29756010&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Anna Mehler Paperny</p>
<p>TORONTO (Reuters) - Canada's Prime Minister and Deputy Prime Minister affirmed on Tuesday their support of women's right to choose after a leaked draft ruling suggests the United States Supreme Court is prepared to strike down a landmark decision legalizing abortion.</p>
<p>The Bloc Quebecois, a federal political party, also moved a motion in Canada's Parliament Tuesday to recognize a woman's "free choice in the matter of abortion."</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland said she was "both shocked and deeply troubled" by the leaked ruling and said her government has a "clear and determined commitment" to protect a woman's right to choose.</p>
<p>"We'll never back down from protecting and promoting women's rights in Canada and around the world," Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said in a tweet.</p>
<p>Canada's Supreme Court decriminalized abortion in a historic 1988 ruling. Ostensibly, since then, abortion has been a medical procedure like any other. But barriers to access persist, especially for people living outside urban areas.</p>
<p>Canada's top court is unlikely to re-criminalize abortion any time soon but if the U.S. Supreme Court overturns Roe v. Wade that could embolden anti-abortion movements and galvanize abortion activists, Canadian observers and advocates both for and against abortion told Reuters.</p>
<p>The U.S. ruling, which is not due until June, will "definitely give juice to the anti-abortion forces," said Judy Rebick, who has been fighting for abortion access in Canada since doctor Henry Morgentaler defied the ban in the 1980s.</p>
<p>But Rebick said abortion opponents face more of an uphill battle in Canada, where activists built community support decades ago.</p>
<p>"You have a huge pro-choice majority which has mobilized time and time again."</p>
<p>Jack Fonseca, director of political operations for the anti-abortion Campaign Life Coalition, predicted a "pro-life blossoming" if the U.S. Supreme Court overturns Roe v. Wade, with people looking to make changes south of the border a reality in Canada.</p>
<p>While Canadian abortion opponents wait for an anti-abortion political sea change, Fonseca said, his group may push for interim measures such as a de-listing of abortion from health services provinces cover.</p>
<p>Canada is unlikely to see a similar rollback of abortion access on a national level, said political scientist Emmett Macfarlane, as the top court is less polarized and partisan than the U.S. Supreme Court.</p>
<p>"What I'll be watching for is, who does this mobilize? Does this mobilize the anti-choice movement in Canada, and are the pro-choice majority complacent? Or does it raise the hackles of the pro-choice majority?"</p>
<p>Carolyn Egan's phone was ringing Tuesday morning with "outraged" people "wanting to do something," said the longtime abortion activist and organizer with Ontario Coalition for Abortion Clinics.</p>
<p>"It's really raising a clarion call here."</p>
<p>(Reporting by Anna Mehler Paperny; Editing by Aurora Ellis)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/canada-leaders-affirm-right-to-choose-after-leak-of-draft-u-s-ruling-overturning-abortion-rights/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29756006&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dominican diplomat is kidnapped in Haiti as violence between rival gangs intensifies</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/dominican-diplomat-is-kidnapped-in-haiti-as-violence-between-rival-gangs-intensifies/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/cars-parked-beside-brown-concrete-building-during-daytime.jpg?id=29754745&width=2000&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>A diplomat assigned to the Dominican Republic’s Port-au-Prince embassy is Haiti’s latest kidnapping victim, a senior Haitian government official has confirmed. Carlos Guillén Tatis was traveling through a gang stronghold and site of ongoing violence by warring armed gangs on Friday when he was reportedly abducted while on his way to the Haitian-Dominican border. Guillén Tatis works as an agricultural adviser in the Dominican embassy and is also reportedly a U.S. citizen. As of late Monday, his whereabouts remained unknown, said the source, confirming that the Haitian government was notified im...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/dominican-diplomat-is-kidnapped-in-haiti-as-violence-between-rival-gangs-intensifies/</guid>
      <category>Lifeandsociety</category>
      <category>Socialissues</category>
      <category>Violence</category>
      <category>Internationaldiplomacy</category>
      <category>Foreignpolicy</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <category>Pub_us</category>
      <dc:creator>Miami Herald</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/cars-parked-beside-brown-concrete-building-during-daytime.jpg?id=29754745&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin alerted wealthy businessmen on day of invasion so they could move their money</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/vladimir-putin-oligarchs/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimyr-putin.jpg?id=29754219&width=2000&coordinates=57%2C0%2C105%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>According to a report from the Washington Post, on the February day that <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/" target="_blank">Russian President Vladimir Putin ordered his army into Ukraine</a>, he summoned some of <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/512-foot-mega-yacht-owned-by-russian-oligarch-alisher-usmanov-seized-by-german-authorities-forbes/" target="_blank">Russia's wealthiest tycoons</a> together to alert not only them but also to warn them <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2022/offshore-putin-russia-oligarchs-pandora/?itid=hp-top-table-main" target="_blank">about what they would face.</a></p><p>The report notes that approximately 36 businessmen involved in the oil gas, banking and chemical industries -- 14 of them identified as billionaires -- heard Putin tell them invading their neighbor was a "necessary measure" before suggesting they should expect economic sanctions to follow.</p><p>According to the Post, he told them: "We all understand the world we live in.”</p><p>The report adds that many of those attending have had a long history of hiding and offshoring their riches, with the Post comparing their names to businessmen named in the leaked Pandora Papers and Paradise Papers.</p><p><strong><em>RELATED: </em></strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-invasion-of-ukraine-2657255351/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Pentagon press secretary claims Russia is 'struggling' with their Ukraine invasion"><strong><em>Pentagon press secretary claims Russia is 'struggling' with their Ukraine invasion</em></strong></a></p><p>"Of the 37 attendees, more than half are linked directly or through a close relative to offshore companies that handled transactions worth hundreds of millions of dollars, making financial investments, issuing loans and forming family trusts," the Post is reporting, adding, "At least 21 of the participants in the Kremlin meeting or their close family members had holdings in the British Virgin Islands, Cyprus or other island jurisdictions known for financial secrecy and tax advantages."</p><p>Noting that Putin has previously objected to “offshorization” by linking it to "the use of offshore companies to tax avoidance and money laundering," the report claims he saw good reason for it and likely also took advantage according to some financial experts.</p><p>With the Post's Peter Whoriskey, writing, "The prevalence of offshore holdings among those invited by Putin reflects the extent to which businessmen at the pinnacle of the Russian economy have transferred wealth out of the country and come to rely on secret arrangements that make transactions difficult to track," former CIA analyst Julia Friedlander, explained, "Putin allows his close circle to tap the financial resources of state companies and the state itself. The money often ends up offshore.”</p><p>Whoriskey added, "Several of those at the Feb. 24 meeting benefited from the privatization of government assets that began with the fall of the Soviet Union, a tumultuous transfer of wealth that created a gaggle of billionaires."</p><p>You can <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2022/offshore-putin-russia-oligarchs-pandora/?itid=hp-top-table-main" target="_blank">read more details here</a>.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/vladimir-putin-oligarchs/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Tom Boggioni</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimyr-putin.jpg?id=29754219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU to unveil plan to replace two-thirds of Russian gas this year</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-to-unveil-plan-to-replace-two-thirds-of-russian-gas-this-year/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29754075&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>AMSTERDAM (Reuters) - The European Commission will present a plan later this month for how the European Union can replace two thirds of its Russian gas use by the end of 2022, the bloc's energy policy chief Kadri Simson said on Tuesday. Speaking in European Parliament, Simson said the EU had reached out to all major gas suppliers to help replace Russian gas with alternatives, and its plan would also replace gas use with renewable energy or through energy savings, where possible. (Reporting by Charlotte Van Campenhout, Kate Abnett)</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-to-unveil-plan-to-replace-two-thirds-of-russian-gas-this-year/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29754075&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online media fueling divisions, global tensions: report</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/online-media-fuelling-divisions-global-tensions-report/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29754149&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ec1564e143c4f33e3a87e6c52f5ef18d" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="119f6" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29754152&width=980"/><figcaption>World map showing the different states of press freedom by countries and territories, compiled by Reporters Without Borders</figcaption></figure></div><p>London (AFP) - Unregulated online content has spread disinformation and propaganda that have amplified political divisions, fanned international tensions and even contributed to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, a media watchdog said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reporters Without Borders, widely known by its French acronym RSF, presented its findings in the 2022 edition of its annual World Press Freedom Index.</p>
<p>Democratic societies, it said, are increasingly fractured by social media spreading disinformation and media pursuing a "Fox News model", referring to the controversial US right-wing television network.</p>
<p>Autocratic regimes meanwhile tightly control information within their societies, using their leveraged position to wage "propaganda wars" against democracies and fuel divisions within them.</p>
<p>Such polarisation is becoming more "extreme," worldwide, RSF's director of operations and campaigns Rebecca Vincent told a news conference in London.</p>
<p>She pointed to the deaths of journalists in the Netherlands and Greece as well as the case of Julian Assange, the WikiLeaks founder who risks extradition and trial in the US for the publication of secret files.</p>
<p>The report showed how Russia, where state-run media overwhelmingly dominates and independent outlets are largely stifled, waged a propaganda war before its invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Evgeniya Dillendorf, a correspondent for the independent Novaya Gazeta newspaper, said the main reason for lack of media diversity in Russia "is not pressure but lack of independent business which would finance it, and the lack of independent judicial system that would defend it".</p>
<p>Novaya Gazeta has suspended publication for the duration of Moscow's military intervention to avoid being shut down.</p>
<p>"The creation of media weaponry in authoritarian countries eliminates their citizens' right to information but is also linked to the rise in international tension, which can lead to the worst kind of wars," RSF Secretary-General Christophe Deloire said.</p>
<p>The "Fox News-isation" of Western media also posed a "fatal danger for democracies because it undermines the basis of civil harmony and tolerant public debate", he added.</p>
<p>Deloire urged countries to adopt legal frameworks to protect democratic online information spaces.</p>
<h1>Record 'very bad'</h1>
<p>The situation is "very bad" in a record 28 countries, according to this year's ranking of 180 countries and regions.</p>
<p>The lowest ranked were North Korea (180th), Eritrea (179th) and Iran (178th), with Myanmar (176th) and China (175th) close behind.</p>
<p>Russia (155th) and its ally Belarus (153rd) were also among the most repressive.</p>
<p>Based on the previous calendar year, this does not reflect Russia's massive media crackdown since President Vladimir Putin sent troops into Ukraine.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's position plummeted dozens of places to 148th, reflecting Beijing's efforts to use "its legislative arsenal to confine its population and cut it off from the rest of the world", RSF said.</p>
<p>"It is the biggest downfall of the year, but it is fully deserved due to the consistent attacks on freedom of the press and the slow disappearance of the rule of law in Hong Kong," Cedric Alviani, head of RSF's Taiwan-based East Asia bureau, told AFP.</p>
<p>Just eight countries were ranked as "good", down from 12 last year.</p>
<p>Nordic countries Norway, Denmark and Sweden again topped the index, while the Netherlands fell from sixth to 28th after top crime reporter, Peter R. de Vries, was gunned down on an Amsterdam street last July.</p>
<p>The Free Press Unlimited group called the fall in the Netherlands "alarming news" and unprecedented, as the country had always been in the top 10 since 2002.</p>
<p>RSF commended Moldova (40th) and Bulgaria (91st) this year due to government changes and "the hope it has brought for improvement in the situation for journalists". </p>
<p>But it noted "oligarchs still own or control the media" in both.</p>
<p>Media polarisation was "feeding and reinforcing internal social divisions in democratic societies" such as the United States (42nd), it said.</p>
<p>That trend was even starker in "illiberal democracies" such as Poland (66th), a European Union country where RSF noted suppression of independent media.</p>
<p>The NGO, launched in 1985 and which has published the yearly index since 2002, has become a thorn in the side of autocratic and despotic regimes around the world.</p>
<p>This year's listing used five new indicators to define press freedom -- political context, legal framework, economic context, sociocultural context, and security -- to reflect its "complexity".</p>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/online-media-fuelling-divisions-global-tensions-report/</guid>
      <category>Media</category>
      <category>Rights</category>
      <category>Disinformation</category>
      <category>Internet</category>
      <category>Ngo</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>AFP</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29754149&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon press secretary claims Russia is 'struggling' with their Ukraine invasion</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-invasion-of-ukraine-2657255351/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/putin-defends-hosting-euro-games-in-st-petersburg-amid-covid-19-spike.jpg?id=26846163&width=2000&coordinates=89%2C0%2C89%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>On CNN Tuesday, Pentagon Press Secretary John Kirby said that Russia's attempted reset its war in Ukraine is not going well.</p><p>"How do you see where Russian forces are now on their objective, on being able to annex parts of eastern Ukraine?" asked anchor Brianna Keilar.</p><p>"They're struggling," said Kirby. "The progress in the east from the Russians has been uneven. It has been impeded, it has been slow. And they have not been able to achieve a whole lot of success there in the east. They're still bombing Mariupol. For all the claims there is no resistance in Mariupol, there is."</p><p>Kirby then explained that even Russian gains are not guaranteed to hold.</p><p><strong><u><em>RELATED: </em></u></strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/putin-puts-west-on-notice-moscow-can-terminate-exports-and-deals/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Putin puts West on notice: Moscow can terminate exports and deals"><strong><u><em>Putin puts West on notice: Moscow can terminate exports and deals</em></u></strong></a></p><p>"They have not achieved really any of the strategic objectives that Mr. Putin set out for, and the Ukrainians are fighting back stiffly, bravely, nimbly, skillfully in the Donbas region," Kirby concluded. "There is a lot of back and forth. The Russians might take a town or two, Ukrainians will take it back. We're still continuing to see that, even over the last 24 hours."</p><p>Initially, Russian forces seemed to be attempting to take the capital city of Kyiv, in the north central area of Ukraine, only to face serious obstacles.</p><p>Russia has subsequently <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/02/russia-ukraine-war-news-putin-live-updates/" target="_blank">pulled back</a> to focus on the eastern areas, where the Kremlin-backed rebels in Donetsk and Luhansk initially declared so called "independent republics" that Russia used as the justification to launch a "security" mission to protect.</p><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-invasion-of-ukraine-2657255351/" target="_blank"><em>Watch below or at this link</em></a><em>:</em></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="207e158cdbe4d04f7d176dda855e819b" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fmrY9TPV_Zg?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">John Kirby says Russia is "struggling" to get back on track in Ukraine</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fmrY9TPV_Zg" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-invasion-of-ukraine-2657255351/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/putin-defends-hosting-euro-games-in-st-petersburg-amid-covid-19-spike.jpg?id=26846163&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Marine Le Pen managed to gain ground with youth voters – and why her success isn’t being replicated by the US right</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/how-marine-le-pen-managed-to-gain-ground-with-youth-voters-and-why-her-success-isnt-being-replicated-by-the-us-right/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/marine-le-pen.jpg?id=29696345&width=2000&coordinates=96%2C0%2C96%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><div>Far-right candidate Marine Le Pen may have missed out on the French presidency, falling <a href="https://www.resultats-elections.interieur.gouv.fr/presidentielle-2022/FE.html">17 pecentage points short</a> of incumbent Emmanuel Macron <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/04/24/world/french-election-runoff-results">in a runoff</a> held April 24, 2022. But to characterize her campaign as a total loss would be missing an essential point: with nearly 41.2% of the vote, a far-right contender came closer to securing the French presidency than at any point in the past.</div><p>She outperformed the previous two times that her party got through to the final round. In 2017, Le Pen received only <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2017/may/07/french-presidential-election-results-latest">33.9% of the vote</a>. Her father and predecessor as head of the Front National – now rebranded as Rassemblement National, or National Rally – won <a href="http://www.electionresources.org/fr/president.php?election=2002">just 17.8% of the vote</a> in the 2002 runoff.</p><p>Marine Le Pen is enjoying an undeniable, upward trend in popularity.</p><h2>Chasing the youth vote</h2><p>The growth in support for France’s far right isn’t taking place in a vacuum. A wave of populist sentiment has swept across <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-62855-4">much of Europe</a> <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/campaign/532781-the-future-of-populism-in-america/">and North America</a> in the last few years. Moreover, the French and American far right have demonstrated a <a href="https://www.leparisien.fr/politique/candace-owens-invitee-de-marion-marechal-macron-n-est-pas-un-leader-fort-21-09-2019-8156766.php">mutual admiration</a> and <a href="https://www.france24.com/fr/france/20220215-%C3%A9ric-zemmour-se-f%C3%A9licite-d-un-long-et-chaleureux-entretien-t%C3%A9l%C3%A9phonique-avec-donald-trump">exchange of strategies</a>. The French right’s <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/04/14/the-french-right-is-obsessed-with-fighting-wokeness/">fight against “wokisme”</a> echoes American conservative discourse around critical race theory. Similarly, the American right <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/tucker-carlson-pushes-racist-great-replacement-theory-yet-again-adl-renews-call-for-fox-to-fire-him">has drawn inspiration</a> from French writer Renaud Camus’ <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/fr/2019/09/20/world/europe/renaud-camus-grand-replacement.html">white nationalist</a> idea of a “<a href="https://www.adl.org/education/references/hate-symbols/you-will-not-replace-us">grand remplacement</a>,” which holds that white populations and culture are being replaced by non-white, non-Christian people.</p><p>But the results of the recent election show something beyond a general growth in support for the far right – something that is happening on both sides of the Atlantic. The French right is succeeding in one key demographic that the <a href="https://morningconsult.com/2021/06/28/global-right-wing-authoritarian-test/">American right has seemingly failed to capture</a>: youth voters.</p><p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="frY0m" rel="border: none" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/frY0m/1/" style="border: none" width="100%"></iframe></p><p><a href="https://www.ipsos.com/fr-fr/presidentielle-2022/second-tour-profil-des-abstentionnistes-et-sociologie-des-electorats">Analysis of the presidential runoff</a> shows that 49% of 25-34 year olds who voted opted for Le Pen – compared to just over 41% of the general population, and 29% of voters over 70.</p><p>This wasn’t always the case. Like in the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2018/03/01/the-generation-gap-in-american-politics/">United States</a>, <a href="https://theconversation.com/le-vote-jeune-existe-t-il-179871">youth voters in France</a> have historically supported progressive and left-leaning platforms. The Front National – which was established as an <a href="https://www.cairn-int.info/article-E_POUV_157_0005--the-origins-of-the-national-front.htm">explicitly neo-fascist, anti-immigrant party</a>, and whose founder Jean-Marie Le Pen has been <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20210901-french-far-right-party-founder-jean-marie-le-pen-faces-new-hate-trial">repeatedly convicted</a> <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20121105195546/http://www.highbeam.com/doc/1P1-93051559.html">by French courts</a> for inciting racial hatred – was especially far from youth politics.</p><p>Indeed, until recently, the French far right’s relation to the under-30 crowd could be summarized in the words of punk rock group Bérurier Noir, which <a href="https://france3-regions.francetvinfo.fr/bretagne/il-y-a-38-ans-berurier-noir-chantait-la-jeunesse-emmerde-le-front-national-entretien-avec-loran-beru-2531640.html">famously sang</a> during a 1989 concert that “la jeunesse emmerde le Front National” – “young people piss off the Front National.” </p><p>This lyric became a rallying cry during the 2002 elections, as youth voters turned out in overwhelming numbers – both to the ballot box and <a href="https://www.20minutes.fr/diaporama/diaporama-15314-images-20-ans-jeunesse-manifestait-contre-extreme-droite-france">to the streets in protest</a> – when the far right advanced to the runoffs for the first time in the Front National’s history. </p><h2>Rebranding the right</h2><p>The tide began to change when <a href="https://www.lefigaro.fr/politique/2011/01/14/01002-20110114ARTFIG00673-marine-le-pen-elue-presidente-du-front-national.php">Marine Le Pen took control</a> of the Front National from her father in 2011. Over the last decade, she has undertaken a conscious process of “<a href="https://www.franceculture.fr/emissions/le-reportage-de-la-redaction/du-fn-au-rn-dix-ans-de-dediabolisation">de-demonizing</a>” the party in an effort to distance itself from its <a href="https://www.liberation.fr/actualites/2017/03/15/le-front-national-face-a-ses-vieux-demons-antisemites_1555982/">antisemitic past</a>. Instead, Le Pen wants to present herself as a <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/europe/20210703-france-s-far-right-marine-le-pen-under-fire-for-going-mainstream">mainstream candidate</a>.</p><p>While, as <a href="https://www.20minutes.fr/elections/presidentielle/2060491-20170502-presidentielle-front-national-vraiment-change">many point out</a>, many of the policies of Rassemblement National <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/election-presidentielle-2022/article/2022/03/31/presidentielle-2022-derriere-la-normalisation-de-marine-le-pen-un-projet-qui-reste-d-extreme-droite_6119942_6059010.html">aren’t substantively different</a> from their far-right roots, the party has tried to appeal to young voters by reframing its stances on issues like <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/2022-presidential-election/article/2022/04/17/le-pen-challenges-macron-s-punitive-ecology-with-her-national-ecology_5980790_16.html">the environment</a> and <a href="https://www.lexpress.fr/actualite/politique/presidentielle-marine-le-pen-et-le-feminisme-un-engagement-de-facade_2169345.html">feminism</a>. Le Pen retreated from her <a href="https://www.linternaute.com/actualite/politique/2626647-marine-le-pen-climatosceptique-l-accusation-de-macron-est-elle-fondee/">previous climate skepticism</a> and embraced a program of so-called <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/politique/article/2022/04/15/marine-le-pen-oppose-son-ecologie-nationale-a-l-ecologie-punitive-d-emmanuel-macron_6122325_823448.html">nationalist ecology</a>, which advocates for energy independence and French-made products. She also positioned herself as a <a href="http://www.slate.fr/story/225591/marine-le-pen-defense-animaux-chats-rassemblement-national-electorat-populaire">pro-animal welfare candidate</a> by calling for stricter regulations on the meatpacking industry, and claimed to “<a href="https://www.nouvelobs.com/tribunes/20220422.OBS57476/marine-le-pen-feministe-defendre-les-femmes-parce-qu-on-est-une-femme-est-un-leurre.html#">defend women</a>” by campaigning against street harassment.</p><p>Critics note that her animal welfare proposals amounted to a <a href="https://www.rtl.fr/actu/politique/presidentielle-2022-cette-mesure-de-le-pen-qui-signifierait-l-interdiction-du-halal-et-du-casher-7900137659">ban on halal and kosher meat</a> and that her rhetoric on street harassment <a href="https://www.leparisien.fr/politique/marine-le-pen-condamne-le-harcelement-de-rue-produit-de-l-immigration-selon-elle-15-01-2018-7502490.php">placed the blame on immigrant men</a> who, according to her campaign videos, either did not know or did not respect “<a href="https://www.franceinter.fr/societe/violences-faites-aux-femmes-que-proposent-les-candidats-a-l-election-presentielle">French cultural codes</a>.”</p><h2>Appealing to youth</h2><p>Beyond reframing, though, the Rassemblement National also proposed a number of concrete fiscal policies that target youth voters. In her <a href="https://www.lejdd.fr/Politique/presidentielle-voici-les-propositions-de-marine-le-pen-et-demmanuel-macron-pour-la-jeunesse-4105995">2022 presidential platform</a>, Le Pen promised to eliminate taxes for those under 30, offer financial assistance to student workers and increase housing for students.</p><p>Le Pen and the Rassemblement National haven’t convinced everyone. It remains a primarily <a href="https://www.lesechos.fr/politique-societe/politique/europe-derriere-lapparent-recentrage-de-marine-le-pen-un-programme-radical-menant-au-frexit-1400170">anti-immigrant, anti-European nationalist party</a> that often faces accusations of <a href="https://www.franceinter.fr/politique/laissez-les-musulmans-tranquilles-deplacement-chahute-pour-marine-le-pen-dans-le-vaucluse">Islamophobia</a>, <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/election-presidentielle-2022/article/2022/04/08/marine-le-pen-se-defend-de-tout-racisme-dans-son-programme-et-denonce-les-propos-outranciers-d-emmanuel-macron_6121222_6059010.html">racism</a> and <a href="https://www.mediapart.fr/journal/france/190422/derriere-la-dediabolisation-de-marine-le-pen-le-veritable-danger-du-rn-pour-les-lgbti">homophobia</a>. </p><p>When Le Pen advanced to the runoffs after the first round of voting on April 10 – <a href="https://www.lejdd.fr/Politique/lecart-entre-jean-luc-melenchon-et-marine-le-pen-se-resserre-fortement-4104913">barely edging out</a> far-left candidate Jean-Luc Mélenchon – huge numbers of students turned out in protest across France, declaring that they would vote “<a href="https://www.lexpress.fr/actualite/societe/ni-le-pen-ni-macron-le-slogan-qui-divise-les-etudiants_2172021.html">neither Macron, nor Le Pen</a>.” Many young voters in 2022 abstained from voting altogether – an estimated <a href="https://www.lesechos.fr/elections/presidentielle/presidentielle-le-taux-dabstention-chez-les-jeunes-restera-eleve-au-second-tour-1400817">30%</a> of those under 35 years old in the first round, climbing to a historic <a href="https://www.publicsenat.fr/article/politique/abstention-des-jeunes-les-politiques-ne-parlent-pas-des-sujets-qui-les-preoccupent">40% in the runoff</a>. </p><h2>Declining support of GOP</h2><p>In both <a href="https://www.lepoint.fr/presidentielle/pourquoi-les-jeunes-ne-votent-plus-11-04-2022-2471686_3121.php">France</a> and the <a href="https://theconversation.com/why-so-few-young-americans-vote-132649">U.S.</a>, younger generations express feelings of disinterest in and neglect by mainstream political institutions.</p><p>Yet young people in the U.S. continue to show <a href="https://morningconsult.com/2021/06/28/global-right-wing-authoritarian-test/">comparatively low levels of support</a> for right-wing authoritarianism. In <a href="https://ropercenter.cornell.edu/how-groups-voted-2016">2016</a> and <a href="https://ropercenter.cornell.edu/how-groups-voted-2020">2020</a>, voters age 18-29 were 10 points lower in their support for Donald Trump compared to the overall population.</p><p>So why aren’t we seeing the French trend in the U.S.? </p><p>It’s important to note that the U.S. Republican Party and the French Rassemblement National are not completely analogous, due at least in part to the fact that the U.S. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2016/04/27/why-are-there-only-two-parties-in-american-politics/">is a two-party system</a>. The Republican Party is the only viable option available to right-wing voters. In France, the Rassemblement National is one of several far-right movements, and is wholly separate from the mainstream conservative Les Républicains party. </p><p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="89090" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/89090/1/" style="border: none" width="100%"></iframe></p><p>Still, the GOP and the Rassemblement National are increasingly occupying the same political space. According to the University of Gothenburg’s V-Dem Institute, the Republican Party <a href="https://www.v-dem.net/static/website/img/refs/vparty_briefing.pdf">shifted dramatically</a> towards illiberal rhetoric between 2002 and 2018, putting it in proximity to European far-right parties. Similarly, the GOP and the Rassemblement National received similar scores on Harvard University’s 2019 <a href="https://www.globalpartysurvey.org/">Global Party Survey</a> in terms of opposition to ethnic minority rights and adherence to liberal democratic principles, norms and practices. </p><p>The GOP and the RN have also demonstrated a growing, <a href="https://www.liberation.fr/actualites/2019/09/28/la-convention-de-la-droite-de-marion-marechal-le-pen-vire-a-la-caricature-radicale_1754246/">mutual recognition</a> and <a href="https://www.francetvinfo.fr/monde/usa/presidentielle/donald-trump/une-delegation-du-rassemblement-national-aupres-de-l-equipe-trumpaux-etats-unis_4165547.html">exchange of ideas</a> over the last few years.</p><p>Indeed, over the last few weeks, far-right groups in France have even begun to echo U.S.-style “<a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/04/28/election-conspiracy-theories-macron-victory-le-pen">Stop the Steal</a>” rhetoric in response to Emmanuel Macron’s vote shares.</p><p>Yet is seems unlikely that far-right segments of the Republican Party can replicate the metamorphosis that allowed Rassemblement National to appeal to youth voters.</p><p>Party structures in the U.S. are significantly more decentralized than in France. While Le Pen was able to lead the charge in “softening” her image, it’s not clear who would play that role in an American context for Republicans. Trump remains a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/cracks-begin-show-republicans-split-over-trump-rnc-meeting-1676470">polarizing figure</a> within the party and <a href="https://theconversation.com/whats-at-stake-for-trump-twitter-and-politics-if-the-tweeter-in-chief-returns-from-banishment-182011">seemingly shows no desire</a> to engage in such “de-demonizing.”</p><p> <img alt="An elderly woman wears a 'Keep America Great Again' hat and holds an American flag." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=45&auto=format&w=754&fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=45&auto=format&w=600&h=407&fit=crop&dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=30&auto=format&w=600&h=407&fit=crop&dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=15&auto=format&w=600&h=407&fit=crop&dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=45&auto=format&w=754&h=511&fit=crop&dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=30&auto=format&w=754&h=511&fit=crop&dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/460856/original/file-20220502-22-12c1hd.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&q=15&auto=format&w=754&h=511&fit=crop&dpr=3 2262w"/></p><p>              An age-old problem for the GOP?</p><p> <a class="source" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/trump-supporter-holds-a-flag-and-wears-a-keep-america-great-news-photo/1229340481?adppopup=true">Aimee Dilger/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images</a></p><p>And the GOP also doesn’t seem to have the political desire to “soften” its image in issues that matter most to youth voters. </p><p>A <a href="https://iop.harvard.edu/youth-poll/fall-2021-harvard-youth-poll%20https://iop.harvard.edu/youth-poll/fall-2021-harvard-youth-poll">2021 survey</a> by the Harvard Kennedy School Institute of Politics found that young Americans list addressing climate change, health care, education, social justice and income inequality as their top priorities – several of which are <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/01/05/gop-red-wave-critical-race-theory-526523">difficult to reconcile</a> with the “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/mar/26/republicans-midterms-culture-war-lgbtq-abortion-book-bans">culture war</a>” that parts of the GOP have made a <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/10/1091543359/15-states-dont-say-gay-anti-transgender-bills">core part of their mandates</a>. </p><p>By and large, major Republican officials remain <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/planetpolicy/2021/05/10/republicans-in-congress-are-out-of-step-with-the-american-public-on-climate/">publicly skeptical</a> that climate change exists, and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/feb/04/joe-biden-climate-crisis-republican-backlash">vote against</a> Democratic-led climate proposals as too expensive or unnecessary. </p><p>The Rassemblement National’s youth-oriented fiscal policies – which often involve direct financial assistance for students, in a distinct break from the party’s “<a href="https://www.lesechos.fr/politique-societe/politique/marine-le-pen-en-operation-seduction-aupres-des-jeunes-1311687">Reaganomics” under Jean-Marie Le Pen</a> in the 1980s – run counter to a GOP that opposes solutions to the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/finance/3469647-republicans-take-aim-at-bidens-authority-on-student-loans/">student debt crisis</a>. </p><p>The GOP seems to be <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2021/12/11/republican-party-gains-temporary-young-voter-strategy-524086">keenly aware</a> of its <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/11/27/blame-game-erupts-over-trumps-decline-in-youth-vote-440811">declining support among youth voters</a>. Yet Republican efforts seem more geared toward tactics such as <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2021/10/22/partisan-gerrymandering-targets-college-campuses">diluting the vote of districts with college campuses, particularly historically Black colleges and universities</a>, and <a href="https://civilrights.org/edfund/resource/youth-vote/">voter ID laws</a> that would make it more difficult for young people to vote. In contrast, Le Pen <a href="https://www.sudouest.fr/france/1er-mai-marine-le-pen-cible-la-jeunesse-2339713.php">openly courted youth voters</a> and dedicated a large part of her <a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=3204171586469277">final rally</a> before the April 24 runoff to calling on young people to get out and vote. </p><p>Part of the GOP approach can likely be ascribed to the fact that young voters are becoming <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/new-census-data-shows-the-nation-is-diversifying-even-faster-than-predicted/">increasingly racially diverse</a> and that young adults of color are <a href="https://time.com/5910291/weve-seen-a-youthquake-how-youth-of-color-backed-joe-biden-in-battleground-states/">an especially strong base</a> for Democratic candidates. But GOP support is dropping among <a href="https://circle.tufts.edu/latest-research/election-week-2020%20">white youths</a>, too.</p><p>It took years for Le Pen’s “de-demonization” among youth voters to start paying dividends – and even then, it was insufficient to propel her to electoral victory. The U.S. will, in a few months, undergo its own elections with the 2022 midterms. It’s <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/04/10/democrats-youth-vote-2022-midterms-john-della-volpe-00024264">far from certain</a> that young people in the U.S. will continue to throw their support behind Democratic candidates. But who they cast their ballot for, and whether they turn out to vote at all, will show just how big the gap is between the Rassemblement National and the GOP in appealing to a younger electorate. </p><p>[<em>The Conversation’s Politics + Society editors pick need-to-know stories.</em> <a href="https://memberservices.theconversation.com/newsletters/?nl=politics&source=inline-politics-need-to-know">Sign up for Politics Weekly</a>.]<img alt="The Conversation" height="1" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/181937/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" width="1"/></p><p><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/kimberly-tower-1340437">Kimberly Tower</a>, PhD Candidate in International Relations and Comparative Politics, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/american-university-1187">American University</a></em> and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/camille-gelix-1340891">Camille Gélix</a>, PHD candidate, <em><a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/sciences-po-2196">Sciences Po </a></em></p><p>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-marine-le-pen-managed-to-gain-ground-with-youth-voters-and-why-her-success-isnt-being-replicated-by-the-us-right-181937">original article</a>.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/how-marine-le-pen-managed-to-gain-ground-with-youth-voters-and-why-her-success-isnt-being-replicated-by-the-us-right/</guid>
      <dc:creator>The Conversation</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/marine-le-pen.jpg?id=29696345&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin puts West on notice: Moscow can terminate exports and deals</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-puts-west-on-notice-moscow-can-terminate-exports-and-deals/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753783&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="1effa5f36aa0d3783635ec87066caf41" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="04f5e" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753786&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Guy Faulconbridge</p>
<p>LONDON (Reuters) -Russian President Vladimir Putin put the West on notice on Tuesday that he could terminate exports and deals, the Kremlin's toughest response yet to the sanctions burden imposed by the United States and allies over the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>Putin, Russia's paramount leader since 1999, signed a broad decree on Tuesday which forbade the export of products and raw materials to people and entities on a sanctions list that he instructed the government to draw up within 10 days.</p>
<p>The decree, which came into force with its publication, gives Moscow the power to sow chaos across markets as it could at any moment halt exports or tear up contracts with an entity or individual it has sanctioned.</p>
<p>The Russian government has 10 days to draw up lists of those it will sanction beyond the Western politicians it has already.</p>
<p>Putin explicitly framed the decree as a response to what he cast as the illegal actions of the United States and its allies meant to deprive "the Russian Federation, citizens of the Russian Federation and Russian legal entities of property rights or the restricting their property rights".</p>
<p>The decree sets out "retaliatory special economic measures in connection with the unfriendly actions of some foreign states and international organizations".</p>
<p>Russia's Feb. 24 invasion of Ukraine prompted the United States and its allies to impose the most severe sanctions in modern history on Russia and Moscow's business elite, steps Putin casts as a declaration of economic war.</p>
<p>The West's attempt to economically isolate Russia - one of the world's biggest producers of natural resources - has propelled the global economy into uncharted waters with soaring prices and warnings of food shortages.</p>
<p>'ECONOMIC WAR'</p>
<p>Putin, 69, has repeatedly warned that Moscow will respond in kind, though until Tuesday the Kremlin's toughest economic response had been to cut off gas supplies to Poland and Bulgaria and demand a new payment scheme for European buyers of gas.</p>
<p>Tuesday's decree forbids the export of products and raw materials to people and entities that the Kremlin has sanctioned. It forbids any transactions with such people or entities - even under current contracts.</p>
<p>Putin tasked the government with drawing up the list of foreign individuals and companies to be sanctioned, as well as defining "additional criteria" for a number of transactions that could be subject to restrictions.</p>
<p>"This is a framework decree," said Tatiana Stanovaya, a non-resident scholar at Carnegie Moscow Center and founder of the R.Politik political analysis firm.</p>
<p>"Now all the specific lists should be developed by the government. That's the main thing and we need to wait for."</p>
<p>Since the West imposed sanctions on Russia, the $1.8 trillion economy has been heading for its biggest contraction since the years following the 1991 break-up of the Soviet Union, amid soaring inflation.</p>
<p>A significant transfer of Russian assets has begun as the Russian state gains even more influence over the economy, many major Western investors - such as energy giants BP and Shell - exit, and oligarchs try to restructure their business empires.</p>
<p>(Writing by Guy Faulconbridge; Editing by Kevin Liffey and Mark Heinrich)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-puts-west-on-notice-moscow-can-terminate-exports-and-deals/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753783&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Ukraine's finest hour'; UK's Johnson says Ukraine will beat Russia</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-s-finest-hour-uk-s-johnson-says-ukraine-will-beat-russia/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753705&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Kylie MacLellan and Elizabeth Piper LONDON (Reuters) -British Prime Minister Boris Johnson told Ukraine on Tuesday he believed it would defeat Russia and expose the "gigantic error" of the Kremlin's invasion as he invoked Britain's wartime leader Winston Churchill to underline his support for Kyiv. Becoming the first Western leader to address Ukraine's parliament since the start of Russia's invasion on Feb. 24, Johnson saluted the country's bravery in exploding "the myth of (Russian President Vladimir) Putin's invincibility". "I have one message for you today: Ukraine will win, Ukraine will...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 12:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-s-finest-hour-uk-s-johnson-says-ukraine-will-beat-russia/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753705&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In new salvo, Russia slams Israeli support of Kiev 'neo-Nazi regime'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/in-new-salvo-russia-slams-israeli-support-of-kiev-neo-nazi-regime/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753484&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="c01f331b1937a8eaf81b924f4403e9fb" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c83ac" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753489&width=980"/><figcaption>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov speaks during a press conference in Moscow. -/Russian Foreign Ministry/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Russia doubled down on its war effort on Tuesday - though this time it focused on its war of words with Israel against the backdrop of Russia's invasion of Ukraine - accusing Israel of supporting a "neo-Nazi regime in Kiev."</p>
<p>Russia began an invasion of Ukraine in February, arguing that it had to "de-Nazify" the country, a claim that was already widely refuted given the fact that Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky is Jewish.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov upped the ante, telling an Italian broadcaster that Zelensky's heritage did not rule out anti-Semitic leanings in the country. "That does not mean anything at all. The wise Jewish people say that the most keen anti-Semites are usually Jews," he told Italian TV channel Rete4.</p>
<p>That prompted a diplomatic backlash from Israel, with Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid urging the Russian leadership on Monday to "open a history book."</p>
<p>Russia's Foreign Ministry fired back on Tuesday, calling Lapid's criticism "anti-historical," adding that basing arguments on Zelensky's Jewish heritage "not only did not hold up, but were also duplicitous."</p>
<p>Furthermore, they said that Ukraine is not only tainted by a "crazy Russophobia and a fight against anything Russian," but also anti-Semitism and anti-Romani sentiments, according to a statement.</p>
<p>An Israeli spokesperson said on Tuesday that the country's Foreign Ministry had "stated its position" during a meeting with Russian Ambassador Anatoly Viktorov the day before, but that both sides had agreed "not to elaborate further." Israeli news agency ynet reported that Israeli officials assume there will be no apology.</p>
<p>Israel has close ties to both Russia and Ukraine. Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett spoke to the leaders of both countries multiple times early in the war.</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="0cdff356b9783e33ceda2998d62706d3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="f20a1" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753491&width=980"/><figcaption>A photo released by the Ukraine Presidency on Sunday 1 May 2022 shows Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky arriving to receive Speaker of the United States House of Representatives Nancy Pelosi during her visit to Ukraine. -/Ukraine Presidency/dpa</figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/in-new-salvo-russia-slams-israeli-support-of-kiev-neo-nazi-regime/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Israel</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753484&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia unleashes rockets in Mariupol, EU readies oil sanctions</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-unleashes-rockets-in-mariupol-eu-readies-oil-sanctions/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753126&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="685976e40fbb83ab2674887385fd63c5" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="469e0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753128&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Joseph Campbell and Tom Balmforth</p>
<p>ZAPORIZHZHIA, Ukraine (Reuters) -Russian forces fired rockets at an encircled steel works in Ukraine's southern port city of Mariupol and thick smoke blackened the sky at the plant where officials on Tuesday said 200 civilians were trapped despite evacuations.</p>
<p>Russia's offensive to capture the east and south after failing to take the capital of Kyiv has been met with commitments by Western powers to supply heavier weapons to Ukraine. On Tuesday, the European Commission is expected to finalise a ban on buying Russian oil in an effort to squeeze Moscow's war chest.</p>
<p>The U.S. Congress is considering a $33 billion military aid package, and the United Kingdom this week vowed an additional $375 million in defence assistance.</p>
<p>Reuters images showed volleys of rockets fired from a Russian truck-mounted launcher towards the sprawling Soviet-era steel complex from the outskirts of Russian-occupied Mariupol on Monday.</p>
<p>The attack followed a UN-brokered ceasefire around the complex that allowed several groups of civilians to escape Mariupol's last holdout of Ukrainian fighters in recent days. It was not immediately clear if new fighting was preventing more evacuations.</p>
<p>Mariupol mayor Vadym Boychenko said he hoped a first column of evacuees would reach the Ukrainian-controlled city of Zaporizhzhia on Tuesday, adding that more civilians were trapped in bunkers and tunnels under the complex and some 100,000 remained in the rest of the city.</p>
<p>"You wake up in the morning and you cry. You cry in the evening. I don't know where to go at all," said Mariupol resident Tatyana Bushlanova, sitting by a blackened apartment block and talking over the sound of shells exploding nearby.</p>
<p>Mariupol is a major target for Russia as it seeks to cut Ukraine off from the Black Sea and connect Russian-controlled territory in the south and east.</p>
<p>Russian bombardments since troops invaded Ukraine on Feb. 24 have flattened cities, killed thousands of civilians and forced more than five million to flee the country.</p>
<p>The war launched by Russian President Vladimir Putin has shifted to the eastern provinces of Donetsk and Luhansk, parts of which were already held by Russian-backed separatists.</p>
<p>Russia's troops are trying to encircle a large Ukrainian force there, attacking from three directions with massive bombardment along the front. Russia calls its actions in Ukraine a "special operation" to disarm Ukraine and protect it from fascists.</p>
<p>Ukraine and the West say the fascist allegation is baseless and that the war is an unprovoked act of aggression.</p>
<p>Western allies of Ukraine have stepped up supplies of increasingly heavy weapons. Ukraine's First Lady Olena Zelenska asked the West to maintain its support.</p>
<p>"We ask you not to stop, to accelerate the pace of heavy weapons provision," she told British television, adding that she had not seen President Volodymyr Zelenskiy since the start of the invasion.</p>
<p>Pope Francis said in an interview published on Tuesday that he had asked for a meeting in Moscow with Putin to try to stop the war but had not received a response. French President Emmanuel Macron will speak with Putin on Tuesday, Macron's office said.</p>
<p>EU SET TO SHUN RUSSIAN OIL</p>
<p>In Brussels, the European Commission is expected to finalise a proposed sixth package of EU sanctions against Russia on Tuesday, including a possible embargo on buying Russian oil. In a major shift, Germany said it was prepared to back an immediate oil embargo.</p>
<p>Kyiv says Russia's energy exports to Europe, so far largely exempt from international sanctions, are funding the Kremlin war effort.</p>
<p>"This package should include clear steps to block Russia's revenues from energy resources," Zelenskiy said in his nightly video address.</p>
<p>EU countries have paid more than 47 billion euros ($47.43 billion) to Russia for gas and oil since it invaded Ukraine, according to research organisation the Centre for Research on Energy and Clean Air.</p>
<p>Ambassadors from EU countries will discuss the proposed sanctions when they meet on Wednesday. Putin responded with retaliatory economic sanctions against "unfriendly" foreign states on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The pope told the newspaper that Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban had told him Russia planned to end the war on May 9, which Russia celebrates as "Victory Day", marking Nazi Germany's surrender in 1945.</p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said earlier this week that Moscow would not rush to meet that symbolic date.</p>
<p>TRAIL OF DESTRUCTION</p>
<p>Ukraine's second biggest city, Kharkiv, was under bombardment, as it has been since the early days of the invasion, the Ukrainian military said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Giving an update on the battle front, Ukraine's general staff said its forces were defending the approach to Kharkiv from Izyum, a town on the Donets river, some 120 km (75 miles) to the southeast, as the enemy left a trail of destruction in Luhansk province.</p>
<p>Some other areas of Donetsk were under constant fire and regional authorities were trying to evacuate civilians from frontline areas, the Ukrainian president's office said.</p>
<p>Russian shelling killed at least three civilians in the town of Vuhledar, the president's office said. Ukraine's military said Russian forces were trying to take the frontline town of Rubizhne.</p>
<p>Reuters could not independently verify Ukraine's battlefield accounts.</p>
<p>Heavy clashes were taking place around Popasna, in Luhansk. Shelling was so intense it was not possible to collect bodies, said regional Governor Serhiy Gaidai.</p>
<p>"I don't even want to speak about what's happening with the people living in Popasna, Rubizhne and Novotoshkivske right now. These cities simply don't exist anymore. They have completely destroyed them."</p>
<p>(Reporting by Reuters bureaus; Writing by Simon Cameron-Moore and Frank Jack Daniel; Editing by Lincoln Feast and Nick Macfie)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4a4329c7e539010b71e61d05a6aa7352" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="15999" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753135&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4e4045ce0b55dfe367a4fb8760bb8dba" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3d0ca" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753139&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="cd8d35ca96287656cbcfe881709b113a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="7fa64" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753141&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b331abde73f92be47a2e970752ec1fd2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="69428" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753147&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-unleashes-rockets-in-mariupol-eu-readies-oil-sanctions/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29753126&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some in Shanghai come out for air as Beijing resumes mass COVID tests</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/some-in-shanghai-come-out-for-air-as-beijing-resumes-mass-tests/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752091&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a55d9e9b17ac83b997ff2d1a550d1e56" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3bee0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752093&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Brenda Goh and Hallie Gu</p>
<p>SHANGHAI/BEIJING (Reuters) - Some of Shanghai's 25 million people came out for brief walks and grocery shopping on Tuesday after enduring more than a month under a COVID lockdown, while China's capital Beijing embarked on another round of mass testing to control a nascent outbreak.</p>
<p>Social media posts showed Shanghai residents strolling in their suburbs, or queuing up at supermarkets that had been allowed to reopen. One picture showed two women carrying a pole with four bulky bags of groceries on their shoulders.</p>
<p>That was the result of an incremental easing of curbs in five of the city's 16 districts from Sunday, home to about a fifth of Shanghai's population, where some people were allowed to leave their housing compounds for the first time in weeks.</p>
<p>The level of the restrictions varied from one residential complex to another. In many compounds, a single person from each household could go out at a time, for a maximum three hours.</p>
<p>Most do not get permission to drive or even ride a bike, prompting jokes on social media.</p>
<p>One WeChat page used to organise group orders for basic necessities during the lockdown listed a donkey priced at 88,888 yuan ($13,450) with a delivery date set after 365 years as an alternative to using vehicles to transport groceries.</p>
<p>"Please count me in for one of those donkey group buys," one resident commented to the post.</p>
<p>In China, the number eight is associated with prosperity.</p>
<p>Increasingly out of step with most other countries which have significantly eased or even completely lifted coronavirus restrictions, China has given no hint of deviating from its "zero COVID" policy.</p>
<p>China has accepted a heavy economic cost and demanded huge personal sacrifices from millions forced into prolonged isolation.</p>
<p>Many of these people have struggled with lost income, difficulty sourcing food and severe delays in access to emergency healthcare and other basic services. This has led to rare outbursts of anger in a sensitive year for President Xi Jinping, who is widely expected to secure a precedent-breaking third leadership term this fall.</p>
<p>Chinese authorities say their COVID policies aim to save as many lives as possible, pointing to the millions of deaths COVID has caused outside China.</p>
<p>Authorities reported 20 new COVID deaths on May 2, all in Shanghai, taking China's total to 5,112 since the pandemic began.</p>
<p>CAPITAL TIGHTENS CURBS</p>
<p>Beijing, with dozens of new cases daily in an outbreak in its second week, is banking on mass testing to locate and isolate infections and avert a Shanghai-like lockdown.</p>
<p>The capital of 22 million tightened COVID curbs over the five-day Labour Day holiday that runs through Wednesday, traditionally one the busiest periods for restaurants and tourism.</p>
<p>Twelve out of 16 Beijing districts will carry out a further three rounds of COVID tests between May 3 and 5, following three previous rounds of screening last week.</p>
<p>The capital's restaurants were closed for dining in and some apartment blocks were sealed shut. Most other venues were either closed, or demanded a negative PCR test from visitors.</p>
<p>Streets were quiet, with many residents fearing they might receive a quarantine order if found to have been in the proximity of a COVID case.</p>
<p>Beijing's new daily cases have been relatively steady since the first infections in the capital emerged on April 22, with a total of 62 detected on May 2.</p>
<p>In Shanghai, the number of cases found outside quarantined areas was up to 73 from 58 - a setback after two consecutive days of zero such cases.</p>
<p>A period of zero cases in such areas, where some movement outside residential compounds is allowed, is a key requirement for a more significant relaxation of COVID curbs.</p>
<p>($1 = 6.6080 Chinese yuan renminbi)</p>
<p>(Reporting by Hallie Gu in Beijing, Brenda Goh and Zhang Yan in Shanghai and the Beijing and Shanghai bureaus; Writing by Marius Zaharia; Editing by Richard Pullin)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e3fcaee0c33af85df61c38dcf22be436" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="11d12" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752095&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="1fe88f2713cc122f4266c7a8d6b9d2fc" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="093dc" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752096&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="5c0b39cd4fbaa51d5d6f392d10556894" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="035d1" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752099&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 05:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/some-in-shanghai-come-out-for-air-as-beijing-resumes-mass-tests/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29752091&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the CIA is working with anti-Putin Russians to secretly gather information</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/anti-putin-russians/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-fbi-takes-over-internet-router-linked-to-russian-hackers-report.jpg?id=26788733&width=2000&coordinates=138%2C0%2C139%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>The CIA is working under Vladimir Putin's nose with Russians trying to circumvent his attacks on Ukraine, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/02/world/ukraine-russia-war-news#the-cia-offers-russians-a-safe-way-to-share-secrets-through-the-dark-web" target="_blank">according to a report in The New York Times</a> </p><p>The New York Times reported Monday that the US's international intelligence agency is using the dark web upload details in a way to bypass any of the Russian monitors. They're also using social media platforms like YouTube to explain to Russians how they can use private networks and a Virtual Private Network (VPN) to encrypt information.  </p><p>"The instructions, written in Russian, are meant to be relatively simple to follow," said the report. "Russians are told to use a VPN to contact the CIA They can also download the Tor browser, which allows users to access the dark web and submit information anonymously, without either the agency knowing where it came from or Russian security services knowing someone was contacting the Americans."<br/></p><p>CIA spokesperson Susan Miller explained that they're working to ensure that any Russian who wants to help the "unjust war" can do so "safely." The report also indicated they're using other means to push out information, but didn't disclose them. </p><p><u><em><strong>RELATED: </strong></em></u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/" target="_self"><u><em><strong>David Petraeus: Top Russian military official getting 'desperate' as Putin leans on him to make progress </strong></em></u></a></p><p>Tor browsers protect the identity of those using it using encryptions bouncing through various different way-points around the world making it difficult to trace. </p><p>For the past months, anti-Putin Russians have protested in whatever ways they could. Putin responded by passing new laws that effectively outlaw using the words "war" or "invasion" to describe the attacks on Ukraine. Thousands of Russians have been arrested for what they're calling "fake news" that opposes the Russian military. </p><p>“The Kremlin is wiping out all options for dissent to ensure that brave anti-war protesters do not return to the streets,” said Hugh Williamson, Europe and Central Asia director <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2022/03/07/russia-criminalizes-independent-war-reporting-anti-war-protests" target="_blank">at Human Rights Watch</a>. “When President Putin goes after such a fundamental right – the cornerstone of democracy – with such totalitarian tactics, he is dispensing with any pretense that his government has any respect for rule of law, human rights, or democracy.”</p><p>Russian Channel One producer <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-tv-protester/" target="_blank">Marina Ovsyannikova staged her own protest</a> in March, uploading a video to her Twitter account before she appeared on air with a poster saying that the government was lying to people about the war. <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/r-2656960142/" target="_blank">She now faces 15 years in prison.<br/></a></p><p><strong><em><u>RELATED: </u></em></strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/" target="_self"><strong><em><u>Pentagon 'cannot confirm' reports that Russia's top general was injured during Ukraine visit</u></em></strong> </a></p><p>After Ovsyannikova was arrested, Channel One colleague <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-russian-war-2656971912/" target="_blank">Zhanna Agalakova also quit her job</a> as the Europe correspondent for the Russian state television outlet. Two other journalists at Channel One's rival station NTV left as well. One of those was 30-year veteran reporter Vadim Glusker and Lilia Gildeyeva who has worked for the channel since 2006.</p><p>On Twitter, people post comments like "Russians, you can stop this war." But as <a href="https://mayavolf.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Maya Volf</a>, a producer for Russian YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/ivarlamov/videos" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ilya Varlamov</a> <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/how-russian-youtubers-are-trying-to-get-around-censorship/" target="_blank">explained</a>, they can't. "Even just getting information and sharing it with others is really dangerous for us and our families. For example, my husband is in Turkey right now because I am afraid for him."</p><p>Meanwhile, the hacker group Anonymous has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/r-2656999569/" target="_blank">worked on several fronts to stop</a> Putin propaganda from being distributed to Russians. They also say that they've hacked at least 700 gigs of data from <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-hacked-anonymous-data/" target="_blank">the Russian Ministry of Culture.</a> </p><p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/02/world/ukraine-russia-war-news#the-cia-offers-russians-a-safe-way-to-share-secrets-through-the-dark-web" target="_blank">Read the full report at the New York Times. </a></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/anti-putin-russians/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sarah K. Burris</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-fbi-takes-over-internet-router-linked-to-russian-hackers-report.jpg?id=26788733&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia reroutes internet traffic in occupied Ukraine to its infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-reroutes-internet-traffic-in-occupied-ukraine-to-its-infrastructure/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/white-and-blue-ceramic-round-plate.jpg?id=29751381&width=2000&coordinates=195%2C0%2C0%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>KYIV (Reuters) - Russia has rerouted internet traffic in the occupied Ukrainian region of Kherson through Russian communications infrastructure, the internet service disruption monitor NetBlocks said on Monday. The move appeared aimed at tightening Moscow's grip on a region where it claims it has taken full control. Russia-appointed authorities in parts of Kherson have said the region would start using the Russian rouble on May 1. London-based NetBlocks said it had tracked a near-total internet blackout across Kherson region on Saturday that affected various Ukrainian providers. Connection was...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-reroutes-internet-traffic-in-occupied-ukraine-to-its-infrastructure/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/white-and-blue-ceramic-round-plate.jpg?id=29751381&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia steps up Ukraine assault as US warns of annexation</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-steps-up-ukraine-as-us-warns-of-annexation/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751280&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="851ba71eb1411ba919b67b0b3832fafa" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="72568" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751282&width=980"/><figcaption>A woman who fled the besieged city of Mariupol arrives at a registration area for internally displaced people in Zaporizhzhia, Ukraine, on May 2, 2022</figcaption></figure></div><p>Zaporizhzhia (Ukraine) (AFP) - Russia on Monday launched a fresh assault on the critical Ukrainian port of Odessa as the United States warned that Moscow was preparing formally to annex embattled regions in the east.</p>
<p>The new heavy fighting came as the European Union said it was bracing for a complete end to Russian gas supplies, with the bloc preparing another package of sanctions sure to anger President Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>After failing to take the capital Kyiv, Moscow has shifted its two-month-old invasion to largely Russian-speaking areas and has stepped up pressure on Odessa, a celebrated cultural hub that is a crucial port on the Black Sea.</p>
<p>Odessa's city council said that a Russian strike hit a residential building housing five people. A 15-year-old boy was killed and a girl was hospitalised, the council said on Telegram.</p>
<p>"A 14-year-old boy was killed. A 17-year-old girl was wounded, she has a shrapnel wound," Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky said in a video address, giving a different age for the boy.</p>
<p>"For what? What did these children... threaten the Russian state with? And that's how they fight. That's all," he said.</p>
<p>Fighting was particularly intense in eastern Ukraine around Izyum, Lyman and Rubizhne as the Russians prepared an attack on Severodonetsk, the farthest city still under Kyiv's control, Ukraine's general staff said.</p>
<p>In Lyman, relentless shelling has reduced hamlets around the city to rubble, according to AFP reporters.</p>
<p>"Half of the city is destroyed," said one resident, lifting luggage onto the roof of his beat-up Soviet-designed Lada car.</p>
<p>"I don't have a house anymore," he said.</p>
<p>The governor of the eastern region of Lugansk expected more intense battles ahead of May 9, the day Russia annually celebrates the 1945 surrender of Nazi Germany to allied forces, including the then-Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, however, told Italian television that Moscow's forces "will not artificially adjust their actions to any date, including Victory Day".</p>
<h1>'Sham referenda'</h1>
<p>Whatever Russia's military decisions, the United States warned that Moscow was preparing imminently to annex both Lugansk and neighbouring Donetsk.</p>
<p>Pro-Russian separatists in the two regions declared independence in 2014, but Moscow has so far stopped short of formally incorporating them as it did that year with the Crimean peninsula, which it seized through special forces in unmarked uniforms.</p>
<p>"Russia plans to engineer referenda upon joining sometime in mid-May," said Michael Carpenter, the US ambassador to the Organisation for Security and Co-operation in Europe.</p>
<p>He said that Russia was considering a similar plan in a third region, Kherson, where Moscow has recently solidified control and imposed use of its ruble currency.</p>
<p>"We think the reports are highly credible," Carpenter told reporters in Washington.</p>
<p>As with Crimea, he vowed that the international community would not support Russian-dictated changes to Ukraine's borders.</p>
<p>"Such sham referenda -- fabricated votes -- will not be considered legitimate, nor will any attempts to annex additional Ukrainian territory," Carpenter said.</p>
<p>"But we have to act with a sense of urgency."</p>
<h1>Evacuating battered Mariupol</h1>
<p>The invasion has killed thousands and displaced more than 13 million people in a war the scale of which has not been seen in Europe for generations.</p>
<p>Among the most battered cities is Mariupol, where an untold number have died and survivors have little access to food, water and medicine as Russia battles to connect the southern and eastern strips of land under its control.</p>
<p>Kyiv said more than 100 civilians were evacuated over the weekend from the sprawling Azovstal steel plant, the last holdout of Ukrainian forces in Mariupol, where soldiers and civilians have been sheltering in a maze of underground tunnels.</p>
<p>Sviatoslav Palamar, deputy commander of Ukraine's Azov unit, said that another 20 people were transferred out on Monday evening, but only after a five-hour delay as "the enemy's artillery caused new rubble and destruction."</p>
<p>Ukraine and Russia have been coordinating civilian evacuations with the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>
<p>US State Department spokesman Ned Price called on Russia to allow humanitarian supplies to enter Mariupol and other besieged cities.</p>
<p>Doing so would "demonstrate that there may be a genuine humanitarian intent behind this evacuation and not just another craven attempt on the part of the Kremlin to charge the narrative," Price said.</p>
<p>Ukrainian forces have recaptured some territory in recent days, including the village of Ruska Lozova, which evacuees said had been occupied for two months.</p>
<p>"It was two months of terrible fear. Nothing else, a terrible and relentless fear," Natalia, a 28-year-old evacuee from Ruska Lozova, told AFP after reaching Kharkiv.</p>
<p>But Kyiv has admitted that Russian forces have captured a string of villages in the east and has asked Western powers to deliver more heavy weapons to bolster its defences there.</p>
<p>Ukraine's defence ministry said Monday that its drones had sunk two Russian patrol boats near the Black Sea's Snake Island, which became a symbol of Ukrainian resistance after soldiers there rebuffed Russian demands to surrender.</p>
<p>"The Bayraktars are working," said Valeriy Zaluzhnyi, the commander in chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, referring to Turkish-made military drones.</p>
<h1>Bracing for new sanctions</h1>
<p>Western powers have levelled unprecedented sanctions against Russia over the war while delivering money and weapons to Ukraine, including a $33-billion (31 billion-euro) arms and support package announced by US President Joe Biden last week.</p>
<p>The European Commission will on Tuesday propose a new package of sanctions, including an embargo on Russian oil, officials said.</p>
<p>After talks on Monday, the European Union warned member states to prepare for a possible complete breakdown in gas supplies from Russia, insisting it would not cede to Moscow's demand that imports be paid for in rubles.</p>
<p>Germany, Europe's largest economy, before the war became heavily dependent on Russian gas, but European views quickly hardened after Putin attacked Ukraine.</p>
<p>EU and French officials said the 27-member bloc was united with Poland and Bulgaria, whose gas supplies were cut last week after they refused to pay in rubles.</p>
<p>Meanwhile British Prime Minister Boris Johnson will announce Tuesday another £300 million ($376 million, 358 million euros) in military aid for Ukraine, his office said.</p>
<p>In a new blow to Russian prestige, European football's governing body, UEFA, announced that Russian clubs had been banned from participating in the Champions League and all other European competitions next season.</p>
<p>Western nations have been trying to show support by reopening embassies in Kyiv that were closed due to the invasion, with Denmark the latest to make the move Monday.</p>
<p>Kristina Kvien, the US charge d'affaires, announced in the western city of Lviv that Washington hopes to have diplomats back in Kyiv by the end of May.</p>
<p>burs-st/caw</p>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-steps-up-ukraine-as-us-warns-of-annexation/</guid>
      <category>Ukraine</category>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Conflict</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>AFP</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751280&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Petraeus: Top Russian military official getting 'desperate' as Putin leans on him to make progress</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=2000&coordinates=0%2C13%2C0%2C13&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>On Monday, former Gen. David Petraeus told CNN's Jake Tapper that a key Russian military official is feeling the heat for the ongoing failure of the invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>"We're told that the chief of staff for the Russian military recently visited Ukraine, including the Donbas region," said Tapper. "The U.S. says it isn't sure why he traveled to the Russian front lines. What do you make of that?"</p><p>"Well, he's probably trying to figure out what is going on, why can't we make progress?" said Petraeus, who previously headed the CIA. "He's down there trying to work with the commander. You know, they now have one commander in charge, General Dvornikov, the Butcher of Syria, known for the bombing of Aleppo in 2016. They really haven't made the progress that they hoped to achieve. And so he's probably down there trying to figure out why is it that we can't achieve combined armed effects. Why is it we can't integrate air and ground operations, why aren't we doing better? And of course, he did narrowly avoid, apparently, the demolition of the command post at which he was located during his visit. With a loss of another Russian general, reportedly."</p><p>"So again, he is probably getting desperate," said Petraeus. "I'm sure that President Putin is putting enormous pressure on him and on Defense Minister Shoigu, to achieve something, again, that he can announce, Putin can announce, on 9 May in Moscow."</p><p><u><em><strong>RELATED: </strong></em></u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/" target="_self"><u><em><strong>Russia just demonstrated their ‘total depravity’ – according to this former US ambassador </strong></em></u></a></p><p>Petraeus has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/consequences-for-putin-s-war-on-ukraine-are-going-to-start-to-come-home-to-roost-in-moscow-gen-david-petraeus/" target="_blank">previously predicted</a> that Putin will face severe political consequences for the Ukraine invasion as the worldwide embargo against Russia causes economic collapse. The war, which experts once feared would result in Russia rapidly seizing the capital city of Kyiv, has stalled out with Russia struggling to hold territory in the east.</p><p>It's been claimed that numerous Russian generals have also been killed in combat, which Petraeus has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-war-why-are-so-many-russian-generals-being-killed/" target="_blank">explained</a> is due to a breakdown in the Russian military's command structure.</p><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/" target="_blank">Watch below or at this link</a>: </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="1a9227ba18a54d18491faf9c7921b3c9" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xetwATi_-IU?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">David Petraeus says Russian military chief of staff is "desperate"</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xetwATi_-IU" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p><strong><br/></strong></p><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p>
<p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter estimates spam, fake accounts comprise less than 5% of users</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/twitter-estimates-spam-fake-accounts-comprise-less-than-5-of-users-filing/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751286&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Sheila Dang (Reuters) -Twitter Inc estimated in a filing on Monday that false or spam accounts represented fewer than 5% of its monetizable daily active users during the first quarter. The social media company had 229 million users who were served advertising in the first quarter. The disclosure came days after Tesla Inc Chief Executive Elon Musk, who has inked a deal to buy Twitter for $44 billion, tweeted that one of his priorities would be to remove "spam bots" from the platform. Twitter said in the filing it faced several risks until the deal with Musk is closed, such as whether adverti...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/twitter-estimates-spam-fake-accounts-comprise-less-than-5-of-users-filing/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751286&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there solid evidence that Hitler had 'Jewish blood'? Here is what historians say</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/is-there-solid-evidence-that-hitler-had-jewish-blood-here-s-what-historians-say/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/hitler.jpg?id=26573801&width=2000&coordinates=139%2C0%2C139%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>The suggestion by Russia's foreign minister that Adolf Hitler had Jewish blood is just the latest version of a conspiracy theory exploiting a gap in the dictator's ancestry.</p><p>Sergei Lavrov's remarks at the weekend, which have sparked a diplomatic row with Israel, reheats rumours over the identity of Hitler's paternal grandfather dating as far back as the 1920s.</p><p>Hitler's father, Alois, was an illegitimate child whose own father was unknown, Austrian historian Roman Sandgruber told AFP.</p><p>Sandgruber, who last year published the first biography of Alois Hitler, explained that the rumours first began circulating in the 1920s, as Adolf Hitler began his rise to power.</p><p>The theory was encouraged by Hitler's political rivals as the Nazi leader took control of Germany in 1933.</p><p>Then after World War II, the memoirs of Nazi war criminal Hans Frank, who governed occupied Poland during the war, revived the story.</p><p>In his memoirs, published after his 1946 execution for war crimes, Frank said he had secretly researched Hitler's ancestry at the request of the Nazi leader himself.</p><p>"This must have been towards the end of the 1930s," wrote Frank, in an extract published by Germany's Der Spiegel magazine at the time.</p><p>Hitler, he said, had told him he was being blackmailed by a nephew over the matter.</p><p>Hitler's paternal grandmother Maria Anna Schicklgruber gave birth to Alois in 1837.</p><p>Frank claimed to have discovered that, at the time, she was employed as a cook for a Jewish family by the name of Frankenberger, in the Austrian city of Graz.</p><p>Her employer had paid her maintenance until Alois reached the age of 14, wrote Frank, claiming that an exchange of letters between her and the family proved this.</p><p>Frank said Hitler had told him that actually his grandmother and her future husband had let the Jewish man think he was the father in order to get the money out of him.</p><p>But historians remain sceptical.</p><p>There is no solid evidence to support Frank's claims, says Sandgruber. One problem is that, at the time in question, Jews did not have the right to live in Graz, he adds.</p><p>So who was Hitler's grandfather? "This is a question without an answer," historian Ofer Aderet wrote in Israel's Haaretz newspaper Monday.</p><p>Some Nazis still aired this theory "as an attempt to provide an explanation for their defeat in World War II", he argued.</p><p>"Other reports claimed that Hitler's persecution of the Jews resulted from feelings of shame about his partial Jewish ancestry," he added.</p><p>"The bottom line, though, is that there is no historical proof for any of this."</p><p>Israel's Foreign Minister Yair Lapid on Monday condemned Lavrov's remarks as "an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error.</p><p>"Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust," Lapid added. This kind of claim was the worst kind of anti-Semitism, he said.</p><p>Prime Minister Naftali Bennett denounced Lavrov's comments as "lies", and the foreign ministry has summoned Russia's ambassador for an explanation.</p><p>Russia has repeatedly justified what it calls its "special military operation" in Ukraine as a mission to "demilitarise" and "denazify" the country.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 21:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/is-there-solid-evidence-that-hitler-had-jewish-blood-here-s-what-historians-say/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/hitler.jpg?id=26573801&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon 'cannot confirm' reports that Russia's top general was injured during Ukraine visit</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/sergei-shoigu-and-valery-gerasimov.jpg?id=29750836&width=2000&coordinates=178%2C0%2C22%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>Russia's top general, Valery Gerasimov, visited the Donbas front in the Ukraine war last week, a Pentagon official said Monday, but reports that he was injured in a Ukrainian attack could not be confirmed.</p><p>"What we can confirm is that we know that for several days last week he was in the Donbas," a senior US defense official told journalists.</p><p>"We don't believe that he's still there -- that he has left and he's back in Russia," the official said.</p><p>"We cannot confirm reports that he was injured."</p><p>According to reports citing Ukraine officials, on Saturday Ukraine forces shelled a command center in Izium, where Gerasimov, chief of general staff of the Russian armed forces, visited to meet with top field commanders.</p><p>But he had apparently left the site before the shelling took place.</p><p>Gerasimov was believed to be touring the front to better understand field conditions and rally his troops as Russian forces, after failing to capture Kyiv in the north, attempt to take control of the Donetsk and Luhansk regions of the east.</p><p>In a daily briefing on the war, the Pentagon official said Monday that Russian forces were making minimal progress in a tough fight against Ukraine troops in the region and called their efforts "anemic."</p><p>"We continue to see minimal at best progress by the Russians in the Donbas. They've had some minor gains east of Izium and Popasna in the Luhansk Oblast."</p><p>The officials described the Russians as winning control of villages, then ceding them back to Ukraine fighters, and characterized Russian forces as demoralized and suffering from poor leadership and organization.</p><p>The Russian effort on the ground is "very tepid, very uneven... and in some cases, quite frankly, the best word to describe it would be anemic," the official said.</p><p>The official did not provide any similar assessment of Ukraine forces.</p><p>Arms deliveries from the United States and Western allies to Ukraine, including heavy artillery, radar systems, and attack drones, continue at a high pace, the official said.</p><p>Over the last 24 hours, two dozen flights carrying US arms landed near Ukraine, and another 11 were planned over the coming 24 hours, officials said.</p><p><strong>NOW WATCH:<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank"> 'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 20:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/sergei-shoigu-and-valery-gerasimov.jpg?id=29750836&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia just demonstrated their ‘total depravity’ – according to this former US ambassador</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/testimony-by-top-diplomat-bill-taylor-on-trump-and-ukraine-elicits-disturbed-responses-from-members-of-congress.jpg?id=24839692&width=2000&coordinates=46%2C0%2C46%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>Responding to recent <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/02/world/europe/israel-russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov.html" target="_blank">comments</a> from Russian foreign minister Sergei V. Lavrov, former U.S. ambassador William Taylor said the remarks "just demonstrate the total depravity, really, evil nature of the Russian government top to bottom." <br/></p><p>"It demonstrates that there is no justification, there <em>was</em> no justification, there's no rationale for this invasion," Taylor said during an MSNBC segment. "Ukraine posed no threat to the Russians -- they [the Russians] had to manufacture some reason ... the moral clarity of this war is there for all to see." </p><p>Moscow has previously claimed that it wants to "de-militarize" and "de-Nazify" Ukraine.</p><p>Lavrov, speaking to Italian outlet Mediaset's Rete 4 channel in an interview released Sunday, claimed that Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy "puts forward an argument of what kind of Nazism can they have if he himself is Jewish."</p><p>Lavrov, according to a transcript posted on the Russian foreign ministry website, then added: "I could be wrong, but Hitler also had Jewish blood."</p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/south-carolina-republican-arrested/" target="_self">South Carolina GOP county chairman arrested for alleged child abuse</a></em></strong></p><p>The comment also prompted fierce criticism from Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid.</p><p>"Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust," Lapid said in a statement. "The lowest level of racism against Jews is to accuse Jews themselves of antisemitism."</p><p>Israel's foreign ministry "has summoned the Russian Ambassador to Israel for a clarification meeting", the statement added.</p><p>Prime Minister Naftali Bennett then denounced Lavrov's "lies" that he said effectively "accuse the Jews themselves of the most awful crimes in history," perpetrated against them.</p><p><em><span></span><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/" target="_blank">Watch the video below or watch here</a>. </em></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d9f69e87c455bc8cf8f7eb1a4147e0d0" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TtukiZG9ac?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">05 02 2022 12 10 21</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6TtukiZG9ac" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p><em>With additional reporting via AFP</em><br/></p><p><strong><br/></strong></p><p><strong>NOW WATCH:<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank"> 'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p>
<p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 18:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sky Palma</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/testimony-by-top-diplomat-bill-taylor-on-trump-and-ukraine-elicits-disturbed-responses-from-members-of-congress.jpg?id=24839692&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QAnon leader who claims to be 'Queen of Canada' says Biden has asked her to mediate Russian peace talks</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/romana-didulo-2657250121/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/romana-didulo.png?id=29749365&width=2000&coordinates=80%2C0%2C120%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>QAnon influencer Romana Didulo claims President Joe Biden has asked her to mediate talks between the U.S. and Russia over the war in Ukraine.</p><p>Didulo, who also claims to be "queen of Canada," says she asked Biden to provide her with her own aircraft to fly to Moscow, or possibly St. Petersburg, for the talks, according to BBC correspondent Shayan Sardarizadeh.</p><p>"I address you today as your commander in chief and Queen," Didulo says in a video posted online. "to the Russian and American people, I address you as the mediator between the United States and Russia pertaining to the Ukraine crises. I have been requested by the commander in chief of the United States armed forces to act as the mediator between Russia and the United States."</p><p>Didulo claimed that aircraft would bear the flag of the "Kingdom of Canada" and be known as "Queen Romana," or "QR1," and she said she asked for military escort for her journey with 13-15 staffers.</p><p>In reality, Biden has not asked Didulo to be a mediator and she will not be getting her own special aircraft to fly to Eastern Europe.</p><p><em>Watch the video below</em>.<br/></p><p><br/></p><blockquote class="rm-embed twitter-tweet" data-partner="rebelmouse" data-twitter-tweet-id="1521158285210046465">
<div style="margin:1em 0">QAnon "queen of Canada" Romana Didulo says she's been asked by Joe Biden to "act as the mediator" between the US and Russia over the war in Ukraine. She's asked Biden to provide her with a "queen Romana one" aircraft for her journey to Moscow.pic.twitter.com/5eSdjDPA9b</div> — Shayan Sardarizadeh (@Shayan Sardarizadeh)
        <a href="https://twitter.com/Shayan86/statuses/1521158285210046465">1651507371</a>
</blockquote>
<script async="" charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X5Ewlf2zcig" target="_blank">Marjorie Taylor Greene says she opposes welfare because women 'need to be married'</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="07d49712fb756df44e7bd0f5e918add5" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X5Ewlf2zcig?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Marjorie Taylor Greene says she opposes welfare because women 'need to be married'</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X5Ewlf2zcig" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/romana-didulo-2657250121/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Travis Gettys</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/romana-didulo.png?id=29749365&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/png">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swiss parliament gets climate lecture after father's hunger strike</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/swiss-parliament-gets-climate-lecture-after-father-s-hunger-strike/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29749217&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Emma Farge and Cecile Mantovani BERN (Reuters) -Climate scientists took turns to deliver speeches on the perils of global warming to the Swiss parliament on Monday in an event triggered by the hunger strike of a frustrated Swiss father on its doorstep last year. Guillermo Fernandez, a father of three, ended a 39-day hunger strike in December when the government submitted to his demand for the session. "It's really fantastic to be here knowing that today the facts are going to be laid out to parliament and the whole Swiss people," he told Reuters in Federal Square, the location of his strike...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/swiss-parliament-gets-climate-lecture-after-father-s-hunger-strike/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29749217&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel keen to set up cyber 'Iron Dome' to curb rise in attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-keen-to-set-up-cyber-iron-dome-to-curb-rise-in/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748621&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="64a387c4a9478e41538ada0469a94baf" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="66f10" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748624&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Steven Scheer</p>
<p>TEL AVIV (Reuters) - Israel's government on Monday ordered communications firms to step up their cyber security efforts in the wake of a rise in attempted hacking attacks.</p>
<p>New regulations are currently being implemented in which mandatory and unified standards will have to be met, the Communications Ministry and Israel's National Cyber Directorate said.</p>
<p>Under the new rules, firms must formulate plans to protect communications networks using a combination of monitoring and control mechanisms to make it possible to establish an up to date picture of cyber protection while ensuring privacy.</p>
<p>"We are trying to put the right standard on communications companies in order to protect Israel and create a kind of 'Iron Dome' from cyber security attacks. We are suffering from thousands of cyber attacks every year," Communications Minister Yoaz Hendel told a news conference.</p>
<p>Israel uses an Iron Dome air-defence system to intercept rockets fired by Palestinian militants, mostly from Gaza.</p>
<p>Hendel said that risks continued to mount, along with more digitisation.</p>
<p>"Communications networks are an attractive target for cyber attacks by hostile elements," Hendel said, citing potential damage or shutdown of services and leakage of information being stored.</p>
<p>According to cyber security firm Check Point, there was a 137% annual jump in average weekly attacks on Israeli companies, to nearly 1,500 per week, in the first three months of 2022.</p>
<p>Gaby Portnoy, Israel's new cyber security czar, said in the last month alone, Israel had seen a sharp rise in attacks trying to bring down websites. He accused Iranians of carrying out many of the attacks.</p>
<p>Last month, he noted, a denial of service attack aimed at bringing down government sites began through telecom providers but ultimately failed.</p>
<p>Portnoy said Israeli telecoms firms had very good cyber security but that the new regulations, which include a higher level of supervision, would be an improvement.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Steven Scheer; Editing by Jeffrey Heller and Bernadette Baum)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 15:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-keen-to-set-up-cyber-iron-dome-to-curb-rise-in/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748621&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Lowest level of racism': Israeli foreign minister buries Russia's Lavrov for comparing Zelenskyy to Hitler</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/sergei-lavrov/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748705&width=2000&coordinates=109%2C0%2C91%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>In response to remarks by Kremlin foreign minister Sergei Lavrov, who said that Adolf Hitler “had Jewish blood” and that the “most rabid antisemites tend to be Jews," Israel has summoned the Russian ambassador and demanded an apology, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/02/israel-summons-russia-envoy-sergei-lavrov-hitler-comments" target="_blank">The Guardian reports</a>. </p><p>Lavrov made comments while defending Russia's invasion of Ukraine, claiming that the Russian military is carrying out a campaign of "denazification." </p><p>“As to [Zelenskiy’s] argument of what kind of nazification can we have if I’m Jewish, if I remember correctly, and I may be wrong, Hitler also had Jewish blood,” Lavrov said during an interview with Italian television channel Mediaset. “It doesn’t mean anything at all.”</p><p>“We have for a long time listened to the wise Jewish people who say that the most rabid antisemites tend to be Jews,” Lavrov continued. “There is no family without a monster.”</p><p>In a statement, Israel's foreign minister Yair Lapid said Lavrov’s remarks "are both an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error."</p><p>“Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust. The lowest level of racism against Jews is to accuse Jews themselves of antisemitism," he said.</p><p><em>Read more at <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/02/israel-summons-russia-envoy-sergei-lavrov-hitler-comments" target="_blank">The Guardian</a>. </em></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/sergei-lavrov/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sky Palma</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748705&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian generals 'extremely frustrated' as they fail all of Putin's 'strategic objectives': CNN military analyst</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=2000&coordinates=0%2C13%2C0%2C13&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>On CNN Monday, Ret. Lt. Gen. Mark Hertling addressed the risk that Vladimir Putin escalates to using weapons of mass destruction in the invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>"I'm sure Mr. Putin and his generals are extremely frustrated, but truthfully, from the very beginning, as we said, they have not put the kind of forces and they have not had the kind of synchronization you need," said Hertling.</p><p>"There's a school of thought — Peggy Noonan wrote, 'The worse Putin's army does on the ground, the greater risk he takes an outlier move, such as using tactical nuclear weapons,'" said CNN anchor Jim Sciutto. "Again, I don't want to overstate that risk. I know it is one the Pentagon takes, at least seriously, and watches for any signs of. Putin can't lose, right? So, do you worry that as he gets more frustrated, that risk becomes greater?"</p><p>"I don't worry about it, Jim, but it is certainly a concern," said Hertling. "I think the intelligence indicators are focused on what might create those kinds of uses of extreme weapons, weapons of mask destruction. So, I firmly believe that the U.S. government and NATO is watching very closely for any indicators of the use of chemical or nuclear weapons and there will be a reaction to that, or preemption in some cases, if that happens."</p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/trump-supporter-kicked-off-plane/" target="_self">Slur-spewing couple kicked off flight — and complain it's because they're Trump supporters</a></em></strong></p><p>"You know, folks — the pundits since the very beginning have said, if we push too hard, Russia is going to use some kind of extreme measure," Hertling continued. "That is certainly a consideration. What we've seen so far is, Mr. Putin, since the very beginning, has failed in achieving every one of his strategic objectives. </p><p>"He continues to adjust his operational objectives. And even then, he continues to fail. So, you know, when you're talking about what is next for him, man, I hope that there's a potential that the Russian people will see what's happening and as more news gets back to the population, that they will take action and get this individual out of the leadership of Russia."</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/" target="_blank">Watch the video below or at this link.</a></strong></p><p><br/></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="dee536be12c69d91d3a4250776252140" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vh1qfjMisdY?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Mark Hertling says Russian generals are "frustrated"</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vh1qfjMisdY&feature=youtu.be" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global forecaster on 'another bad year for democracy': Is the world near a dire tipping point?</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/democracy-2657249124/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-gallows-set-up-by-the-capitol-rioters-screengrab.png?id=27789537&width=2000&coordinates=100%2C0%2C100%2C0&height=1500"/><br/><br/><p>Global democracy is sick. In the United States, Donald Trump's supporters in the Republican Party <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/15/do-the-democrats-know-how-to-fight-jan-6-committee-signals-its-still-scared-of/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">continue to steamroll the Democrats and other pro-democracy forces</a>. To say that the latter have for the most part been hapless, uncoordinated and paralyzed by denial is not overstating the case. </p><p>Political scientists and other experts have warned that in the wake of the Trump presidency and the coup attempt of January 2021, the country is now an "anocracy," hovering in limbo between naked authoritarianism and a slowly failing democracy.</p><p>As I have repeatedly warned <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/28/latest-hate-rally-a-master-class-in-mind-control/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this is an existential struggle</a>: If the Republicans and the larger white right achieve their goals the United States will become a living nightmare for anyone who is not a rich white "Christian" heterosexual male, or otherwise deemed to be a "real American" and one of the MAGA-elect Trump cultists.</p><p>Writing at the Financial Times, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a2e499d0-10f0-4fa2-8243-e23eedc4f9f4" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">columnist Martin Wolf describes this moment</a> of peril and impending disaster:</p><blockquote>"An American 'Caesarism' has now become flesh." I wrote this in March 2016, even before Donald Trump had become the Republican nominee for the presidency. Today, the transformation of the democratic republic into an autocracy has advanced. By 2024, it might be irreversible. If this does indeed happen, it will change almost everything in the world….<br/>Thus, health permitting, Trump will be the next Republican candidate. He will be backed by a party that is now his tool. Most important, in the words of David Frum, erstwhile speechwriter for George W Bush, "what the United States did not have before 2020 was a large national movement willing to justify mob violence to claim political power. Now it does." It does so because its members believe their opponents are not "real" Americans. A liberal democracy cannot long endure if a major party believes defeat is illegitimate and must be rendered impossible.<br/></blockquote><p>Political scientist Thomas Homer-Dixon echoed these concerns in a <a href="https://homerdixon.com/states-of-emergency/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">widely read essay</a> last December in the Globe and Mail, warning that American democracy could collapse by 2015, "causing extreme domestic political instability, including widespread civil violence, and that by 2030, "if not sooner, the country could be governed by a right-wing dictatorship":</p><blockquote>We mustn't dismiss these possibilities just because they seem ludicrous or too horrible to imagine. In 2014, the suggestion that Donald Trump would become president would also have struck nearly everyone as absurd. But today we live in a world where the absurd regularly becomes real and the horrible commonplace.<br/>Leading American academics are now actively addressing the prospect of a fatal weakening of U.S. democracy…. Once Republicans control Congress, Democrats will lose control of the national political agenda, giving Mr. Trump a clear shot at recapturing the presidency in 2024. And once in office, he will have only two objectives: vindication and vengeance.<br/></blockquote><p>In the shadow of such darkness we must not surrender to despair. That is how the global right and the fascist movement wins. Instead, those who believe in true social democracy and the liberal democratic project must stare unflinchingly into the darkness, exile the hope-peddlers and naïve optimists who believe that compromise with such evil is possible, critically assess the reality of the crisis, and then organize and rally to victory.</p><p>Two months ago, Russian President Vladimir Putin, a hero and champion of the global right, unleashed a devastating war of aggression against Ukraine. The Ukrainians have resisted valiantly, and <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/19/colin-clarke-truth-facts-ukraine/" target="_blank">Russia's military has been embarrassed</a>. What many experts foresaw as a quick campaign of conquest appears that it will now be a long slog of grinding death and destruction. The United States and its NATO allies have rallied to the aid of Ukraine; for the moment, at least, Western democracy seems (superficially) renewed through conflict with its former Cold War enemy.</p><p>French President Emmanuel Macron recently defeated Marine Le Pen and the far-right National Rally Party in that country's recent elections. However important that victory appears during this moment of democratic crisis, one should still be cautious for what it ultimately means about the power of the global right and its power in France and other Western European democracies. In her newsletter Lucid, historian Ruth Ben-Ghiat unpacks the larger significance of Le Pen's near-miss, which could have led to "the first female-led far-right government in Europe":</p><blockquote>In the conclusion to my 2020 book on the subject, I singled Le Pen out in suggesting that such a shift is inevitable. "That male model of authoritarian power... may give way in the future as female-led authoritarian states emerge. ... Yet a female-led rightist state would pose no threat to authoritarianism's appeal as a legitimating force of misogyny, kleptocracy, and, in many countries, White racial domination." ...<br/>For some voters, her "softer" feminine image likely goes a long way in making her seem acceptable. Her tasteful and understated clothing blunts the brute force of her racist proposals, such as her idea of eliminating birthright citizenship to more easily target French Muslims for discrimination. ... <br/>In fact, as the global right doubles down on its attention to families — claiming it is a priority to protect children and schools from pedophilic homosexuals, satanist Soros puppets, childless left-wing radicals, and more — being a mother, who can mobilize other mothers, will become an advantage in politics. …<br/>In the coming years, shifts in far-right tactics intended to normalize extremism and the aging of the current strongman cohort will likely produce a new wave of illiberal female leaders.<br/>While these authoritarians won't pose bare-chested, in the tradition of Benito Mussolini and Putin, they will be just as racist, corrupt, and violent as like-minded male leaders, and just as dedicated to using disinformation to create the alternate reality they need to stay in power.<br/></blockquote><p>A hopeful commitment to the basic idea that progress and societal improvement are attainable constitute the beating heart of the centuries-old Western democratic project. The fascist tide can be beaten back by leaning into those democratic and pluralistic values and dreams and then making them real for the mass public.</p><p>The global democracy crisis is real; the future remains unwritten and what happens next is very much in flux.</p><p>What do we know and where do we go from here? In an effort to answer these questions, I recently spoke with <a href="https://www.eiu.com/analysts/andrew-salomone-viteritti" target="_blank">Andrew Viteritti</a>, a senior member of the global forecasting team at the Economist Intelligence Unit, about its recent report, "Democracy Index 2021: the China Challenge."</p><p>In this conversation, Viteritti explains the unit's findings that how global democracy has fallen to its lowest levels since the Economist began tracking it in 2016. He also reports that in many "advanced" or "mature" democracies there is growing cynicism and distrust of government and its ability to solve problems such as price inflation or the COVID pandemic, and that those sentiments are being exploited by illiberal and other anti-democracy forces. Viteritti also discusses the challenge that China's "state capitalism" model represents for global democracy, and what Donald Trump's coup attempt of 2021 and related events tell us about extreme partisan political polarization and how it has imperiled the basic functions of government.</p><p>Toward the end of this conversation, Viteritti expresses optimism that despite all these challenges to democracy in the U.S. and around the world, democratic institutions have shown themselves to be much stronger than many expected, which should be a source of hope for the future. </p><p><em>This conversation has been edited for clarity and length.</em></p><p><strong>How are you feeling about democracy and the overall state of the world, as it faces so many political and other crises?</strong></p><p>The most recent edition of the Democracy Index shows that we've seen another bad year for democracy. The average global score has continued to decline. It is now at an all-time low by our measurements, 5.28 out of a scale of 10. That is a bigger decline than what we saw even in our previous studies, in the 2020 study, which is remarkable when you consider that was the year when the coronavirus pandemic hit. That had many implications for the state of democratic institutions, and also public perceptions towards government.</p><p>It is important to note that the decline that we saw in 2021 was only matched once before in our history of the study, which started in 2006. That was in 2010, in the shadow of the global financial crisis.</p><p>In our new study, many of what we call "full democracies" have also now fallen down to the "flawed democracy" category. We saw the number of authoritarian regimes increase as well. We also saw every region suffer a decline in its average score, except for Eastern Europe. The score there was unchanged. It is a very reasonable response to all this to feel very concerned and very discouraged.</p><p><strong>The public mood, both here in the United States and around the world, is that something is very wrong. How do we quantify that?</strong></p><p>One of the tools that we use for scoring individual countries is called the World Values Survey. It's authoritative, it's global in focus, it's up to date and it's standardized. We have results for the 165 countries and two territories that we cover in the Democracy Index. What we are seeing is that there is certainly a souring of public attitudes worldwide toward political institutions, the capacity of governments to respond to pressing concerns about the state of the economy and economic security, political concerns and also social concerns.</p><p>This is a trend that we've seen become acute in specific regions across the world as well as in specific countries, the United States included. These trends were at play before the coronavirus pandemic happened, but the pandemic accentuated and aggregated these trends, and even made these negative trends appear in countries where we had not seen evidence for such attitudes before. One example would be Canada, where there is a growing skepticism towards the ability of government to respond to these big societal and economic and political issues.</p><p><strong>Canada just endured mass protests and disruptions by a so-called Freedom Convoy of truckers supposedly protesting COVID restrictions and protocols. What do we know about such anxieties and anger?</strong></p><p>That reflects an increasing skepticism toward government and the capacity of governments to act effectively to solve collective problems. Canada is a very mature and strong democracy. But we still have seen a slippage in that country's ranking in our study in the functioning of government and measures of the health of political culture.</p><p>There has also been a hardening of attitudes. This has manifested itself in various countries. For example, in the United States there is intense polarization. Society has become incredibly divided, to the point where public consensus has virtually collapsed on even basic fundamental issues such as election results and public health practices around the pandemic. That was a trend that we discussed at length in our 2020 report for the Democracy Index and another trend that we explored in our most recent 2021 edition for the United States.</p><p>Polarization now has become the biggest threat to United States democracy, because not only has it generated an intense cleavage in United States society where we have these two camps that do not see eye to eye, but it has translated into the fact that it is now very hard for political institutions and democratic institutions to function. Looking at the data, there is little to suggest that polarization and that hardening of attitudes is going to ease up anytime soon. Reproductive rights are a big fault line right now. And of course, we're in a period where key elections are approaching, the midterms this year and the presidential election in 2024. Both Republicans and Democrats are going to frame these elections in existential terms. This does not bode well for the state of polarization in the United States, nor does it suggest that we're going to see things get better anytime soon.</p><p><strong>Whatever happened to the "end of history" and the ultimate triumph of liberal democracy?</strong></p><p>In this year's Democracy Index report we focus on what we describe as the "China challenge." We are in a moment where there is tension and conflict between two very distinct political systems. Is there a "China model" for democracy? What are its features? Is that sustainable? Can it be exported? Does China's leadership even want their system of government to be exported? Our quick answer to that is no.</p><p>We also look at the Western democratic model. Is there a democratic recession in the West, which many have been talking about, and which our studies certainly suggest is true over the years? We examine the causes and symptoms, and then ultimately what can be done to stop it. Ultimately, is the Western model of democracy — with its supposed superiority — sustainable?</p><p>There are some reasons to be optimistic when it comes to the state of democracy in the world, including the United States. One, we've seen very impressive voter participation in the United States. There was record voter turnout in the November 2020 elections. There was also record voter turnout in the runoff elections in Georgia that took place shortly afterward. And there are many reasons to believe we're going to see high voter participation and political engagement continue throughout this year, especially in the run-up to the midterms.</p><p>It is impossible to not think of the extraordinary events that happened at the beginning of 2021, which was our assessment period for the new study. Of course, we saw Donald Trump refuse to accept the results of an election that was held in a free and fair way. We saw Republican lawmakers also back that effort. We saw a sizable portion of the electorate refuse to accept those results.</p><p>It was pretty extraordinary to then see that Joe Biden's inauguration took place very smoothly. During Biden's first year in office, he didn't really face any major disruptions. To our eyes, that points to the strength and durability of United States political institutions. It is fair to assume that a smooth transition of power for Biden and a lack of disturbances over the first year in office for the new president would not have taken place in a country with weaker democratic institutions.</p><p>But at the same time, it is important not to take those institutions for granted. It remains to be seen whether these institutions can withstand similar types of stresses to those they saw at the beginning of 2021 and even during 2020, whether in terms of frequency or in terms of magnitude.</p><p><strong>What do we know about the health of global democracy and how it was impacted by the pandemic?</strong></p><p>There is a valid question as to whether, once we emerge from the pandemic, we will see any improvement in the democracy scores in our study. That may very well happen, especially since some of the indicators we use include public perceptions of things like whether governments are responding to crises effectively, and also questions about personal freedom.</p><p>There is also a risk that the trends that we've seen in policymaking by governments during the pandemic could in fact become "sticky" and thus could outlast the pandemic. There is an open-ended question as to whether governments will walk away from these restrictions quickly as the pandemic recedes. It's not a question that we have an answer to at the moment, because we're still in the middle of the pandemic.</p><p><strong>Where does your optimism come from? I am quite surprised by it.</strong></p><p>When we closed out 2020 and started 2021, it was a pretty dark moment for the United States for many reasons. And even just to see that bright spot in terms of the durability of the country's democratic institutions is very valid, valuable and positive, and certainly a reason to be optimistic.</p><p><strong>What about what experts call "democratic backsliding," or the many examples of how Republicans are seeking to undermine democracy with their new Jim Crow strategy and other attacks? There is great concern about an existential democracy crisis in America, and perhaps even violent insurrection or civil war.</strong></p><p><strong></strong>Polarization is one of the biggest issues in the country, and it hasn't gotten any better over the past year. We're not at the point of civil war, but we do have to keep an eye on this issue of polarization because there's nothing to suggest that it's going to go away immediately.</p><p><strong>Where do these global trends bring us? How close are we to democratic collapse?</strong></p><p>Our previous report was published at the beginning of 2020. In those two years, we see considerable slippage in terms of democracy at the global level. Certainly, that is alarming. One would assume that if we continue to see that happen next year, it could well be that the decline will continue to gain momentum and become harder to reverse.</p><p>What happens once the pandemic eases? There is reason to believe that will relieve some of the pressure that we've seen weighing down on the democracy scores of countries across the world. We will have to wait and see where the data takes us next year.</p><p><br/></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/democracy-2657249124/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Chauncey Devega, Salon</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-gallows-set-up-by-the-capitol-rioters-screengrab.png?id=27789537&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/png">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavrov's comparison of Zelensky to Hitler blasted by Israel, Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/lavrov-s-comparison-of-zelensky-to-hitler-blasted-by-israel-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748573&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="760a73089d8aa2b3274578ab5fe0f617" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="850a3" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748576&width=980"/><figcaption>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov speaks during a press conference in Moscow. -/Russian Foreign Ministry/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Israeli and Ukrainian leaders have denounced Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov's comparison of Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky to Hitler as inaccurate and insulting.</p>
<p>Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba said his counterpart in Moscow "could not help hiding the deeply-rooted anti-Semitism of the Russian elites."</p>
<p>"His heinous remarks are offensive to [Zelensky], Ukraine, Israel, and the Jewish people. More broadly, they demonstrate that today’s Russia is full of hatred towards other nations," he wrote on Twitter.</p>
<p>Lavrov had defended Russian President Vladimir Putin's goal of the "de-Nazification" of Ukraine with war and said Zelensky's Jewish ancestry did not undermine Putin's position.</p>
<p>Lavrov said that Zelensky may indeed be a Jew, but "Adolf Hitler also had Jewish blood."</p>
<p>"That does not mean anything at all. The wise Jewish people say that the most keen anti-Semites are usually Jews," he told Italian TV channel Rete4 on Sunday evening, prompting outrage in Israel.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett said Monday that Lavrov's words were "untrue and their intentions are wrong."</p>
<p>"The goal of such lies is to accuse the Jews themselves of the most awful crimes in history, which were perpetrated against them," he said in a statement.</p>
<p>In a similar vein, Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid said the remarks were "an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error."</p>
<p>Lapid continued: "My grandfather was not killed by Jews, but by Nazis." He told Lavrov to "open a history book."</p>
<p>Six million Jews were murdered by Nazi Germans and their collaborators during the Holocaust.</p>
<p>Ukraine, then part of the Soviet Union, was also occupied by Nazi Germany during World War II. Researchers estimate that at least 1.5 million Jews were murdered on what is today the territory of Ukraine, according to US Holocaust Memorial Museum.</p>
<p>The Israeli Ministry of Foreign Affairs summoned the Russian ambassador to Israel for clarifications on Lavrov's comments.</p>
<p>Dani Dayan, head of the Israeli Holocaust memorial Yad Vashem, called Lavrov's remarks as quoted as "absurd, delusional, dangerous and deserving of condemnation."</p>
<p>"Lavrov is propagating the inversion of the Holocaust - turning the victims into the criminals on the basis of promoting a completely unfounded claim that Hitler was of Jewish descent," he said in a statement.</p>
<p>"Equally serious is calling the Ukrainians in general, and President Zelensky in particular, Nazis. This, among other things, is a complete distortion of the history and an affront to the victims of Nazism."</p>
<p>German government spokesperson Steffen Hebestreit called Lavrov's statement "absurd."</p>
<p>"I think the Russian propaganda that is being made in this case by Foreign Minister Lavrov does not need to be commented on any further," he said in Berlin.</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="95c384e262241b47887f62fdeb22b02c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="6fe8a" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748579&width=980"/><figcaption>A photo released by the Ukraine Presidency on Sunday 1 May 2022 shows Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky arriving to receive Speaker of the United States House of Representatives Nancy Pelosi during her visit to Ukraine. -/Ukraine Presidency/dpa</figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/lavrov-s-comparison-of-zelensky-to-hitler-blasted-by-israel-ukraine/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Israel</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748573&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Commission accuses Apple of breaking bloc's competition rules</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-commission-accuses-apple-of-breaking-bloc-s-competition-rules/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748210&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="eaf03776947e1b7e591bb27771fd2bb7" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="24f0f" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748212&width=980"/><figcaption>The logo of the technology company Apple is seen at the Apple Store in downtown Munich. Apple is infringing EU competition rules with its Apple Pay system, the European Commission has found after months of preliminary investigation. Sven Hoppe/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>US tech giant Apple is infringing EU competition rules with its Apple Pay system, the European Commission has found after months of preliminary investigation.</p>
<p>The commission has "indications that Apple restricted third-party access to key technology" to the benefit of Apple products, European Competition Commissioner Margrethe Vestager said in a statement.</p>
<p>The European Union's top competition regulator contends that access restrictions for developers around mobile wallet technology on Apple's IOS operating system distorts market competition and suppresses innovation.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-commission-accuses-apple-of-breaking-bloc-s-competition-rules/</guid>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Eu</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748210&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's Bolshoi drops shows by two directors who spoke out against war</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-s-bolshoi-drops-shows-by-two-directors-who-spoke-out-against-war/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748214&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="87b8da802f1baa0a3845091cb1c696d2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b6280" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748220&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>LONDON (Reuters) - Russia's Bolshoi Theatre has upset opera and ballet fans by abruptly cancelling a series of shows this week by directors who have spoken out against the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The theatre gave no reason for dropping Timofey Kuliabin's production of the opera "Don Pasquale" and Kirill Serebrennikov's ballet "Nureyev".</p>
<p>Kuliabin has used his Instagram account to express solidarity with Ukraine and ridicule Russia's description of its actions there. In one post, he showed a mocked-up version of the cover of Leo Tolstoy's "War and Peace", replacing the first word of the title with "Special Operation" - the term used by the Kremlin to describe the invasion.</p>
<p>Serebrennikov told France 24 in an interview last month that "it's quite obvious that Russia started the war", and that it was breaking his heart.</p>
<p>"It's war, it's killing people, it's the worst thing (that) ever might happen with civilisation, with mankind... It's a humanitarian catastrophe, it's rivers of blood," he said.</p>
<p>Both directors are currently outside Russia.</p>
<p>The replacement of the two shows with "The Barber of Seville" and "Spartacus", two longstanding staples of the Bolshoi's repertoire, drew hundreds of mostly critical online comments from ticketholders. Many demanded in vain to know the reason.</p>
<p>"What disrespect to the spectators and artists!" one woman, Valeria, wrote on the Bolshoi's Telegram channel.</p>
<p>There was particular outrage at the cancellation of Serebrennikov's "Nureyev", a controversial production that premiered at the Bolshoi in 2017. The story of dancer Rudolf Nureyev, who defected to the West in 1961, included a tender scene with his gay lover that tested the Kremlin's tolerance for what it calls "homosexual propaganda".</p>
<p>(Reporting by Mark Trevelyan; Editing by Peter Graff)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-s-bolshoi-drops-shows-by-two-directors-who-spoke-out-against-war/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748214&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tears and chocolate as New Zealand opens its borders to 60 more countries</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/tears-and-chocolate-as-new-zealand-opens-its-borders-to-60-more-countries/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747543&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="27da19d5011f38ac5502990c1e5bdbdd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9aeaa" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747545&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Lucy Craymer</p>
<p>WELLINGTON (Reuters) - New Zealand welcomed thousands of travellers from around the globe on Monday as the country opened its borders to visitors from around 60 nations including the United States, Britain and Singapore for the first time since COVID-19 hit in early 2020.</p>
<p>Maori cultural performers sang songs at the arrivals gate in Auckland and travellers were handed popular locally made chocolate bars as the first flights came in from Los Angeles and San Francisco.</p>
<p>Friends and family hugged and cried as people were reunited for what was for some the first time in more than two years.</p>
<p>Garth Halliday, who was waiting at the airport for his son, daughter-in-law and grandson to land from London, told local media it made him happy and emotional to see so many families reunited.</p>
<p>New Zealand had some of the toughest curbs in the world during the pandemic and only recently started to ease the increasingly unpopular measures, hoping to boost tourism and ease labour shortages now the Omicron variant is widespread domestically.</p>
<p>Borders were opened to New Zealanders and Australians in February and March. Now visitors from around 60 visa-waiver countries can enter as long as they are vaccinated and test negative for COVID. There are no requirements for isolation.</p>
<p>New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern told attendees at the U.S. Business Summit in Auckland that overseas visitors will really "bring back a piece that has been missing from New Zealand and New Zealanders."</p>
<p>On Monday, 43 international flights were scheduled to arrive or depart from Auckland International Airport carrying around 9,000 passengers.</p>
<p>Air New Zealand Chief Customer and Sales Officer Leanne Geraghty said demand had exceeded expectations with many of the services filling up.</p>
<p>"This is welcome news for the New Zealand tourism industry who has weathered a difficult storm," she said.</p>
<p>Tourists from a number of countries including India and China continue to be barred with restrictions for them not being lifted until October.</p>
<p>(The story is updated to correct day of the week in first paragraph)</p>
<p>(Reporting by Lucy Craymer; Editing by Lincoln Feast)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/tears-and-chocolate-as-new-zealand-opens-its-borders-to-60-more-countries/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747543&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>