<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>(ISC)² Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/</link>
    <description>Voice of the Certified Cybersecurity Professional</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:15:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>http://www.typepad.com/</generator>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/isc2Blog" />
    <feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="isc2blog" />
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <item>
      <title>CCSP Exam – Many Changes on the Way!</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/05/ccsp-exam-many-changes-on-the-way.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/05/ccsp-exam-many-changes-on-the-way.html</guid>
      <description>On August 1, several changes will be made to the CCSP exam. We are excited to share that the CCSP exam will be available in four more languages. Currently, the CCSP exam is available in English and Japanese. We will also be offering the CCSP exam in Chinese, Korean, German and Spanish beginning in August. In addition to these new languages, we will be updating the length of the CCSP exam. As announced earlier this year for the CISSP exam, 25 pre-test (unscored) items will be added to the exams in all languages. These items do not impact the pass/fail...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-contrast="auto"> <a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e152ead5200b-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2022-04-29 at 9.49.31 AM" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b6788340282e152ead5200b img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e152ead5200b-120wi" style="margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="Screen Shot 2022-04-29 at 9.49.31 AM" /></a>On August 1, several changes will be made to the CCSP exam. We are excited to share that the CCSP exam will be available in four more languages. Currently, the CCSP exam is available in English and Japanese. We will also be offering the CCSP exam in Chinese, Korean, German and Spanish beginning in August.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">In addition to these new languages, we will be updating the length of the CCSP exam. As announced earlier this year for the </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/notice/Cissp-exam-length"><span data-contrast="none">CISSP exam,</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> 25 pre-test (unscored) items will be added to the exams in all languages. These items do not impact the pass/fail result of a candidate’s exam, but they are indistinguishable from operational (scored) items, so if you’re taking the exam, you should consider each item carefully and select the best possible answer. To allow candidates sufficient time to answer all items, the time limit for the CCSP exam is increasing from three to four hours.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Lastly, as announced in December 2021, the CCSP exam content will be refreshed on August 1. Specifically, Domain 2: Cloud Data Security will increase from 19% to 20% and Domain 5: Cloud Security Operations will decrease from 17% to 16%. You can find the August 1, 2022 version of the CCSP Exam Outline here </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Certifications/Exam-Outlines/CCSP-Exam-Outline-2022.ashx"><span data-contrast="none">https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Certifications/Exam-Outlines/CCSP-Exam-Outline-2022.ashx</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> with additional languages coming soon to the </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/Certifications/CCSP/Certification-Exam-Outline"><span data-contrast="none">CCSP Exam Outline page</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">If you’re registered for the CCSP after August 1, but would like to move your exam up before these changes go into effect, </span><span data-contrast="auto">you may do so by </span><a href="https://home.pearsonvue.com/isc2/contact"><span data-contrast="none">contacting Pearson VUE</span><span data-contrast="auto">.</span></a> <span data-contrast="auto">If you have any questions at all about these changes, please contact our Exam Administration team</span><span data-contrast="none"> at </span><a href="mailto:examadministration@isc2.org"><span data-contrast="none">examadministration@isc2.org</span></a><span data-contrast="none">.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=_s9fJZqOkHE:JDMhVMiaw-k:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>Cloud Security</category>
      <category>Cybersecurity Certifications</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(ISC)² Hellenic Chapter Wins Award for Creating Educational Materials</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/isc2-hellenic-chapter-wins-award-for-creating-educational-materials.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/isc2-hellenic-chapter-wins-award-for-creating-educational-materials.html</guid>
      <description>The (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter was awarded the bronze award for its initiatives and activities in the category of Public Cybersecurity Awareness at the Greece Cybersecurity Awards 2022 by Boussias. The event, a first of its kind in Greece, highlighted two cybersecurity categories: Cybersecurity Projects Per Industry Sector and Cybersecurity Projects Per Solution. The chapter was one of the winners among 33 awards given. The chapter was recognized for its efforts in promoting awareness of cybersecurity to the public and creating educational materials to train children and families. The (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter members volunteer and work together to provide free trainings...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-contrast="none"> <a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e15191e0200b-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="CyberSec Awards Greece Mar22 photo 1" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b6788340282e15191e0200b img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e15191e0200b-320wi" style="margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="CyberSec Awards Greece Mar22 photo 1" /></a>The (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter was awarded the bronze award for its initiatives and activities in the category of Public Cybersecurity Awareness at the Greece Cybersecurity Awards 2022 by </span><a href="https://www.boussias.com/"><span data-contrast="none">Boussias</span></a><span data-contrast="none">. The event, a first of its kind in Greece, highlighted two cybersecurity categories: </span><span data-contrast="auto">Cybersecurity Projects Per Industry Sector and Cybersecurity Projects Per Solution</span><span data-contrast="none">. The chapter was one of the winners among 33 awards given.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">The chapter was recognized for its efforts in promoting awareness of cybersecurity to the public and creating educational materials to train children and families. The (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter members volunteer and work together to provide free trainings to the community. To date, they have conducted 11 trainings educating more than 500 individuals.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">The Chapter has created animated educational videos, </span><em><span data-contrast="none">Super CyberKids</span></em><span data-contrast="none">, appropriate for children and families, on cybersecurity topics. These videos are recorded in Greek and available to the public through the chapter’s </span><a href="https://isc2-chapter.gr/"><span data-contrast="none">website</span></a><span data-contrast="none">. They welcome professionals from public, private and educational sectors to use them in educating children.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6b503200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="CyberSec Awards Greece Mar22 photo 4" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6b503200c img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6b503200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="CyberSec Awards Greece Mar22 photo 4" /></a>The (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter was featured in the <a href="https://magazines.isc2.org/pages/2021/2021-09/something-for-everyone-at-this-years-isc2-security-congress/">InfoSecurity Professional Magazine</a> highlighting their resiliency during the Covid-19 pandemic while continuing to provide educational materials and positively impacting the community. Additionally, Board Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johniliadis/">John Iliadis</a>, PhD, CISSP-ISSMP, recently contributed to the (ISC)² blog <a href="https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/cloud-a-shakespearean-drama.html">&quot;Cloud: A Shakespearean Drama?&quot;</a> discussing the challenges we face when deciding on the best storage solutions.&#0160;</p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span><span data-contrast="none">This chapter continues to give back to the community and is a great example of (ISC)² members who inspire a safer and more secure cyber world.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{}">&#0160;</span><span data-contrast="none">For more information on joining or starting an (ISC)² Chapter, visit </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/Chapters"><span data-contrast="none">https://www.isc2.org/Chapters</span></a><span data-contrast="none">.</span></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=OAY6IiAChiM:H6k1Fc7Jl3U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>(ISC)² Chapters</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLOUD: A SHAKESPEAREAN DRAMA?</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/cloud-a-shakespearean-drama.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/cloud-a-shakespearean-drama.html</guid>
      <description>By John Iliadis, PhD, CISSP-ISSMP, CMgr MCMI, CRISC. John is an IT Infrastructure Manager; he also serves as a Board Member of (ISC)² Hellenic Chapter. Opinions expressed herein do not express the views or opinions of any third party or employer. Cloud migrations probably evoke emotions of love and hate at the same time, to most cybersecurity professionals. Going cloud (or not) presents a kind of dilemma that was first expressed some 400 years ago. Hamlet was the first one, To Cloud or Not to Cloud? The past ten years have been a turbulent period. Global financial crises emerged, while...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>By </em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johniliadis/"><em>John Iliadis</em></a><em>, PhD, CISSP-ISSMP, CMgr MCMI, CRISC. John is an IT Infrastructure Manager; he also serves as a Board Member of (ISC)²&#0160;Hellenic Chapter. Opinions expressed herein do not express the views or opinions of any third party or employer.</em></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6ae6b200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="CLOUD: A SHAKESPEAREAN DRAMA?" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6ae6b200c img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa6ae6b200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="CLOUD: A SHAKESPEAREAN DRAMA?" /></a>Cloud migrations probably evoke emotions of love and hate at the same time, to most cybersecurity professionals. Going cloud (or not) presents a kind of dilemma that was first expressed some 400 years ago. Hamlet was the first one, <em>To Cloud or Not to Cloud?</em></p>
<p>The past ten years have been a turbulent period. Global financial crises emerged, while the Great Digital Transformer (aka COVID-19) doesn’t want to part company with us; at least not yet. “The greatest danger in times of turbulence is not the turbulence; it is to act with yesterday’s logic,” according to P. Drucker. During this turbulent period, we seek the holy grail of business transformation, adapting our logic to current, emerging needs.</p>
<p>This is probably why cloud has come to attract so much attention; it seems to provide a unique transformation opportunity. The year 2020 was the first time <a href="https://www.srgresearch.com/articles/2020-the-year-that-cloud-service-revenues-finally-dwarfed-enterprise-spending-on-data-centers">cloud spending surpassed, by a lot, on-premises spending</a>.</p>
<p>Are there any side-effects to our newfound love for cloud? There’s a <a href="https://www.isc2.org/articles/cloud-configuration-what-do-you-need-to-consider">concise (ISC)²&#0160;article about that</a>. Key points: according to a <a href="https://www.trustwave.com/en-us/resources/library/documents/2020-trustwave-global-security-report/">Trustwave research</a> the volume of attacks targeting cloud services more than doubled, while according to a <a href="https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/featured/survey-security-configs-cloud/">Tripwire survey</a>, 76% of participants said it’s difficult to maintain secure configurations in the cloud. Besides that, a shortage of qualified people in cloud security is proving to be <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Landing-Pages/2021/Cloud-Adoption-and-the-Skills-Shortage/CSR-eBook.ashx">a large impediment to cloud adoption</a>. These issues should probably be factored in the decision of going cloud, especially during a period when cyber risks surpass even the types of lending and liquidity risks that led to the Great Recession in 2008, <a href="https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2021/04/cyber-threats-the-financial-systems-top-risk.html">according to Federal Reserve Chairman Jerome Powell</a>.</p>
<p>To confront with some of these issues, enterprises have started <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/About/Leadership/Annual-Reports/isc2-annual-report-2020.ashx">requiring cloud security certifications</a>, like the <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Certifications/CCSP">CCSP from (ISC)²</a>, for certain security roles within the organization. At the same time, the <a href="https://cloud.connect.isc2.org/career-pursuers-report">top area of professional development</a> that cybersecurity professionals are pursuing is cloud security.</p>
<p>What’s interesting, if not bizarre, is the fact that there are organizations that return to the on-premises world, cutting short their public cloud journey. There are no hard facts to identify, beyond a shadow of a doubt, the root causes for this return to on-premises. However, such business moves could be attributed to not-so-informed decisions about going cloud, inadvertently creating <a href="https://journalofcloudcomputing.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13677-019-0149-4">unpredictable OpEx</a> costs, while <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/05/27/cost-of-cloud-paradox-market-cap-cloud-lifecycle-scale-growth-repatriation-optimization/">having market value being lost due to cloud impact on margins</a>.</p>
<p>We have probably been treating public cloud as a panacea, while in fact public cloud is only a means to an end. An organization has to decide first what is the business goal and then decide on the means to achieve it. For any organization, public cloud is like any other infrastructure investment; it’s a tool, like a screwdriver, that can be used to serve a specific, predetermined (business) purpose.</p>
<p>Before embarking on a public cloud journey, a business case must be agreed upon, taking into consideration strategy, risks, TCO, ROI, etc. Cloud providers have even formed detailed adoption frameworks to prevent customer churn, and nudge organizations towards following said frameworks to the letter. These adoption frameworks can be used while the business case is drafted, to investigate whether public cloud is the right tool one should use as a means to achieve the business goals that have been set.</p>
<p>If there’s a solid business case that takes into consideration factors like the aforementioned, public cloud can potentially be transformed from a simple tool to an opportunity that must be exploited and a strength that must be leveraged. If no such business case exists, public cloud is just another tool. Even worse, it can become a threat and a weakness for the organization that will embark on a public cloud journey, having exercised cloudy judgment with no due diligence.</p>
<p>Perhaps Hamlet was wrong, there is no cloud dilemma, after all.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=G8KeJJXw6Xc:M8P7WpCFWhg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>Cloud Security</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Cybersecurity: Addressing the Boogeyman in the Room</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/quantum-cybersecurity-addressing-the-boogeyman-in-the-room.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/quantum-cybersecurity-addressing-the-boogeyman-in-the-room.html</guid>
      <description>Duncan Jones, Head of Cybersecurity for Cambridge Quantum, recently spoke with Fierce Electronics about quantum cybersecurity and where it’s headed. In the interview, Duncan referred to quantum as “a boogeyman for cyber,” but said “it’s also going to help us as well.” With rapidly advancing technology, as many as 80% of cyber pros believe that quantum computers will become powerful enough over the next few years to break current encryption methods. For organizations looking to prepare for the threat of quantum and figure out the best path forward, Duncan will be presenting on how to protect your organization against threats...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-contrast="auto"> <a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e1516750200b-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="SECURE-Webinar-Quantum-Cyber" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b6788340282e1516750200b img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e1516750200b-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="SECURE-Webinar-Quantum-Cyber" /></a>Duncan Jones, Head of Cybersecurity for Cambridge Quantum, </span><a href="https://www.fierceelectronics.com/electronics/quantinuums-duncan-jones-quantum-safe-encryption"><span data-contrast="none">recently spoke with Fierce Electronics</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> about quantum cybersecurity and where it’s headed. In the interview, Duncan referred to quantum as “a boogeyman for cyber,” but said “it’s also going to help us as well.” </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">With rapidly advancing technology, as many as 80% of cyber pros believe that quantum computers will become powerful enough over the next few years to break current encryption methods. For organizations looking to prepare for the threat of quantum and figure out the best path forward, Duncan will be presenting on how to protect your organization against threats to encryption – before “Q-Day” arrives. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">In his upcoming (ISC)² SECURE Webinar, </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/Events/SECURE-Webinars-EMEA"><strong><span data-contrast="none">The Threat and Promise of Quantum Cybersecurity</span></strong></a><span data-contrast="auto">, Duncan will cover </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-level="1" data-aria-posinset="1" data-font="Symbol" data-leveltext="" data-listid="1"><span data-contrast="auto">The history of the quantum threat to modern-day encryption</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></li>
<li aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-level="1" data-aria-posinset="2" data-font="Symbol" data-leveltext="" data-listid="1"><span data-contrast="auto">Adversaries’ current strategy of “hack now, decrypt later&quot;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></li>
<li aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-level="1" data-aria-posinset="3" data-font="Symbol" data-leveltext="" data-listid="1"><span data-contrast="auto">NIST algorithms and quantum-proof key generation</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></li>
<li aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-level="1" data-aria-posinset="4" data-font="Symbol" data-leveltext="" data-listid="1"><span data-contrast="auto">How to ensure a timely integration of solutions</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Speaking to Fierce Electronics, Duncan said “We’re in a position where the world has never been more in need of a foundation for protection.” </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Join us virtually for this exciting session on Monday, 25 April at 1:00 p.m. BST (8:00 a.m. EST) for The </span><strong><span data-contrast="auto">Threat and Promise of Quantum Cybersecurity. </span></strong><a href="https://web.cvent.com/event/d1bda058-2ea5-45d7-a833-03e6cd893593/regPage:617b1dc3-3ddb-4468-8087-049a4e6e51e8"><span data-contrast="none">Registration is open now</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> and priced at U.S. $99 for (ISC)² members. Plus, use the code SECURE22 at checkout and get an extra 20% off! You’ll earn 1.5 CPE credits when you attend this session, and (ISC)² will apply those to your member account on your behalf.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=E2I9cC6r4GM:rZRhmThKO4U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>(ISC)² Events</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 04:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Ransomware Attacks Increasing and How Can We Prevent Them?</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/why-are-ransomware-attacks-increasing.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/why-are-ransomware-attacks-increasing.html</guid>
      <description>Malicious cyberattacks increased exponentially in 2021. A record number of almost 850,000 complaints related to cybersecurity were recorded by Americans last year resulting in close to U.S. $7 billion lost, according to the FBI’s Internet Crime Compliant Center (IC3). Among the types of cybercrimes reported to the FBI, ransomware is on the rise and becoming more sophisticated in recent years while remote work and schooling are more prevalent. For those unaware, ransomware is a malicious software (malware) that makes a computer unusable while a cyber criminal holds data hostage until they are paid. The Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA)...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64529200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="Ransomware Attacks Increasing" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64529200c img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64529200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="Ransomware Attacks Increasing" /></a>Malicious cyberattacks increased exponentially in 2021. A record number of almost 850,000 complaints related to cybersecurity were recorded by Americans last year resulting in close to U.S. $7 billion lost, according to the <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/PDF/AnnualReport/2021_IC3Report.pdf">FBI’s Internet Crime Compliant Center (IC3)</a>.</p>
<p>Among the types of cybercrimes reported to the FBI, ransomware is on the rise and becoming more sophisticated in recent years while remote work and schooling are more prevalent. For those unaware, ransomware is a malicious software (malware) that makes a computer unusable while a cyber criminal holds data hostage until they are paid.</p>
<p>The Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/alerts/aa22-040a">reports</a> that ransomware tactics and techniques have continued to evolve and become a larger threat.</p>
<p>In response to several high-profile cyberattacks, (ISC)² commissioned a research report, “<a href="https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2021/12/isc2-ransomware-study.html">Ransomware in the C-Suite: What Cybersecurity Leaders Need to Know About What Executives Need to Hear</a>,” to offer executives and cybersecurity teams recommended actions to bolster ransomware defenses. The report offers five key tips for cybersecurity leaders to consider when discussing ransomware threats with executives. To learn more about the five key tips and what executives want to know about ransomware threats, visit: <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Research/Ransomware-Study">https://www.isc2.org/Research/Ransomware-Study</a>.</p>
<p>In 2021, 14 out of 16 critical infrastructure sectors considered vital to the United States were victimized with reports of 649 ransomware attacks. The healthcare and public health industry was the hardest hit by ransomware followed by the financial services sector. The IC3 expects that critical infrastructures will continue to be heavily targeted in 2022 and beyond.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/sites/default/files/publications/AA22-040A_2021_Trends_Show_Increased_Globalized_Threat_of_Ransomware_508.pdf">2021 Trends Report</a> by cybersecurity authorities in the United States, Australia and the United Kingdom recognize ransomware as one of the biggest cyber threats and provide suggested actions to take to protect against ransomware including: updating operating systems and software, implementing user training for awareness of suspicious links, using Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP), having offline backups and using multifactor authentication (MFA).</p>
<p>Education and awareness are the keys to preventing ransomware. To help increase ransomware education and prevention, the <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Development">(ISC)² Professional Development Institute</a> offers the course <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Development/Express-Learning-Courses/Ransomware-Identify-Protect-Detect-Recover">Ransomware: Identify, Protect, Detect, Recover</a>. This online course is free for (ISC)² members and associates as part of your member benefits.</p>
<p>Join for free and read what your peers have to say about <a href="https://community.isc2.org/t5/Industry-News/Federal-Government-2021-Ransomware-statistics/m-p/50282#M5744">ransomware</a> as they discuss the latest topics like this on the <a href="https://community.isc2.org/">(ISC)² Community</a>.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=pNKn0G_fKJ4:c2mBkjBzRR4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>Ransomware</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Service and Diversity – Nominate a Colleague Today!</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/celebrating-service-and-diversity.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/celebrating-service-and-diversity.html</guid>
      <description>Great team members like yours help our cybersecurity community share education, host stellar events, create a sense of community and continue to grow. The (ISC)² Global Achievement Awards honors these contributors annually. This year’s award winners will be highlighted during (ISC)² Security Congress being held in person in Las Vegas and online globally, October 10-12. The (ISC)² James R. Wade Service Award highlights the engagement of volunteers who merit special distinction for their sustained and valuable service to (ISC)². Those who volunteer to support the greater cybersecurity community to help promote a safe and secure cyber world are valued in...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402788076e431200d-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="EVENTS-GAA-2022-Nominations-Open-230x240" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402788076e431200d img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402788076e431200d-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="EVENTS-GAA-2022-Nominations-Open-230x240" /></a>Great team members like yours help our cybersecurity community share education, host stellar events, create a sense of community and continue to grow. The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/About/Award-Programs">(ISC)² Global Achievement Awards</a> honors these contributors annually. This year’s award winners will be highlighted during <a href="https://congress.isc2.org/event/ddd188c4-b9cd-4eb0-bd9a-2c7810df496e/summary">(ISC)² Security Congress</a> being held in person in Las Vegas and online globally, October 10-12.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/About/Award-Programs/Service-Award">(ISC)² James R. Wade Service Award</a> highlights the engagement of volunteers who merit special distinction for their sustained and valuable service to (ISC)². Those who volunteer to support the greater cybersecurity community to help promote a safe and secure cyber world are valued in our network. Do you know an active (ISC)² volunteer whose impact should be rewarded? Consider nominating them today. &#0160;</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.isc2.org/About/Award-Programs/Diversity-Award">(ISC)² Diversity Award</a> celebrates individuals who represent the core values of our association through impactful contributions that drive us toward a more diverse cybersecurity workforce. Last year’s Diversity Award recipient for the Asia-Pacific Region and <a href="https://www.isc2.org/About/Award-Programs/Mid-Career-Professional-Award">(ISC)² Mid-Career Professional Award</a> winner Neha Malhotra, CISSP, CCSP said, “A never give-up attitude is so important in life as it is in our profession of defending our digital footprint. It also brings me great joy and motivation, reflecting on all the challenges I have overcome so far. More so, winning these awards really firms up my belief that I am on the right trajectory, and leaves me super inspired to put in even more efforts, continue learning and contributing to the security profession and industry with the best of my capabilities, and motivate others to do so as well.”</p>
<p>Do you know someone who fits this distinction? Consider nominating them today. Showcase a colleague that has significantly impacted the advancement of diversity in our field by suggesting them for this award! Nominable actions can be through an engagement activity such as scholarships, advocacy, nonprofit work, or other means to create a level playing field for the inclusion of all individuals in the world of cybersecurity.</p>
<p><em>&#0160;</em>Nominations for the above categories are open to all (ISC)² members and will remain available through May 13. See the full list of <a href="https://www.isc2.org/About/Award-Programs">award opportunities and submit an application</a> to honor an impactful professional.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=WkHQSIn-fA4:tgk6W7cQYB0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>(ISC)² Events</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does Volunteering at (ISC)² Mean? Hear From Volunteer Lisa Vaughan</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/volunteering.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/volunteering.html</guid>
      <description>Volunteering is at the heart of the mission of (ISC)². The individuals who offer their time, skills and knowledge positively impact their community helping create a safer and more secure cyber world. We want to highlight some of our volunteers, the impact they make on the cybersecurity profession and the world at large during annual Volunteer Appreciation Week. We interviewed Lisa Vaughan, CISSP to discuss her cybersecurity career, the various volunteer roles she has held at (ISC)² and the impact volunteering has on her life. Lisa is the Executive Director, Information Technology for Hexagon U.S. Federal. In addition to holding...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e14fc361200b-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="Volunteer-Get-Involved" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b6788340282e14fc361200b img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340282e14fc361200b-500wi" style="margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="Volunteer-Get-Involved" /></a><a href="https://www.isc2.org/Volunteer">Volunteering</a> is at the heart of the mission of (ISC)². The individuals who offer their time, skills and knowledge positively impact their community helping create a safer and more secure cyber world.</p>
<p>We want to highlight some of our volunteers, the impact they make on the cybersecurity profession and the world at large during annual Volunteer Appreciation Week.</p>
<p>We interviewed Lisa Vaughan, CISSP to discuss her cybersecurity career, the various volunteer roles she has held at (ISC)² and the impact volunteering has on her life.</p>
<p>Lisa is the Executive Director, Information Technology for <a href="https://hexagonusfederal.com/">Hexagon U.S. Federal</a>. In addition to holding the CISSP, she also has the PMP certification.</p>
<p><strong>Where did your career begin? What prompted your initial interest in cybersecurity? </strong></p>
<p>I’ve been in the IT industry for about 37 years. So, I was doing cybersecurity before it was recognized as a “thing.” I began my IT career as a computer programmer. I built applications that performed data validation to eliminate data integrity issues, credential verification that validated users, and became involved in the physical security aspects of data centers as a computer operations technician. I also learned the skill of cryptography that I was able to creatively introduce into legacy programming languages.</p>
<p>I’ve worked in many different industries throughout my career. When I was working for a large healthcare organization, I had the opportunity to move into cybersecurity. My CIO said, “Go get that certification and we’ll move you into InfoSec.” That journey started with obtaining my CISSP and becoming a member of (ISC)² in 2013. My (ISC)² membership has been a great enhancement to my career through continuing education and training through the <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Development">(ISC)² Professional Development Institute</a>, <a href="https://www.isc2.org/News-and-Events/Webinars">webinars</a> and other information that is provided as part of my (ISC)² membership. I’ve been incorporating this knowledge into my leadership roles in information technology and information security.</p>
<p><strong>Describe your volunteer journey and what encouraged you to volunteer with (ISC)²? </strong></p>
<p>I began volunteering with (ISC)² as a <a href="https://congress.isc2.org/">Security Congress</a> volunteer in 2017. I became interested in volunteering after attending the 2016 Security Congress where I recognized the gender gap in the cybersecurity workforce, specifically the number of women in cybersecurity careers. This motivated me to reach out to (ISC)² staff to find out how I could volunteer in ways that would help make a <a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64e49200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="(ISC)2 Ambassadors" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64e49200c img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa64e49200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="(ISC)2 Ambassadors" /></a><br />difference.&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>What volunteer roles have you participated in at (ISC)² and how has that been beneficial? </strong></p>
<p>My volunteerism with (ISC)² has spanned quite a few areas. Each of these volunteer opportunities has been unique and has provided me with opportunities to meet other (ISC)² members from across the globe. It has been very rewarding!</p>
<ul>
<li>Security Congress Volunteer
<ul>
<li>Benefit: Assisting (ISC)² to ensure a successful experience for attendees and meeting other volunteers from across the globe.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Security Congress Ambassador
<ul>
<li>Benefit: Similar experience to being a volunteer and provided the opportunity to share information and experiences with others as a Security Congress Ambassador.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Security Congress Presenter</li>
<ul>
<li>Benefit: One especially meaningful experience that I had was meeting someone with whom I served on a panel at a prior Security Congress. I had not met this person before serving on the panel with them. When I described to this person the struggles that my local chapter was having with finances and local participation, she made a significant financial contribution that allowed us to hold several events that extended our reach and got more local members involved. It changed the course of that chapter for the better.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>President of a local <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Chapters">(ISC)² Chapter</a>
<ul>
<li>Benefit: Growing the cybersecurity community in my local area.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.isc2.org/Membership/CPE-Opportunities">Exam Item-Writing Workshop</a>/Item-Re-writing Workshop
<ul>
<li>Benefits: Increasing my cyber knowledge! It’s not easy to write questions that have multiple answers to choose from . Another benefit was meeting other cybersecurity practitioners from around the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Chapter Advisory Committee
<ul>
<li>Benefits: Helping the (ISC)² Chapter leadership team continue to enhance the programs and resources that are offered by chapters, supporting chapters that are struggling and need a little help, sharing ideas with a group of people who are all interested in making the chapter program a success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Global Advocacy Committee
<ul>
<li>Benefits: Working with the (ISC)² CEO and other leaders within the organization to create opportunities for (ISC)² to have greater influence in the advocacy of serving the global cyber security community.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340278807891ee200d-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="(ISC)2 Volunteers at Congress" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b6788340278807891ee200d img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b6788340278807891ee200d-320wi" style="margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="(ISC)2 Volunteers at Congress" /></a>Volunteering is very important to me, and I encourage all cybersecurity professionals to get involved with volunteer activities as it benefits the greater community. Having the opportunity to meet other (ISC)² members and work with the talented staff at (ISC)² has allowed me to create lasting friendships – you can’t put a price tag on that!</p>
<p><strong>Where would you encourage others to spend their time volunteering at (ISC)²? </strong></p>
<p>There is a diverse selection of volunteer opportunities within (ISC)². I’d like to think there is something for everyone. The thousands of (ISC)² members bring their own unique set of skills, education, and experiences that can be used in a variety of ways. I would encourage every member to just get involved!</p>
<p><strong>How has your engagement with (ISC)² (including volunteering, professional networking, educational experiences, etc.) positively impacted your career? </strong></p>
<p>I’ve been able to mentor people who are not as far along in their career, which has helped me build that mentoring skillset that I can apply in my workplace. I’ve also met some outstanding professionals who I’ve been able to reach out to when I’ve had questions, concerns, and even technology and staffing needs. The exposure from volunteering with (ISC)² has also led to other professional speaking engagements where I’ve been able to share experiences and further expand my professional network.&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>What do you look forward to the most for (ISC)² and the cybersecurity industry?</strong></p>
<p>I’m so excited that we will be able to meet for Security Congress in person this year! It will be a great event in Las Vegas, and I can’t wait to re-connect with friends and colleagues there!</p>
<p>As our world continues to rely on technology in almost every aspect of our lives, cybersecurity will become increasingly more important and challenging. The (ISC)² organization is helping its members to be prepared for these challenges.</p>
<p><strong><em>Fun fact:</em></strong> I attended a CISSP boot camp in Orlando, FL, in 2013, where I met a fellow classmate named David Shearer. Yes, that’s the one – former CEO of (ISC)². Luckily, we both passed the exam on the first try. It was a PAPER exam!</p>
<p>Our volunteer portal makes it easy for anyone to become an (ISC)<sup>2</sup> Volunteer with a <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Volunteer/How-to-Volunteer">three-step process</a> of creating a profile, completing an interest form, and reviewing a few important policy documents. If you’d like to become more involved with (ISC)<sup>2</sup>, you can learn about many <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Volunteer/Volunteer-Opportunities">volunteer opportunities</a> and complete a <a href="https://www.isc2.org/volunteer/volunteer-interest">volunteer interest form</a>.&#0160;</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=JMipUDqNUEw:_poBrHyS06w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>(ISC)² Chapters</category>
      <category>(ISC)² Events</category>
      <category>Center for Cyber Safety and Education</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 07:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SECURE London stokes debate on the future of the cybersecurity workforce</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/secure-london-stokes-debate-on-the-future-of-the-cybersecurity-workforce.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/secure-london-stokes-debate-on-the-future-of-the-cybersecurity-workforce.html</guid>
      <description>April’s event calendar kicked off with (ISC)² SECURE London, a return to regional events for (ISC)² members and a conference that took place amid an unprecedented time for our industry and for practitioners. A global skills gap of over 2.7 million, years of disruption due to the pandemic and unprecedented digital transformation, geopolitical strife at the doorstep of Europe generating global cyberattack fallout and profound changes in the threats being faced and the technologies, tools and tactics that counter them. The day began with a keynote from Chris Ensor, Deputy Director for Cyber Skills and Growth at the NCSC. Ensor...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa4dc6f200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="EVENTS-SS-Digitell-SECURE_SUMMIT_London-Web-Banners-300x525-Site-Icon" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa4dc6f200c img-responsive" height="502" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa4dc6f200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="EVENTS-SS-Digitell-SECURE_SUMMIT_London-Web-Banners-300x525-Site-Icon" width="287" /></a>April’s event calendar kicked off with <a href="https://www.isc2.org/Events/SECURE-London">(ISC)² SECURE London</a>, a return to regional events for (ISC)² members and a conference that took place amid an unprecedented time for our industry and for practitioners. A global skills gap of over 2.7 million, years of disruption due to the pandemic and unprecedented digital transformation, geopolitical strife at the doorstep of Europe generating global cyberattack fallout and profound changes in the threats being faced and the technologies, tools and tactics that counter them.</p>
<p>The day began with a keynote from <a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/section/about-ncsc/ncsc-leadership#section_5">Chris Ensor</a>, Deputy Director for Cyber Skills and Growth at the NCSC. Ensor discussed the lifecycle of the cybersecurity industry in the UK, the emerging similarities with other much-relied-upon sectors such as the medical profession, but also how organizations are struggling more than those in other sectors to clearly define roles and ensure skills development that meets the needs of the profession. Ensor talked about the critical role that education plays in addressing the workforce challenge, but also how many current efforts create a near 10-year lead time before they will impact the near three-million global cybersecurity skills shortage. How do we make meaningful progress today? Through initiatives that bring more people into the profession quickly, without compromising quality and by overcoming the insistence on high levels of experience for every role, right down to the entry-level.</p>
<p><strong>A tale of two tracks</strong></p>
<p>Dual tracks allowed attendees to explore a variety of themes, from how to plan and deliver a successful security awareness program, told from the perspective of Data Protection Officer (DPO) Laurie-Anne Bourdain, CISSP from Isabel Group. Meanwhile, Paul Schwarzenberger, CISSP, a cloud security specialist from Celidor took attendees on a security deep dive into the three prevailing cloud platforms to determine which came out on top. Schwarzenberger looked at everyday use cases and live demonstrations to compare the security architectures and features across AWS, GCP and Azure.</p>
<p>Prevention of internal security issues was examined in detail by Dave Cartwright, CISSP, the Head of IT Risk and Security at Standard Bank ICS. Cartwright’s talk, developed from a recent magazine article he wrote on the same issue, examined how regardless of the investment in training, education, policy and more, organizations will still face human induced cyber risk, simply because eventually someone will do something they shouldn’t – be it intentionally or accidentally. Determining how to react and when is key to minimizing repeat incidents. As is defining whether a documented policy can apply to all instances. Going zero-tolerance can be counter-productive, while going zero-blame can also result in a lack of remedy from repeat offenders if there is no motivation to improve.</p>
<p>Current geopolitical and health issues have put the importance of robust supply chain cybersecurity in stark focus. (ISC)² CISO Jon France explored the latest developments and impacts on supply chains and critical infrastructure, discussing how supply chain cybersecurity practices have had to change and adapt in the face of COVID, digital attack, and an increasingly interconnected world of infrastructure.</p>
<p>Diversity, equity and inclusion (DEI) is at the forefront of industry efforts to expand both the workforce and the talent pool, as well as make cybersecurity a more welcoming and accessible career path for more people. A panel bringing together Andrew Elliot, deputy director of cyber security innovation and skills at DCMS, Richard Yorke, managing director of Cyber Cheltenham, Catherine Burn, associate director at cybersecurity recruiter LT Harper and Dr. Sanjana Mehta, Advocacy Director at (ISC)² explored with the audience what a diverse ecosystem means, who must be involved to deliver a successful diversity and inclusion effort and debated why a more inclusive cyber profession will ultimately ensure the delivery of a safer cyber world for individuals and organizations alike.</p>
<p><strong>The power of the crowd</strong></p>
<p>The technical side of cybersecurity was then put under the microscope, first by Alex Haynes, CISSP, the CISO at software provider CDL, then by Joseph Carson, CISSP, chief security scientist and advisory CISO at access management provider Delinea. Haynes provided a deep dive into the concept of crowdsourced security. For the last decade, crowdsourced security has had a fundamental impact on pentesting, but it’s not without risks. As well as discussing the pros and cons, Haynes also provided attendees with insight into how the approach has been weaponized in the Ukraine conflict and has impacted innocent bystanders. Carson wrapped up the technical sessions with an extensive look at ransomware incidents and a step-by-step demonstration of an attack and how to effectively respond to it.</p>
<p>The day concluded with an interactive (ISC)² Insights session. This was a chance for attendees to pose questions to a panel comprised of (ISC)²&#0160;CEO Clar Rosso, CISO Jon France, CISSP and board member Yiannis Pavlosoglou, CISSP, Attendees quizzed the panel on a variety of subjects including plans for the forthcoming Entry-Level Cybersecurity Certification, dealing with the UK and global skills gap, the potential for government regulation of cybersecurity professional development and the role of a no-blame culture in cybersecurity response and remediation.</p>
<p>For (ISC)², SECURE London also represented an important milestone, the first purely in-person event we have staged as an organization since the COVID-19 pandemic took hold. Safely bringing together representatives from across our industry to meet, network and debate has been something we’ve looked forward to doing for a long time, with the results well worth the wait.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=oEFkdq6FBZU:Tqv6lFVZjo0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <category>(ISC)² Events</category>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 12:24:17 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WINNING TACTICS FOR SECURITY AWARENESS INNOVATIONS via EXPERIENCE (2 of 2)</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/winning-tactics-for-security-awareness2.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/winning-tactics-for-security-awareness2.html</guid>
      <description>By Samuel Rugi, an MSc Information technology (Security), Certified Information Security Professional (CISSP), Certified Information Security Management (CISM), Cybersecurity Mentor at the Cyversity Organization and a Co-Chair Leadership LaunchPad at Technology Association of Oregon. Key Items to Consider for an Impactful Security Awareness Agenda 1 - Identify and understand security drivers and what they mean to the business. Confidentiality Integrity Availability 2 - Interlink those critical drivers with the following security themes. People Technology Data and Privacy Processes 3 - Understand the business environment. Threats Customers Public Community (Local, Regional, Continental and Global) Governance Structures Political, Social, Religious and Economic...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>By </em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuelrugi20/"><em>Samuel Rugi</em></a><em>, an MSc Information technology (Security), Certified Information Security Professional (CISSP), Certified Information Security Management (CISM), Cybersecurity Mentor at the Cyversity Organization and a Co-Chair Leadership LaunchPad at Technology Association of Oregon.</em></p>
<p><strong> <a class="asset-img-link" href="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa1be0c200c-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="Winning Tactics2" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402942fa1be0c200c img-responsive" src="https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402942fa1be0c200c-320wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="Winning Tactics2" /></a>Key Items to Consider for an Impactful Security Awareness Agenda</strong></p>
<p>1 - Identify and understand security drivers and what they mean to the business.</p>
<ul>
<li>Confidentiality</li>
<li>Integrity</li>
<li>Availability</li>
</ul>
<p>2 - Interlink those critical drivers with the following security themes.</p>
<ul>
<li>People</li>
<li>Technology</li>
<li>Data and Privacy</li>
<li>Processes</li>
</ul>
<p>3 - Understand the business environment.</p>
<ul>
<li>Threats</li>
<li>Customers</li>
<li>Public Community (Local, Regional, Continental and Global)</li>
<li>Governance Structures</li>
<li>Political, Social, Religious and Economic Triggers</li>
</ul>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>Tools and Resources to Consider to be Successful and Keep Winning</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Governance Body</strong>: While it&#39;s easy to do a lot of communication in an organization, it can be an uphill task with slim chances of success if you don&#39;t have the blessing of a security governance body at the executive leadership. Most organizations call this the Cybersecurity Committee (SC) or Cybersecurity Boards. If you don&#39;t have one, influence and get one. It&#39;s a critical body in the security programs while determining industry frameworks and standards to emulate and the impact on the business and their value addition.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Security Policies</strong>: Policies, Standards, Procedures and Guidelines - This tool comes from your security program, which addresses the security strategy for the organization; make sure the communication strategy is well articulated or in line with the governance tools. They also need to be timely revised as per your organization&#39;s business requirements and cyber risk management strategy.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Security Metrics and Reports</strong>: Collect KPI and KRI and report to the governance body. This help in making sure you are hitting the maturity milestone that you have set up, so they need to be storytelling, actionable, on time, and consistent. KPI would come from technology and program features, while KRI would mainly come from data gathered from the effectiveness of security controls and tools.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Security Data Context</strong>: Collecting data and information and presenting it is exceptional. However, the security value and return on investment are only identifiable through the in-house Cyber/information security body of Knowledge from deep security analysis and Cyber/Security Wisdom ripening, as an organization matures. Both provide the executive with a deep security check, the organization with insights, as security evolves and responds to new challenges daily.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Affiliation</strong>: The organization and security personnel need to join Cybersecurity industry-recognized bodies like (ISC)², where one can learn or gather more intelligence, free tools and resource to improve your program and security posture. Internal affiliation is also essential.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Highly Skilled Cybersecurity Professional</strong>: Indeed, one needs an excellent formal education, i.e., a bachelor&#39; or Master&#39;s degree or at least undertaking specialized training in an institution of higher learning is an advantage. The academic skillsets required to succeed in driving change within a homogeneous business environment facing a competitive business terrain.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Formal Education Attributes</strong>: Combined with experience helps one to develop intellectual judgment, independent analytical and security mindset, equipped with skills to collect, present statistics and trends, understand business acumen and tools and how to tailor communication from a security perspective to fit into an evolving business requirement. Today, it is good to remember that most organizations&#39; decisions are made or driven by highly successful academic intellects; one needs them to succeed effortlessly with a zero-dollar investment.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Develop Security Communication Strategy</strong>: Like any other communication strategy, it&#39;s vital to have a security-driven communication strategy highlighting stakeholders&#39; key roles and responsibilities. The communication lifecycle should keep track of the maturity level of the program.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Champions</strong>: Influencing good behaviors requires dedicated security champions. These are individuals who necessarily don&#39;t work in a security team but have a great interest in advocating for security matters within their business unit. Empower them with resources, create time to collaborate, brainstorm with them, and ensure the leadership recognizes their effort.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Communication Tools/Platform</strong>: Established a centralized location where all security resources are shared. And accessible to all the parties you wish to reach. The Communication and Human resources team may already have one that you could leverage and save cost.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Training and Benchmarks</strong>: Attend tailored security or communication training to advance your staff knowledge in this domain. Learn from specialized industry experts and keep track of your trends, check on how others are responding to cyber challenges. It&#39;s information available for free or open-source resource yet a powerful tool to help develop your strategies. Industry conferences and meetups provide fantastic resources to test new tools or gather new findings as the cybersecurity industry evolves.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Budget</strong>: As the organization&#39;s security awareness program starts taking shape and you have supporting evidence for the maturity level, it is probably a good time to start budgeting for tailored security training and championing efforts in the annual, quarterly or multi-year strategic plan.</li>
</ul><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=eb7727l-9LU:WzdxCJLYCPM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Stand with All of You</title>
      <link>https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/isc2-dei-statement.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2022/04/isc2-dei-statement.html</guid>
      <description>(ISC)² Organizational Statement in Opposition of Anti-DEI Legislation As the world’s foremost cybersecurity professional organization, (ISC)² is leading the charge to ensure our profession reflects the diversity of the world we serve. Diversity, equity and inclusion are strategic priorities for the individuals and organizations (ISC)² represents, and we believe that inspiring a safe and secure cyber world means ensuring a diverse, equitable and inclusive cybersecurity profession. Today, our profession does not reflect the world we live in, and at the same time, the current Cybersecurity Workforce Gap as tracked by the (ISC)² Cybersecurity Workforce Study reports unfilled demand for more...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><span data-contrast="none">(ISC)² Organizational Statement in Opposition of Anti-DEI Legislation</span></em><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">As the world’s foremost cybersecurity professional organization, (ISC)² is leading the charge to ensure our profession reflects the diversity of the world we serve. Diversity, equity and inclusion are strategic priorities for the individuals and organizations (ISC)² represents, and we believe that inspiring a safe and secure cyber world means ensuring a diverse, equitable and inclusive cybersecurity profession.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">Today, our profession does not reflect the world we live in, and at the same time, the current Cybersecurity Workforce Gap as tracked by the (ISC)² Cybersecurity Workforce Study reports unfilled demand for more than 2.7 million professionals. Building a more diverse and inclusive profession is key to addressing the workforce shortage.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">As an association that is actively driving change to ensure a more diverse, equitable and inclusive workforce and workplaces, we are troubled by any legislative measures that not only limit, but in some instances, outlaw, discussions about and considerations of diversity in schools and the workplace. These laws stand in direct opposition to our core values, and they could hinder the ability of organizations to directly address diversity, equity and inclusion in the workplace, which is vital for success in a globally interconnected world. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">Only through frank and honest discussion can we break down barriers, establish common ground and affirm, for all, that DEI is about inclusion for everyone, not exclusion for anyone. We stand with other professional organizations like </span><a href="https://www.asaecenter.org/en/about-us/news_releases/2022/asae-statement-in-opposition-to-florida-stop-woke-act"><span data-contrast="none">the American Society of Association Executives (ASAE)</span></a><span data-contrast="none"> in opposing such laws as they undermine the development of a diverse and inclusive cybersecurity workforce. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">(ISC)² represents almost 170,000 certified members in 175 countries worldwide. Our </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/DEI/ISC2-DEI-Strategic-Plan.ashx?la=en&amp;hash=DD5EFF69E37F3D9A01093B591A9ABBB150A53214"><span data-contrast="none">DEI Strategic Plan</span></a><span data-contrast="none"> outlines the steps our organization is taking to ensure diverse, equitable and inclusive practices, and our </span><a href="https://www.isc2.org/dei"><span data-contrast="none">DEI Resource Center</span></a><span data-contrast="none"> provides dozens of guides that serves as a roadmap for other organizations and individuals seeking to establish similar programs. We will continue this important work and speak out against actions that curtail the progress we are making to inspire a safe and secure cyber world.&#0160;</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&#0160;</span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">We support all our members globally, including members who may be directly affected by laws of limitation, and we will work to preserve their rights and expand our DEI practices.</span></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?a=So-HVVEJU40:Azpv7A6SaIU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/isc2Blog?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <dc:creator>(ISC)² Management</dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 08:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- ph=1 -->