<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Panda Security Mediacenter</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter</link>
    <description>All the info about your cybersecurity</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:11:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2016/11/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
      <title>Panda Security Mediacenter</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Internet scams are a daily reality for the UK</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/internet-scams-uk/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/internet-scams-uk/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[scams]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28497</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Almost half of the UK population believes they have been targeted by scammers at least once. </div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/internet-scams-uk/">Internet scams are a daily reality for the UK</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/05/pandasecurity-cybersecurity-uk.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">Cybercrime is increasingly common – but we tend to hear about multi-million dollar heists that affect big business and governments. However, normal people are also being targeted by cybercriminals every single day.</p>
<p>Recent shows like The Tinder Swindler and Inventing Anna have shown just how common online scams are – and how effective they can be. It’s no surprise that UK police recorded just under 135,000 cyber crimes last year.</p>
<h2><strong>Everyone knows someone</strong></h2>
<p>A recent survey found that two-thirds of British adults have been targeted by criminals. 20% of people have been approached by scammers running a romance fraud (like The Tinder Swindler) and 25% have been asked for cash by someone they met online. Incredibly, 44% of those approached admit to having paid at least some cash to the scammer.</p>
<p>To be effective, the fraudsters pretend to be someone known by the victim. Most attacks seem to come from service providers (banks, ISPs, ecommerce websites), friends or close family members.</p>
<h2><strong>How are scammers winning?</strong></h2>
<p>Most people believe that online scams are becoming more sophisticated and that newer technologies allow criminals to carry out more attacks. Yet despite this, the scams themselves are still quite similar.</p>
<p>More than half of attempted scams (62%) are still started using email for instance. This is followed by SMS text messaging (52%) and social media (29%). Which means that people are still being scammed through the same channels.</p>
<p><a href="https://repository.pandasoftware.com/Panda/FREEAV/191254/PANDAFREEAV.exe"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Free Antivirus " src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/src/uploads/2020/02/pandasecurity-free-antivirus-bullets-download.jpg" alt="Download Panda Free Antivirus" width="600" height="200" border="0" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>It’s becoming easier to fall for a scam</strong></h2>
<p>The actual methods used to con victims have changed very little – scammers simply pretend to be a someone trusted by their victims. However, we ourselves may be making it easier for criminals to attack us.</p>
<p>How? According to the majority of people surveyed, it’s because we have shared too much personal information online. Using social media, it is very easy for scammers to find the names and other details of our friends and family for instance. They can then use that information to build more convincing, effective scams.</p>
<h2><strong>Protecting yourself against online scams &#8211; the same rules apply</strong></h2>
<p>There are several things you can do to protect yourself against becoming a victim:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learn to spot suspicious emails</strong> – our handy guide shows you <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/protecting-email-phishing-attacks/">how to identify a phishing email</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Be phone smart</strong> – discover how to identify and block <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/text-message-scams/">text message scams</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid social media scams</strong> – read more about the <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/social-media-scams/">Top 10 social media scams</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t overshare</strong> – scammers can find out all kinds of information from how you use social media (even the posts you ‘like’). Take a look at the ‘<a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/college-students-cybersecurity/">Don’t overshare on social media</a>’ section here for more.</li>
<li><strong>Use anti-malware</strong> to prevent scammers from installing viruses and trojans that can steal your personal data and passwords (<a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/homeusers/#plans">download a free trial of Panda Dome</a>).</li>
</ul>
<p>Ultimately, the best way to avoid becoming one of the majority people who are attacked, is to keep your wits about you. Use the links above to learn more about how scammers work – and how to better protect yourself against them.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/internet-scams-uk/">Internet scams are a daily reality for the UK</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/internet-scams-uk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are you making this important TikTok error?</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/tiktok-error/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/tiktok-error/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TikTok]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28494</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-tiktok-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Many parents are breaking TikTok’s age restrictions - but they may be creating even bigger problems for their toddlers.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/tiktok-error/">Are you making this important TikTok error?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-tiktok-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">A new report suggests that 16% of all children in the UK aged between 3 and 4 years old are currently using the TikTok video sharing app. This rises to 33% of all kids aged 5-7.</p>
<h2><strong>What is the problem?</strong></h2>
<p>The TikTok terms of service are clear – no one under the age of 13 is permitted to create an account of view videos. Similar to other online services (YouTube, Facebook, Google etc) TikTok actually has a team of moderators who identify and remove content posted by young children.</p>
<p>However, toddlers are unlikely to be signing up for their own TikTok user accounts. Instead they will be using their parent’s phones to watch videos which are signed into a valid adult user account.</p>
<p>There are two problems with this however. First, TikTok is strictly for use by over-13s. Accounts are not meant to be shared or accessed by underage people. If TikTok suspects this has been happening, they may cancel the parents account and permanently ban them from the service.</p>
<p>Second, the age limit exists because TikTok users sometimes share content that is unsuitable for young children. TikTok is legally obliged to protect youngsters from these videos (such as promoting eating disorders, violence or pornography). Banning under-13s is a very simple way to ensure they can meet their commitments. Parents who allow their toddlers to use TikTok are taking a risk that their children may be exposed to something inappropriate – even if it is by accident.</p>
<h2><strong>There’s a bigger problem…</strong></h2>
<p>But it’s not just the content on TikTok that may be problematic. Child development experts are increasingly concerned that the use of ultra-short format media is actually damaging kids’ learning abilities.</p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pandasecurity.pandaav&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;track=190548"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Panda Mobile Security" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2021/02/Banner-Mobile-EN.png" alt="Download Panda Mobile Security" width="600" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>They have found that children are now struggling to focus on longer content – like films and television programs. Almost all children are using a second device – like a tablet or phone – at the same time as watching TV or trying to learn. This is having a serious negative impact on their education as they are unable to concentrate for long enough to grasp what they are being taught.</p>
<p>Over the longer term, this inability to concentrate will have a significant negative impact on their educational achievement. Some will struggle in their exams, failing to reach their full potential at school.</p>
<h2><strong>How to stop underage TikTok use</strong></h2>
<p>As any adult knows, social media is quite addictive – even for kids. This means that any parent whose toddler already uses TikTok will face a struggle trying to get them to kick the habit. However, the rules are clear – under-13s are forbidden from using the platform. Encouraging children to break the rules will have serious consequences – your account may be deleted. Worse still, your child may suffer long term problems at school by constantly engaging with shortform content.</p>
<p>For older kids who have their own devices, consider installing a tool like Panda Parental Control. This app allows you to better understand how your kids are using their devices and help them to avoid harmful or unhelpful content.</p>
<p>With Panda Parental Control you can block age-restricted websites and apps for instance, instantly solving the problem of signing-up to services before they are old enough. You can also set time limits to help kids stay off their devices at school or when they are supposed to be doing their homework.</p>
<p>You can learn more about Panda Parental Control and how it will help you better protect <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/homeusers/dome-family/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/tiktok-error/">Are you making this important TikTok error?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/tiktok-error/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical infrastructure organizations in the USA on high alert for cyber attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/social-media/critical-infrastructure-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/social-media/critical-infrastructure-cyber-attacks/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 11:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybercrime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28489</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">American critical infrastructure is undeder a persisten threat, according to the FBI and NSA. These attacks are nothing new. </div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/social-media/critical-infrastructure-cyber-attacks/">Critical infrastructure organizations in the USA on high alert for cyber attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-infrastructure-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">Government agencies released a warning about p<a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/alerts/aa22-103a#revisions">ossible upcoming threats to US critical infrastructure</a>. High-profile security organizations, including the FBI and NSA, are warning<strong> that there is an ongoing advanced persistent threat</strong> coming from cybercriminals. Bad actors can gain complete system access to critical infrastructure elements such as industrial control system/supervisory control and data acquisition devices. Hackers appear to have developed new tools that could allow them to gain full system access to pretty essential parts of the USA’s critical infrastructure.</p>
<p>In particular, energy sector organizations that include <strong>liquefied natural gas plants appear to be at high risk</strong> from the recently discovered malware. In addition, the alert highlighted that Windows-based engineering workstations and OT environments using ASRock motherboard drivers are at exceptionally high risk of the malicious code. As this is an ongoing investigation, currently, there is no information on how the US protection agencies have found the malware.</p>
<p><a href="https://repository.pandasoftware.com/Panda/FREEAV/191254/PANDAFREEAV.exe"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Free Antivirus " src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/src/uploads/2020/02/pandasecurity-free-antivirus-bullets-download.jpg" alt="Download Panda Free Antivirus" width="600" height="200" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>The newly developed tools could scan for, compromise, and control affected devices. The alert does not mention a nation that might be behind the development of those tools, but experts have been openly pointing fingers at Russia. The relations between the US and Russia have not been excellent lately. Over the last couple of months, things have gotten worse after Russia’s latest invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/60Minutes/status/1516537125482737676">In an interview for ‘60 Minutes’</a>, Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco told correspondent Bill Whitaker that Russians pose a serious and persistent threat and America should be on high alert for possible attacks on organizations from the energy sector. Over the last ten years, Russians have been able to hack hundreds of companies and organizations worldwide, including them <a href="https://www.govtech.com/security/doj-russian-hackers-attempted-to-hack-kansas-nuclear-plant#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20U.S.%20Department,take%20control%20of%20critical%20infrastructure.&amp;text=The%20agents%20are%20accused%20of,property%20of%20an%20energy%20facility.">getting into the computer networks of a nuclear power company</a> located in Kansas. In addition, in 2015, Russia-sponsored bad actors managed to cause a blackout for nearly a quarter-million Ukrainians after getting into the networks of three Ukrainian powerplants. Furthermore, Russians appear to be behind cyber-attacks explicitly designed to kill people. Knowing that a foreign state whose current relationship with the USA is so dire can exploit the weaknesses of energy companies is undoubtedly a scary thought.</p>
<p>Luckily the possible threats have been crossed before any damage has been done, and <strong>government agencies are actively working on addressing the risks</strong> presented by the new malware. Government agencies have provided recommendations to all energy companies who could potentially be affected by the malware and have advised on ways to detect it, ensuring that the malicious will not disrupt critical devices or functions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/social-media/critical-infrastructure-cyber-attacks/">Critical infrastructure organizations in the USA on high alert for cyber attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/social-media/critical-infrastructure-cyber-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Women in Cybersecurity Who Are Reshaping the Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/women-in-cybersecurity-2/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/women-in-cybersecurity-2/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28436</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-Hero-Image-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="woman-working-on-laptop" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Women make up roughly 24% of cybersecurity professionals. While this is an improvement from a mere 11% since 2017, historical obstacles remain for women looking&#8230;</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/women-in-cybersecurity-2/">12 Women in Cybersecurity Who Are Reshaping the Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-Hero-Image-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="woman-working-on-laptop" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><p>Women make up roughly <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">24%</a> of cybersecurity professionals. While this is an improvement from a mere 11% since 2017, historical obstacles remain for women looking to join or move up in the massive global industry of security. In addition to the large gender disparity in cybersecurity, women in the field are compensated less on average than men. In 2021, <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">29%</a> of men said they earned between $50,000 and $99,999, while only 17% of women reported the same.</p>
<p>Amid all of this is the staggering increase in cybercrime — particularly <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/ransomware-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ransomware</a>, the <a href="https://www.ibm.com/security/data-breach/threat-intelligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top threat type</a> for 2021. Of the top 10 countries with the highest volume of ransomware, the U.S. suffered as many attacks as the other nine countries combined — <a href="https://www.sonicwall.com/medialibrary/en/white-paper/mid-year-2021-cyber-threat-report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">times four</a>. Even with the global attention cybersecurity has seen in the last few years, a major skills shortage persists, reaching nearly <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3 million globally</a> in 2021.</p>
<p>One thing is clear: Cybersecurity needs more women. In order to build strong cultures of cyber resilience across the globe, employers should prioritize attracting, empowering and retaining talented female cybersecurity professionals. Women in or aspiring toward cybersecurity roles represent an untapped reservoir of potential when it comes to the widening cybersecurity workforce gap.</p>
<p>Luckily, there are plenty of incredible women blazing the trail for a more diverse and inclusive industry in the world of security. Take a look below at some of today’s most notable women in cybersecurity to learn how they’re reshaping the industry as we know it.</p>
<h2>1. Chani Simms</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Meta Defence Labs (Managing Director and Co-founder)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Founder: SHe CISO Exec. Cybersecurity Leadership Empowerment program</li>
<li aria-level="1">Co-founder: InfoSec for Equality and Women</li>
<li aria-level="1">Licensed Computer Hacking Forensics Investigator (EC-Council)</li>
</ul>
<p>Chani Simms is an award-winning cybersecurity leader and C-level advisor who helps organizations implement information security and data protection programs. She began working as an IBM engineer specializing in IT infrastructure, systems management, virtualization, and data centers while studying for her computer science degree.</p>
<p>Eventually, she worked her way up to specialize in IT and security and now works with SMEs as a virtual CISO, data protection officer, Cyber Essentials Assessor, and IASME governance auditor. In addition to managing security company Meta Defence Labs, she went on to found SHe CISO Exec., a global training and mentoring platform for information security industry professionals.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Founded SHe CISO Exec. to train information security professionals and create emotionally intelligent cybersecurity leaders</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28443" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-Chani-Simms.png" alt="chani-simms" width="1441" height="609" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-Chani-Simms.png 1441w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-Chani-Simms-300x127.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-Chani-Simms-1100x465.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-Chani-Simms-530x224.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1441px) 100vw, 1441px" /></p>
<h2>2. Nicole Eagan</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Darktrace (Chief Strategy Officer and AI Officer)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:  </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">AI Leader of the Year – Tech Leaders Awards 2020</li>
<li aria-level="1">#1 position – The Software Report’s Top 25 Women Leaders in Cybersecurity 2020</li>
</ul>
<p>Dubbed “AI Leader of the Year” in 2020, Nicole Eagan has blazed her own trail in the world of AI and cybersecurity since leaving her role as chief marketing officer at HP Autonomy in 2012. Since then, she’s made strides positioning her current company, Darktrace, as an international leader in cyber defense in her role as chief strategy &amp; AI officer for the firm.</p>
<p>Nicole’s leadership of Darktrace’s innovative approach to <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/deepfake-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disruptive AI technology</a> helped shape one of the most effective solutions to global cybersecurity challenges, resulting in the company’s 600% year-over-year growth.</p>
<p>Under Nicole’s leadership, Darktrace has defended smart cities like Las Vegas — whose water reclamation system and industrial IoT sensors were under attack by state-sponsored threat actors — using bespoke security strategies when standard security tools proved insufficient for this type of advanced infrastructure.</p>
<p>Nicole has established herself as one of the most remarkable voices in the cybersecurity industry — traveling the world to raise awareness about topics ranging from adaptive AI cyber defenses in building tomorrow’s cities of the future and AI-powered threats to regulatory compliance and cyber risk. In addition to her commitment to leading the change in how organizations approach cyberattacks, she also leads internal and external efforts to solve the issue of gender disparity faced by women in the cybersecurity industry.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Established Darktrace as the global leader of AI cyber defense by developing state-of-the-art AI algorithms that detect never-before-seen cyberattacks</p>
<h2>3. Rana el Kaliouby</h2>
<p><strong>Companies:</strong> Smart Eye (CEO), Affectiva (Co-founder and CEO)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">University of Cambridge: Ph.D., Computer Science</li>
<li aria-level="1">Massachusetts Institute of Technology: Post-Doc, Computer Science &amp; Technology</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Advisor: Boston Children’s Hospital Simulator Program</li>
<li aria-level="1">Executive Fellow: Harvard Business School</li>
<li aria-level="1">Steering Committee Member: All Raise</li>
</ul>
<p>Rana el Kaliouby is an Egyptian American scientist, entrepreneur, and AI leader on a mission to bring emotional intelligence to the world of AI. Since growing up in the Middle East and moving to the United States to become an entrepreneur, she’s spearheaded the application of artificial emotional intelligence in a slew of industries and established herself as a global leader in AI.</p>
<p>After making her exit as CEO of Affectiva — an MIT spin-off company she co-founded to humanize how people interact with technology — she stepped into her current role as CEO of Smart Eye, which acquired Affectiva in 2021. Her work is helping to scale the company to a global AI powerhouse, with a key focus on ethics, diversity, equity, and inclusion.</p>
<p>Rana’s track record for using innovative technology to address the needs of several international markets reflects her deep passion for ethical AI in today’s digitally driven world. She’s applied her skills to a variety of markets including automotive, robotics, and education as well as areas like mental health and autism.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Established and continues to lead the emotion AI industry</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28444" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-Rana-el-Kaliouby.png" alt="Rana-el-Kaliouby" width="1441" height="609" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-Rana-el-Kaliouby.png 1441w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-Rana-el-Kaliouby-300x127.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-Rana-el-Kaliouby-1100x465.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-Rana-el-Kaliouby-530x224.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1441px) 100vw, 1441px" /></p>
<h2>4. Kirsten Davies</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Unilever (Chief Information Security Officer)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:  </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">University of Puget Sound: B.A., International Political Science &amp; Government</li>
<li aria-level="1">International Institute of Human Rights (Strasbourg, France): International Law, Human Rights certificates</li>
<li aria-level="1">Johns Hopkins University: International Law and Business, Human Rights certificates</li>
<li aria-level="1">Prosci Institute: Advanced certificate in Change Management</li>
</ul>
<p>Having lived and worked on four continents, Kirsten Davies’ global approach to information security, data privacy and enterprise risk has led to her recognition as a true thought leader in cybersecurity transformation. Her skillful approach to cybersecurity has led to accomplishments like building Africa’s first end-to-end security function and negotiating the first-ever Cyber Security Master Agreement with the German Workers Council for Hewlett Packard Enterprise.</p>
<p>Prior to her newest role as global CISO for Unilever, she served as CISO for The Estée Lauder Companies, where she led a foundational restructuring of core cybersecurity capabilities, overhauled the information security policy suite, commanded the data integrity program and doubled the size of the program — all while prioritizing diversity and inclusion across all genders and ethnicities.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Achieved the first-ever Cyber Security Master Agreement with the German Workers Council for Hewlett Packard Enterprise (HPE), now replicated across HPE’s 20+ Works Councils in EMEA</p>
<h2>5. Kate Maxwell</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Microsoft (Chief Technology Officer, Worldwide Defense &amp; Intelligence)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown: B.S., Computer Science</li>
<li aria-level="1">George Mason University: Master’s in Systems Engineering</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Member: The Startup Ladies</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Member: TechPoint Foundation for Youth</li>
</ul>
<p>Prior to her current role with Microsoft’s Worldwide Defense &amp; Intelligence (D&amp;I) division, Kate Maxwell put her knowledge of computer science and systems engineering to work for 16 years in the aerospace field, working for defense contractor Raytheon Technologies to better understand frontline defense technology.</p>
<p>As her expertise grew, she found the corporate contractor environment wasn’t suited for her passion for bringing disruptive, innovative technology ideas to life, which ultimately led to her digital transformation position at Microsoft.</p>
<p>While digital transformation in government is its own challenge, Maxwell has proven determined to follow her passion for leveraging the intersection of technology and culture to advance organizations, missions, and multinational alliances.</p>
<p>“As technologists, we often run after the amazing and shiny new technology,” she says. “But if we don’t get the culture right and really seek to understand how people and technology interact, that new technology is not going to take hold. Period.”</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Using cloud computing, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and high-performance computing to deliver digital transformation to the international defense allied community</p>
<h2>6. Shivon Zilis</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Neuralink (Director of Operations), OpenAI, Creative Destruction Lab</p>
<p><strong>Accolades: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Yale: B.A., Economics and Philosophy</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Member: OpenAI</li>
<li aria-level="1">Fellow: Creative Destruction Lab</li>
</ul>
<p>Ruthlessly dedicated to machine intelligence for good, Shivon Zilis has spent most of her career focusing on how machine learning can solve pressing real-world problems. Her journey has taken her from project director at Tesla to partner and founding member of Bloomberg Beta, a $75 million venture fund that invests in startups transforming the future of work, to her current positions as founding fellow of Creative Destruction Lab.</p>
<p>In addition to her position as a board member for OpenAI, an AI research company dedicated to ensuring that AI benefits all of society, she’s been heads-down at Neuralink since 2017 developing the future of brain machine learning by building devices to help people with paralysis.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Developed brain machine interfaces to build innovative devices for people with paralysis</p>
<h2>7. Lauren Knausenberger</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> United States Airforce (Chief Information Officer)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">The Wharton School: MBA</li>
<li aria-level="1">Venture Partner: NextGen Venture Partners</li>
</ul>
<p>As CIO of the Department of Air Force, which includes the Air Force and Space Force, Lauren Knausenberger leads a 20,000-person team of IT experts working to advance the cybersecurity landscape of the Department of Defense.</p>
<p>Since joining the Air Force in 2017, Lauren has quickly established herself as one of the most important drivers of innovation for the Air Force’s Information Technology portfolio. In the wake of increasing pressure from airmen and women for the Air Force to solve widespread IT issues, Lauren has been a vocal advocate of leveraging modern technology to replace an outdated IT infrastructure and better serve U.S. warfighters.</p>
<p>In the face of rapidly evolving cyberattacks, Lauren has led the Air Force in eradicating outdated IT policies and introducing an IT-as-a-service model to bolster the department’s cybersecurity. In 2021, she worked to scale Platform One and Cloud One, the Air Force’s software development platform for the Defense Department, and spearheaded initiatives to improve the department’s cloud strategy and shift to a fully zero-trust model.</p>
<p>Her modernization initiatives and digital transformation efforts are helping transform the Air Force and bolster the country’s global competitive advantage. She’s also focused on growing Digital University, an online platform for warfighters to grow their technical skills and for airmen to learn more agile processes.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Spearheaded Operation Flamethrower, an initiative to eradicate outdated IT policies and modernize the Air Force’s cyber landscape</p>
<h2>8. Sheila Jordan</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Honeywell (Chief Digital Technology Officer)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Florida Institute of Technology: MBA</li>
<li aria-level="1">Cisco Executive Sponsor Catalyst Award</li>
</ul>
<p>Sheila Jordan is a passionate IT leader who’s made her mark driving global IT strategy and transformation for a slew of organizations. Her belief in the power of digital transformation to realign the structure of businesses is how she’s helped companies maximize the value of technology investments and implement end-to-end data-driven digital experiences to create more impactful customer journeys.</p>
<p>Sheila’s holistic approach to digital transformation has led to her recruitment for a variety of roles. As former senior vice president at Cisco, she integrated key IT services that touched Cisco’s global workforce and spearheaded the shift to a more intuitive consumer experience. As former chief information officer at global cybersecurity leader Symantec, she drove the IT vision and strategy while ensuring the firm stayed ahead of emerging technology trends. Today, Sheila commands Honeywell’s digital transformation strategy in her current role as chief digital technology officer.</p>
<p>Aside from being a driving force behind IT infrastructure and services, Sheila is passionate about breaking down the underrepresentation of women in senior leadership roles in the technology field. By focusing on collaboration and motivating leadership, Sheila is a change agent and example to leaders looking to understand what unique programs should be pursued in order to attract and retain more women in the workplace.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry: T</strong>ransformed Symantec’s business by successfully splitting IT and security operations</p>
<h2>9. Lakshmi Hanspal</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Amazon (Global Chief Information Security Officer, Devices &amp; Services)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Boston University: M.S., Computer Science</li>
</ul>
<p>Lakshmi Hanspal is a trailblazer in the digital and cybersecurity world, championing security leaders to fully evolve into their increasingly critical roles. Her skills in information security, risk management, and privacy have led her through an array of senior positions, where she’s combined her cybersecurity expertise with her talent for driving engagement and collaboration among C-suite executives to facilitate buy-in on key security initiatives.</p>
<p>Passionate about securing digital transformation and supporting socially conscious commerce, Lakshmi advises several Silicon Valley startups and serves on the advisory boards of eight cloud companies. She most recently joined the board of directors for Spectrum Labs, a company dedicated to building safe, inclusive, engaged online communities through <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/panda-security/facial-recognition-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the power of AI</a> and making the internet a safer place for all.</p>
<p>Aside from leading the charge for collaborative, business-centric global security solutions, Lakshmi also works to promote women in technology and develop the next generation of female talent. Prior to her current role as Amazon’s global chief information security officer, she was the global chief security officer at Box and became the third female on Box’s executive board.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry: </strong>Advocating for greater organizational cybersecurity buy-in and teaching leaders how to create organizational cultures of security built upon trust</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28445" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-Lakshmi-Hanspal.png" alt="Lakshmi-Hanspal-quote" width="1441" height="609" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-Lakshmi-Hanspal.png 1441w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-Lakshmi-Hanspal-300x127.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-Lakshmi-Hanspal-1100x465.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-Lakshmi-Hanspal-530x224.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1441px) 100vw, 1441px" /></p>
<h2>10. Nasrin Rezai</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Verizon (Chief Information Security Officer)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Harvard Business School: Leadership Development certification</li>
</ul>
<p>Nasrin Rezai is a technical visionary and agent of change in the global cybersecurity world. Unafraid to dive headfirst into the evolving security challenges faced by business leaders, her commitment to changing the way we think about cybersecurity has enabled her to design security solutions for large enterprises and champion stronger security culture.</p>
<p>Her skills in global technology risk management and leading transformative change of risk culture have taken her through various chief information security officer roles. She currently serves as the CISO at Verizon, where she commands the firm’s information security strategy to protect its customers and leading networks.</p>
<p>Working from the mantra “Do your part. Be cyber smart,” Nasrin is actively working to shift society’s view of cybersecurity from something scary and inaccessible to something <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/tips/tech-relationship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we all play a role in</a> for the greater good. She’s also passionate about helping others develop their potential, especially women in pursuit of leadership roles in the tech industry.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry: </strong>Advocating for a more accessible, humanized approach to cybersecurity for all — consumers, businesses, and society</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28446" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-Nasrin-Rezai.png" alt="Nasrin-Rezai-quote" width="1441" height="609" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-Nasrin-Rezai.png 1441w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-Nasrin-Rezai-300x127.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-Nasrin-Rezai-1100x465.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-Nasrin-Rezai-530x224.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1441px) 100vw, 1441px" /></p>
<h2>11. Kamelia Aryafar</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Google (Director of Engineering, Cloud Artificial Intelligence)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Drexel University: Ph.D. and M.S. in Computer Science and Machine Learning</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Member: Initiative of Analytics and Data Science Standards (IADSS)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Advisory Board Member: SCU Retail Management Institute</li>
<li aria-level="1">Board Member: Women of MENA in Technology</li>
</ul>
<p>Kamelia Aryafar is the director of engineering and head of retail and consumer solutions in Google Cloud AI, where she leads applied artificial intelligence teams in solving retailers’ problems. Before her role at Google, Kamelia leveraged her customer-centric approach to machine learning to lead the integration of state-of-the-art AI algorithms across product teams for Overstock.com.</p>
<p>Kamelia began her journey in 2013 as a data scientist at Etsy, where she collaborated with product teams to implement machine learning and AI algorithms throughout the company. This was the start of her established expertise in the machine learning community, in which she remains an active member — she often speaks at industry conferences, serves on several advisory boards, and has published a slew of papers in scientific journals.</p>
<p>Her passion for machine learning goes beyond her corporate prowess — her commitment to advancing the field of AI also expands into supporting <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/technology/girls-in-tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">women in STEM</a> and teaching aspiring undergraduates the skills they need to succeed in the ever-changing security sector.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Advocating for leaders to create an environment for women, immigrants, and minorities to enter STEM fields</p>
<h2>12. Natasha Sayce-Zelem</h2>
<p><strong>Company:</strong> Prime Video at Amazon (Global Head of Partner Engineering)</p>
<p><strong>Accolades:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Founder: Empowering Women with Tech</li>
</ul>
<p>Natasha Sayce-Zelem is Amazon’s global head of partner engineering — a seemingly unlikely title, considering her early career as a freelance music photographer.</p>
<p>Prior to her role at Amazon, Natasha was the head of technology at broadcast media company Sky, where she commanded the digital trading department using machine learning and conversational user interface technology to develop data-driven customer journeys.</p>
<p>In 2016, she founded Empowering Women with Tech, a support network showcasing female role models working in science and technology with the goal of encouraging more women to consider a career in STEM. One of her focus areas is breaking the stigma surrounding information technology and teaching women just how creative a career in technology and science can be.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on the cybersecurity industry:</strong> Helping women harness their untapped skills and encouraging more women to find a career in STEM</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28447" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/05-Natasha-Sayce-Zelem.png" alt="Natasha-Sayce-Zelem-quote" width="1441" height="649" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/05-Natasha-Sayce-Zelem.png 1441w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/05-Natasha-Sayce-Zelem-300x135.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/05-Natasha-Sayce-Zelem-1100x495.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/05-Natasha-Sayce-Zelem-530x239.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1441px) 100vw, 1441px" /></p>
<h2>How Can Women Succeed in the Cybersecurity World?</h2>
<p>Men may outnumber women in cybersecurity <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx">by 3 to </a>1, but women are increasingly joining the field and taking on leadership roles in higher numbers. While women still face an uphill battle in terms of compensation, an <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(ISC)2 study</a> reveals that women in cybersecurity have higher levels of education and more certifications than men. As women continue to prioritize higher education and certifications, a path to accelerated career advancement in the field is slowly but surely being forged.</p>
<p>The increasing representation of women in cybersecurity shown in the latest <a href="https://www.isc2.org/-/media/ISC2/Research/ISC2-Women-in-Cybersecurity-Report.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">(ISC)2 study</a> represents a positive upward trend — both for women and the cybersecurity industry as a whole. Here’s how women can continue the trend.</p>
<h3>Invest in Skills Training and Networking</h3>
<p>Breaking into the cybersecurity field requires at least three things: skills, networks, and perseverance.</p>
<p><strong>Skills/training:</strong> With the increasing global demand for cybersecurity professionals, you won’t struggle to secure a role in the industry even with minimal technical skills and training. That said, you can improve your chances by developing your skills in the areas that employers are looking for. Identify the most important skills highlighted in the positions you’re interested in and invest in growing in those areas.</p>
<p><strong>Networks:</strong> In the cybersecurity world, more collaboration yields more success — especially if you’re trying to break into the field for the first time. Finding organizations with people in the roles you aspire to hold is critical to navigating the cybersecurity field, and finding mentors and role models can provide the clarity you need to find your place in the industry.</p>
<p><strong>Perseverance:</strong> A <a href="https://resource.cobalt.io/hubfs/2017%20Women%20in%20Cybersecurity%20A%20Progressive%20Movement.pdf?t=1501765756737" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> of 300 women cybersecurity employees found that less than half came into the industry with a background in IT or computer science, and instead had diverse backgrounds in fields like psychology, internal auditing, or compliance. So don’t write yourself off from positions because you feel underqualified. Keep applying, networking, and growing your skills, and remember that your potential isn’t based on past experiences alone.</p>
<h3>Take Risks and Make Your Voice Heard</h3>
<p>One of the keys for women in entry- or mid-level positions looking to forge a path to higher-level roles is pushing to take on new projects and opportunities that you don’t feel completely qualified for.</p>
<p>Women tend to chronically underestimate themselves — a popular <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jackzenger/2018/04/08/the-confidence-gap-in-men-and-women-why-it-matters-and-how-to-overcome-it/?sh=cdd230c3bfa1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> by Hewlett Packard revealed that men apply for a job or promotion even if they meet just 60% of the requirements, while women apply only if they meet 100% of them. When women resist taking the risk of a stretch opportunity, they limit their ability to gain deeper experience and a broader perspective of the organization.</p>
<p>While organizations must play their part in creating a culture that supports women’s voices, women can also prioritize their own commitment to stepping out and making themselves heard. And while there are certainly plenty of assertive women who have no problem making their opinions known in the workplace, an unfortunate truth is that these are often the same women who struggle to get promoted.</p>
<p>One Accenture Cybersecurity Forum (ACF) Women’s Council member <a href="https://acn-marketing-blog.accenture.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/JumpingtheHurdles_C.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>, “A skill I had to learn was not to communicate in ways where I didn’t get labeled a ‘challenge.’ You still have to have your voice — and be loud with that voice — but in ways that effectively get you what you want.”</p>
<h2>Women in Cybersecurity Associations and Groups to Follow</h2>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.wicys.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women in CyberSecurity</a> (WiCyS)</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://womenscyberjutsu.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women’s Society of Cyberjutsu</a> (WSC)</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.cybher.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CybHER</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.womenofsecurity.com/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WoSEC: Women of Cybersecurity</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.wisporg.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women in Security and Privacy</a> (WISP)</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.sans.org/scholarship-academies/womens-academy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The SANS Women’s Immersion Academy</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://code.likeagirl.io/tagged/cybersecurity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Code Like a Girl</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.icmcp.org/about-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">International Consortium of Minority Cybersecurity Professionals</a> (ICMCP)</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://iapp.org/connect/communities/sections/women-leading-privacy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women Leading Privacy</a> (subset of International Association of Privacy Professionals)</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.infosecgirls.in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">InfosecGirls</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.womentech.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WomenTech Network</a></li>
</ol>
<p>While the gender divide in cybersecurity is clear, these women — and their contributions to the world of cybersecurity — are paving the way to ensure more gender inclusion in the future.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28448" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity.png" alt="Women-in-Cybersecurity" width="1440" height="10308" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity.png 1440w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-300x2148.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-1100x7874.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-286x2048.png 286w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/Women-in-Cybersecurity-530x3794.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/women-in-cybersecurity-2/">12 Women in Cybersecurity Who Are Reshaping the Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/women-in-cybersecurity-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Smurf Attack?</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/smurf-attack/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/smurf-attack/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 17:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Malware]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28481</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/smurf-attacks-hero-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="distressed-man-on-laptop" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">A Smurf attack is a distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack in which an attacker floods a victim’s server with spoofed Internet Protocol (IP) and Internet Control&#8230;</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/smurf-attack/">What Is a Smurf Attack?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/smurf-attacks-hero-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="distressed-man-on-laptop" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" /><p>A Smurf attack is a distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack in which an attacker floods a victim’s server with <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/what-is-spoofing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spoofed</a> Internet Protocol (IP) and Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) packets. As a result, the target’s system is rendered inoperable. This type of attack gets its name from a DDoS.Smurf malware tool that was widely used in the 1990s. The small ICMP packet generated by the malware tool can cause significant damage to a victim’s system, hence the name Smurf.</p>
<h2>How Does a Smurf Attack Work?</h2>
<p>Smurf attacks are similar to a form of denial-of-service (DoS) attacks called ping floods, since they’re accomplished by flooding a victim’s computer with ICMP Echo Requests. The steps in a Smurf attack are as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Attacker locates the target’s IP address:</strong> An attacker identifies the target victim’s IP address.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Attacker creates spoofed data packet:</strong> Smurf malware is used to create a spoofed data packet, or ICMP Echo Request, that has its source address set to the real IP address of the victim.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Attacker sends ICMP Echo Requests:</strong> The attacker deploys ICMP Echo Requests to the victim’s network, causing all connected devices within the network to respond to the ping via ICMP Echo Reply packets.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Victim is flooded with ICMP replies:</strong> The victim then receives a flood of ICMP Echo Reply packets, resulting in a denial-of-service to legitimate traffic.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Victim’s server becomes overloaded:</strong> With enough ICMP Reply packets forwarded, the victim’s server is overloaded and potentially rendered inoperable.</li>
</ol>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28482" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-smurf-attack-diagram.png" alt="murf-attack-diagram" width="1440" height="1070" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-smurf-attack-diagram.png 1440w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-smurf-attack-diagram-300x223.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-smurf-attack-diagram-1100x817.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/01-smurf-attack-diagram-530x394.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /></p>
<h3>Smurf Attack Amplifiers</h3>
<p>Another component to Smurf attacks that increases their damage potential is the use of Smurf amplifiers. The amplification factor correlates to the number of hosts on the victim’s IP broadcast network.</p>
<p>For example, an IP broadcast network with 300 hosts will yield 300 responses for every fake ICMP Echo Request. This enables an attacker with low bandwidth to successfully disable a victim’s system, even if that system has much higher bandwidth. Smurf amplifiers can be deployed as long as the attacker maintains a connection and the amplifiers are broadcasting the ICMP traffic.</p>
<h3>Smurf Attack Example</h3>
<p>To put this type of attack into simpler terms, it’s helpful to picture a metaphorical Smurf attack example. Think of a trickster (the DDoS.Smurf malware) calling an office (the IP broadcast network) while masquerading as the company’s CEO.</p>
<p>In our example, the trickster asks a manager to tell every employee to return his call (the ICMP Echo Requests) on his private number to give a project status update — but the private number (the spoofed IP address) actually belongs to the trickster’s targeted victim. As a result, the victim receives an onslaught of unwanted phone calls (the ICMP Echo Replies) from each employee in the office.</p>
<h2>Types of Smurf Attacks</h2>
<p>Smurf attacks are generally categorized as basic or advanced. The only difference in the type of attack is the degree of the attack that takes place.</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Basic:</strong> The attacker floods a single victim’s network with ICMP Echo Request packets.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Advanced:</strong> The attack is identical to a basic attack, except the Echo Request Packets are configured to allow them to respond to additional third-party victims, enabling the attacker to target multiple victims at once.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28483" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-advanced-smurf-attack.png" alt="advanced-smurf-attack" width="1440" height="801" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-advanced-smurf-attack.png 1440w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-advanced-smurf-attack-300x167.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-advanced-smurf-attack-1100x612.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/02-advanced-smurf-attack-530x295.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /></p>
<h3>What’s the Difference Between a Smurf Attack and a DDoS Attack?</h3>
<p>A DDoS attack aims to prevent victims from accessing their network by flooding it with fake information requests. A Smurf attack is a form of a DDoS attack that renders a victim’s network inoperable in a similar way, but the difference is that it does so by exploiting IP and ICMP vulnerabilities. Leveraging these vulnerabilities is what sets a Smurf attack apart, in turn increasing the potential for damage.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28484" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack.png" alt="smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack" width="1440" height="801" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack.png 1440w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack-300x167.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack-1100x612.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/03-smurf-attack-vs-ddos-attack-530x295.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /></p>
<h3>What’s the Difference Between a Smurf Attack and a Fraggle Attack?</h3>
<p>Both a Fraggle attack and a Smurf attack are forms of a DDoS attack that aim to flood a victim’s system with fake information requests. The difference is that while a Smurf attack uses spoofed ICMP packets, a Fraggle attack uses spoofed User Datagram Protocol (UDP) traffic to achieve the same goal. Everything else about these attacks are the same.</p>
<h2>Consequences of a Smurf Attack</h2>
<p>While the goal of a Smurf attack is to render a victim’s system useless for days or even hours, iit can also be the first step toward more harmful attacks like data theft or <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/news/identity-theft-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">identity theft</a>. Either way, the consequences of a Smurf attack remain:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Revenue loss:</strong> A company server that’s inoperable for hours or days on end often means a halt in business operations, resulting in lost revenue and frustrated customers.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Data theft:</strong> Attackers can gain unauthorized access to the data on the victim’s host server during an attack.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Reputational damage:</strong> If your clients’ confidential data is leaked after an attack, it can lead to a permanent breach in their trust and loyalty to your organization.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Mitigation Methods and How to Protect Yourself</h2>
<p>Mitigating a Smurf attack comes down to securing your network, which begins with your router. To protect yourself, you’ll need to configure how your routers and devices interact with ICMP packets. This involves two important prevention steps:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Disable IP broadcasting</strong> on all network routers.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Configure your network devices to <strong>not respond to ICMP Echo Requests</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28485" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-smurf-attack-prevention.png" alt="smurf-attack-prevention" width="1440" height="801" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-smurf-attack-prevention.png 1440w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-smurf-attack-prevention-300x167.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-smurf-attack-prevention-1100x612.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/04-smurf-attack-prevention-530x295.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /></p>
<p>If your current router is an older model, it’s wise to invest in a new one, as newer models usually come with the above configurations already in place by default.</p>
<p>In addition to these steps, investing in an antivirus and <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/malware/malware-removal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">anti-malware</a> solution to secure your firewalls adds an added layer of protection to your network.</p>
<p>As with <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/panda-security/types-of-cybercrime/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most cyberattacks</a>, prevention is often the best strategy for protection. While Smurf attacks are nothing new, they remain a <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/cybersecurity-trends/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">common tactic among cybercriminals</a> looking to exploit vulnerable networks. To further protect yourself from cyberattacks in all their forms, consider installing a <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/homeusers/free-antivirus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">trusted antivirus software</a> to keep all your devices secure.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/smurf-attack/">What Is a Smurf Attack?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/smurf-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FBI warns sextortion of teenagers is on the rise</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/fbi-warns-sextortion/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/fbi-warns-sextortion/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 09:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[sextortion]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28478</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Money-driven predators are increasingly going after teenage boys. Here is how to notice if your kid is a victim, and what to do. </div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/fbi-warns-sextortion/">FBI warns sextortion of teenagers is on the rise</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-sextortion-2.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">The FBI Pittsburgh Field Office has issued a warning about increased <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/sextortion-scams/">sextortion</a> incidents. The government agency has said that predators have been targeting young males in a sextortion scheme involving adults posing as age-appropriate females swindling teenagers, mainly between 14 and 17 years old. This particular scheme involves predators encouraging boys to share provocative videos and images and includes<strong> blackmailing them for money afterward</strong>. In addition, cybercriminals threaten to release the imagery to friends and family if the victim refuses to cooperate.</p>
<p>Social media, games, and apps all have instant messaging features that essentially are hunting grounds for child predators. Bad actors from all over the world scout for potential victims and use deception and manipulation to convince young teenagers to create explicit materials. Unfortunately, the lockdowns over the last two years have made the job of child predators easier as teenagers end up spending more time on phones, tablets, and gaming.</p>
<p>Parents and caregivers have to look for suspicious behavior and report it to the authorities. Many antivirus solutions offer<a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/homeusers/dome-family/"> ways to stay on top of your children’s online behavior</a>. Law enforcement is actively encouraging teenagers and parents to report possible child predators. Unfortunately, in many cases,<strong> teenagers are so embarrassed that they pay the predators</strong> and the crimes go unreported. However, this is precisely what criminals want so they can move on to the next victim.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/homeusers/dome-family/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Parental Control" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2021/02/Banner-Family-EN.png" alt="Parental Control " width="600" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>Parents should ask questions and get involved when their teenage child shows signs of distress, i.e., requests for money but cannot explain the purpose and shows signs of depression or nervousness. Last month, a 17-year-old teenager from Michigan killed himself a few hours after blackmailers threatened to release a naked picture. <strong>Sextortion is a crime</strong>, and educating children about cyber predators is strongly advisable.</p>
<p>FBI Pittsburgh Special Agent in Charge Mike Nordwall stated that these are not the traditional child predators who are just out for explicit images. Instead, he said<strong> they’re very much money-driven</strong>, and the FBI wants parents and caregivers to discuss schemes like this. Law enforcement agencies wish kids and parents to know that if someone they’ve met online starts asking for provocative images or behavior, and eventually money, that person should be reported.</p>
<p>If you believe that your child might be in trouble or is a potential predator victim, you are advised to <strong>contact a local FBI field office</strong>. FBI wanted to clarify that imagery, videos, and texts should not be deleted before the authorities review them. Even though teenagers, and even adults, may find talking about those types of incidents embarrassing, the only way to prevent predators from continuing to do what they do, is to cooperate with law enforcement and provide as much evidence as possible. The more evidence authorities have, the more likely it is for them to identify and prosecute the perpetrator, thus preventing the criminal from causing any further damage.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/fbi-warns-sextortion/">FBI warns sextortion of teenagers is on the rise</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/fbi-warns-sextortion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is drone delivery taking off soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/drone-delivery-taking-off/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/drone-delivery-taking-off/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 12:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28472</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Drone delivery has been the next big thing for many years now. So, when is it finally becoming mainstream?</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/drone-delivery-taking-off/">Is drone delivery taking off soon?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-drone-deliveries.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">In 2013, Jeff Bezos teased that consumers would soon see 30-minute drone deliveries. The concept of getting something delivered with a drone sounded futuristic yet realistic enough, as the drone technology was developing reasonably fast. However, nearly a decade later, drone deliveries have not yet been able to go mainstream. In 2019 Amazon showed a redesign of their Prime Air delivery drone, and there have been some test runs, but it is a fact that <strong>we do not see drones making deliveries around town yet</strong>. Earlier this week, The Verge <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/11/23020549/amazon-struggling-drone-deliveries-prime-air-bezos">reported</a> that Amazon is still struggling to make drone deliveries to work.</p>
<p>Amazon has not been the only major player interested in delivering goods with drones. Last year Walmart launched <a href="https://www.supermarketnews.com/technology/walmart-launches-drone-deliveries-droneup">its first commercial drone delivery</a> for online customers in Arkansas with Virginia-based DroneUp. However, the hopes for nationwide drone delivery are still on standby for Walmart, too, as they only covered a 50-mile radius of its headquarters in The Natural State.</p>
<p><a href="https://repository.pandasoftware.com/Panda/FREEAV/191254/PANDAFREEAV.exe"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Free Antivirus " src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/src/uploads/2020/02/pandasecurity-free-antivirus-bullets-download.jpg" alt="Download Panda Free Antivirus" width="600" height="200" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Dominos made history by delivering <a href="https://dronedj.com/2022/01/27/dominos-pizza-drone-delivery-new-zealand/">the world&#8217;s first pizza by drone</a> in New Zealand in 2016. However, their partnership with SkyDrop has not transformed the world of pizza delivery yet either. Dominos has promised to continue trials later this year, so people in select cities might actually be able to order Dominos by the end of 2022. Dominos has successfully delivered pizza using ground robots, but drones are still a work-in-progress. However, Domino&#8217;s CEO stated that drone delivery would be an essential component of their pizza deliveries in the future.</p>
<p>Alphabet just announced that they would be <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/alphabets-wing-to-launch-drone-delivery-in-dallas-fort-worth-area-11649325601">launching a drone delivery service</a> in Dallas-Fort Worth area. The service offered by Wing, an Alphabet subsidiary, will see its largest rollout in the USA. Their customer will be Walgreens which hopes to stage deliveries from the parking lot of a store in the area. They plan to allow consumers to choose from over 100 items, including over-the-counter medicine, household essentials, and other lightweight, vital everyday products.</p>
<p>We may soon be able to order ice cream and pizza and get it delivered by a drone, but this is something we have heard for ten years. Even though many companies claim this will be coming soon,<strong> mainstream implementation is probably years away</strong>. As of this moment, there is no drone-delivery company in the U.S. that is fully certified to fly everywhere without the involvement of a human, i.e., a person controlling or monitoring the UAV&#8217;s fly and behavior during delivery. However, the FAA has highlighted that they are actively working on developing regulations that would allow it to issue such authorization sooner than later.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/drone-delivery-taking-off/">Is drone delivery taking off soon?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/technology/drone-delivery-taking-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers stole $600 million in crypto and are having trouble laundering it</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/600-million-crypto/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/600-million-crypto/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28466</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Cryptocurrency transactions are not anonymous. Regulations keep hackers at bay and avoid them running away with the money.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/600-million-crypto/">Hackers stole $600 million in crypto and are having trouble laundering it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">Hackers managed to penetrate the Ronin Network and stole <strong>more than half a billion worth of crypt</strong>o from the Ethereum-linked sidechain developed by Sky Mavis called Axie Infinity. The online video game uses Ethereum-based cryptocurrencies and allows players to collect NFTs, which represent digital pets known as Axies. The security breach at Ronin Network is one of the largest <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/news/weirdest-cyber-heist/">cryptocurrency heists</a> on record ever. According to Ronin Network, on March 23rd, 2022, approximately 173,600 Ethereum and 25.5M USDC were drained by cybercriminals. The stolen funds are worth roughly $600 million.</p>
<p>The attacker used “hacked private keys” to make its way into the network and stole all the funds in two transactions leaving tens of thousands of players in limbo. Earlier this month, Sky Mavis announced that they have secured funding for about a quarter of the stolen funds and will begin working on reimbursing all of the users affected by the data breach of the blockchain powering the NFT game Axie Infinity. In the meantime, hackers have been looking for ways to launder the stolen virtual money, which is apparently not an easy task.</p>
<p>When cryptocurrencies initially appeared on the horizon, everyone thought that virtual transactions and wallets were anonymous, but as the blockchain evolved and got mainstream, more and more people realized that<strong> transactions are not anonymous.</strong> The US government has been working on <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/how-safe-are-your-crypto-assets/">regulating crypto exchanges</a> for years and laundering through crypto has proven to be a pain for the hackers responsible for this heist too. <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/">Other countries have followed suit and have ramped up law-enforcement efforts</a> to seize stolen funds and limit money laundering.</p>
<p><a href="https://repository.pandasoftware.com/Panda/FREEAV/191254/PANDAFREEAV.exe"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Free Antivirus " src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/src/uploads/2020/02/pandasecurity-free-antivirus-bullets-download.jpg" alt="Download Panda Free Antivirus" width="600" height="200" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Wall Street Journal reported that the thieves responsible for the hack have <strong>minimal options for laundering the funds</strong>. The ownership of the crypto addresses holding the stolen funds is unclear, but blockchain analysts have been observing tens of millions of dollars worth of stolen crypto move to virtual money exchanges located in the Bahamas and Seychelles.</p>
<p>Trading in Axie Infinity was frozen until company representatives assessed the damages caused by the cyber-attack. However, the company says that they are here to stay and are working on resuming operations. Even though the investigation continues, the game company is confident that this was an external breach as all of the evidence they’ve collected so far confirms that the attack was socially engineered rather than a technical flaw.</p>
<p>The Ronin Network bridge is expected to<strong> open once it has undergone a security upgrade</strong> and several audits, which according to the network representative, take several weeks. While things appear to be under control, with company partners reimbursing players, the hack has put a shadow on the industry. It has undoubtedly made investors and players skeptical of NFT and play-to-earn games. The NFTs in such games have both virtual and real-world value and, as such, are targets for cyber thieves.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/600-million-crypto/">Hackers stole $600 million in crypto and are having trouble laundering it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/600-million-crypto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UK about to begin regulating cryptocurrencies?</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 11:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=28451</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">Rumours suggest the Treasury is about to implement financial safeguards to better protect investors and prevent fraud.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/">Is the UK about to begin regulating cryptocurrencies?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2022/04/pandasecurity-crypto.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">The growing popularity of cryptocurrencies has started to catch the attention of governments. In Britain, reports suggest that the Treasury (the UK’s finance ministry) is about to announce new plans to regulate the crypto market. These new regulations are intended to better protect UK crypto investors and close some of the loopholes being used by fraudsters and criminals.</p>
<h2><strong>Starting with stablecoins</strong></h2>
<p>Like most technologies, the <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/security-info/cryptocurrency/">cryptocurrency</a> market has developed considerably faster than governments have been able to regulate it. Now that crypto coins have matured, they have been forced to act.</p>
<p>The Treasury has been working with several companies and trade groups to better understand how the market works and what help they need. Because of the complexities of the various crypto platforms, initial regulations will focus on “stablecoins”.</p>
<h2><strong>What is a stablecoin?</strong></h2>
<p>One of the problems with popular cryptocurrencies like <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/bitcoin-definition-hacks/">Bitcoin</a> and Ethereum is that their value is tied directly the coin itself. This is why the value of these coins fluctuates so much; fortunes can be made and lost in a matter of hours.</p>
<p>Stablecoins, like Tether, Diem and Digix Gold Tokens, are slightly different. The value of these coins is determined by a physical asset or fiat currency, like the US Dollar or Euro. This offers two significant benefits for investors.</p>
<p><a href="https://repository.pandasoftware.com/Panda/FREEAV/191254/PANDAFREEAV.exe"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" title="Download Free Antivirus " src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/src/uploads/2020/02/pandasecurity-free-antivirus-bullets-download.jpg" alt="Download Panda Free Antivirus" width="600" height="200" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>First, you always know exactly how much your coin is worth. You can sell your Tether coin and withdraw its value in US Dollars whenever you want. Second, the stablecoin market must have large enough reserves of the supporting currency to cover every coin in circulation. These reserves ensure that investors can always get their cash back out of the system.</p>
<p>Although ‘safer’ than pure cryptocurrencies, there are still risks associated with stablecoin investments. If the value of the Dollar or other supporting asset crashes, the coin’s value will also be affected. And this is why regulators in the UK are focusing on stablecoins first.</p>
<h2><strong>What will regulation change?</strong></h2>
<p>The most significant change will be official government recognition of regulated cryptocurrencies for payments. Stablecoin transactions will be afforded many of the same protections that traditional fiat payments enjoy.</p>
<p>Regulation offers protection for investors and platform operators, with legal processes to follow in the event of disputes, insolvency or <a href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/security/cryptocurrency/">criminal activity</a>. And the UK government hopes that these safeguards will prove attractive to crypto companies, encouraging them to invest in the local economy. Eventually it is hoped that Britain will be established as a global center for cryptocurrencies, as it already is for other financial services.</p>
<p>The Treasury is due to make their announcement very soon, at which point the plans will be clearer. The framework proposals will also provide some guidance about how other, non-stablecoin cryptocurrencies may be regulated in future too. We will watch how the situation develops with interest.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/">Is the UK about to begin regulating cryptocurrencies?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/panda-security/uk-regulating-cryptocurrencies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can you tell if a shortened link is secure?</title>
      <link>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/shortened-link-secure/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/shortened-link-secure/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Panda Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 09:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[links]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[shortened urls]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/?p=12537</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="post-excerpt">&#160; At some time in our (digital) lives, we’re bound to come across shortened links or URLs, on social networks, for example, you can’t avoid&#8230;</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/shortened-link-secure/">How can you tell if a shortened link is secure?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="300" height="225" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-feed size-feed wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-1100x825.jpg 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links-530x398.jpg 530w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-shorten-links.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="dropcap dropcap-simple">At some time in our (digital) lives, we’re bound to come across <strong>shortened links</strong> or URLs, on <strong>social networks</strong>, for example, you can’t avoid them.</p>
<p>There’s no doubting that they are highly useful. In a <strong>tweet</strong>, for example, characterized by the famous character limit, a shortened URL creates space to write something else. Moreover, they offer other characteristics, though one of these has become a double-edged sword: You don’t know where it will take you.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-28430 size-full" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-tweet-eng.jpg" alt="" width="694" height="548" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-tweet-eng.jpg 694w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-tweet-eng-300x237.jpg 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-tweet-eng-530x419.jpg 530w" sizes="(max-width: 694px) 100vw, 694px" /></p>
<p>This is where you have to tread carefully. A shortened link is really a mystery. You don’t know <strong>which website it will take you</strong> to or what might appear on the screen. As such, these shortened URLs are the <strong>perfect tool for malware</strong> and <a title="What is Phishing?  " href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/malware/what-is-phishing/"><strong>phishing</strong></a>. Click them at your peril.</p>
<p>Yet there’s no need to panic. Just because you come across them every day on <strong>Twitter</strong> and they could contain a nasty surprise doesn’t mean that every one is a booby trap. Some simple caution and common sense can prevent a catastrophe on your computer.</p>
<p>To start with, be careful with the <strong>source of the URL</strong>. If it’s an <strong>online media channel</strong> or blog that is tweeting the headline of an article and a link to it, it is reasonable to suppose that the link will take you to the article. So click away! However, if you find a message from a known (or unknown) contact saying, &#8220;Hey, you look great in this photo!&#8221; and with a shortened link, be very wary.</p>
<p>Among the numerous services used to shorten inks, some are more reliable than others. The <a href="https://goo.gl/">Google</a> and <strong><a title="bitly" href="https://bitly.com/">Bit.ly</a></strong> services are among the most secure, though not so much so that you can confidently <strong>click</strong> them if the source is unknown.</p>
<h2>How can you tell if a shortened link is secure?</h2>
<p>Using your <strong>common sense</strong> is a good initial filter to apply when deciding whether or not to click, though it is not infallible. Fortunately, there are quite a few tools that let you expand <strong>shortened links</strong>, or in other words, see what&#8217;s really behind each link and avoid disasters.</p>
<p>First, here’s a little trick if you come across <strong>Bit.ly</strong> or <strong>Google shortened links</strong>. Copy the link, paste it in your browser address bar and, before hitting &#8216;Enter&#8217;, add the &#8220;+&#8221; symbol. This way you can see the statistics associated with the URL, and more importantly, you can see which website it takes you to, among other things.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-28432 size-full" src="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-bitly.png" alt="" width="1266" height="579" srcset="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-bitly.png 1266w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-bitly-300x137.png 300w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-bitly-1100x503.png 1100w, https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/src/uploads/2014/11/pandasecurity-bitly-530x242.png 530w" sizes="(max-width: 1266px) 100vw, 1266px" /></p>
<p>Apart from this useful trick, a <strong>browser extension</strong> or a visit to a certain <strong>website</strong> could also be enough to prevent any cyber-criminals from giving you a nasty surprise through an apparently interesting link.</p>
<p>Websites such as <a title="Unshorten" href="http://www.unshorten.it/">Unshorten.it</a> reverse the process of URL shorteners. Enter any suspect shortened URLs in these pages and you can see exactly where they take you.</p>
<p>As we said before, these are not the only ways of <strong>ensuring the security of the shortened URLs</strong> that you come across every day on social networks. Probably the most convenient way is to install an extension on your browser that tells you where these links point to without having to continually consult an external website as we described above.</p>
<p>Both for Google Chrome and for <strong>Mozilla Firefox</strong>, there is a solution to deal with the problem of shortened links.</p>
<ul>
<li>For Firefox, you can use the corresponding version of Unshorten.it. Whereas the website expands shortened links, the add-on for Firefox does so directly from the browser, thereby saving you a few seconds. Instead of having to <strong>open a new tab</strong> in the browser and cut and paste the URL, this extension means that you only have to right-click the shortened link and select the option: &#8216;Unshorten this link&#8217;.</li>
<li>If you use <strong>Google Chrome</strong>, you also have plenty of options. For example, LongURL (that’s right, the Google browser version of the website we mentioned before), is an add-on that displays all the data regarding the shortened link – including the URL.</li>
</ul>
<p>Regardless of the method you choose, you’ll still have to employ some common sense to decide whether <strong>the page is bona fide or not</strong>. When you expand a link and the name of the <strong>website isn’t familiar</strong> or what you see is a completely incomprehensible Web address, you’d better be cautious and not go there. In this case, the saying is quite appropriate: ‘Better safe than sorry’.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/shortened-link-secure/">How can you tell if a shortened link is secure?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter">Panda Security Mediacenter</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pandasecurity.com/en/mediacenter/tips/shortened-link-secure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>