<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber Security Archives - IT Governance UK Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/category/cyber-security/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog</link>
    <description>Protect - Comply - Thrive</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 08:19:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <!--Theme by MyThemeShop.com-->
    <image>
      <url>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/favicon.ico</url>
      <title>Cyber Security Archives - IT Governance UK Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>3 reasons cyber security training is essential</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/3-reasons-cyber-security-training-is-essential</link>
      <comments>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/3-reasons-cyber-security-training-is-essential#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Training]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=34547</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Organisations are always looking for ways to improve their security practices, and one of the most effective ways to achieve this is by providing employees with&#160;cyber security training. A Lucy Security study found that 96% of respondents agreed that a greater level of awareness over cyber security threats contributed to overall improvements in their defences. Despite that, comparatively few provided adequate training to help staff mitigate the risks of data breaches and cyber attacks. For example, only 81% of respondents said they conduct phishing simulations, and only 51% say their organisation has a mechanism to report suspicious emails. There has </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/3-reasons-cyber-security-training-is-essential">3 reasons cyber security training is essential</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Organisations are always looking for ways to improve their security practices, and one of the most effective ways to achieve this is by providing employees with&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cybersecurity-training" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyber security training</a>.</p>



<p>A <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200929005323/en/Lucy-Security-Study-Demonstrates-Cybersecurity-Awareness-Increases-IT-Security" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lucy Security study</a> found that 96% of respondents agreed that a greater level of awareness over cyber security threats contributed to overall improvements in their defences.</p>



<p>Despite that, comparatively few provided adequate training to help staff mitigate the risks of data breaches and cyber attacks.</p>



<p>For example, only 81% of respondents said they conduct phishing simulations, and only 51% say their organisation has a mechanism to report suspicious emails.</p>



<p>There has never been a better time is there to boost your organisation’s knowledge of effective information security practices. Here are three reasons to consider it.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>1. You’ll reduce the risk of data breaches</strong></h2>



<p>Almost all <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-breaches" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data breaches</a> are caused by a mistake somewhere in the organisation. So if you want to keep your organisation secure, your employees to know what they’re doing.</p>



<p>That doesn’t only mean negligence – it could also be mistakes that you don’t even know are mistakes, such as gaps in your policies, ineffective processes or a lack of proper technological defences.</p>



<p>Placing staff on information security training courses will help them understand the mistakes they’re making and teach them to work more effectively.</p>



<p>This is especially useful if you intend to commit to a framework such as <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso27001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 27001</a>, the international standard for information security, as there are specific courses that teach you how to follow the Standard’s requirements.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>2. You’ll meet compliance requirements</strong></h2>



<p>Cyber security laws and regulations inevitably contain complex requirements, so organisations need employees with specialist knowledge to achieve compliance.</p>



<p>For example, organisations that are required to appoint a <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-protection-officer-dpo-under-the-gdpr" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DPO (data protection officer)</a> under the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-protection-dpa-and-eu-data-protection-regulation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EU GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation)</a> must find someone with an in-depth understanding of data protection law.</p>



<p>The stakes associated with the position are huge; if the DPO doesn’t perform their tasks in accordance with the GDPR’s requirements, the organisation is liable to face <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/dpa-and-gdpr-penalties" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">regulatory action</a>.</p>



<p>It’s therefore paramount that the DPO is given every resource available to do their job properly, and training courses should always be sought where possible.</p>



<p>They are not only the quickest way of studying but also usually include exams, which reassures employers that the individual is qualified.</p>



<p>The same advice applies for individuals in roles that involve compliance with the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/pci_dss" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard)</a>, ISO 27001 or any other law or framework.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>3. You’ll foster career growth</strong></h2>



<p>Training courses enable employees to pick up new skills and gain more advanced qualifications, which will help them move into more senior roles.</p>



<p>This isn’t only beneficial for them but also their employers. It’s getting increasingly hard to find qualified information security professionals, with <a href="https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/uk-cyber-skills-shortage-rises" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">82% of UK-based organisations saying that there is a cyber security skills shortage</a>.</p>



<p>Finding qualified personnel isn’t the only problem. A small pool of skilled workers also means job candidates can command a higher salary and more benefits.</p>



<p>As such, organisations might not be able to afford qualified professionals even if they can find them.</p>



<p>They should therefore do whatever they can to support employees who want to go on training courses. Organisations will almost certainly benefit from the extra knowledge, and it eases the pressure of finding skilled personnel in the job market.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Which course is right for you?</strong></h2>



<p>Cyber security is a broad industry, so you need to decide which area suits you best. To help you make that choice, here are some of our most popular training courses:</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso27001-information-security-training" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 27001 training courses</a></strong></li></ul>



<p>Knowledge of ISO 27001, the international standard for information security, is an absolute must for anyone who handles sensitive data. We offer several ISO 27001 courses, including <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso27001-certified-isms-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an introduction to the Standard</a> and guidance on specific roles, such as <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso27001-certified-isms-internal-auditor-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">internal auditor</a> and <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso27001-certified-isms-lead-implementer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lead implementer</a>.</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso22301-courses" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 22301 training courses</a></strong></li></ul>



<p><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso22301-business-continuity-standard" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 22301</a> is the international standard for business continuity. Organisations that follow its framework can be sure that they’ll continue operating when disaster strikes.</p>



<p>Our <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso22301-certified-bcms-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Foundation-level course</a> covers the essentials of the Standard, but we also offer advanced courses for those that want to lead an <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso22301-certified-bcms-lead-implementer-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">implementation project</a> or <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso22301-certified-bcms-lead-auditor-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">audit</a>.</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/pci-dss-training-courses" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PCI DSS training courses</a></strong></li></ul>



<p>Any organisation that transmits, processes or stores payment card data must comply with the PCI DSS. Our training courses help you understand <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/pci-dss-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the basics of the Standard</a>, <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/pci-dss-implementation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">implement its requirements</a> and <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/pci-dss-v3-saq-workshop" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">complete the SAQ (self-assessment questionnaire)</a>.</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/gdpr-training" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GDPR training courses</a></strong></li></ul>



<p>The GDPR is the most significant update to information security law in more than twenty years. Anyone who handles personal data or is responsible for data protection needs to comply with its requirements.</p>



<p>Regular staff should familiarise themselves with the Regulation via our <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/Product/certified-eu-general-data-protection-regulation-foundation-gdpr-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Foundation-level course</a>, senior staff would benefit from our <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/Product/certified-eu-general-data-protection-regulation-practitioner-gdpr-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Practitioner course</a> and those looking to fulfil the DPO role should enrol on our <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-data-protection-officer-c-dpo-masterclass-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified DPO training course</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso27001-information-security-training" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/ISO-27001-banner-training-Blog.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-29774" width="646" height="215" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/ISO-27001-banner-training-Blog.jpg 600w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/ISO-27001-banner-training-Blog-300x100.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 646px) 100vw, 646px" /></a></figure></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><em>A version of this blog was originally published on 31 October 2018.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/3-reasons-cyber-security-training-is-essential">3 reasons cyber security training is essential</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/3-reasons-cyber-security-training-is-essential/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the best qualifications for cyber security in 2022?</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-best-qualifications-for-a-career-in-cyber-security</link>
      <comments>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-best-qualifications-for-a-career-in-cyber-security#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 15:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ISO 27001]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Training]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CISMP]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CISSP]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ISO27001]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Lead Imlementer]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[qualifications]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=22578</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>There has never been a better time to start a career in cyber security. Organisations’ reliance on IT technical solutions has only increased with the switch to remote working, creating a massive demand for qualified personnel. But what qualifications do you need for cyber security? It can be tricky knowing where to begin. Cyber security is a complex, multidisciplinary field with varied opportunities depending on your skills and interests. This blog explains the best cyber security courses to help you get started. Start with the basics and learn your trade Those in the early stage of their careers should get </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-best-qualifications-for-a-career-in-cyber-security">What are the best qualifications for cyber security in 2022?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There has never been a better time to start a career in cyber security. </p>



<p>Organisations’ reliance on IT technical solutions has only increased with the switch to remote working, creating a massive demand for qualified personnel.</p>



<p>But what qualifications do you need for cyber security? </p>



<p>It can be tricky knowing where to begin. Cyber security is a complex, multidisciplinary field with varied opportunities depending on your skills and interests.</p>



<p>This blog explains the best cyber security courses to help you get started.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Start with the basics and learn your trade</strong></h2>



<p>Those in the early stage of their careers should get as much practical experience as possible and look to achieve industry-standard cyber security qualifications.</p>



<p>An excellent place to train in cyber security is the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-cyber-security-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified Cyber Security Foundation Training Course</a>. </p>



<p>From social engineering to security in the Cloud, you will gain foundation-level knowledge of the threat landscape, cyber attack methodology, legal and regulatory obligations, and incident response.</p>



<p>The next step is the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-cyber-security-practitioner-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified Cyber Security Practitioner Training Course</a>. This course will teach you how to deliver infrastructure, application, information and operational security by implementing appropriate technical and organisational controls.</p>



<p>You will also learn how to deal with cyber security incidents and understand the basic principles of evidence collection and digital forensics.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>To further develop your cyber security career, we recommend the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cismp-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CISMP (Certificate in Information Security Management Principles)</a>&nbsp;qualification.</p>



<p>CISMP is widely regarded as the ‘qualification of choice’ for IT security professionals and is recognised across the UK as an essential first rung on the ladder to a successful career.</p>



<p>The framework is ideal for those getting started in the industry and for professionals who require a deeper understanding of the subject to develop their overall business skills.</p>



<p>It’s particularly valuable to those working in the public sector. It is part of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/articles/about-certified-professional-scheme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CCP (CESG Certified Professional) scheme</a>, which is the UK government’s approved standard of competence for cyber security.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Do you need the technical stuff?</strong></h2>



<p>To advance in any cyber security field, you’ll need some technical expertise – but you don’t necessarily need a comprehensive understanding of programming or hacking.</p>



<p>You can become an IT specialist or manager if you’re familiar with hardware, software, networks and applications and the security threats associated with them.</p>



<p>For those interested in technical training, there are plenty of options. For a career in security IT admin or operations, the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/comptia-security-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CompTIA Security+ Training Course</a> delivers the knowledge required to install and configure systems to secure devices, applications and networks.</p>



<p>Others might be interested in ethical hacking or penetration testing, which involves identifying and exploiting vulnerabilities in an organisation’s systems using the same techniques as a criminal hacker – except you don’t perform malicious actions.</p>



<p>Organisations hire penetration testers to discover where their weaknesses are and how they could be exploited.</p>



<p>The demand for ethical hackers has skyrocketed in the past few years, as businesses realise the need for practical assessments of their systems.</p>



<p>If this sounds like the career for you, you can develop the skills you need on our&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-ethical-hacker-ceh-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) Training Course</a>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Don’t leave management qualifications until later</strong></h2>



<p>Most cyber security careers culminate in a management position, which means that you might be leading a group of specialists in an area where you are not an expert.</p>



<p>Anyone interested in becoming a cyber security manager should consider gaining appropriate qualifications in ISO 27001 and the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).</p>



<p><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso27001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 27001</a> is the international standard for information security. Its best-practice approach enables organisations to address their security needs through an ISMS (information security management system).</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-iso-27001-isms-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified ISO 27001 ISMS Foundation Training Course</a> and <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-iso-27001-isms-lead-implementer-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified ISO 27001 ISMS Lead Implementer Training Course</a> deliver a complete education and globally recognised IBITGQ qualifications.</p>



<p>No matter what area of cyber security you move into, you will almost certainly come across the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-protection-dpa-and-eu-data-protection-regulation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GDPR and its UK equivalent</a> – whether you handle personal data or  design or use systems intended to uphold its requirements.</p>



<p>Data protection and data privacy are at the core of cyber security, so it’s worth getting a solid understanding of these issues. To get started on the GDPR, we recommend the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/certified-gdpr-foundation-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Certified GDPR Foundation Training Course</a>.</p>



<p>Those with several years’ experience in cyber security may also consider becoming a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cism-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CISM<sup>®</sup> (Certified Information Security Manager)</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cissp-accelerated-training-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CISSP<sup>®</sup> (Certified Information Security Systems Professional)</a>.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Get started with our free guide</strong></h2>



<p>You can find out more about getting started in the industry with our&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/careers-in-cyber-security-and-data-privacy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyber Security Careers Guide</a>.</p>



<p>We look at various cyber security professions and explain the skills and experience you need.</p>



<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/careers-in-cyber-security-and-data-privacy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Download now</strong></a></div>
</div>



<div style="height:32px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/careers-in-cyber-security-and-data-privacy"></a>You’ll also discover which training courses can help you advance in each career path and how IT Governance can help.</p>



<p>Our training courses offer a structured learning path from foundation to advanced level, helping IT, privacy and security practitioners develop the skills needed to deliver best practice and compliance in organisations.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/careers-in-cyber-security-and-data-privacy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="532" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LinkedIn-1040px-x-540px-1-1024x532.png" alt="" class="wp-image-41825" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LinkedIn-1040px-x-540px-1-1024x532.png 1024w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LinkedIn-1040px-x-540px-1-300x156.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LinkedIn-1040px-x-540px-1-768x399.png 768w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/LinkedIn-1040px-x-540px-1.png 1040w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></figure></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-best-qualifications-for-a-career-in-cyber-security">What are the best qualifications for cyber security in 2022?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-best-qualifications-for-a-career-in-cyber-security/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security’s Impact on Climate Change: What Can Organisations Do?</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/cyber-securitys-impact-on-climate-change-what-can-organisations-do</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43673</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Last year, the World Economic Forum listed cyber crime alongside climate change as two of the biggest threats society faces in the next decade. Although they might appear to be distinct problems, there are ways that they influence one another. Most obviously, cyber crime by its nature involves the use of computers, which consume energy. This is no small matter. IT Governance found more than 1,200 publicly disclosed security incidents in 2021, which correlates to society’s increasingly reliance on computers and the expanding influence that criminal hackers have. Their techniques are becoming more sophisticated, meaning organisations need to respond in </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/cyber-securitys-impact-on-climate-change-what-can-organisations-do">Cyber Security’s Impact on Climate Change: What Can Organisations Do?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last year, <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/world-economic-forum-cyber-crime-is-one-of-the-key-threats-of-the-next-decade" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the World Economic Forum</a> listed cyber crime alongside climate change as two of the biggest threats society faces in the next decade.</p>



<p>Although they might appear to be distinct problems, there are ways that they influence one another. Most obviously, cyber crime by its nature involves the use of computers, which consume energy.</p>



<p>This is no small matter. IT Governance found <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/data-breaches-and-cyber-attacks-in-2021-5-1-billion-breached-records" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than 1,200 publicly disclosed security incidents in 2021</a>, which correlates to society’s increasingly reliance on computers and the expanding influence that criminal hackers have.</p>



<p>Their techniques are becoming more sophisticated, meaning organisations need to respond in kind – creating a technological arms race resulting in more computers, more powerful systems and a higher energy consumption.</p>



<p>Perhaps the most significant example of this is the Cloud. According to&nbsp;<a href="https://info.flexera.com/CM-REPORT-State-of-the-Cloud?lead_source=Website%20Visitor&amp;id=Blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a report by the software firm Flexera</a>, 92% of organisations use more than one, with the average respondent using 2.6 public Clouds and 2.7 private ones.</p>



<p>Millions of people rely on the Cloud to access information and services, with facilities filled with high-powered CPUs, terabytes of RAM and petabytes of storage. It’s therefore no surprise that Cloud storage centres account for <a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/microsoft-teams-up-with-accenture-goldman-on-greener-software" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1% of the world’s electricity use</a>.</p>



<p>Then there’s blockchain mining. The process describes the way people create bitcoins, requiring computers to solve complex computational maths problems.</p>



<p>In the early days of bitcoin mining, individuals could create new bitcoins using a standard computer set-up, but the process has grown so complex that it now requires a room full of specialised tools.</p>



<p>Many people argue that the environmental cost of this is a necessary evil. The blockchain has been <a href="https://www.cm-alliance.com/cybersecurity-blog/the-future-use-cases-of-blockchain-for-cybersecurity" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">touted as a panacea for all sorts of cyber security risks</a>, yet the technology is perhaps most famous in cyber security circles for the way bitcoin has helped cyber criminals launder their ill-gotten gains.</p>



<p>Regardless of whether the cyber security benefits of blockchain mining outweigh the risks it creates, the biggest issue is how catastrophically bad for the environment it is.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/09/03/climate/bitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The New York Times reports</a> that the process of creating Bitcoin consumes about 91 terawatt-hours of electricity annually – about that of a small country.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>ISO 50001 and smarter energy use</strong></h2>



<p>Whatever your opinion is on the benefits of blockchain mining, the Cloud or other technologies we’ve referenced, one thing that all of can agree on is that organisations should be more vigilant about their energy use.</p>



<p>One factor that influences this is the climate crisis. The more energy we use – particularly if it’s not coming from a sustainable source – the worse it is for the environment.</p>



<p>But another, more pragmatic issue, is the economic costs of energy waste. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/02/03/uk-energy-bills-to-rise-by-over-50percent-in-april-as-ofgem-announces-hike.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The UK faces record energy bills</a>, with organisations and individuals being urged to cut their electricity and fuel use to reduce their costs.</p>



<p>Of course, organisations can’t be expected to cut processes that are essential for their day-to-day operations. They instead need to find a middle ground between responsible energy use and productivity.</p>



<p>This is where ISO 50001 can help. It’s the international standard for energy management, providing a framework for organisations of all sizes to reduce their energy use and associated costs.</p>



<p>Organisations can use ISO 50001 to gain a better understanding of the way they use energy and to achieve more effective leadership focus on energy policies. The Standard helps organisations:</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li>Reduce their energy usage;</li><li>Save money by managing energy more efficiently;</li><li>Reduce their carbon footprint;</li><li>Increase energy security; and</li><li>Demonstrate a commitment to improved energy performance.</li></ul>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Get started with ISO 50001</strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/5494.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43674" width="185" height="185" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/5494.png 320w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/5494-300x300.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/5494-150x150.png 150w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/5494-65x65.png 65w" sizes="(max-width: 185px) 100vw, 185px" /></figure></div>



<p>You can find out more about the Standard with IT Governance’s <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso-50001-toolkit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 50001 Toolkit</a>.</p>



<p>With more than 40 customisable templates, documents, work instructions and records, this toolkit contains everything you need to boost your organisation’s energy management system.</p>



<p>You’ll also receive full coverage of the Standard with a range of compliance tools, including the Gap Analysis tool, Document Management Tool, Responsibilities Map and Energy Review Plan.</p>



<p>The package has been developed by experience management system consultants, so you can be sure that you’re on the right track.</p>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/iso-50001-toolkit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Get started</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/cyber-securitys-impact-on-climate-change-what-can-organisations-do">Cyber Security’s Impact on Climate Change: What Can Organisations Do?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 ways to detect a phishing email – with examples</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/5-ways-to-detect-a-phishing-email</link>
      <comments>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/5-ways-to-detect-a-phishing-email#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Phishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishingstaffawareness]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=31599</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Phishing is one of the most common types of cyber crime, but despite how much we think we know about scam emails, people still frequently fall victim. According to Proofpoint’s 2022 State of the Phish Report, 83% of organisations fell victim to a phishing attack last year. Meanwhile, Verizon&#8217;s 2021 Data Breach Investigations Report found that 25% of all data breaches involve phishing. In this blog, we use real phishing email examples to demonstrate five clues to help you spot scams. 1. The message is sent from a public email domain No legitimate organisation will send emails from an address </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/5-ways-to-detect-a-phishing-email">5 ways to detect a phishing email – with examples</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/phishing?promo_name=Phishing_5_ways&amp;promo_id=Blog&amp;promo_creative=Phishing_Main&amp;promo_position=In_Text" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Phishing</a> is one of the most common types of cyber crime, but despite how much we think we know about scam emails, people still frequently fall victim.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/uk/resources/threat-reports/state-of-phish">Proofpoint’s 2022 State of the Phish Report</a>, 83% of organisations fell victim to a phishing attack last year.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/en-gb/resources/reports/dbir/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Verizon&#8217;s 2021 Data Breach Investigations Report</a> found that 25% of all data breaches involve phishing.</p>



<p>In this blog, we use real phishing email examples to demonstrate five clues to help you spot scams.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>1. The message is sent from a public email domain</strong></h2>



<p>No legitimate organisation will send emails from an address that ends ‘@gmail.com’.</p>



<p>Not even Google.</p>



<p>Most organisations, except some small operations, will have their own email domain and company accounts. For example, legitimate emails from Google will read ‘@google.com’.</p>



<p>If the domain name (the bit after the @ symbol) matches the apparent sender of the email, the message is probably legitimate.</p>



<p>By contrast, if the email comes from an address that isn&#8217;t affiliated with the apparent sender, it&#8217;s almost certainly a scam.</p>



<p>The most obvious way to spot a bogus email is if the sender uses a public email domain, such as &#8216;@gmail.com&#8217;.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="911" height="1024" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF-911x1024.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-43663" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF-911x1024.jpeg 911w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF-267x300.jpeg 267w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF-768x863.jpeg 768w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF-1366x1536.jpeg 1366w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/59C99078-E7CB-42FE-9B95-0664543232DF.jpeg 1668w" sizes="(max-width: 911px) 100vw, 911px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Image: <a href="https://www.pickr.com.au/how-to/2021/how-to-spot-a-paypal-phishing-email/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pickr</a></em></p>



<p>In this example, you can see that the sender&#8217;s email address doesn&#8217;t line up with the content of the message, which appears to be from PayPal.</p>



<p>However, the content of the message looks realistic, and the attacker has customised the sender&#8217;s name field so that it will appear in recipients&#8217; inboxes as ‘Account Support’.</p>



<p>Other phishing emails will take a more sophisticated approach by including the organisation’s name in the local part of the domain. In this instance, the address might read ‘paypalsupport@gmail.com’.</p>



<p>At first glance, you might see the word ‘PayPal’ in the email address and assume that it was legitimate. However, you should remember that the important part of the address is what comes after the @ symbol. This dictates the organisation from which the email has come.</p>



<p>If the email is from ‘@gmail.com&#8217; or another public domain, you can be sure that has come from a personal account.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/images/product/medium/4566.png" alt="Phishing Staff Awareness Course" width="175" height="175"/></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Want to educate your staff on the threat of phishing?</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Our <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-training-programme" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phishing Staff Awareness Training Programme</a> contains everything your employees need to detect scam emails.</strong></p>



<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-training-programme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Get started</strong></a></div>
</div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>2. The domain name is misspelt</strong></h2>



<p>There’s another clue hidden in domain names that provide a strong indication of phishing scams ­– and it unfortunately complicates our previous clue.</p>



<p>The problem is that anyone can buy a domain name from a registrar. And although every domain name must be unique, there are plenty of ways to create addresses that are indistinguishable from the one that’s being spoofed.</p>



<p>Take a look at this example:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="537" height="666" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43664" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image.png 537w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-242x300.png 242w" sizes="(max-width: 537px) 100vw, 537px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Image: <a href="https://blog.goptg.com/watch-out-for-these-new-office-365-phishing-attacks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PTG</a></em></p>



<p>Here, scammers have registered the domain ‘microsfrtfonline.com’, which to a casual reader mimics the words &#8216;Microsoft Online&#8217;, which could reasonably be considered a legitimate address.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, some fraudsters get even more creative. The Gimlet Media podcast ‘Reply All’ demonstrated that in the episode <a href="https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/rnhoww/97-what-kind-of-idiot-gets-phished" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">What Kind Of Idiot Gets Phished?</a>.</p>



<p>Phia Bennin, the show&#8217;s producer, hired an ethical hacker to phish various employees. He bought the domain ‘gimletrnedia.com’ (that’s r-n-e-d-i-a, rather than m-e-d-i-a) and impersonated Bennin.</p>



<p>His scam was so successful that he tricked the show’s hosts, Gimlet Media’s CEO and its president.</p>



<p>As Bennin went on to explain, you don’t even need to fall victim for a criminal hacker to gain vital information.</p>



<p>In this scam, the ethical hacker, Daniel Boteanu, could see when the link was clicked, and in one example that it had been opened multiple times on different devices.</p>



<p>He reasoned that the target’s curiosity kept bringing him back to the link but that he was suspicious enough not to follow its instructions.</p>



<p>Boteanu explains:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>I’m guessing [the target] saw that something was going on and he started digging a bit deeper and […] trying to find out what happened […]</em></p><p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>And I’m suspecting that after, [the target] maybe sent an email internally saying, “Hey guys! This is what I got. Just be careful. Don’t click on this […] email.</em></p></blockquote>



<p>Boteanu’s theory is exactly what had happened. But why does that help the hacker? Bennin elaborates:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>The reason Daniel had thought [the target] had done that is because he had sent the same email to a bunch of members of the team, and after [the target] looked at it for the fourth time, nobody else clicked on it.</em></p><p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>And that’s okay for Daniel because he can try, like, all different methods of phishing the team, and he can try it a bunch of different times. [And] since [the target is] sounding alarm bells, he probably won’t include [him] in the next phishing attempt.</em></p></blockquote>



<p>Therefore, in many ways, criminal hackers often still win even when you’ve thwarted their initial attempt.</p>



<p>That is to say, indecisiveness in spotting a phishing scam provides clues to the scammer about where the strengths and weaknesses in your organisation are.</p>



<p>It takes very little effort for them to launch subsequent scams that make use of this information, and they can keep doing this until they find someone who falls victim.</p>



<p>Remember, criminal hackers only require one mistake from one employee for their operation to be a success. As such, everyone in your organisations must be confident in their ability to spot a scam upon first seeing it.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/how-to-spot-a-phishing-email?promo_name=Phishing_5_ways&amp;promo_id=Blog&amp;promo_creative=Phishing_Quiz&amp;promo_position=Banner_Middle" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-39891 size-full" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/phishing-quiz-blog.png" alt="Take our phishing quiz" width="640" height="200" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/phishing-quiz-blog.png 640w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/phishing-quiz-blog-300x94.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>3. The email is poorly written</strong></h2>



<p>You can often tell if an email is a scam if it contains poor spelling and grammar.</p>



<p>Many people will tell you that such errors are part of a ‘filtering system’ in which cyber criminals target only the most gullible people.</p>



<p>The theory is that, if someone ignores clues about the way the message is written, they’re less likely to pick up clues during the scammer’s endgame.</p>



<p>However, this only applies to outlandish schemes like the oft-mocked Nigerian prince scam, which you have to be incredibly naive to fall victim to.</p>



<p>That, and scams like it, are manually operated: once someone takes to the bait, the scammer has to reply. As such, it benefits the crooks to make sure the pool of respondents contains only those who might believe the rest of the con.</p>



<p>But this doesn’t apply to phishing.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>See also:</strong></p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/the-effects-of-phishing-awareness-training-wear-off-over-time" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The effects of phishing awareness training wear off over time</a></li><li><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/6-reasons-phishing-is-so-popular-and-so-successful" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phishing attacks: 6 reasons why we keep taking the bait</a></li><li><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog?s=catches+of+the+month">Catches of the month: A round-up of the latest phishing scams</a></li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>With phishing, scammers don’t need to monitor inboxes and send tailored responses. They simply dump thousands of crafted messages on unsuspecting people.</p>



<p>As such, there’s no need to filter out potential respondents. Doing so reduces the pool of potential victims and helps those who didn&#8217;t fall victim to&nbsp;alert others to the scam, like we saw in the earlier example with Gimlet Media.</p>



<p>So why are so many phishing emails poorly written? The most obvious answer is that the scammers aren’t very good at writing.</p>



<p>Remember, many of them are from non-English-speaking countries and from backgrounds where they will have limited access or opportunity to learn the language.</p>



<p>With this in mind, it becomes a lot easier to spot the difference between a typo made by a legitimate sender and a scam.</p>



<p>When crafting phishing messages, scammers will often use a spellchecker or translation machine, which will give them all the right words but not necessarily in the proper context.</p>



<p>Take this example of a scam imitating Windows:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Windows.png" alt="A phishing email claiming that there has been &quot;unusual sign-in activity&quot;" class="wp-image-38111" width="631" height="463" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Windows.png 549w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Windows-300x220.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 631px) 100vw, 631px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Image: </em><a href="https://www.knowbe4.com/phishing"><em>KnowBe4</em></a></p>



<p>No individual word is spelled incorrectly, but the message is full of grammatical errors that a native speaker wouldn’t make, such as “We detected something unusual to use an application”.</p>



<p>Likewise, there are strings of missed words, such as in “a malicious user might trying to access&#8221; and “Please contact Security Communication Center&#8221;.</p>



<p>These are consistent with the kinds of mistakes people make when learning English. Any supposedly official message that’s written this way is almost certainly a scam.</p>



<p>That’s not to say any email with a mistake in it is a scam, however. Everyone makes typos from time to time, especially when they’re in a hurry.</p>



<p>It’s therefore the recipient’s responsibility to look at the context of the error and determine whether it’s a clue to something more sinister. You can do this by asking:</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li>Is it a common sign of a typo (like hitting an adjacent key)?</li><li>Is it a mistake a native speaker shouldn’t make (grammatical incoherence, words used in the wrong context)?</li><li>Is this email a template, which should have been crafted and copy-edited?</li><li>Is it consistent with previous messages I’ve received from this person?</li></ul>



<p>If you’re in any doubt, look for other clues that we&#8217;ve listed here or contact the sender using another line of communication, whether that&#8217;s in person, by phone, via their website, an alternative email address or through an instant message client.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>4. It includes infected attachments or suspicious links</strong></h2>



<p>Phishing emails come in many forms. We&#8217;ve focused on emails in this article, but you might also get scam text messages, phone calls or social media posts.</p>



<p>But no matter how phishing emails are delivered, they all contain a payload. This will either be an infected attachment that you’re asked to download or a link to a bogus website.</p>



<p>The purpose of these payloads is to capture sensitive information, such as login credentials, credit card details, phone numbers and account numbers.</p>



<p>In this next section, we&#8217;ll explain how each of those works.</p>



<h3 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Infected attachments</strong></h3>



<p>An infected attachment is a seemingly benign document that contains <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/malware-protection?promo_name=Phishing_5_ways&amp;promo_id=Blog&amp;promo_creative=Malware&amp;promo_position=In_Text" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">malware</a>. In a typical example, like the one below, the phisher claims to be sending an invoice:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="756" height="393" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43665" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-1.png 756w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-1-300x156.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 756px) 100vw, 756px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Source: </em><a href="https://www.mailguard.com.au/blog/fraudulent-invoice-email-carries-an-adobe-id-phishing-pdf-attachment" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>MailGuard</em></a></p>



<p>It doesn’t matter whether the recipient expects to receive an invoice from this person or not, because in most cases they won’t be sure what the message pertains to until they open the attachment.</p>



<p>When they open the attachment, they’ll see that the invoice isn’t intended for them, but it will be too late. The document unleashes malware on the victim’s computer, which could <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/7-types-of-malware-you-need-to-look-out-for" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">perform any number of nefarious activities</a>.</p>



<p>We advise that you never open an attachment unless you are fully confident that the message is from a legitimate party. Even then, you should look out for anything suspicious in the attachment.</p>



<p>For example, if you receive a pop-up warning about the file’s legitimacy or the application asks you to adjust your settings, then don’t proceed.</p>



<p>Contact the sender through an alternative means of communication and ask them to verify that it’s legitimate.</p>



<h3 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Suspicious links</strong></h3>



<p>You can spot a suspicious link if the destination address doesn’t match the context of the rest of the email.</p>



<p>For example, if you receive an email from Netflix, you would expect the link to direct you towards an address that begins ‘netflix.com’.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, many legitimate and scam emails hide the destination address in a button, so it’s not immediately apparent where the link goes to.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="538" height="507" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43666" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-2.png 538w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/image-2-300x283.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 538px) 100vw, 538px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Image: </em><a href="https://www.mailguard.com.au/blog/netflix-spoofed-once-again-in-phishing-email-scam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>MailGuard</em></a></p>



<p>In this example, the scammers are claiming that there is an issue with the recipient’s Netflix subscription. The email is designed to direct them to a mock-up of Netflix’s website, where they will be prompted to enter their payment details.</p>



<p>By including the link within a button that says ‘Update account now’, the fraudsters achieve two thing. First, it makes the message look genuine, with buttons become increasingly popular in emails and website. But more importantly, it hides the destination address – making it instead a hyperlink.</p>



<p>To ensure you don’t fall for schemes like this, you must train yourself to check where links go before opening them.</p>



<p>Thankfully, this is straightforward: on a computer, hover your mouse over the link, and the destination address appears in a small bar along the bottom of the browser.</p>



<p>On a mobile device, hold down on the link and a pop-up will appear containing the link.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>5. The message creates a sense of urgency</strong></h2>



<p>Scammers know that most of us procrastinate. We receive an email giving us important news, and we decide we’ll deal with it later.</p>



<p>But the longer you think about something, the more likely you are to notice things that don’t seem right.</p>



<p>Maybe you realise that the organisation doesn’t contact you by that email address, or you speak to a colleague and learn that they didn’t send you a document.</p>



<p>Even if you don’t get that ‘a-ha’ moment, coming back to the message with a fresh set of eyes might help reveal its true nature.</p>



<p>That’s why so many scams request that you act now or else it will be too late. This has been evident in every example we’ve used so far.</p>



<p>PayPal, Windows and Netflix all provide services that are regularly used, and any problems with those accounts could cause immediate inconveniences.</p>



<p>The manufactured sense of urgency is equally effective in workplace scams.</p>



<p>Criminals know that we&#8217;re likely to drop everything if our boss emails us with a vital request, especially when other senior colleagues are supposedly waiting on us.</p>



<p>A typical example looks like this:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" width="1060" height="645" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment.jpg" alt="A phishing email imitating the recipient's boss" class="wp-image-38114" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment.jpg 1060w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment-300x183.jpg 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment-768x467.jpg 768w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment-1024x623.jpg 1024w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/attachment-223x137.jpg 223w" sizes="(max-width: 1060px) 100vw, 1060px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Source: </em><a href="https://www.mailguard.com.au/blog/whaling-ceo-fraud-business-email-compromise-targeted-spear-phishing-attacks-continue-to-trouble-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>MailGuard</em></a></p>



<p>Phishing scams like this are particularly dangerous because, even if the recipient did suspect foul play, they might be too afraid to confront their boss.</p>



<p>After all, if they are wrong, they&#8217;re essentially&nbsp;implying that there was something unprofessional about the boss&#8217;s request.</p>



<p>However, organisations that value cyber security would accept that it’s better to be safe than sorry and perhaps even congratulate the employee for their caution.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Prevent phishing by educating your employees</strong></h2>



<p>To combat the threat of phishing, organisations must provide regular staff awareness training.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s only by reinforcing advice on avoiding scams that your team can develop good habits and detect malicious messages as second nature.</p>



<p>With our <strong><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-training-programme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phishing Staff Awareness Training Programme</a></strong>, these lessons are straightforward.</p>



<p>The online subscription course explains everything you need to know about phishing, and is updated each month to cover the latest scams.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-training-programme" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="200" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Phishing-staff-awareness.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43661" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Phishing-staff-awareness.png 640w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Phishing-staff-awareness-300x94.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></figure></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><em>A version of this blog was originally published on 16 March 2018.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/5-ways-to-detect-a-phishing-email">5 ways to detect a phishing email – with examples</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/5-ways-to-detect-a-phishing-email/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Cyber Threat Management?</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-cyber-threat-management</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 08:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43646</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cyber threat management is the process of identifying, analysing, evaluating and addressing an organisation’s cyber security requirements. With more than a 1,000 publicly disclosed security incidents last year – and countless others that weren’t reported – cyber security is a growing priority. It’s only by actively monitoring threats throughout their lifecycle that organisations can identify the risks that they face and the steps they should take to mitigate them. Why is cyber threat management important? Cyber threat management helps organisations prevent data breaches, but it also ensures that they’re equipped to deal with security risks when they do occur. This </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-cyber-threat-management">What is Cyber Threat Management?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cyber threat management is the process of identifying, analysing, evaluating and addressing an organisation’s cyber security requirements.</p>



<p>With more than a <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/data-breaches-and-cyber-attacks-in-2021-5-1-billion-breached-records" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1,000 publicly disclosed security incidents last year</a> – and countless others that weren’t reported – cyber security is a growing priority.</p>



<p>It’s only by actively monitoring threats throughout their lifecycle that organisations can identify the risks that they face and the steps they should take to mitigate them.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Why is cyber threat management important?</strong></h2>



<p>Cyber threat management helps organisations prevent data breaches, but it also ensures that they’re equipped to deal with security risks when they do occur.</p>



<p>This keeps damages to a minimum and reduces the costs associated with a data breach. According to a <a href="https://www.ibm.com/uk-en/security/data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ponemon Institute report</a>,&nbsp; organisations that can contain a breach within 30 days save more than $1 million (about £720,000) compared to those who take longer.</p>



<p>To ensure that you can respond to a breach promptly, you must have an effective threat management system in place. The framework increases the collaboration between people, processes and technology, helping organisations detect and respond to incidents.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Common cyber threat management challenges</strong></h2>



<p>When creating a cyber threat management system, organisations must consider a variety of factors.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Lack of visibility</strong></h4>



<p>Organisations must ensure that there are no blind spots in their information security processes. This means ensuring that you have complete visibility of the threat landscape, including internal and external risks.</p>



<p>The lack of visibility often stems from siloed processes, the lack of integration between point solutions, and undefined or inconsistent procedures across the organisation.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Lack of insight and reporting</strong></h4>



<p>An effective cyber threat management system should have KPIs that help security teams track their ability to detect and respond to information security risks.</p>



<p>This should include the MTTD (mean time to detect a risk) and the MTTR (mean time to respond). You should also monitor your return on investment, which is calculated by multiplying the average cost of a security incident by the number of incidents you might expect to experience in a given timeframe.</p>



<p>Creating reports based on this data and analysing the results can be a challenge. One issue is that, for the information to be valuable, organisations need a large sample size.</p>



<p>Organisations that experience information security risks infrequently are therefore limited in how often they can analyse the data.</p>



<p>Additionally, because organisations evolve over time, and the threat landscape always changing, it can be difficult to gain actionable results from these reports.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Skill shortages</strong></h4>



<p>There is a perpetual cyber security skills shortage, with <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3247708/security/research-suggests-cybersecurity-skills-shortage-is-getting-worse.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more than half of organisations saying that they lack qualified staff</a>.</p>



<p>It is therefore challenging to find qualified talent, and equally hard to retain them. With such a high demand, cyber security experts can demand generous salaries and career growth opportunities.</p>



<p>Organisations that are unable to provide those will find themselves left behind.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Best practices for cyber threat management</strong></h2>



<p>Some experts believe that the key to effective cyber threat management is technology. Tools such as automation and AI and help organisations counter sophisticated cyber attacks and give security teams insights into the threat landscape.</p>



<p>However, technology is only one part of the equation. Organisations must look at the ways they can use people and processes to address the full threat lifecycle – from identifying threats to responding to breaches.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Insight</strong></h4>



<p>Organisations must have a complete understanding of their sensitive assets and resources. This is where a <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/data-flow-mapping-tool" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data flow map</a> can help; it enables organisations to identify and visualise the ways that information moves through their systems.</p>



<p>The data flow map is often a valuable tool when conducting a <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/vsrisk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">risk assessment</a>, as it provides further insight into the way an organisation could be compromised.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Detection</strong></h4>



<p>Threat detection ensures that the organisation is promptly alerted to suspicious activity.</p>



<p>There are a variety of threat detection tools that organisations can use. Additionally, security teams should log suspicious activity and investigate signs of a data breach.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Response</strong></h4>



<p>When a security incident occurs, organisations must act quickly. They can do this by implementing an <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cyber-incident-response-management" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">incident response plan</a> that includes a framework for threat analysis, mitigation and continual improvement.</p>



<h4 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Recovery</strong></h4>



<p>Finally, organisations must consider recovery activities that ensure the organisation can continue functioning during disruption. This includes <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cyber-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyber resilience</a> and business continuity planning.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Simplify cyber threat management with IT Governance</strong></h2>



<p>For organisations looking to develop a cyber threat management system, IT Governance can help.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cyber-risk-management-diagram.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43649" width="217" height="215" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cyber-risk-management-diagram.png 350w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cyber-risk-management-diagram-300x297.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cyber-risk-management-diagram-150x150.png 150w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/cyber-risk-management-diagram-65x65.png 65w" sizes="(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px" /></figure></div>



<p>Our selection of <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cyber-security-risk-management" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyber risk management services</a> contain the support you need to understand the threat landscape, and detect, respond to and recover from cyber security incidents.</p>



<p>We provide guidance on developing suitable methods for managing risks in line with ISO 27005, the international standard for information security risk management.</p>



<p>Our experts can help you:</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li>Establish internal and external risk context, scope and boundaries, identify and assessing risks</li><li>Create communication lines with stakeholders to inform them of the likelihood and consequences of identified risks and risk statuses;</li><li>Establish priorities for risk treatment and acceptance;</li><li>Establish priorities to reduce the chance of risks occurring;</li><li>Develop risk monitoring and risk review processes; and</li><li>Educate stakeholders and staff about the risks to the organisation and the actions being taken to mitigate those risks.</li></ul>



<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cyber-security-risk-management"><strong>Get started</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-cyber-threat-management">What is Cyber Threat Management?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Information Security Management?</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-information-security-management</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43569</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Information security management is a way of protecting an organisation’s sensitive data from threats and vulnerabilities. The process is typically embedded via an ISMS (information security management system), which provides the framework for managing information security. At the centre of the framework is information risk management in, which organisations assess risks and the ways that they can compromise the confidentiality, integrity and availability of information. By managing risks, organisations gain a comprehensive understanding of the specific ways that they could suffer data breaches and other disruptive events, and the steps they can take to protect themselves. With the ever-growing threat </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-information-security-management">What Is Information Security Management?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Information security management is a way of protecting an organisation’s sensitive data from threats and vulnerabilities.</p>



<p>The process is typically embedded via an <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-an-isms-and-9-reasons-why-you-should-implement-one" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISMS (information security management system)</a>, which provides the framework for managing information security.</p>



<p>At the centre of the framework is information risk management in, which organisations assess risks and the ways that they can compromise the confidentiality, integrity and availability of information.</p>



<p>By managing risks, organisations gain a comprehensive understanding of the specific ways that they could suffer data breaches and other disruptive events, and the steps they can take to protect themselves.</p>



<p>With the ever-growing threat of data breaches and associated regulatory action, it’s essential that organisations manage information security risks effectively. In this blog, we explain how you can create such a system and the benefits of doing so.</p>



<h2 id="why-is-information-security-management-important"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Why is information security management important?</strong></h2>



<p>Modern businesses process and store vast amounts of sensitive data. The information might be necessary to provide services, to improve the user experience or to make better decisions about the way it operates.</p>



<p>Whatever the purpose of this data, it’s essential that organisations protect it. If unauthorised actors get their hands on the information, whether that’s from a cyber attack or a privacy breach, it will cause lasting damage.</p>



<p>The introduction of the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-protection-dpa-and-eu-data-protection-regulation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation)</a> and its UK equivalent have emphasised the importance of effective information security, giving supervisory authorities the power to issue sizeable fines.</p>



<p>But by creating an ISMS, organisations mitigate the risk of a breach and demonstrate to regulators that they take information security seriously. This will help during the investigation stage and will result in a more lenient penalty – or potentially no penalty at all.</p>



<h2 id="benefits-of-information-security-management"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Benefits of information security management</strong></h2>



<p>In addition to reducing the risk of data breaches and subsequent penalties, information security management provides a variety of other benefits.</p>



<p>For example, organisations that implement an ISMS will:</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li><strong>Reduce information security costs</strong></li></ul>



<p>Thanks to the risk assessment and analysis approach of an ISMS, organisations can reduce costs spent on indiscriminately adding layers of defensive technology that might not work.</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li><strong>Improve company culture</strong></li></ul>



<p>The Standard’s holistic approach covers the whole organisation, not just IT, and encompasses people, processes and technology.</p>



<p>This enables employees to readily understand risks and embrace security controls as part of their everyday working practices.</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li><strong>Win new business and enter new sectors</strong></li></ul>



<p>Many organisations nowadays will only work with third parties that can demonstrate effective information security. This is understandable, given that a data breach could result in costly delays, and may even instigate a supply chain attack.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>What are the objectives of information security management?</strong></h2>



<p>The main objective of information security management is to prevent data breaches, but it’s helpful to break this down into more granular detail.</p>



<p>For example, the prevention of data breaches begins with risk management, in which an organisation identifies its information assets and the ways they can be compromised.</p>



<p>To do this, organisations must split risk into its constituent components:</p>



<ul style="padding-top: 5px;"><li><strong>Vulnerabilities</strong>: known flaws that can be exploited to damage or compromise sensitive information.</li><li><strong>Threats</strong>: the actions by which vulnerabilities are exploited. For example, a cyber criminal leveraging a software flaw.</li><li><strong>Likelihood</strong>: how likely it is that a vulnerability will be exploited.</li><li><strong>Impact</strong>: the damage that occurs when a threat is exploited. This encompasses delays, lost business, financial effects and reputational damage.</li></ul>



<p>Meanwhile, organisations also need to consider the different ways that information can be breached. This can be considered across the three pillars of information security.</p>



<p>The first is <strong>confidentiality</strong>, which refers to whether information is accessible to or disclosed to unauthorised people.</p>



<p>Second is <strong>integrity</strong>, which refers to the completeness and accuracy of sensitive information.</p>



<p>Finally, there is the <strong>availability </strong>of sensitive information, which refers to whether authorised users are able to access information on demand.</p>



<h2 id="information-security-management-standards-and-compliance"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Information security management standards and compliance</strong></h2>



<p>In many cases, information security management is not simply a recommendation but a compliance requirement.</p>



<p>For example, any organisation that wishes to certify to <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso27001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 27001</a>, the international standard that describes best practice for information security, must implement an ISMS.</p>



<p>Likewise, an ISMS is a required for organisations that are subject to the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/pci_dss" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard)</a> and the US’s HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act).</p>



<p>Additionally, although the GDPR doesn’t expressly require organisations to implement an ISMS, doing so helps them achieve compliance.</p>



<p>This includes the requirement to adopt “appropriate technical and organisational measures” to protect sensitive data.</p>



<p>Notably, the Regulation doesn’t provide detailed guidance on how organisations should do this, instead compelling companies to look at existing best practices, such as those outlined in ISO 27001.</p>



<h2 id="get-started-with-iso-27001"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Get started with ISO 27001</strong></h2>



<p>For those looking for further guidance on ISO 27001 and how it helps organisations with information security management, IT Governance is here to help.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/infosec-iso27001-introduction-apr-21.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43570" width="267" height="189" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/infosec-iso27001-introduction-apr-21.png 512w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/infosec-iso27001-introduction-apr-21-300x212.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/infosec-iso27001-introduction-apr-21-211x150.png 211w" sizes="(max-width: 267px) 100vw, 267px" /></figure></div>



<p>Our free green paper, <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/green-papers/information-security-and-iso-27001-an-introduction" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Information Security and ISO 27001 – An introduction</strong></a>, provides a comprehensive overview of the Standard and the benefits of implementing an ISMS.</p>



<p>You’ll discover how ISO 27001 works, and the ways it relates to ISO 27002, ISO 9001 and ISO 14001.</p>



<p>You’ll also learn how the Standard can help your organisation meet its legal and regulatory obligations, and the value of certification.</p>



<p>The guide also contains key points to consider when implementing your ISMS, helping you get develop effective information security management processes.</p>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/green-papers/information-security-and-iso-27001-an-introduction" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Download now</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-is-information-security-management">What Is Information Security Management?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 cyber security predictions for 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/9-cyber-security-predictions-for-2022</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43556</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Everybody wants to know what the future holds. Those who are a step ahead of the rest can foresee challenges and avoid falling into pitfalls, or they can spot opportunities and ride to success. This is as true in the cyber security landscape as it is in any other. But predictions are difficult. After all, who at the start of 2020 could have foreseen what the next two years would be like? (Except maybe Time Magazine.) Granted, vaccine rollouts have helped control the pandemic, with restrictions easing in much of the world. But there remains great uncertainty about how we’ll </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/9-cyber-security-predictions-for-2022">9 cyber security predictions for 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Everybody wants to know what the future holds. Those who are a step ahead of the rest can foresee challenges and avoid falling into pitfalls, or they can spot opportunities and ride to success.</p>



<p>This is as true in the cyber security landscape as it is in any other. But predictions are difficult. After all, who at the start of 2020 could have foreseen what the next two years would be like? (<a href="https://time.com/magazine/us/4766607/may-15th-2017-vol-189-no-18-u-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Except maybe Time Magazine</a>.)</p>



<p>Granted, vaccine rollouts have helped control the pandemic, with restrictions easing in much of the world. But there remains great uncertainty about how we’ll come out of the crisis and what business challenges await us.</p>



<p>To help you understand what might be in store in 2022, we’ve collected nine forecasts from cyber security experts.</p>



<h2 id="1-cyber-insurance-will-become-more-popular-and-more-comprehensive"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>1. Cyber insurance will become more popular and more comprehensive</strong></h2>



<p>Over the past few years, organisations across the globe have come to understand just how pervasive cyber threats are.</p>



<p>This is not just a result of the pandemic but also the increase in cyber attacks and security incidents caused by employees failing to follow policies and processes.</p>



<p>It’s led to a growing trend for organisations to purchase cyber insurance, which <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/emilsayegh/2022/01/06/predicting-what-2022-holds-for-cybersecurity/?sh=6299c3ab2b72" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Forbes contributor Emil Sayegh</a> believes will continue in 2022.</p>



<p>“Faced with a costly environment of escalating risks, the cyber insurance industry has seen many challenges in the past year,” he said.</p>



<p>“Even though many businesses are required to carry cyber insurance, these conditions are leading to companies no longer purchasing extensive policies. This market squeeze will certainly affect the cyber insurance industry itself.</p>



<p>“We are going to see this happen, but we will also see a resurgence of cyber insurance as companies become more aware of the risks associated with data breaches and standardize on what it takes to attain coverage.”</p>



<p>We’ve already seen insurers adjust their policies, tightening the definition of ‘cyber attacks’ and reducing the circumstances under which pay-outs are necessary.</p>



<p>Sayegh believes that, in response, organisations will purchase more extensive policies to protect them from a wider array of threats.</p>



<h2 id="2-cyber-insurance-premiums-will-increase"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>2. Cyber insurance premiums will increase</strong></h2>



<p>That’s not the only way the cyber insurance industry will change this year, <a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3646258/top-8-cybersecurity-predictions-for-2022.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to Liz Miller</a>, an analyst at Constellation Research.</p>



<p>Miller says that the increased demand for cyber insurance and the rise in high-profile data breaches will lead to premiums “shooting up”.</p>



<p>“[Cyber insurance is] much more expensive these days as costs surge, and are most likely to continue soaring,” she predicts.</p>



<p>“Insurances are like double-edged swords: while they do provide security coverage and have become a &#8216;must-have&#8217; for organizations, they have also alerted the attackers to asking for even more ransom in the attacks, knowing it’s all covered.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h3 id="panel-discussion-how-to-prevent-and-respond-to-the-most-successful-vulnerabilities-exploited-by-attackers"><strong>Panel discussion: How to prevent and respond to the most successful vulnerabilities exploited by attackers</strong></h3>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/laptop-with-bright-screen.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/laptop-with-bright-screen.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43557" width="291" height="195" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/laptop-with-bright-screen.png 400w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/laptop-with-bright-screen-300x200.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 291px) 100vw, 291px" /></a></figure></div>



<p>Join our experts for this webinar, where we analyse attacks such as Log4j, and provide insight into how cyber criminals deploy attacks.</p>



<p>This 45-minute presentation will help you understand the most successful vulnerabilities exploited by attackers.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll also provide tips on the approaches you can take to handle vulnerabilities and the measures you implement to reduce risks.</p>



<p>The presentation is on 24 February 2022, from 3pm.</p>



<div style="height:16px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/resources/cyber-security"><strong>Register now</strong></a></div>
</div>



<div style="height:11px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 id="3-software-supply-chain-attacks-will-become-widespread"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>3. Software supply chain attacks will become widespread</strong></h2>



<p>Supply chain security has come under greater scrutiny in recent years, as organisations recognise the damage that can result from third-party breaches.</p>



<p>Disruption within the supply chain can result in delays and an inability to provide services. Plus, in several high-profile cases, criminal hackers have been able to exploit vulnerabilities and target organisations through the supply chain.</p>



<p>Justin Fier, the director of cyber intelligence and analytics at Darktrace, <a href="https://www.darktrace.com/en/blog/the-future-of-cyber-security-software-supply-chain-attacks-become-a-given-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">believes this will become a major problem in 2022</a>.</p>



<p>“One area of focus is the need to enhance software supply chain security. There are many aspects included that most would consider industry best practice of a robust DevSecOps program, but one area that will see increased scrutiny is providing the purchaser, the government in this example, a software bill of materials,” he writes.</p>



<p>“This would be a complete list of all software components leveraged within the software solution, along with where it comes from.</p>



<p>“The expectation is that everything that is used within or can affect your software, such as open source, is understood, versions tracked, scrutinized for security issues and risks, assessed for vulnerabilities, and monitored, just as you do with any in-house developed code.</p>



<p>“This will impact organizations that both consume and those that deliver software services.</p>



<p>“Considering this can be very manual and time-consuming, we could expect that Third-Party Risk Management teams will likely play a key role in developing programs to track and assess software supply chain security, especially considering they are usually the front line team who also receives inbound security questionnaires from their business partners.”</p>



<h2 id="4-the-great-resignation-will-increase-insider-threats"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>4. The ‘Great Resignation’ will increase insider threats</strong></h2>



<p>One of the more unexpected side-effects of the pandemic has been that people are quitting their jobs in record numbers.</p>



<p>‘The Great Resignation’ began in the US, with employees posting online about unfair work expectations at a time when social distancing restrictions were being ignored by many.</p>



<p>The trend later spread to the UK, with the <a href="https://www.ons.gov.uk/employmentandlabourmarket/peopleinwork/employmentandemployeetypes/bulletins/employmentintheuk/november2021" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Office for National Statistics reporting</a> that 979,000 people left their jobs between July and September 2021.</p>



<p>One of the driving forces of ‘The Great Resignation’ is people’s sense of resentment in the workplace. <a href="https://www.darktrace.com/en/blog/the-future-of-cyber-security-2022-predictions-from-darktrace/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Toby Lewis, the head of threat analysis at Darktrace</a>, believes this increases the risk of employees acting maliciously against their employer.</p>



<p>“We can expect to see disgruntled employees steal information or employees unintentionally taking information with them to their next job. We have also seen criminal groups attempt to recruit insiders by offering a large sum of money or a portion of the ransom,” he writes.</p>



<p>“Whether intentional or unintentional, insiders will become a growing priority for businesses in 2022. With more organizations relying on cloud communication and collaboration applications, these threats become even more difficult to detect across sprawling digital infrastructures.</p>



<p>“With employees working remotely, enforcing the return of equipment and data will become even more difficult.”</p>



<h2 id="5-criminal-hackers-will-target-mobile-devices"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>5. Criminal hackers will target mobile devices</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/about/press-releases/2021_advanced-persistent-threats-in-2022-what-to-look-out-for-next-year" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kaspersky’s cyber security predictions for 2022</a> focuses on APTs (advanced persistent threats), which are stealth attacks typically performed by nation states or state-sponsored groups. Among its APT forecasts is an increase in attacks targeting mobile device.</p>



<p>“Mobile devices have always been a tidbit for attackers, with smartphones travelling along with their owners everywhere, and each potential target acting as a storage for a huge amount of valuable information” Kaspersky said.</p>



<p>It said that iOS users need to be especially careful. The researchers saw a significant increase in attacks targeting the iOS platform, and it expects that trend to continue in 2022.</p>



<h2 id="6-there-will-be-an-increase-in-nation-state-attacks"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>6. There will be an increase in nation-state attacks</strong></h2>



<p>The possibility of state-sponsored cyber attacks will already be on people’ minds, thanks to the growing tensions between Russia and Ukraine.</p>



<p>Russian actors have previously targeted Ukraine, while pro-Ukrainian ‘hacktivists’ recently struck back with <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/01/31/1076895949/group-launched-cyberattacks-to-try-to-keep-russian-troops-out-of-belarus?t=1643968782429" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a cyber attack on Belarusian railway lines</a> in an effort to keep Russian forces out of the country.</p>



<p>But this isn’t the only conflict that could be played out in cyberspace, with China, the US, North Korea and Israel having all been associated with state-sponsored attacks in recent years.</p>



<p>John Bambenek, the principal threat researcher at Netenrich, believes <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/96781-top-15-cybersecurity-predictions-for-2022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we could see further nation-state attacks in 2022</a>.</p>



<p>“Recent years have seen cyberattacks large and small conducted by state and non-state actors alike. State actors organize and fund these operations to achieve geopolitical objectives and seek to avoid attribution wherever possible,” he said.</p>



<p>“Non-state actors, however, often seek notoriety in addition to the typical monetary rewards. Both actors are part of a larger, more nebulous ecosystem of brokers that provides information, access, and financial channels for those willing to pay.</p>



<p>“Rising geopolitical tensions, increased access to cryptocurrencies and dark money, and general instability due to the pandemic will contribute to a continued rise in cyber threats in 2022 for nearly every industry.”</p>



<h2 id="7-password-less-authentication-will-fail-without-multifactor-authentication"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>7. Password-less authentication will fail without multifactor authentication</strong></h2>



<p>Last year, Windows revealed plans to remove passwords from its operating system. It is instead giving users the ability to log in using biometric authentication, a hardware token or an email with an OTP (one-time password).</p>



<p>When confirming the decision, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2021/09/15/the-passwordless-future-is-here-for-your-microsoft-account/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft said</a>: “Nobody likes passwords. They’re inconvenient. They’re a prime target for attacks.”</p>



<p>That might be true, but <a href="https://www.watchguard.com/uk/wgrd-resource-center/cyber-security-predictions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to WatchGuard Technologies</a>, the alternative isn’t viable. The security company doesn’t doubt that the move will be popular with users. However, it believes it will be equally popular with criminal hackers, who will find ways to exploit the system.</p>



<p>“Though we commend Microsoft for making this bold move, we believe all single-factor authentication mechanisms are the wrong choice and repeat password mistakes of old,” WatchGuard wrote.</p>



<p>“Biometrics are not a magic pill that’s impossible to defeat – in fact, researchers and attackers have repeatedly defeated various biometric mechanisms.</p>



<p>“Sure, the technology is getting better, but attack techniques evolve too (especially in a world of social media, photogrammetry and 3D printing).</p>



<p>“In general, hardware tokens are strong single factor option too, but the RSA breach proved that they are not undefeatable either. And frankly, cleartext emails with an OTP are simply a bad idea.”</p>



<p>WatchGuard states that Microsoft’s decision is a sideways step, introducing other technologies that are commonly associated with multifactor authentication while weakening their integrity by removing the need for a password.</p>



<p>“In our opinion, Microsoft (and others) could have truly solved this problem by making MFA mandatory and easy in Windows,” WatchGuard writes.</p>



<p>“You can still use [the alternatives] as one easy factor of authentication, but organizations should force users to pair it with another, like a push approval to your mobile phone that’s sent over an encrypted channel (no text or clear email).”</p>



<h2 id="8-remote-work-will-affect-organisations-security"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>8. Remote work will affect organisations’ security</strong></h2>



<p>Even with COVID-19 restrictions easing, many organisations are continuing to give employees the opportunity to work from home. Although you’d expect organisations to have by now found a way to balance convenience with security, it’s proving a challenging task.</p>



<p>Moreover, Andrew Howard, CEO of Kudelski Security, <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2021/12/23/five-cybersecurity-predictions-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">believes employees are not doing their part</a>.</p>



<p>“As more companies adopt a hybrid approach, technical security will increase while personal security will decrease,” he writes.</p>



<p>“Since employees are working remotely, employee/employer relationships are turning transactional and devoid of trust. This may cause weaker employee buy-in to internal security training programs as employees experience a lack of ownership and personal responsibility in helping to secure their organizations.</p>



<p>“Especially as Gen Z enters the workforce, the increasingly common belief that governments should take primary responsibility for protecting data and a lack of company loyalty will negatively impact already existing privacy issues.”</p>



<h2 id="9-ransomware-attacks-will-slow"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>9. Ransomware attacks will slow</strong></h2>



<p>We’ll end our list on a positive note, with <a href="https://www.securityweek.com/predictions-securityweeks-2022-cybersecurity-outlook" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SecurityWeek’s editor-at-large, Ryan Naraine, predicting</a> that we’ll see fewer ransomware attacks in 2022.</p>



<p>“Major ransomware outbreaks will slowly subside as companies beef up defenses and counter-operations by global law enforcement disrupt and (partially) disable the high-profile gangs,” he writes.</p>



<p>“In 2022, security leaders will continue to prioritize the basics (properly tested backups, patching, multi-factor authentication and secure cloud deployments) to reduce exposure to ransomware extortion, making it more of a nuisance than a national security threat.</p>



<p>“We will see a blurring of the lines between ransomware and nation-state data theft and espionage campaigns (see prediction on Iran and North Korea below).”</p>



<h2 id="plan-for-success-in-2022"; style="text-transform: none;" ><strong>Plan for success in 2022</strong></h2>



<p>If there’s one thing that each of these experts’ predictions has in common, it’s that organisations must adapt to the ever-evolving cyber threat landscape if they are to survive and thrive in 2022.</p>



<p>Whether you’re concerned about ransomware, remote working, insider threats or any other risk, you must take the time to review your security measures and determine whether they are fit for the current environment.</p>



<p>This might mean <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/category/penetration-testing?promo_name=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_id=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_creative=update_and_refresh&amp;promo_position=InText" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">testing your infrastructure</a> to identify vulnerabilities, <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/category/itgp-toolkits?promo_name=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_id=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_creative=update_and_refresh&amp;promo_position=CTAButton" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">updating your documentation</a> to bolster your GDPR compliance, or improving your employees’ security and data protection awareness with <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/category/staff-awareness-e-learning-courses?promo_name=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_id=2022_marketing_campaign&amp;promo_creative=update_and_refresh&amp;promo_position=CTAButton" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staff awareness training</a>.</p>



<p>No matter what you’re looking to improve this year, IT Governance is here to help. Our products and resources are created by experts and designed for organisations of any size.</p>



<p>Whatever 2022 has in store, you can at least control your cyber risks.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/set-your-organisation-up-for-success?promo_name=homepage&amp;promo_id=carousel-1-success2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43487" width="726" height="227" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10.png 640w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10-300x94.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 726px) 100vw, 726px" /></a></figure></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/9-cyber-security-predictions-for-2022">9 cyber security predictions for 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catches of the Month: Phishing Scams for February 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/catches-of-the-month-phishing-scams-for-february-2022</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 08:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Catches of the Month]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43547</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our February 2022 review of phishing attacks, in which we explore the latest scams and the tactics that cyber criminals use to trick people into handing over their personal information. This month, we look at a bogus online contest designed to capture your Facebook login details, the latest Microsoft scam and whether ‘passwordless’ security can mitigate the threat of scams. Fraudsters are hijacking Facebook accounts via Messenger Facebook Messenger users are being warned about a phishing campaign in which fraudsters impersonate your friends and hijack your account. Victims receive a message from one of their contacts asking for </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/catches-of-the-month-phishing-scams-for-february-2022">Catches of the Month: Phishing Scams for February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to our February 2022 review of phishing attacks, in which we explore the latest scams and the tactics that cyber criminals use to trick people into handing over their personal information.</p>



<p>This month, we look at a bogus online contest designed to capture your Facebook login details, the latest Microsoft scam and whether ‘passwordless’ security can mitigate the threat of scams.</p>



<h2 id="fraudsters-are-hijacking-facebook-accounts-via-messenger" ;="" style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Fraudsters are hijacking Facebook accounts via Messenger</strong></h2>



<p>Facebook Messenger users are being <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/finland-warns-of-facebook-accounts-hijacked-via-messenger-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">warned about a phishing campaign</a> in which fraudsters impersonate your friends and hijack your account.</p>



<p>Victims receive a message from one of their contacts asking for help registering for an online contest.</p>



<p>According to the message, there is a huge cash prize for the winner, and to enter, they need to share the link with a friend, who will receive an authentication code to verify that they are real.</p>



<p>However, the code is actually part of Facebook’s password reset mechanism. If the victim shares the code, the fraudster can use it change the victim’s password and take control of their account.</p>



<p>Unless you know the pretext, this is a tricky scam to spot because the message really is coming from someone you know. But how is the scammer able to do this?</p>



<p>The answer is that their message is just one part of a more sophisticated attack. It begins with one compromised account – which can be done using any traditional phishing method or via a brute-force attack.</p>



<p>The attacker then goes through the users’ contacts, finding phone numbers or email addresses, which they can use to begin the login process before selecting the ‘forgot your password’ option.</p>



<p>This will send the one-time password to the victim’s account. From there, they send the victim the request for the code via Facebook Messenger, under the guise that it is part of contest.</p>



<p>Because the attacker performs the same scam on countless people in the victim’s contact list, one compromised account can result in hundreds more being hijacked.</p>



<p>It’s a time-consuming operation, because one-time passwords have a short lifespan, which indicates that the attackers are monitoring the attacks in real-time. Nonetheless, the nature of the campaign means that it can grow exponentially.</p>



<p>The scam was first spotted by Finland’s National Cyber Security Centre, which warns Facebook users to be wary of any impromptu request for information via Messenger.</p>



<p>“If the&nbsp;message sender is a friend, you can contact him, for example, by phone and ask if he is aware of this&nbsp;message. This information should not be disclosed to strangers,” <a href="https://www.kyberturvallisuuskeskus.fi/fi/ttn_20012022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the organisation advises</a>.</p>



<p>Additionally, because the attacker will be performing the same scam on multiple people in the victim’s friend list, you may have mutual friends who have been targeted. If you receive a message that looks suspicious, you should friends whether they’ve received the same message.</p>



<p>Likewise, if you spot that your friend’s account has been hijacked, you should warn mutual friends to ensure that they don’t fall victim.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/set-your-organisation-up-for-success" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43487" width="667" height="208" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10.png 640w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Blog-Horizontal-640px-x-200px-10-300x94.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 667px) 100vw, 667px" /></a></figure></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2 id="microsoft-users-targeted-by-oauth-scam" ;="" style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Microsoft users targeted by OAuth scam</strong></h2>



<p>Microsoft’s Security Intelligence team are warning Office 365 customers about a <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-warns-about-this-phishing-attack-that-wants-to-read-your-emails/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">phishing scam that’s designed to capture their login permissions</a>.</p>



<p>Microsoft is the <a href="https://www.brandshelter.com/en/news/microsoft-leads-big-brands-as-most-phished-company" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most phished company in the world</a>, and attacks such as this are an almost ever-present threat.</p>



<p>However, what differentiates this scam from others like it is that it isn’t simply targeting victims’ passwords. It instead uses a malicious app dubbed ‘Upgrade’, and asks users to grant it OAuth permissions.</p>



<p>OAuth is an open standard that’s used to grant third-party apps access to account information and data within apps.</p>



<p>In this case, the attackers use OAuth permissions to read and write emails and calendar items, create inbox rules and view the victims’ contacts.</p>



<p>In a tweet, <a href="https://twitter.com/MsftSecIntel/status/1484623341155610624" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft confirmed that</a> it has deactivated the app in Azure AD, and has notified affected customers. But this isn’t necessarily the end of the matter.</p>



<p>Microsoft has acknowledged that <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2021/07/14/microsoft-delivers-comprehensive-solution-to-battle-rise-in-consent-phishing-emails/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">consent-phishing emails that abuse OAuth are on the rise</a>, and that attacks are hard to prevent because they don’t conform to many techniques common to phishing.</p>



<p>“In most cases, consent phishing attacks do not involve password theft, as access tokens don&#8217;t require knowledge of the user&#8217;s password, yet attackers are still able to steal confidential data and other sensitive information,” Microsoft notes.</p>



<p>“Attackers can then maintain persistence in the target organization and perform reconnaissance to further compromise the network.”</p>



<h2 id="microsoft-strikes-back-against-scammers" ;="" style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Microsoft strikes back against scammers</strong></h2>



<p>In more positive Microsoft-based phishing news, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-blocked-billions-of-brute-force-and-phishing-attacks-last-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the tech giant spoke last week</a> about its successful attempts to identify and prevent online attacks.</p>



<p>In 2021, it blocked 25.6 billion Azure AD brute-force authentication attacks and intercepted 35.7 billion phishing emails.</p>



<p>The news demonstrates the effectiveness of the anti-malware software Microsoft Defender, which comes as standard with Windows devices. However, it’s worth remembering that no matter how robust these systems are, they will never be 100% effective.</p>



<p>Indeed, the success of online fraud is a numbers game. It costs almost nothing to send a phishing email, so attackers can launch hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of emails and it only takes one person to fall victim for their efforts to have been worth it.</p>



<p>It’s why Microsoft’s corporate vice president for security, compliance and identity, Vasu Jakkal, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/02/03/cyber-signals-defending-against-cyber-threats-with-the-latest-research-insights-and-trends/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">urges individuals to consider additional ways to secure their accounts</a> beyond the use of passwords.</p>



<p>“For example, our research shows that across industries, only 22 percent of customers using Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD), Microsoft&#8217;s Cloud Identity Solution, have implemented strong identity authentication protection as of December 2021,” Jakkal&nbsp;said.</p>



<p>&#8220;MFA (multi-factor authentication) and passwordless solutions can go a long way in preventing a variety of threats and we&#8217;re committed to educating customers on solutions such as these to better protect themselves.”</p>



<p><a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/two-factor-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The benefits of MFA authentication</a> are widely discussed, but ‘passwordless solutions’ will be a new concept to many. Microsoft has been rolling out the concept over the past year, giving users the option to replace passwords with biometric authentication, a hardware token or an email with a one-time password.</p>



<p>Many people are celebrating the move, given both the insecurity and inconvenience of passwords. However, not everyone is on board.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.watchguard.com/uk/wgrd-resource-center/cyber-security-predictions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">WatchGuard Technologies</a> describes ‘passwordless solutions’ “simply repeat[ing] the mistakes from history”.</p>



<p>It adds: “The only strong solution to digital identify validation is multi-factor authentication (MFA). In our opinion, Microsoft (and others) could have truly solved this problem by making MFA mandatory&nbsp;and&nbsp;easy in Windows.”</p>



<h2 id="can-you-spot-a-scam" ;="" style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Can you spot a scam?</strong></h2>



<p>As we move into 2022, organisations should consider email security and phishing awareness at one of their biggest priorities.</p>



<p>All companies are vulnerable, no matter their size or the sector, so it’s essential to understand how you might be targeted and what you can do to prevent a breach.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GRC-eLearning-Phishing.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43399" width="145" height="145" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GRC-eLearning-Phishing.png 586w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GRC-eLearning-Phishing-300x300.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GRC-eLearning-Phishing-150x150.png 150w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GRC-eLearning-Phishing-65x65.png 65w" sizes="(max-width: 145px) 100vw, 145px" /></figure></div>



<p>You can help educate your staff with IT Governance’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-course" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Phishing Staff Awareness Training Programme</a>.</p>



<p>This 45-minute course&nbsp;uses real-world examples like the ones we’ve discussed here to explain how phishing attacks work, the tactics that cyber criminals use and how you can detect malicious emails.</p>



<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/phishing-staff-awareness-course"><strong>Get started</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/catches-of-the-month-phishing-scams-for-february-2022">Catches of the Month: Phishing Scams for February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the benefits of cyber security as a service?</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-benefits-of-cyber-security-as-a-service</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43445</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>With organisations’ cyber security requirements becoming more complex and the threat of cyber attacks growing each year, many decision-makers are turning towards cyber security as a service. This approach, also known as managed cyber security, works by outsourcing cyber security to a third party. Organisations such as IT Governance that offer cyber security as a service assign dedicated experts to oversee the organisation’s data protection and data privacy needs. As such, you’ll be guaranteed to have greater cyber security advice at your disposal, but the service isn’t just about improving the knowledge at your disposal. In this blog, we look </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-benefits-of-cyber-security-as-a-service">What are the benefits of cyber security as a service?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With organisations’ cyber security requirements becoming more complex and the threat of cyber attacks growing each year, many decision-makers are turning towards <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/cyber-security-as-a-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyber security as a service</a>.</p>



<p>This approach, also known as managed cyber security, works by outsourcing cyber security to a third party.</p>



<p>Organisations such as IT Governance that offer cyber security as a service assign dedicated experts to oversee the organisation’s data protection and data privacy needs. As such, you’ll be guaranteed to have greater cyber security advice at your disposal, but the service isn’t just about improving the knowledge at your disposal.</p>



<p>In this blog, we look at three other ways that cyber security as a service can benefit your organisation, and help you understand how the process works.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>1. You’ll achieve security peace of mind</strong></h2>



<p>The stakes involved in cyber security have never been higher. According to <a href="https://www.ibm.com/uk-en/security/data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IBM’s Cost of a Data Breach Report 2020</a>, organisations spend £2.9 million on average recovering from security incidents.</p>



<p>This includes the costs associated with detecting a breach, notifying affected customers, regulatory penalties and customer churn.</p>



<p>Getting cyber security right therefore isn’t simply a case of avoiding a disruptive incident. Rather, it affects the long-term health of an organisation and could be the difference between a minor setback and going out of business.</p>



<p>With this looming over organisations, it’s understandable that they might worry. But without the right guidance in place, it is difficult to know how to protect yourself. Even organisations that do take steps to bolster their defences won’t be sure that the measures they have in place are adequate or if their spending is appropriate.</p>



<p>But with cyber security as a service, you can focus on doing what your business does best and let the data protection experts handle the rest.</p>



<p>Services typically come with a dedicated team of experts, tools, training and support that can be deployed immediately, protecting you from a range of threats.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>2. You’ll save money</strong></h2>



<p>Cyber security as a service saves organisations money in two ways. As we discussed in our first point, the service mitigates the risk of a data breach and, by extension, the costs associated with it.</p>



<p>Additionally, it’s a more cost-effective way of gaining cyber security support than hiring an in-house personnel.</p>



<p>The salary of an experienced cyber security analyst is typically £70,000 a year or more – and depending on the size of your organisation, you will probably need additional team members to oversee your day-to-day security operations.</p>



<p>By contrast, <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cyber-security-as-a-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IT Governance’s Cyber Security as a Service</a> begins at just £15,000 a year and covers everything you need to protect your organisation.</p>



<p>You’ll receive a pool of experts who can help address network infrastructure, information security, Cloud computing and anything else that’s relevant to your organisation.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>3. You’ll receive cyber insurance cover</strong><strong>﻿</strong><strong></strong></h2>



<p>Many cyber-security-as-a-service offerings include <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/cyber-insurance-a-guide-for-businesses" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cyber insurance</a> as part of the package.</p>



<p>Cyber insurance is a specific type of protection that helps organisations mitigate the financial costs associated with information security incidents.</p>



<p>These costs typically won’t be included in standard business insurance policies, which tend to cover only the damage or loss of equipment itself, rather than harm caused by a cyber security event.</p>



<p>Cyber insurance instead covers the costs of incidents that affect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of information. This includes cyber attacks and data breaches, as well as other events that impact IT systems and networks.</p>



<p>Policies generally provide organisations with the means to manage the incident. This includes forensic investigation, incident response, legal assistance and public relations support.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Our expertise, your peace of mind</strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CSAAS.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43446" width="159" height="159" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CSAAS.png 320w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CSAAS-300x300.png 300w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CSAAS-150x150.png 150w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/CSAAS-65x65.png 65w" sizes="(max-width: 159px) 100vw, 159px" /></figure></div>



<p>You can find out more about <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cyber-security-as-a-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IT Governance’s Cyber Security as a Service</a> package on our website.</p>



<p>The annual subscription service can be tailored to suit your organisation, with our experts happy to help you determine what protections you need to implement.</p>



<div style="height:1px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/cyber-security-as-a-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Get started</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/what-are-the-benefits-of-cyber-security-as-a-service">What are the benefits of cyber security as a service?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 14 Cloud Security Principles explained</title>
      <link>https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/the-14-cloud-security-principles-explained</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Irwin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 09:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/?p=43442</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cloud security is an essential part of today’s cyber security landscape. With hybrid working now the norm, many organisations are relying on Cloud services to access data from home or the office. But whenever organisations adopt technological solutions such as this, they must acknowledge the risks that come with it. Indeed, Cloud computing can increase the risk of data breaches and regulatory non-compliance, as well as introducing other vulnerabilities. To mitigate these risks, the NCSC (National Cyber Security Centre) created the Cloud Security Principles, which outline 14 guidelines for protecting information stored online. In this blog, we look at those </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/the-14-cloud-security-principles-explained">The 14 Cloud Security Principles explained</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cloud security is an essential part of today’s cyber security landscape. With <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/information-security-for-hybrid-working" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hybrid working</a> now the norm, many organisations are relying on Cloud services to access data from home or the office.</p>



<p>But whenever organisations adopt technological solutions such as this, they must acknowledge the risks that come with it. Indeed, Cloud computing can <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/top-5-cloud-security-challenges-risks-and-threats" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increase the risk of data breaches</a> and regulatory non-compliance, as well as introducing other vulnerabilities.</p>



<p>To mitigate these risks, the NCSC (National Cyber Security Centre) created the <a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/cloud-security/implementing-the-cloud-security-principles" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cloud Security Principles</a>, which outline 14 guidelines for protecting information stored online.</p>



<p>In this blog, we look at those principles and explain the steps you can take to meet them.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>1. Data in transit protection</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: User data transiting networks should be adequately protected against tampering and eavesdropping.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: There are many ways you can bolster your network security, such as auditing and mapping your infrastructure to look for vulnerabilities. This might include spotting misconfigured firewalls or physical security threats.</p>



<p>You should also make sure firmware and software are up to date, check that default passwords have been changed and secure your physical premises.</p>



<p>Additionally, you should consider encrypting data or using VPNs where possible. Encryption can greatly reduce the risk of data being compromised in transit, but it will also make sharing data more complex and will require significant resources.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, VPNs protect remote users by extending your organisation’s private network across a public network. This enables employees to send and receive data as if their computer was directly connected to your organisation’s network.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>2. Asset protection and resilience</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: User data, and the assets storing or processing it, should be protected against physical tampering, loss, damage or seizure.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: The NCSC breaks down this principle into six parts: physical location and legal jurisdiction, data centre security, data at rest protection, data sanitisation, equipment disposal, and physical resilience and availability.</p>



<p>Physical location and legal jurisdiction is relevant if you are subject to laws such as the <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/data-protection-dpa-and-eu-data-protection-regulation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation)</a>, which contain strict rules on data depending on its location.</p>



<p>To determine this, you must identify the locations at which your data is stored, processed and managed, and consider how this affects your compliance with relevant legislation.</p>



<p>Similarly, you should consider whether the legal jurisdiction within which the Cloud service provider operates applies to you.</p>



<p>Data centre security refers to the controls you have implemented to protect the physical locations in which data is stored. This should cover the threat of unauthorised access, tampering, theft and reconfiguration of systems.</p>



<p>Data at rest protection refers to the security of information stored in the Cloud, and data sanitation refers to the process of supplying resources, transferring them and having users return them when no longer needed.</p>



<p>Equipment disposal requires organisations to securely delete or discard information at the end of its lifecycle. Physical records should be shredded, while digital documents and other relevant information – such as credentials and configuring information – should be wiped from hard drives.</p>



<p>Finally, physical resilience and availability refers to an organisation’s ability to function in the event of failures, security incidents and cyber attacks.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>3. Separation between users</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: A malicious or compromised user of the service should not be able to affect the service or data of another.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: Factors that affect user separation include where the separation controls are implemented, who the organisation shares the service with and the level of assurance available in the implementation of separation controls.</p>



<p>As such, organisations must understand the types of user that they share the Cloud service with and implement appropriate tools. This might include virtualisation technologies or other software that can separate users.</p>



<p>Whenever organisations use such tools, they must also conduct regular <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/combined-infrastructure-and-web-application-penetration-test" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">penetration tests on their infrastructure and web applications</a> to look for vulnerabilities.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>4. Governance framework</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: The service provider should have a security governance framework which coordinates and directs its management of the service and information within it. Any technical controls deployed outside of this framework will be fundamentally undermined.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: Organisations should begin by appointing a board representative (or a person with the direct delegated authority) to take responsibility for the security of the Cloud service. This will typically be the chief information officer, chief security officer or someone with a similar title.</p>



<p>Next, they should document a framework for security governance containing policies addressing key aspects of information security.</p>



<p>The organisation must also implement processes to identify and ensure compliance with relevant legal and regulatory requirements.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>5. Operational security</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: The service needs to be operated and managed securely in order to impede, detect or prevent attacks. Good operational security should not require complex, bureaucratic, time consuming or expensive processes.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: There are four things to consider here, the first of which is configuration and change management. This means ensuring that changes to the system have been properly tested and authorised.</p>



<p>The second thing to consider is vulnerability management, which involves identifying and mitigating security issues in constituent components.</p>



<p>Third, you must implement protective monitoring, which enables you to detect cyber attacks and unauthorised activity on the service.</p>



<p>Finally, you must create an incident management system to ensure that you can respond to incidents and recover a secure, available service.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>6. Personnel security</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: Where service provider personnel have access to your data and systems you need a high degree of confidence in their trustworthiness. Thorough screening, supported by adequate training, reduces the likelihood of accidental or malicious compromise by service provider personnel.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: Service providers must conduct security screening for employees and provide regular security training.</p>



<p>This should include explanations of the security responsibilities associated with specific roles and the ways in which the organisation screens and manages personnel within privileged roles.</p>



<p><a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/417085/BS7858.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BS7858</a> outlines a basic standard for personnel screening, and organisations are advised to follow its guidelines.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>7. Secure development</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: Services should be designed and developed to identify and mitigate threats to their security. Those that aren’t may be vulnerable to security issues which could compromise your data, cause loss of service or enable other malicious activity.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: Organisations must create an <a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/how-to-create-an-iso-27001-secure-development-policy-with-template" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ISO 27001 secure development policy</a> to ensure that development is carried out in line with industry good practice.</p>



<p>They should also regularly monitor new and evolving threats, taking appropriate steps to adjust their service accordingly.</p>



<p>Additionally, organisations should implement configuration management processes to guarantee the integrity of the solution through development, testing and deployment.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>8. Supply chain security</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: The service provider should ensure that its supply chain satisfactorily supports all of the security principles which the service claims to implement.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: If your organisation relies on third-party products and services, you must understand how your information is shared with and accessible to those partners and how it flows through their supply chain.</p>



<p>You must also review the service provider’s procurement processes, looking at the security requirements it places on third-party suppliers. Similarly, you must understand how the service provider manages third-party security risks and the ways it enforces the security requirements of its suppliers.</p>



<p>Finally, you should review how the service provider verifies that hardware and software used in the service is genuine and has not been tampered with.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>9. Secure user management</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: Your provider should make the tools available for you to securely manage your use of their service. Management interfaces and procedures are a vital part of the security barrier, preventing unauthorised access and alteration of your resources, applications and data.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: There are two things you must address here. First, users must be properly authenticated before they are allowed to perform management activities, report faults or request changes to the service.</p>



<p>These changes can be performed through a service management web portal or by telephone/email.</p>



<p>Second, you must implement role-based access controls within management interfaces to prevent users from making unauthorised changes that could affect the service.</p>



<p>This step also protects management interfaces in the event that an employee’s account is compromised by criminal hackers.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>10. Identity and authentication</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: All access to service interfaces should be constrained to authenticated and authorised individuals.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: This principle requires a series of technical solutions. First, you should implement two-factor authentication to strengthen the login process.</p>



<p>By doing this, you protect employees’ accounts in the event that their password is compromised, because an attacker will still need the hardware or software token.</p>



<p>You should also obtain a TLS client certificate, which will provide strong cryptographic protection, and implement identity federation with your existing identity provider.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>11. External interface protection</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: All external or less trusted interfaces of the service should be identified and appropriately defended.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: You must first understand the physical and logical interfaces from which your information is available and how access to your data is controlled.</p>



<p>Once you have this information, you must implement measures to ensure that the service identifies and authenticates users to an appropriate level over those interfaces. This includes the Internet, community networks and private networks.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>12. Secure service administration</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: Systems used for administration of a cloud service will have highly privileged access to that service. Their compromise would have significant impact, including the means to bypass security controls and steal or manipulate large volumes of data.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: To begin, you must understand which service administration model is being used by.</p>



<p>Next, you should assess the risks associated with that administration model. The <a href="http://Next,%20you%20should%20assess%20the%20risks%20associated%20with%20that%20administration%20model.%20For" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NCSC outlines those risks</a> on its website. If you cannot determine which service administration model is used, you should refer to the risks associated with the <em>Direct service administration </em>approach.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>13. Audit information for users</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: You should be provided with the audit records needed to monitor access to your service and the data held within it. The type of audit information available to you will have a direct impact on your ability to detect and respond to inappropriate or malicious activity within reasonable timescales.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: This principle refers to the way in which you will receive audit information rather than what you will do with it.</p>



<p>As such, your requirements relate to the processes related to receiving the information. This means establishing how and when audit information will be provided, including the format of the data, and the data retention period associated with it.</p>



<p>The NCSC splits this into three potential scenarios: the service provider might not offer any audit information, it might provide some information (perhaps as a result of negotiation) or it might make specific information available.</p>



<p>For the audit information to be useful, you must insist on receiving complete, specific details. If you don’t, you will face regulatory compliance issues and could be at greater risk of security incidents.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>14. Secure use of the service</strong></h2>



<p><strong>What the NCSC says</strong>: The security of Cloud services and the data held within them can be undermined if you use the service poorly. Consequently, you will have certain responsibilities when using the service in order for your data to be adequately protected.</p>



<p><strong>How you can achieve it</strong>: Your responsibilities here are subject to the deployment models you use, the features of those services and the scenario in which you intend to use the service.</p>



<p>For example, with infrastructure- and platform-as-a-service offerings, the organisation is responsible for significant aspects of their security, including the installation and configuration of an operating system, the deployment of applications and their maintenance.</p>



<p>The NCSC provides a guide for organisations <a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/cloud-security/iaas" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">configuring infrastructure-as-a-service securely</a>.</p>



<p>Separately, it recommends that organisations identify the security requirements related to its use of service and educate staff on how to use and manage that service securely.</p>



<h2 style="text-transform: none;"><strong>Secure your Cloud services</strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Securing-the-Cloud.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43397" width="124" height="176" srcset="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Securing-the-Cloud.png 320w, https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Securing-the-Cloud-211x300.png 211w" sizes="(max-width: 124px) 100vw, 124px" /></figure></div>



<p>You can find more tips like the ones in this blog by reading&nbsp;<a href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/securing-cloud-services-a-pragmatic-guide-second-edition" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Securing Cloud Services: A pragmatic guide</a>.</p>



<p>This book, written by security architect Lee Newcombe, explains everything you need to know about Cloud security. It covers the key concepts of Cloud computing and the its security architectures, and then looks at the security considerations you must acknowledge.</p>



<p>It’s ideal for anyone looking at implementing Cloud services, whether that’s infrastructure-, platform-, software- or function-as-a-service.</p>



<div style="height:1px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-9 wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-luminous-vivid-orange-background-color has-background" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/shop/product/securing-cloud-services-a-pragmatic-guide-second-edition" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Buy now</strong></a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog/the-14-cloud-security-principles-explained">The 14 Cloud Security Principles explained</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.itgovernance.co.uk/blog">IT Governance UK Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>