<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>VIPRE</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.vipre.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.vipre.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 14:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/1524767738-favicon-1.ico</url>
      <title>VIPRE</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Cybersecurity Tips Everyone Should Know</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/holiday-cybersecurity-tips-everyone-should-know/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/holiday-cybersecurity-tips-everyone-should-know/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 14:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VIPRE Bites]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6468</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>It’s the most wonderful time of the year — and not to mention the most chaotic.  Whether you’re trying to meet end of the year deadlines, shop for last-minute gifts, snag seasonal deals, or plan a festive party, it’s common to find yourself much more distracted than usual around the holidays. Unfortunately, this hectic holiday [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/holiday-cybersecurity-tips-everyone-should-know/">Holiday Cybersecurity Tips Everyone Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s the most wonderful time of the year — and not to mention the most chaotic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you’re trying to meet end of the year deadlines, shop for last-minute gifts, snag seasonal deals, or plan a festive party, it’s common to find yourself much more distracted than usual around the holidays. Unfortunately, this hectic holiday spirit is a breeding ground for cybercrime and other nefarious online activity. Hackers use this chaos to their advantage; in fact, a </span><a href="https://www.experian.com/blogs/ask-experian/survey-some-consumers-would-risk-identity-theft-for-an-online-holiday-deal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 Experian survey</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> found that one in four Americans have been a victim of identity theft or fraud during the holidays. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To keep your online security and privacy in check, here are some tips to keep in mind this holiday season.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Slow down online. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if you see an unbeatable deal with only an hour left in the sale, it’s important to not get caught up in the fervor of online activity during the holidays. Like we mentioned earlier, cybercriminals and hackers thrive on this frantic energy to slip in and scam when they can. That’s why it’s strongly encouraged to stay extra vigilant and careful around the holidays when you’re online. Double check you’re using encrypted websites, pay attention to <a href="https://www.vipre.com/resource/what-is-phishing/" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">phishing</a> and signs of other scams, and don’t give any personal or financial information away too quickly. While you’re at, familiarize yourself with the various </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">attack vectors</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that bad actors use to do their damage. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Check your credit and bank statements more often than you usually do.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like we mentioned above, identity theft and other forms of cybercrime tend to spike around the holiday season. Be sure to keep a closer eye on your bank statements more regularly to prevent any suspicious activity from flying under your radar. Make it a daily habit (or at least every other day) to glance at your statements and scan for anything out of the ordinary.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Remember the golden rule: if it looks too good to be true, it probably is. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Found a deal online you just can’t say no to? Do yourself a favor and pause before going for it. Even if you’ve stumbled upon the Black Friday bargain of a lifetime, deals that seem too good to be true </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">usually</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are just that. Steer away from ridiculously-cheap prices, and always stay wary of Instagram and other social media ads, emails, and other pop-ups that can lure you in while fronting for something much more fraudulent. If you want to dig into it, be sure to look up the alleged deal from the website directly to ensure it’s legitimate. In simple terms, think before you buy. Check out our </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/is-this-link-a-scam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">Safe Link Checker</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for more insight on what to look out for.  </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Check the status of your order directly on the website that you purchased from. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you place an online order, companies typically send out an email with the tracking info for your package that contains a link to view its status. While this is convenient to the customer, it’s not uncommon for cybercriminals to create legitimate-looking phishing emails that mimic these actual tracking emails. Take the extra precaution of checking on the status of your order by avoiding clicking the tracking link in the email and directly going to the website you ordered from instead. For a quick refresher on phishing emails and what to look out for, take a look at our guide </span><a href="https://labs.vipre.com/how-to-deal-with-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">here</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Watch out for charity scams. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re the charitable type when the holidays roll around, be sure to proceed with caution. Many criminals take advantage of the gift-giving spirit to try and scam people into <a href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/massive-high-profile-twitter-attack-elon-musk-kim-kardashian-bill-gates-and-others/" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">“donating” their money</a>. To stay safe, take time to do a little research ahead of making any charitable donations. Only donate to reputable and trusted charities, and always verify phone numbers for them. Be wary of emails from unfamiliar senders that ask for donations, as these are more than likely scams. And even if a familiar brand pops into your inbox asking for your money, skip the risk and visit their website or call them directly to learn more. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">6. Use public Wi-Fi with caution while traveling. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While this piece of advice is the golden standard no matter the season, public Wi-Fi should be treated with extra caution around this time. If you’re traveling for the holidays and relying on airport and hotel hotspots, keep in mind that public Wi-Fi is inherently unsafe. Any person using the same network can spy on your internet traffic and potentially steal or jeopardize your private details. Keep your connection secure by using a VPN. Our </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/home-protection/internet-shield-vpn-by-vipre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" style="font-weight:500;color:#2EA6DF;">Internet Shield VPN</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a simple and secure option for keeping your Wi-Fi activity completely shielded from third-party snooping, and protects up to 10 devices. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Update all passwords. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before you get started with any online shopping, take a few minutes to update all your passwords to stronger, harder-to-guess passwords. With increased cybercrime during this season, bad actors are working even harder to crack passwords and do serious damage. To create a strong password, combine letters and numbers instead of just letters, and opt for longer phrases instead of simple words. Never use passwords with words that could be easy to figure out with the right snooping, such as your birthday or mother’s maiden name. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">8. Use a credit card for online shopping.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To add an extra layer of protection to your finances while shopping online, always use a credit card. In the case of theft or hacking, using a credit card ensures an easier solution to the issue as it will affect the bank and not your actual money. This also limits the amount of money the thief can steal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With these simple online habits, you’ll be able to enjoy the holiday season without the stress of putting your privacy and security at risk. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/holiday-cybersecurity-tips-everyone-should-know/">Holiday Cybersecurity Tips Everyone Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/holiday-cybersecurity-tips-everyone-should-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIPRE SafeSend 5.0 Has Arrived</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-safesend-5-0-has-arrived/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-safesend-5-0-has-arrived/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kerri Taylor]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[VIPRE for Business]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6441</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The VIPRE team has been working tirelessly to bring you consistently improved data protection, and today we have a big announcement: VIPRE SafeSend 5.0 is ready. This update to our SafeSend software is a big improvement in several ways, introducing exciting updates to help keep your information as secure as possible. What is VIPRE SafeSend? [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-safesend-5-0-has-arrived/">VIPRE SafeSend 5.0 Has Arrived</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The VIPRE team has been working tirelessly to bring you consistently improved data protection, and today we have a big announcement: VIPRE SafeSend 5.0 is ready. This update to our SafeSend software is a big improvement in several ways, introducing exciting updates to help keep your information as secure as possible.</p>
<h3>What is VIPRE SafeSend?</h3>
<p>Email is a necessity in the modern era, but email interfaces leave users prone to mistakes. Sending a classified email to the wrong recipient can spell disaster, so it is crucial to protect against potential mishaps. VIPRE SafeSend is a software tool built with this purpose in mind. Featuring a suite of features focused on securing email communications, SafeSend massively reduces the risk of human error to keep your sensitive information safe.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/safe-send-software-outlook/"><span style="font-weight: 700;color: #1BA8DE;">SafeSend safeguards your emails</span></a> in a variety of ways. It is capable of identifying email addresses external to your organization, which helps prevent accidental sharing of privileged information. SafeSend can also scan emails and email attachments for sensitive data, which stops unintentional leaks of information. SafeSend also implements an audit trail to decrease the risk of liability. These features and more are made available through two software options: a PC add-in and a web add-in. The add-ins can be configured to activate due to specific triggers which you decide on based on relevancy to your business.</p>
<h3>What’s new in SafeSend 5.0?</h3>
<p>SafeSend 5.0 introduces new and updated features to the software. One major change is that the web add-in now allows SafeSend to function with MAC devices and mixed OS environments. This introduces more flexibility to those looking to use SafeSend as an answer to their email data protection and compliance troubles. Another key update is that we have extended the DLP add-on module to the web add-in, meaning that users of the web add-in can now benefit from increased protection for their sensitive data.</p>
<p>New features for the PC add-in will help massively in protecting information. Data loss prevention has been enhanced in version 5.0, which allows for both the DLP content scanning rules and the DLP client keyword/domain list rules to run at the same time. SafeSend can also now automatically scan files that have been encrypted by Microsoft RMS, and this addition requires no extra setup whatsoever. Group list expansion has been added and requires no extra setup, and SafeSend will also now highlight any email addresses in a distribution list that use external domains.</p>
<p>With all these features working in tandem, your data is more secure than ever before.</p>
<h3>Where can you learn more about VIPRE SafeSend?</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In tandem with the new version of SafeSend, we’ve updated our <a href="http://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/VIPRE_2019_DS_SafeSend_0611_US-2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 700;color: #1BA8DE;">data sheet</span></a>. Here, you can learn about all of SafeSend 5.0’s features and determine how it can help your business. In addition to the data sheet, you can explore SafeSend on the </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/safe-send-software-outlook/"><span style="font-weight: 700;color: #1BA8DE;">VIPRE website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or watch the short video below.</span></p>
<p><script src="https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/rv00u4o1bw.jsonp" async></script><script src="https://fast.wistia.com/assets/external/E-v1.js" async></script></p>
<div class="wistia_responsive_padding" style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;">
<div class="wistia_responsive_wrapper" style="height:100%;left:0;position:absolute;top:0;width:100%;">
<div class="wistia_embed wistia_async_rv00u4o1bw videoFoam=true" style="height:100%;position:relative;width:100%">
<div class="wistia_swatch" style="height:100%;left:0;opacity:0;overflow:hidden;position:absolute;top:0;transition:opacity 200ms;width:100%;"><img src="https://fast.wistia.com/embed/medias/rv00u4o1bw/swatch" style="filter:blur(5px);height:100%;object-fit:contain;width:100%;" alt="" aria-hidden="true" onload="this.parentNode.style.opacity=1;" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;<br />
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Interested in securing your email communications with VIPRE SafeSend? </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/safe-send-software-outlook/"><span style="font-weight: 700;color: #1BA8DE;">Contact our team</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and get started today. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-safesend-5-0-has-arrived/">VIPRE SafeSend 5.0 Has Arrived</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-safesend-5-0-has-arrived/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIPRE Advanced Security Gets Perfect AV-TEST Ratings</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-advanced-security-gets-perfect-av-test-ratings/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-advanced-security-gets-perfect-av-test-ratings/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[AV Test]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6434</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>VIPRE Advanced Security is once again standing out as a leading security product with the ratings to prove it. In the recent AV-TEST Product Review and Certification Report for July-Aug 2021, VIPRE Advanced Security received the highest ratings in protection, performance, and usability — a perfect 6.0/6.0 in every single category.  AV-TEST evaluated 21 security [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-advanced-security-gets-perfect-av-test-ratings/">VIPRE Advanced Security Gets Perfect AV-TEST Ratings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VIPRE Advanced Security is once again standing out as a leading security product with the ratings to prove it. In the recent </span><a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/antivirus/home-windows/windows-10/august-2021/vipre-security-vipre-advancedsecurity-11.0-211424/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">AV-TEST Product Review and Certification Report for July-Aug 2021</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, VIPRE Advanced Security received the highest ratings in protection, performance, and usability — a perfect 6.0/6.0 in every single category. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AV-TEST evaluated 21 security products by using realistic tests to observe how each service stands up against real-world threats and scenarios, such as malware, worms, email threats, and Trojan horses. The test also examined daily usage of the product and how it impacts the computer and its speed. In the end, VIPRE Advanced Security showed its ability to reliably deliver the best protection against the most current threats without sacrificing performance or speed.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With VIPRE Advanced Security, it’s easy to stay secure online with these unbeatable features:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antivirus Plus</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Third-Party Patching </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anti-Spam Protection </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firewall Security</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mac Compatibility</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b>About AV-TEST</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/about-the-institute/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">AV-TEST</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> GmbH is the independent research institute for IT security from Germany. Over the last 15 years, AV-TEST has consisted of experts performing quality-assuring comparisons and testing of virtually all internationally relevant IT security products.</span></p>
<p><b>About VIPRE</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For over 25 years, VIPRE Security has been a leading provider of advanced security products purpose-built to protect every major attack vector from today’s most costly and malicious online threats. Learn more </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-advanced-security-gets-perfect-av-test-ratings/">VIPRE Advanced Security Gets Perfect AV-TEST Ratings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-advanced-security-gets-perfect-av-test-ratings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s Why SMBs Need Improved Cybersecurity Now More Than Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/heres-why-smbs-need-improved-cybersecurity-now-more-than-ever/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/heres-why-smbs-need-improved-cybersecurity-now-more-than-ever/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 16:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VIPRE for Business]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[small business security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6432</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all heard about big companies getting hit by data breaches — Yahoo, Facebook, Marriott International, and more have notoriously fallen victim to large-scale attacks that rocked news headlines. But what about small-to-medium-sized businesses (SMBs)? While many SMB owners and employees might assume their smaller size makes them less valuable targets, they couldn’t be more [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/heres-why-smbs-need-improved-cybersecurity-now-more-than-ever/">Here’s Why SMBs Need Improved Cybersecurity Now More Than Ever</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve all heard about big companies getting hit by data breaches — </span><a href="https://www.wired.com/2016/12/yahoo-hack-billion-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yahoo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/stolen-data-of-533-million-facebook-users-leaked-online-2021-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/31/what-to-do-if-you-were-affected-by-the-latest-marriott-data-breach.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marriott International</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and more have notoriously fallen victim to large-scale attacks that rocked news headlines. But what about small-to-medium-sized businesses (SMBs)? While many SMB owners and employees might assume their smaller size makes them less valuable targets, they couldn’t be more wrong. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fact, </span><a href="https://securityintelligence.com/articles/state-small-business-cybersecurity-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">43 percent of the most common digital attacks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> target SMBs. So what exactly makes smaller businesses so vulnerable to these threats?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The shift to a more digital workflow as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic didn’t exactly help; unfortunately, </span><a href="https://www.rapidfiretools.com/blog/2021/07/20/small-businesses-are-at-big-risk-for-cyberattacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">22 percent of SMBs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> transferred to remote work without any kind of threat prevention plan. Even prior to the pandemic, a 2019 survey revealed that </span><a href="https://staysafeonline.org/blog/the-impact-of-data-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">only 14 percent of SMBs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rated their ability to prevent and properly address cyber risks and vulnerabilities as useful. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a number of reasons that SMBs find themselves at risk for security breaches. According to </span><a href="https://www.untangle.com/inside-untangle/top-barriers-to-it-security-for-smbs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Untangle</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 32 percent of SMBs cited </span><b>budget constraints</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a barrier to better security, 24 percent blamed </span><b>employees for not following guidelines</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and 14 percent cited having</span><b> limited time to research new threats</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wondering why a threat actor would even go after an SMB? Smaller businesses do, in fact, present valuable assets that make them targets, such as: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employee and customer records</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access to financial information including bank accounts</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access to larger companies and their networks through the supply chain </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without proper IT security, the cost of suffering a cyber attack can be a devastating blow to SMBs. </span><a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/small-businesses-underestimate-financial-damage-of-cyberattacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to AppRiver Software</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, $149,000 was the average cost of a data breach for an SMB in 2019, and most SMB leaders </span><a href="https://staysafeonline.org/blog/the-impact-of-data-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">estimate</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the cost of a data breach to be around $10,000. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are the most common ways cybercriminals can attack your small business?</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are four main </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">attack vectors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or paths, that threat actors often use to infiltrate small businesses. Let’s break them down.</span></p>
<p><b>Email</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email is the #1 attack vector for SMBs, and serves as a primary starting point for malware, phishing, and other types of attacks. </span></p>
<p><b>Endpoints</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An endpoint is anything that connects to a network, such as: laptops, desktop computers, smart phones, tablets, point-of-sale (POS) terminals, and other devices. Potential attackers can exploit endpoints using various forms of malware.</span></p>
<p><b>Network</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any network that connects to the internet and is used by your employees (e.g., your company’s network, the free WiFi at a coffee shop, customer networks) can be used by cybercriminals to attack your business. </span></p>
<p><b>Humans</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Human error has proven to be one of the biggest vulnerabilities for SMBs. In fact, </span><a href="https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/dbir/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">85% of data breaches</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> involve a human element, which can include anything from an employee using weak passwords, clicking on a phishing link, sharing private information with someone from outside the company, etc. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">How SMBs can improve security</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the privacy and security obstacles that come with running an SMB, taking the right approach is possible with an informed understanding of what your business needs, and how it can fit into your work model. Start by breaking down your security plan into the following steps:</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make a thorough assessment of your current cybersecurity defenses. What are the potential risks your company faces if there’s a breach? Where do your biggest vulnerabilities lie?</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decide how you want to manage cybersecurity. Do you have the resources and time to take care of it in-house, or will outsourcing make it easier and safer for you?</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implement layered security measures to detect and block attacks. Are you making sure to secure every layer of your business beyond just one or two security tools? </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Educate employees on cybersecurity threats and best practices. When was the last time your team gained the proper tools to defend your business? Do they know how to spot a phishing email or other types of hacking attempts?</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For our full step-by-step guide to improving your SMB’s security, download our free ebook </span><a href="https://info.vipre.com/Layered_Security.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We’ll guide you with detailed insight, tips, statistics and more to make your SMB more secure than ever. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/heres-why-smbs-need-improved-cybersecurity-now-more-than-ever/">Here’s Why SMBs Need Improved Cybersecurity Now More Than Ever</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/heres-why-smbs-need-improved-cybersecurity-now-more-than-ever/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be CyberSmart about Attack Vectors</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kerri Taylor]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 22:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[VIPRE for Home]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[attack vectors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[becybersecure]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[vipresecure]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6385</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Most antivirus and cybersecurity solutions tell you that they protect your attack vectors. If you’re familiar with the industry, you know exactly what that means. However, most people aren’t cybersecurity professionals. So, they may want to know, “What are attack vectors?” Attack Vectors Attack vectors are the way cybercriminals try to attack you. Attack may [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/">Be CyberSmart about Attack Vectors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most antivirus and cybersecurity solutions tell you that they protect your attack vectors. If you’re familiar with the industry, you know exactly what that means. However, most people aren’t cybersecurity professionals. So, they may want to know, “What are attack vectors?”</p>
<h3>Attack Vectors</h3>
<p>Attack vectors are the way cybercriminals try to attack you. Attack may be a bit broad. This means that they attempt to steal your information, <a href="/is-this-link-a-scam/">scam</a> or defraud you, or in some rare instances <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/10/01/ransomware-attack-might-have-caused-another-death/">cause you physical harm</a>. These attack vectors don’t necessarily start with malware. Other paths and scenarios begin with social engineering. Criminals use a variety of attack vectors in case any of them are blocked. Spreading their malicious intent across different attempts allows them to ferret out weaknesses in your cybersecurity. VIPRE is going to help you become cyber smart about the most common attack vectors.</p>
<h3>Attack Vector &#8211; Email</h3>
<p>Email is one of the most attacked vectors, if not <a href="/blog/email-security-how-to-secure-your-1-threat-vector/">the #1</a>. Cybercriminals can acquire lists of email addresses through the dark net, through guessing your address on LinkedIn, or even calling up your company and asking for it. This attack vector is relatively <a href="https://labs.vipre.com/buer-loader-found-in-an-unusual-email-attachment/">easy to exploit</a>. Now, there are plenty of security measures in place already. Most Email Service Providers do some filtering of spam and malicious emails. However, occasionally something will slip by. If it happens to a large enough company, that slip up can <a href="/blog/disneys-latest-pirates-film-held-ransom-real-pirates/#email">become infamous</a>. Security products like <a href="/products/home-protection/vipre-adv-security/">VIPRE Advanced Security</a> and <a href="/products/business-protection/email-cloud/">VIPRE Email Cloud</a> provide email protection to secure this attack vector.</p>
<p>One of the truly insidious sides of this vector is how it can lull you into doing something risky. Cybercriminals will <a href="/blog/unicef-college-scam-job-offers/">impersonate legitimate organizations</a>. They’ll also <a href="/blog/hackers-target-veterans-seeking-jobs/">target vulnerable groups</a>. A final common tactic you need to be aware of is <a href="/blog/phishing-during-covid-19/">exploiting people’s fears</a>. These examples all rely on an individual trusting the email’s source well enough to lower their defenses.  </p>
<h3>Attack Vector &#8211; Apps</h3>
<p>Virtually all mainstream app stores utilize some level of security practices. Typically apps are scanned and vetted before becoming available for consumers. However, you still need to be careful. Security improvements are <a href="/blog/android-security-safe-enough/">made year over year</a>. That just means hackers work harder to attack you in app stores like the <a href="/blog/beware-downloading-apps-microsofts-windows-store/">Microsoft Windows’ Store</a>. The main gist of protecting yourself is to make sure an app has been on a store for some time and comes from a reputable publisher. This vector can be especially dangerous. You can override your security precautions when installing a malicious app.</p>
<h3>Attack Vector &#8211; Social Media</h3>
<p><a hef="/blog/massive-high-profile-twitter-attack-elon-musk-kim-kardashian-bill-gates-and-others/">Twitter</a> can be an attack vector. In a famous example, celebrity accounts were used to swindle folks. Twitter hacks can also involve persuading someone to surrender posting permissions for their account. <a href="/blog/facebook-copy-paste-quizzes-fun-folly/">Facebook</a> can also be used to harvest information from people. These are two of the most difficult attack vectors to secure because they rely on exploiting the perception of trust in order to attack you. This is why you have to be cyber smart. Don&#8217;t share information on Facebook and make sure you really know all of your friends.</p>
<h3>Attack Vector &#8211; Third Party Update/Supply Chain Vendor</h3>
<p>The most common third party update exploitation is hitting a piece of software that hasn&#8217;t been updated (Chrome, I&#8217;m looking at you). However, the most infamous third party attack was <a href="/blog/fireeye-solarwinds-sunburst-hack-what-you-need-to-know/">with FireEye in late 2020</a>. The security company got hit by an update that was signed as securely coming from SolarWinds. However, it delivered a payload of malware. This situation was peculiar because it involved two giants of the security industry. However, the attack vector is not uncommon. That’s why it’s important to have multiple layers of security keeping your software up to date. VIPRE offers auto patch functionality for third party software <a href="https://success.vipre.com/advanced-security-home-windows-manage/home-windows-manage-patch-management?from_search=72651723">for personal</a> and <a href="https://success.vipre.com/endpoint-server-policies/endpoint-server-patch-management-settings?from_search=72651723">professional use</a>.</p>
<h3>#BeVIPRESecure</h3>
<p>There are more attack vectors out there, which is why you need to be VIPRE Secure. VIPRE is a proud <a href="https://staysafeonline.org/cybersecurity-awareness-month/champions/view-all/#:~:text=VIPRE">champion of cybersecurity month</a>. You can learn more about being <a href="/cybersecurity-awareness-month-2021/">cyber secure here</a> or by visiting our friends at <a href="https://inspiredelearning.com/free-resources/cybersecurity-awareness-month-2021/">Inspired eLearning</a>.<br />
<img alt="" width="296" height="300" data-src="http://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-296x300.png" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5090 lazyloaded" src="http://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-296x300.png" srcset="https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-296x300.png 296w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-1010x1024.png 1010w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-768x779.png 768w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-1515x1536.png 1515w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-100x100.png 100w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-83x84.png 83w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-394x399.png 394w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-77x78.png 77w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color-212x215.png 212w, https://www.vipre.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/CAM_LOGO_full_color.png 1530w" sizes="(max-width: 296px) 100vw, 296px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/">Be CyberSmart about Attack Vectors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/be-cybersmart-about-attack-vectors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Risky Business Activities You Should Stop Doing NOW!</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/6-risky-business-activities-you-should-stop-doing-now/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/6-risky-business-activities-you-should-stop-doing-now/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kerri Taylor]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 01:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6241</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>As a SMB end user, you are most vulnerable to the wiles of hackers and criminals when you are doing high-risk things without knowing just how risky they are. Below are activities you should stop doing now. &#160; Sharing Information Over Public WiFi Using an unsecured network to share anything you care about is a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/6-risky-business-activities-you-should-stop-doing-now/">6 Risky Business Activities You Should Stop Doing NOW!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<style>.basic-content__text>ol li:before {
    content: '';}ol{list-style:decimal;padding-left:19px;}</style>
<p>As a SMB end user, you are most vulnerable to the wiles of hackers and criminals when you are doing high-risk things without knowing just how risky they are. Below are activities you should stop doing now.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="1">
<li><strong> Sharing Information Over Public </strong><strong>WiFi</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Using an unsecured network to share anything you care about is a bit like talking aloud in a public space, giving bystanders information.</p>
<p>Use public WiFi sparingly. Never use it for banking, or for sending or receiving important information. This goes double for anything confidential.</p>
<p>Some hackers specifically target unsecured wireless networks and sit quietly across the street, accessing all your information.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong> Not Updating Outdated Software</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Vulnerable, unpatched software is a top cause of malware infections today. Many data breaches can be traced back to out-of-date applications that were exploited by cybercriminals via malicious email attachments or web-based attacks. These created major threat vectors. Many organizations have yet to secure them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong> Using Malicious Applications on Your Android Devices</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Google’s Android, the world’s most popular mobile OS, has always been a major target for hackers, who try to penetrate the OS via various malware methods — seeking to steal data and identities, and to control devices.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong> Not Backing Up Your Information Frequently</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>This is a very risky habit you need to break now. If you get hacked, lose your device, or a thief steals your device, then you will will deeply regret not taking the time to back up your files, emails, and so on. Ideally, you should do a backup at least once a week, but preferably once every twenty-four hours.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong> Using the Same Password Over and Over</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>This is a perfect way to invite a hacker into your life. Make sure you use a different password for everything you do online. Each password should be long and strong. Use a mixture of upper and lower cases, numbers, punctuation marks, and symbols. Don’t use real words or family names. The longer and more complex you make your password, the harder it will be for a hacker to break it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Carefree Clicking on your Phone</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Who doesn’t have their business email on their phone? Emails flood our inbox and we “know” and “trust” that sender. Right? On our phones it’s a lot harder to notice if that email address is spoofed. Email security and security awareness training are now more crucial than ever, especially with the growing remote workforce.</p>
<p>Give your security a check-up and see the full suite of solutions that <a style="color: #1ba8de;" href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/">VIPRE</a> has to offer.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/6-risky-business-activities-you-should-stop-doing-now/">6 Risky Business Activities You Should Stop Doing NOW!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/6-risky-business-activities-you-should-stop-doing-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are You Vulnerable To Ransomware? 6 Questions to Ask Yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/are-you-vulnerable-to-ransomware-6-questions-to-ask-yourself/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/are-you-vulnerable-to-ransomware-6-questions-to-ask-yourself/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kerri Taylor]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 17:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech Talk]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VIPRE for Business]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[email security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[endpoint security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Awareness Training]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=6140</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>As the ransomware epidemic continues to spread, ask yourself how vulnerable your business is to cyber-extortion. Because ransomware incidents can severely impact business processes and leave organizations without the data they need to operate and deliver mission-critical services. A vulnerability assessment is a good first step to strengthening your defenses. Fending off ransomware attacks requires [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/are-you-vulnerable-to-ransomware-6-questions-to-ask-yourself/">Are You Vulnerable To Ransomware? 6 Questions to Ask Yourself</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the ransomware epidemic continues to spread, ask yourself how vulnerable your business is to cyber-extortion. Because ransomware incidents can severely impact business processes and leave organizations without the data they need to operate and deliver mission-critical services. A vulnerability assessment is a good first step to strengthening your defenses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fending off ransomware attacks requires a multilayered strategy. If all you’ve done so far is to rely on antivirus scans and the good sense of your users to not click on suspicious emails, you’re doing the minimum. Yes, endpoint security is a vital element in your malware defense, but it cannot do the job alone. For instance, failing to educate users on the dangers of phishing amounts to business malpractice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With that in mind, here are six questions to ask in assessing your ransomware vulnerability. Your answers should make it obvious in which areas of security you need to invest:</span></p>
<ol>
<li><b>Are you training users on the dangers of phishing?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">66% of ransomware infections are due to spam and phishing emails. You need to invest in an </span><strong><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/vipre-security-awareness-training/">education program</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that explains how phishing attacks occur and, through repeated training exercises, conditions users to spot and report suspected phishing emails. End users are targets, employees and individuals should be aware of the threat of ransomware and how it is delivered. </span></li>
<li><b>Do you backup your business data regularly?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Backup your data, system images, and configurations, test your backups, and keep the backups offline. Verify the integrity of those backups and test the restoration process to ensure it is working.</span></span></li>
<li><b>Do you have anti-phishing email security?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">You should deploy policy-based </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/email-cloud/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">e<strong>mail security</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at the server level to defend against phishing as well as spam, viruses and other threats. Your email security solution should include secure email inspection, cleansing and management.</span></span></li>
<li><b>Have you deployed endpoint security with specific ransomware protection?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">As malware threats increase in sophistication, so should the tools to combat them. </span><strong><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/endpoint-security/">Endpoint security</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is integral to a layered defense strategy; you need to leverage an advanced solution that effectively helps prevent ransomware, and defends against the malware and attack vectors that are used to spread this pervasive threat. Your security strategy must take into account all the devices that access your network, which means all laptops, smartphones and tablets should be secured. You also should consider encryption and strong authentication policies for added protection.</span></span></li>
<li><b>Do you have a patch management policy?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ransomware authors often exploit vulnerabilities in Microsoft Office files, JavaScript downloaders and Windows Scripting Files (WSF) to carry out attacks. That’s why testing and implementing patches when they are released is imperative. An automated patch management solution is your best bet.</span></span></li>
<li><b>Are your security solutions up to date?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">A commitment to cyber hygiene and best practices is critical to protecting your networks. Prevention is the most effective defense against ransomware and it is critical to take precautions for protection. Infections can be devastating to an individual or organization, and recovery may be a difficult process requiring the services of a reputable data recovery specialist.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><b>If you answered “no” to any of the questions:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to avoid a ransomware attack, start working on turning those no’s into yes’s. Ransomware is a growing criminal activity involving numerous variants. Since 2012 when police locker ransomware variants first emerged, ransomware variants have become more sophisticated and destructive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information about how to build a comprehensive, layered security strategy check out our ebook, “</span><strong><a href="https://info.vipre.com/SMB_Under_Attack_eBook.html?utm_source=blog&amp;ut%20_medium=website&amp;utm_campaign=2136-blog-vp">SMBs Under Attack eBook</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">”.</span></p>
<p><b>If you answered “yes” to all the questions:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s awesome! Remember, endpoint security helps but it cannot do the job alone. Continue training your users and securing your threat vectors and using tools like </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VIPRE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to create a solid defense.</span></p>
<p><b>Download: </b><a href="https://info.vipre.com/SMB_Under_Attack_eBook.html?utm_source=blog&amp;ut _medium=website&amp;utm_campaign=2136-blog-vp"><b>SMBs Under Attack eBook</b></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/are-you-vulnerable-to-ransomware-6-questions-to-ask-yourself/">Are You Vulnerable To Ransomware? 6 Questions to Ask Yourself</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/are-you-vulnerable-to-ransomware-6-questions-to-ask-yourself/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIPRE Releases Security Advisory on Microsoft Exchange Server Attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-releases-security-advisory-on-microsoft-exchange-server-attacks/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-releases-security-advisory-on-microsoft-exchange-server-attacks/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 20:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[advisory]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=5605</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>VIPRE Security has released a security update related to last week’s attack affecting Microsoft Exchange Server 2013, 2016, and 2019. The Microsoft Security Response Center issued a detailed update March 5th with information and guidance for customers who may be affected. KrebsOnSecurity was first to report the hack. “This is the real deal,” Chris Krebs, the former head [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-releases-security-advisory-on-microsoft-exchange-server-attacks/">VIPRE Releases Security Advisory on Microsoft Exchange Server Attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">VIPRE Security has released a security update related to last week’s attack affecting Microsoft Exchange Server 2013, 2016, and 2019. The Microsoft Security Response Center issued a detailed update March 5</span><span class="s2"><sup>th</sup></span><span class="s1"> with <a href="https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2021/03/02/multiple-security-updates-released-for-exchange-server/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">information and guidance</span></a> for customers who may be affected.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">KrebsOnSecurity was first to report the hack. “This is the real deal,” Chris Krebs, the former head of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, said on Twitter, referring to the attacks on on-premises Exchange, which is also known as Outlook Web Access. “If your organization runs an OWA server exposed to the internet, assume compromise between 02/26-03/03.” </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As details began to emerge, a <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2021/03/02/new-nation-state-cyberattacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">Microsoft blog points</span></a> to a newly identified threat actor they are calling <b>Hafnium</b> which operates from China. And according to Microsoft, while Hafnium is based in China, it conducts its operations primarily from leased virtual private servers (VPS) in the United States.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Even administrators who have diligently patched their systems may still be at risk. Fortunately, IT pros can look to the Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), who last week released <a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/alerts/aa21-062a" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">Alert (AA21-062A)</span></a> Mitigate Microsoft Exchange Server Vulnerabilities and advised:</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">“This Alert includes both tactics, techniques and procedures (TTPs) and the indicators of compromise (IOCs) associated with this malicious activity. To secure against this threat, CISA recommends organizations examine their systems for the TTPs and use the IOCs to detect any malicious activity. If an organization discovers exploitation activity, they should assume network identity compromise and follow incident response procedures. If an organization finds no activity, they should apply available patches immediately and implement the mitigations in this Alert.”</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">VIPRE recommends always keeping Windows machines patches up-to-date including VIPRE Email Security for Exchange. VIPRE Endpoint Security offers third-party patch management to cover the critical vulnerabilities in common applications and web browsers. <a href="https://www.vipre.com/resource/vipres-patch-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">VIPRE breaks down patch management</span></a> in the following short video.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s3"><a href="https://www.vipre.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler="">VIPRE Security</a></span><span class="s1"> recommends that all organizations utilize a <a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">layered security approach</span></a> when implementing defensive measures. A top-rated <a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/endpoint-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">endpoint security solution</span></a> coupled with advanced <a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/email-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">email security</span></a> and threat intelligence solutions will ensure that you are protected from malicious threats via multiple attack vectors.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Explore <a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/vipre-trial-evaluations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ol-has-click-handler=""><span class="s3">VIPRE’s cybersecurity solutions</span></a> with a 30-day free trial.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-releases-security-advisory-on-microsoft-exchange-server-attacks/">VIPRE Releases Security Advisory on Microsoft Exchange Server Attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-releases-security-advisory-on-microsoft-exchange-server-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIPRE Receives AV-TEST Award 2020 for Best Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-receives-av-test-award-2020-for-best-performance/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-receives-av-test-award-2020-for-best-performance/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 19:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[awards]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=5603</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>It takes more than simply getting the job done for a security product to stand out — setting new standards for digital defense is the key to what AV-TEST calls being a true “game changer” in IT security. Now, VIPRE’s award-winning reputation and testing achievements has once again placed us at the top of that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-receives-av-test-award-2020-for-best-performance/">VIPRE Receives AV-TEST Award 2020 for Best Performance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It takes more than simply getting the job done for a security product to stand out — setting new standards for digital defense is the key to what AV-TEST calls being a true “game changer” in IT security. Now, VIPRE’s award-winning reputation and testing achievements has once again placed us at the top of that category. We’re thrilled to announce that VIPRE Advanced Security has been awarded the </span><a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/news/av-test-award-2020-for-vipre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 AV-TEST for performance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to our consistent outstanding achievements displayed in AV’s comprehensive tests throughout the year, VIPRE’s performance has been recognized as a high standard for security. As AV-Test noted, VIPRE has shined as a true leader amongst other products, continuously defending against cyber criminals and advanced threats.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;&#8216;Advanced Security&#8217; from VIPRE combines good protection with outstanding performance ratings and thus offers consumers an excellent product for the effective protection of private PCs,” said Maik Morgenstern, CEO of AV-TEST. “The product placed a low load on system resources, as evidenced by extensive tests, which is why the AV-TEST Institute recognized it with the Best Performance 2020 Award.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><b>Profile: AV-Test Award Protocol </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The AV-TEST Award is reserved for game changers: IT security products that not only successfully defend against digital threats, but also set new standards in all tests performed over the course of a year. AV-TEST recognizes services like VIPRE that continuously achieve this consistency, and that encourage trust from consumers and businesses alike. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Winners of this award also receive the clear buying recommendation of AV-TEST’s laboratory experts.</span></p>
<p><b>About AV-Test</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/about-the-institute/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">AV-TEST</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> GmbH is the independent research institute for IT security from Germany. Over the last 15 years, AV-TEST has consisted of experts performing quality-assuring comparison and testing of virtually all internationally relevant IT security products.</span></p>
<p><b>About VIPRE</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For over 25 years, VIPRE Security has been a leading provider of advanced security products purpose-built to protect every major attack vector from today’s most costly and malicious online threats. Learn more </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/products/business-protection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-receives-av-test-award-2020-for-best-performance/">VIPRE Receives AV-TEST Award 2020 for Best Performance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/vipre-receives-av-test-award-2020-for-best-performance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do I Have a Virus on My Computer? Here’s How to Tell.</title>
      <link>https://www.vipre.com/blog/do-i-have-a-virus-on-my-computer-heres-how-to-tell/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vipre.com/blog/do-i-have-a-virus-on-my-computer-heres-how-to-tell/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[VIPRE Security]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 21:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Tips]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[computer virus]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.vipre.com/?p=5538</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Like human viruses, computer viruses are highly contagious. Once they infect your device, computer viruses replicate and wreak havoc throughout your operating system. The damage can be severe. Viruses can corrupt software, make programs unusable, and delete important files. A virus can also target your hard drive, which can alter your system performance or even [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/do-i-have-a-virus-on-my-computer-heres-how-to-tell/">Do I Have a Virus on My Computer? Here’s How to Tell.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like human viruses, computer viruses are highly contagious. Once they infect your device, computer viruses replicate and wreak havoc throughout your operating system. The damage can be severe. Viruses can corrupt software, make programs unusable, and delete important files. A virus can also target your hard drive, which can alter your system performance or even crash it entirely. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Viruses can also give hackers access to your machine, allowing them to pillage your data. This not only can destroy your privacy; it can also have devastating financial consequences. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Considering our increasing dependence on technology, none of these outcomes are ideal. With that in mind, you should be doing everything possible to prevent your computer from getting viruses. Here’s everything you need to know about computer viruses, from how they occur to how to prevent them, what operating systems can get them, and what to do if your device does get infected.</span></p>
<h3><b>How do computers get viruses in the first place?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There isn’t one single way all computers get viruses, but one of the most common ways is through downloading infected files. Oftentimes, these files are free to download and include pirated content such as films, televisions shows, music, and even games. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another common way computer viruses spread is via malicious links. These links are commonly distributed through email and text messages in a cyber attack method known as phishing. Phishing attacks act as a bait and switch. They try to make these links seem legitimate and enticing, but send users elsewhere. Sometimes, these malicious links also appear on illegitimate websites trying to pose as legitimate ones.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, viruses are often found on external hard drives, such as USBs. When you plug them into your device, your device becomes infected. </span></p>
<h3><b>Can Macs get viruses?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems common knowledge that Windows computers can get viruses, but what about Macs? Apple and their Mac products have a longstanding reputation of being virus-proof. This good reputation isn’t entirely undeserved, but it also isn’t entirely accurate either. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Macs are less susceptible to viruses than Windows computers, but they can absolutely get them. In fact, Mac viruses are far from rare. So while Mac users may be slightly less likely to get viruses than Windows users, you still can’t let your guard down if you have a Mac. To ensure your Mac remains virus-free, you should still take the same precautions.</span></p>
<h3><b>How do I know if I have a virus on my computer?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if you’re not a tech expert, there are several indicators that may suggest the presence of a virus on your computer. These indicators include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Difficulty restarting or shutting down your computer</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slow performance when opening files, programs, software, links, etc </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frequent unexpected pop-ups</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Missing or corrupted documents and files</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frequent errors messages</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frequent system or program crashes</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frequent URL redirects</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presence of new apps or programs you don’t remember downloading</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presence of emails in your outbox you don’t remember sending</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overactive hard drive fan, even when you are using significant processing power</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>How do I prevent my computer from getting a virus?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are two important components of virus prevention: </span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Antivirus software</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You </span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the first component, </span><a href="https://www.vipre.com/vipre-home-protection-products/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;color: #1ba8de;">VIPRE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has you covered with a full security suite of home protection products. These offerings include options for Mac users, so you can protect your device no matter what operating system your computer has. With VIPRE, your computer will be guarded with a number of Antivirus features, including real time scans and malware, spyware, and ransomware detection and removal. VIPRE also updates automatically to ensure there are no lapses in your protection.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While VIPRE’s Antivirus protection is comprehensive, you still remain a crucial component of virus prevention. Think of VIPRE as the last line of defense, and yourself as the first. VIPRE will work to mitigate any threats you’re unable to deal with, but you can still make your computer vulnerable if you let your guard down. For example, VIPRE cannot prevent you from plugging an infected USB drive into your computer. So, it’s important you remain alert when you’re surfing the web. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Follow these tips to reduce your chances of getting infected:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Never click on suspicious links online, or in your inboxes. If a message seems suspicious, confirm with the sender in a separate line of communication if possible, or manually log into the relevant online account to confirm its authenticity. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Only use SSL protected websites, which are indicated by a closed padlock in the URL address bar. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be extra mindful when downloading anything online – only download for legitimate sources.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regularly backup your computer.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Always keep your software and applications up-to-date.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>What should I do if my computer does get a virus?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your computer is showing signs that it has been infected with a virus, </span><a href="https://homesupport.vipre.com/support/solutions/articles/1000249027-how-to-manually-start-a-scan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;color: #1ba8de;">manually start a full VIPRE system scan</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If VIPRE detects a virus, simply follow the prompts. If VIPRE detects a threat that you deem safe, you can add it to the </span><a href="https://homesupport.vipre.com/support/solutions/articles/1000264709-managing-always-allowed-items-and-exclusions"><span style="font-weight: 400;color: #1ba8de;">“Always Allowed” list </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">so that it won’t be detected in future scans. Otherwise, </span><a href="https://homesupport.vipre.com/support/solutions/articles/1000264703-manage-quarantined-items" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;color: #1ba8de;">VIPRE will quarantine the threat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a safe place so that it cannot harm your computer. If you need further assistance, the </span><a href="https://homesupport.vipre.com/support/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;color: #1ba8de;">VIPRE support team</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is always happy to help.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In extreme cases, or cases where you didn’t have active Antivirus protection, you may  need to uninstall then reinstall your operating system, restore a previous backup version, or have a professional assist you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep in mind that the cost and ease of preventing viruses with VIPRE is far less than cleaning up the damage done by harmful viruses. So always ensure your VIPRE Antivirus protection is active, and maintain safe online behavior to keep your system secure.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com/blog/do-i-have-a-virus-on-my-computer-heres-how-to-tell/">Do I Have a Virus on My Computer? Here’s How to Tell.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.vipre.com">VIPRE</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vipre.com/blog/do-i-have-a-virus-on-my-computer-heres-how-to-tell/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>