<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Krebs on Security</title>
    <atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
    <description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:22:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Russia to Rent Tech-Savvy Prisoners to Corporate IT?</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/05/russia-to-rent-tech-savvy-prisoners-to-corporate-it/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/05/russia-to-rent-tech-savvy-prisoners-to-corporate-it/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 21:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia's War on Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59685</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Faced with a brain drain of smart people fleeing the country following its invasion of Ukraine, the Russian Federation is floating a new strategy to address a worsening shortage of qualified information technology experts: Forcing tech-savvy people within the nation's prison population to perform low-cost IT work for domestic companies.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_59692" style="width: 745px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59692" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/ruprisonhacker.png" alt="" width="735" height="489" class="size-full wp-image-59692" /><p id="caption-attachment-59692" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Proxima Studios, via Shutterstock.</p></div>
<p>Faced with a brain drain of smart people fleeing the country following its invasion of Ukraine, the Russian Federation is floating a new strategy to address a worsening shortage of qualified information technology experts: Forcing tech-savvy people within the nation&#8217;s prison population to perform low-cost IT work for domestic companies.</p>
<p>Multiple Russian news outlets published stories on April 27 saying the Russian <strong>Federal Penitentiary Service</strong> had announced a plan to recruit IT specialists from Russian prisons to work remotely for domestic commercial companies.</p>
<p>Russians sentenced to forced labor will serve out their time at one of many correctional centers across dozens of Russian regions, usually at the center that is closest to their hometown. <strong>Alexander Khabarov</strong>, deputy head of Russia&#8217;s penitentiary service, said his agency had received proposals from businessmen in different regions to involve IT specialists serving sentences in correctional centers to work remotely for commercial companies.</p>
<p>Khabarov told Russian media outlets that under the proposal people with IT skills at these facilities would labor only in IT-related roles, but would not be limited to working with companies in their own region.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are approached with this initiative in a number of territories, in a number of subjects by entrepreneurs who work in this area,&#8221; Khabarov told <a href="https://www.rbc.ru/society/27/04/2022/626914459a7947739ffe8d31" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Russian state media organization TASS</a>. &#8220;We are only at the initial stage. If this is in demand, and this is most likely in demand, we think that we will not force specialists in this field to work in some other industries.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Russian media site Lenta.ru, since March 21 nearly <a href="https://lenta.ru/news/2022/04/04/vaccc/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">95,000 vacancies in IT have remained unfilled in Russia</a>. Lenta says the number unfilled job slots actually shrank 25 percent from the previous month, officially because &#8220;many Russian companies are currently reviewing their plans and budgets, and some projects have been postponed.&#8221; The story fails to even mention the recent economic sanctions that are currently affecting many Russian companies thanks to Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine in late February.<span id="more-59685"></span></p>
<p>The <strong>Russian Association for Electronic Communications</strong> (RAEC) estimated recently that between 70,000 and 100,000 people will leave Russia as part of the second wave of emigration of IT specialists from Russia. &#8220;The study also notes that the number of IT people who want to leave Russia is growing. Experts consider the USA, Germany, Georgia, Cyprus and Canada to be the most attractive countries for moving,&#8221; Lenta reported of the RAEC survey.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear how many &#8220;IT specialists&#8221; are currently serving prison time in Russia, or precisely what that might mean in terms of an inmate&#8217;s IT skills and knowledge. According to <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/shared/spl/hi/uk/06/prisons/html/nn2page1.stm" rel="noopener" target="_blank">the BBC</a>, about half of the world&#8217;s prison population is held in the United States, Russia or China. The BBC says Russia currently houses nearly 875,000 inmates, or about 615 inmates for every 100,000 citizens. The United States has an even higher incarceration rate (737/100,000), but also a far larger total prison population of nearly 2.2 million.</p>
<p><strong>Sergei Boyarsky</strong>, deputy chairman of the Russian Duma&#8217;s Committee on Information Policy, said the idea was worth pursuing if indeed there are a significant number of IT specialists who are already incarcerated in Russia.</p>
<p>&#8220;I know that we have a need in general for IT specialists, this is a growing market,&#8221; said Boyarsky, who was among the Russian leaders sanctioned by the United States Treasury on Marc. 24, 2022 in response to the Russian invasion of Ukraine. Boyarsky is head of the St. Petersburg branch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Russia" rel="noopener" target="_blank">United Russia</a>, a strongly pro-Putin political party that holds more than 70 percent of the seats in the Russian State Duma. </p>
<p>&#8220;Since they still work there, it would probably be right to give people with a profession that allows them to work remotely not to lose their qualifications,&#8221; Boyarsky was <a href="https://lenta.ru/news/2022/04/27/ocenili/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">quoted as saying of potentially qualified inmates</a>. &#8220;At a minimum, this proposal is worth attention and discussion if there are a lot of such specialists.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Russia&#8217;s penitentiary service, the average salary of those sentenced to forced labor is about 20,000 rubles per month, or approximately USD $281. Russian news outlet <a href="https://www.rbc.ru/society/27/05/2021/60aeecac9a7947178ce8708d" rel="noopener" target="_blank">RBC reports</a> that businesses started using prison labor after the possibility of creating correctional centers in organizations appeared in 2020. RBC notes that Russia now has 117 such centers across 76 Russian regions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/05/russia-to-rent-tech-savvy-prisoners-to-corporate-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can Now Ask Google to Remove Your Phone Number, Email or Address from Search Results</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/you-can-now-ask-google-to-remove-your-phone-number-email-or-address-from-search-results/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/you-can-now-ask-google-to-remove-your-phone-number-email-or-address-from-search-results/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Tools]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[briansclub]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Michelle Chang]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Techcrunch]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59639</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Google said this week it is expanding the types of data people can ask to have removed from search results, to include personal contact information like your phone number, email address or physical address. The move comes just months after Google rolled out a new policy enabling people under the age of 18 (or a parent/guardian) to request removal of their images from Google search results.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google</strong> said this week it is expanding the types of data people can ask to have removed from search results, to include personal contact information like your phone number, email address or physical address. The move comes just months after Google rolled out a new policy enabling people under the age of 18 (or a parent/guardian) to request removal of their images from Google search results.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59643" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/googledoxx.png" alt="" width="748" height="704" /></p>
<p>Google has for years accepted requests to remove certain sensitive data such as bank account or credit card numbers from search results. In <a href="https://blog.google/products/search/new-options-for-removing-your-personally-identifiable-information-from-search/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post on Wednesday</a>, Google&#8217;s <strong>Michelle Chang</strong> wrote that the company&#8217;s expanded policy now allows for the removal of additional information that may pose a risk for identity theft, such as confidential log-in credentials, email addresses and phone numbers when it appears in Search results.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we receive removal requests, we will evaluate all content on the web page to ensure that we&#8217;re not limiting the availability of other information that is broadly useful, for instance in news articles,&#8221; Chang wrote. &#8220;We&#8217;ll also evaluate if the content appears as part of the public record on the sites of government or official sources. In such cases, we won&#8217;t make removals.&#8221;</p>
<p>While Google&#8217;s removal of a search result from its index will do nothing to remove the offending content from the site that is hosting it, getting a link decoupled from Google search results is going to make the content at that link far less visible. According to recent estimates, Google enjoys somewhere near 90 percent market share in search engine usage.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity decided to test this expanded policy with what would appear to be a no-brainer request: I asked Google to remove search result for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=briansclub" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BriansClub</a>, one of the largest (if not THE largest) cybercrime stores for selling stolen payment card data.</p>
<p>BriansClub has long abused my name and likeness to pimp its wares on the hacking forums. Its homepage includes a copy of my credit report, Social Security card, phone bill, and a fake but otherwise official looking government ID card. <span id="more-59639"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_59647" style="width: 764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59647" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59647" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/bclogin.png" alt="" width="754" height="492" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/bclogin.png 1133w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/bclogin-768x501.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/bclogin-782x510.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 754px) 100vw, 754px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59647" class="wp-caption-text">The login page for perhaps the most bustling cybercrime store for stolen payment card data.</p></div>
<p>Briansclub updated its homepage with this information in 2019, after it got massively hacked and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/10/briansclub-hack-rescues-26m-stolen-cards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a copy of its customer database was shared with this author</a>. The leaked data &#8212; which included 26 million credit and debit card records taken from hacked online and brick-and-mortar retailers &#8212; was ultimately shared with dozens of financial institutions.</p>
<p><em>TechCrunch</em> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/04/28/google-request-removal-personal-contact-information-search-results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that the policy expansion comes six months after Google started allowing people under 18 or their parents request to delete their photos from search results. To <a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/10949130?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">do so</a>, users need to specify that they want Google to remove “Imagery of an individual currently under the age of 18” and provide some personal information, the image URLs and search queries that would surface the results. Google also lets you submit requests to remove non-consensual explicit or intimate personal images from Google, along with involuntary fake pornography, TechCrunch notes.</p>
<p>This post will be updated in the event Google responds one way or the other, but that may take a while: Google&#8217;s automated response said: &#8220;Due to the preventative measures being taken for our support specialists in light of COVID-19, it may take longer than usual to respond to your support request. We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause, and we’ll send you a reply as soon as we can.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Update: 10:30 p.m. ET:</strong> An earlier version of this story incorrectly stated that people needed to show explicit or implicit threats regarding requests to remove information like one&#8217;s phone number, address or email address from a search result. A spokesperson for Google said &#8220;there is no requirement that we find the content to be harmful or shared in a malicious way.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/you-can-now-ask-google-to-remove-your-phone-number-email-or-address-from-search-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting Fake EDRs With ‘Credit Ratings’ for Police</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/fighting-fake-edrs-with-credit-ratings-for-police/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/fighting-fake-edrs-with-credit-ratings-for-police/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 14:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[emergency data request]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Kodex]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Matt Donahue]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Meta]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tiktok]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59232</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[When KrebsOnSecurity last month explored how cybercriminals were using hacked email accounts at police departments worldwide to obtain warrantless Emergency Data Requests (EDRs) from social media and technology providers, many security experts called it a fundamentally unfixable problem. But don't tell that to Matt Donahue, a former FBI agent who recently quit the agency to launch a startup that aims to help tech companies do a better job screening out phony law enforcement data requests -- in part by assigning trustworthiness or "credit ratings" to law enforcement authorities worldwide.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When KrebsOnSecurity recently explored how cybercriminals were using <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/hackers-gaining-power-of-subpoena-via-fake-emergency-data-requests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hacked email accounts at police departments worldwide</a> to obtain warrantless <strong>Emergency Data Requests</strong> (EDRs) from social media firms and technology providers, many security experts called it a fundamentally unfixable problem. But don&#8217;t tell that to <strong>Matt Donahue</strong>, a former FBI agent who recently quit the agency to launch a startup that aims to help tech companies do a better job screening out phony law enforcement data requests &#8212; in part by assigning trustworthiness or &#8220;credit ratings&#8221; to law enforcement authorities worldwide.</p>
<div id="attachment_59587" style="width: 765px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59587" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59587" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/kodex.png" alt="" width="755" height="521" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/kodex.png 635w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/kodex-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 755px) 100vw, 755px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59587" class="wp-caption-text">A sample Kodex dashboard. Image: Kodex.us.</p></div>
<p>Donahue is co-founder of <a href="https://www.kodex.us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kodex</a>, a company formed in February 2021 that builds security portals designed to help tech companies &#8220;manage information requests from government agencies who contact them, and to securely transfer data &amp; collaborate against abuses on their platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>The 30-year-old Donahue said he left the FBI in April 2020 to start Kodex because it was clear that social media and technology companies needed help validating the increasingly large number of law enforcement requests domestically and internationally.</p>
<p>&#8220;So much of this is such an antiquated, manual process,&#8221; Donahue said of his perspective gained at the FBI. &#8220;In a lot of cases we&#8217;re still sending faxes when more secure and expedient technologies exist.&#8221;</p>
<p>Donahue said when he brought the subject up with his superiors at the FBI, they would kind of shrug it off, as if to say, &#8220;This is how it&#8217;s done and there&#8217;s no changing it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;My bosses told me I was committing career suicide doing this, but I genuinely believe fixing this process will do more for national security than a 20-year career at the FBI,&#8221; he said. &#8220;This is such a bigger problem than people give it credit for, and that&#8217;s why I left the bureau to start this company.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the stated goals of Kodex is to build a scoring or reputation system for law enforcement personnel who make these data requests. After all, there are tens of thousands of police jurisdictions around the world — including roughly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_enforcement_in_the_United_States#:~:text=There%20are%2017%2C985%20U.S.%20police,and%20federal%20law%20enforcement%20agencies." target="_blank" rel="noopener">18,000 in the United States alone</a> — and all it takes for hackers to abuse the EDR process is illicit access to a single police email account.</p>
<p>Kodex is trying to tackle the problem of fake EDRs by working directly with the data providers to pool information about police or government officials submitting these requests, and hopefully making it easier for all customers to spot an unauthorized EDR.</p>
<p>Kodex&#8217;s first big client was cryptocurrency giant <strong>Coinbase</strong>, which confirmed their partnership but otherwise declined to comment for this story. <strong>Twilio</strong> confirmed it uses Kodex&#8217;s technology for law enforcement requests destined for any of its business units, but likewise declined to comment further.</p>
<p>Within their own separate Kodex portals, Twilio can&#8217;t see requests submitted to Coinbase, or vice versa. But each can see if a law enforcement entity or individual tied to one of their own requests has ever submitted a request to a different Kodex client, and then drill down further into other data about the submitter, such as Internet address(es) used, and the age of the requestor&#8217;s email address.</p>
<p>Donahue said in Kodex&#8217;s system, each law enforcement entity is assigned a credit rating, wherein officials who have a long history of sending valid legal requests will have a higher rating than someone sending an EDR for the first time.</p>
<p>&#8220;In those cases, we warn the customer with a flash on the request when it pops up that we&#8217;re allowing this to come through because the email was verified [as being sent from a valid police or government domain name], but we&#8217;re trying to verify the emergency situation for you, and we will change that rating once we get new information about the emergency,&#8221; Donahue said.</p>
<p>&#8220;This way, even if one customer gets a fake request, we&#8217;re able to prevent it from happening to someone else,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;In a lot of cases with fake EDRs, you can see the same email [address] being used to message different companies for data. And that&#8217;s the problem: So many companies are operating in their own silos and are not able to share information about what they&#8217;re seeing, which is why we&#8217;re seeing scammers exploit this good faith process of EDRs.&#8221;</p>
<h2>NEEDLES IN THE HAYSTACK</h2>
<p>As social media and technology platforms have grown over the years, so have the volumes of requests from law enforcement agencies worldwide for user data. For example, in its <a href="https://www.verizon.com/about/investors/transparency-report" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest transparency report</a> mobile giant <strong>Verizon</strong> reported receiving 114,000 data requests of all types from U.S. law enforcement entities in the second half of 2021.</p>
<p>Verizon said <em>approximately 35,000 of those requests (~30 percent) were EDRs</em>, and that it provided data in roughly 91 percent of those cases. The company doesn&#8217;t disclose how many EDRs came from foreign law enforcement entities during that same time period. Verizon currently asks law enforcement officials to send these requests via fax.</p>
<p>Validating legal requests by domain name may be fine for data demands that include documents like subpoenas and search warrants, which can be validated with the courts. But not so for EDRs, which largely bypass any official review and <em>do not require the requestor to submit any court-approved documents</em>.</p>
<p>Police and government authorities can legitimately request EDRs to learn the whereabouts or identities of people who have posted online about plans to harm themselves or others, or in other exigent circumstances such as a child abduction or abuse, or a potential terrorist attack.</p>
<p>But as KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/hackers-gaining-power-of-subpoena-via-fake-emergency-data-requests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported in March</a>, it is now clear that crooks have figured out there is no quick and easy way for a company that receives one of these EDRs to know whether it is legitimate. Using illicit access to hacked police email accounts, the attackers will send a fake EDR along with an attestation that innocent people will likely suffer greatly or die unless the requested data is provided immediately.</p>
<p>In this scenario, the receiving company finds itself caught between two unsavory outcomes: Failing to immediately comply with an EDR — and potentially having someone’s blood on their hands — or possibly leaking a customer record to the wrong person. That might explain why the compliance rate for EDRs is usually quite high &#8212; often upwards of 90 percent.</p>
<p>Fake EDRs have become such a reliable method in the cybercrime underground for obtaining information about account holders that several cybercriminals have started offering services that will submit these fraudulent EDRs on behalf of paying clients to a number of top social media and technology firms.<span id="more-59232"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_59126" style="width: 771px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59126" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59126" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinity-warrant.png" alt="" width="761" height="770" /><p id="caption-attachment-59126" class="wp-caption-text">A fake EDR service advertised on a hacker forum in 2021.</p></div>
<p>An individual who&#8217;s part of the community of crooks that are abusing fake EDR told KrebsOnSecurity the schemes often involve hacking into police department emails by first compromising the agency’s website. From there, they can drop a backdoor “shell” on the server to secure permanent access, and then create new email accounts within the hacked organization.</p>
<p>In other cases, hackers will try to guess the passwords of police department email systems. In these attacks, the hackers will identify email addresses associated with law enforcement personnel, and then attempt to authenticate using passwords those individuals have used at other websites that have been breached previously.</p>
<h2>EDR OVERLOAD?</h2>
<p>Donahue said depending on the industry, EDRs make up between 5 percent and 30 percent of the total volume of requests. In contrast, he said, EDRs amount to less than three percent of the requests sent through Kodex portals used by customers.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity sought to verify those numbers by compiling EDR statistics based on annual or semi-annual transparency reports from some of the largest technology and social media firms. While there are no available figures on the number of fake EDRs each provider is receiving each year, those phony requests can easily hide amid an increasingly heavy torrent of legitimate demands.</p>
<p><strong>Meta/Facebook</strong> <a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/government-data-requests/data-types/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> roughly 11 percent of all law enforcement data requests &#8212; 21,700 of them &#8212; were EDRs in the first half of 2021. Almost 80 percent of the time the company produced at least some data in response. Facebook has long used its own online portal where law enforcement officials must first register before submitting requests.</p>
<div id="attachment_59601" style="width: 766px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59601" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59601" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/fbgovtdatareq.png" alt="" width="756" height="462" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/fbgovtdatareq.png 1009w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/fbgovtdatareq-768x470.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/fbgovtdatareq-782x478.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 756px) 100vw, 756px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59601" class="wp-caption-text">Government data requests, including EDRs, received by Facebook over the years. Image: Meta Transparency Report.</p></div>
<p><strong>Apple</strong> <a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/transparency/emergency-requests.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it received 1,162 emergency requests for data in the last reporting period it made public &#8212; July &#8211; December 2020. Apple&#8217;s compliance with EDRs was 93 percent worldwide in 2020. Apple&#8217;s website says it accepts EDRs via email, after applicants have filled out a supplied PDF form. [As a lifelong Apple user and customer, I was floored to learn that the richest company in the world &#8212; which for several years has banked heavily on privacy and security promises to customers &#8212; still relies on email for such sensitive requests].</p>
<p><strong>Twitter</strong> <a href="https://transparency.twitter.com/en/reports/information-requests.html#2021-jan-jun" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> it received 1,860 EDRs in the first half of 2021, or roughly 15 percent of the global information requests sent to Twitter. Twitter accepts EDRs via an interactive form on the company&#8217;s website. Twitter reports that EDRs decreased by 25% during this reporting period, while the aggregate number of accounts specified in these requests decreased by 15%. The United States submitted the highest volume of global emergency requests (36%), followed by Japan (19%), and India (12%).</p>
<p><strong>Discord</strong> <a href="https://discord.com/blog/discord-transparency-report-h1-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> receiving 378 requests for emergency data disclosure in the first half of 2021. Discord accepts EDRs via a specified email address.</p>
<p>For the six months ending in December 2021, <strong>Snapchat</strong> <a href="https://snap.com/en-US/privacy/transparency/legal-requests" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it received 2,085 EDRs from authorities in the United States (with a 59 percent compliance rate), and another 1,448 from international police (64 percent granted). Snapchat has a form for submitting EDRs on its website.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok</strong>&#8216;s <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/transparency/en-us/information-requests-2021-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resources on government data requests</a> currently lead to a &#8220;Page not found&#8221; error, but a company spokesperson said TikTok received 715 EDRs in the first half of 2021. That&#8217;s up from 409 EDRs in the previous six months. Tiktok handles EDRs via a form on its website.</p>
<p>The current transparency reports for both <strong>Google</strong> and <strong>Microsoft</strong> do not break out EDRs by category. Microsoft <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/corporate-responsibility/law-enforcement-requests-report" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> that in the second half of 2021 it received more than 25,000 government requests, and that it complied at least partly with those requests more than 90 percent of the time.</p>
<p>Microsoft runs its own portal that law enforcement officials must register at to submit legal requests, but that portal doesn&#8217;t accept requests for other Microsoft properties, such as <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/legal/transparency" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn</a> or <a href="https://github.blog/2021-02-25-2020-transparency-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github</a>.</p>
<p>Google <a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/user-data/overview?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it received more than 113,000 government requests for user data in the last half of 2020, and that about 76 percent of the requests resulted in the disclosure of some user information. Google doesn&#8217;t publish EDR numbers, and it did not respond to requests for those figures. Google also runs its own portal for accepting law enforcement data requests.</p>
<p><strong>Verizon</strong> <a href="https://www.verizon.com/about/sites/default/files/2022-04/US-Transparency-Report-2H-2021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> (PDF) receiving more than 35,000 EDRs from just U.S. law enforcement in the second half of 2021, out of a total of 114,000 law enforcement requests (Verizon doesn&#8217;t disclose how many EDRs came from foreign law enforcement entities). Verizon said it complied with approximately 91 percent of requests. The company accepts law enforcement requests via snail mail or fax.</p>
<div id="attachment_59603" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59603" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59603" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/vzgovdatareq.png" alt="" width="747" height="660" /><p id="caption-attachment-59603" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Verizon.com.</p></div>
<p><strong>AT&amp;T</strong> <a href="https://about.att.com/content/dam/csr/2019/transparency/2022/2022-February-Transparency-Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> (PDF) it received nearly 19,000 EDRs in the second half of 2021; it provided some data roughly 95 percent of the time. AT&amp;T requires EDRs to be faxed.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/_admin/uploads/2021/07/2020-Transparency-Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recent transparency report</a> published by <strong>T-Mobile</strong> says the company received more than 164,000 &#8220;emergency/911&#8221; requests in 2020 &#8212; but it does not specifically call out EDRs. Like its old school telco brethren, T-Mobile requires EDRs to be faxed. T-Mobile did not respond to requests for more information.</p>
<div id="attachment_59602" style="width: 691px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59602" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59602" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/tmobgovdatareq.png" alt="" width="681" height="478" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/tmobgovdatareq.png 635w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/tmobgovdatareq-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 681px) 100vw, 681px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59602" class="wp-caption-text">Data from T-Mobile&#8217;s most recent transparency report in 2020. Image: T-Mobile.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/fighting-fake-edrs-with-credit-ratings-for-police/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked Chats Show LAPSUS$ Stole T-Mobile Source Code</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/leaked-chats-show-lapsus-stole-t-mobile-source-code/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/leaked-chats-show-lapsus-stole-t-mobile-source-code/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Amtrak]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Bitbucket]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Doxbin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Electronic Arts]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[emergency data request]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Everlynn]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Flashpoint]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Genesis]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Globant]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Iqor]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[KT]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[LAPSUS$]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Lapsus$ Jobs]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Michelin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Device Management]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mox]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Recursion Team]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russian Market]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SASCAR]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SIM swapping]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Slack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[source code theft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SWATting]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[T-Mobile Atlas]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[WhiteDoxbin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59472</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity recently reviewed a copy of the private chat messages between members of the LAPSUS$ cybercrime group in the week leading up to the arrest of its most active members last month. The logs show LAPSUS$ breached T-Mobile multiple times in March, stealing source code for a range of company projects. T-Mobile says no customer or government information was stolen in the intrusion.

LAPSUS$ is known for stealing data and then demanding a ransom not to publish or sell it. But the leaked chats indicate this mercenary activity was of little interest to the tyrannical teenage leader of LAPSUS$, whose obsession with stealing and leaking proprietary computer source code from the world’s largest tech companies ultimately led to the group’s undoing.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>KrebsOnSecurity recently reviewed a copy of the private chat messages between members of the <strong>LAPSUS$</strong> cybercrime group in the week leading up to the arrest of its most active members last month. The logs show LAPSUS$ breached <strong>T-Mobile</strong> multiple times in March, stealing source code for a range of company projects. T-Mobile says no customer or government information was stolen in the intrusion.</p>
<p>LAPSUS$ is known for stealing data and then demanding a ransom not to publish or sell it. But the leaked chats indicate this mercenary activity was of little interest to the tyrannical teenage leader of LAPSUS$, whose obsession with stealing and leaking proprietary computer source code from the world&#8217;s largest tech companies ultimately led to the group&#8217;s undoing.</p>
<p>From its inception in December 2021 until its implosion late last month, LAPSUS$ operated openly on its <strong>Telegram</strong> chat channel, which quickly grew to more than 40,000 followers after the group started using it to leak huge volumes of sensitive data stolen from victim corporations.</p>
<p>But LAPSUS$ also used private Telegram channels that were restricted to the core seven members of the group. KrebsOnSecurity recently received a week&#8217;s worth of these private conversations between LAPSUS$ members as they plotted their final attacks late last month.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/lapsus-school.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-59501 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/lapsus-school.png" alt="" width="635" height="527" /></a></p>
<p>The candid conversations show LAPSUS$ frequently obtained the initial access to targeted organizations by purchasing it from sites like <strong>Russian Market</strong>, which sell access to remotely compromised systems, as well as any credentials stored on those systems.</p>
<p>The logs indicate LAPSUS$ had exactly zero problems buying, stealing or sweet-talking their way into employee accounts at companies they wanted to hack. The bigger challenge for LAPSUS$ was the subject mentioned by &#8220;Lapsus Jobs&#8221; in the screenshot above: Device enrollment. In most cases, this involved social engineering employees at the targeted firm into adding one of their computers or mobiles to the list of devices allowed to authenticate with the company&#8217;s virtual private network (VPN).</p>
<p>The messages show LAPSUS$ members continuously targeted <strong>T-Mobile</strong> employees, whose access to internal company tools could give them everything they needed to conduct hassle-free &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sim-swapping/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SIM swaps</a>&#8221; &#8212; reassigning a target&#8217;s mobile phone number to a device they controlled. These unauthorized sim swaps allow an attacker to intercept a target&#8217;s text messages and phone calls, including any links sent via SMS for password resets, or one-time codes sent for multi-factor authentication.</p>
<div id="attachment_59494" style="width: 772px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59494" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-59494" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob.png" alt="" width="762" height="410" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob.png 1277w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob-768x413.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob-782x421.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/samsungtmob-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 762px) 100vw, 762px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-59494" class="wp-caption-text">The LAPSUS$ group had a laugh at this screenshot posted by their leader, White, which shows him reading a T-Mobile news alert about their hack into Samsung. White is viewing the page via a T-Mobile employee&#8217;s virtual machine.</p></div>
<p>In one chat, the LAPSUS$ leader &#8212; a 17-year-old from the U.K. who goes by the nicknames &#8220;<strong>White</strong>,&#8221; &#8220;<strong>WhiteDoxbin</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Oklaqq</strong>&#8221; &#8212; is sharing his screen with another LAPSUS$ member who used the handles &#8220;<strong>Amtrak</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Asyntax</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>The two were exploring T-Mobile&#8217;s internal systems, and Amtrak asked White to obscure the T-Mobile logo on his screen. In these chats, the user &#8220;<strong>Lapsus Jobs</strong>&#8221; is White. Amtrak explains this odd request by saying their parents are aware Amtrak was previously involved in SIM swapping.</p>
<p>&#8220;Parents know I simswap,&#8221; Amtrak <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/parentsknowisimswap.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>. &#8220;So, if they see [that] they think I&#8217;m hacking.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59485" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/parentsknowisimswap.png" alt="" width="764" height="688" /></p>
<p>The messages reveal that each time LAPSUS$ was cut off from a T-Mobile employee&#8217;s account &#8212; either because the employee tried to log in or change their password &#8212; they would just <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/anothertmob.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">find or buy another set of T-Mobile VPN credentials</a>. T-Mobile currently has approximately 75,000 employees worldwide.</p>
<p>On March 19, 2022, the logs and accompanying screenshots show LAPSUS$ had <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hasatlas1.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gained access to <strong>Atlas</strong></a>, a powerful internal T-Mobile tool for managing customer accounts.</p>
<div id="attachment_59482" style="width: 773px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59482" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-59482" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod.png" alt="" width="763" height="412" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod.png 1274w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod-768x415.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod-782x422.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/atlas-dod-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 763px) 100vw, 763px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-59482" class="wp-caption-text">LAPSUS$ leader White/Lapsus Jobs looking up the Department of Defense in T-Mobile&#8217;s internal Atlas system.</p></div>
<p>After gaining access to Atlas, White proceeded to look up T-Mobile accounts associated with the <strong>FBI</strong> and <strong>Department of Defense</strong> (see image above). Fortunately, those accounts were listed as requiring additional verification procedures before any changes could be processed.</p>
<p>Faced with increasingly vocal pleadings from other LAPSUS$ members <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/killatlasin1second.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">not to burn their access to Atlas and other tools</a> by trying to SIM swap government accounts, White unilaterally decided to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/anothertmob.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">terminate the VPN connection permitting access to T-Mobile&#8217;s network.</a></p>
<p>The other LAPSUS$ members desperately wanted to SIM swap some wealthy targets for money. Amtrak <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/whyyyyyyy.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">throws a fit</a>, saying &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/workedreallyhardforthis.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">I worked really hard for this!</a>&#8221; White calls the Atlas access trash and then kills the VPN connection anyway, saying he wanted to focus on using their illicit T-Mobile access to steal source code.</p>
<div id="attachment_59483" style="width: 777px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59483" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-59483" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket.png" alt="" width="767" height="414" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket.png 1274w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket-768x415.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket-782x422.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mob-bitbucket-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 100vw, 767px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-59483" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot taken by LAPSUS$ inside T-Mobile&#8217;s source code repository at Bitbucket.</p></div>
<p>Perhaps to mollify his furious teammates, White changed the subject and told them he&#8217;d gained access to T-Mobile&#8217;s <strong>Slack</strong> and <strong>Bitbucket</strong> accounts. He said he&#8217;d figured out how to upload files to the virtual machine he had access to at T-Mobile.<span id="more-59472"></span></p>
<p>Roughly 12 hours later, White posts a screenshot in their private chat showing his automated script had downloaded more than 30,000 source code repositories from T-Mobile.</p>
<div id="attachment_59484" style="width: 773px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mobsourcedl.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59484" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-59484" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mobsourcedl.png" alt="" width="763" height="423" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mobsourcedl.png 1315w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mobsourcedl-768x426.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/t-mobsourcedl-782x434.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 763px) 100vw, 763px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-59484" class="wp-caption-text">White showing a screenshot of a script that he said downloaded all available T-Mobile source code.</p></div>
<p>In response to questions from KrebsOnSecurity, T-Mobile issued the following statement:</p>
<p>&#8220;Several weeks ago, our monitoring tools detected a bad actor using stolen credentials to access internal systems that house operational tools software. The systems accessed contained no customer or government information or other similarly sensitive information, and we have no evidence that the intruder was able to obtain anything of value. Our systems and processes worked as designed, the intrusion was rapidly shut down and closed off, and the compromised credentials used were rendered obsolete.&#8221;</p>
<h2>CONSIDER THE SOURCE</h2>
<p>It is not clear why LAPSUS$ was so fixated on stealing source code. Perhaps LAPSUS$ thought they could find in the source clues about security weaknesses that could be used to further hack these companies and their customers. Maybe the group already had buyers lined up for specific source code that they were then hired to procure. Or maybe it was all one big Capture the Flag competition, with source code being the flag. The leaked chats don&#8217;t exactly explain this fixation.</p>
<p>But it seems likely that the group routinely tried to steal and then delete any source code it could find on victim systems. That way, it could turn around and demand a payment to restore the deleted data.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59500 aligncenter" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/lowerlevelsource.png" alt="" width="633" height="614" /></p>
<p>In one conversation in late March, a LAPSUS$ member posts screenshots and other data indicating they&#8217;d gained remote administrative access to a multi-billion dollar company. But White is seemingly unimpressed, dismissing the illicit access as not worth the group&#8217;s time because there was no source code to be had.</p>
<p>LAPSUS$ first surfaced in December 2021, when it hacked into Brazil&#8217;s Ministry of Health and deleted more than 50 terabytes of data stored on the ministry&#8217;s hacked servers. The deleted data included information related to the ministry&#8217;s efforts to track and fight the COVID-19 pandemic in Brazil, which has suffered <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/24/world/americas/brazil-500000-covid-deaths.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a disproportionate 13 percent of the world&#8217;s COVID-19 fatalities</a>. LAPSUS$&#8217;s next 15 victims were based either in Latin America or Portugal, according to cyber threat intelligence firm <a href="https://www.flashpoint-intel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flashpoint</a>.</p>
<p>By February 2022, LAPSUS$ had pivoted to targeting high-tech firms based in the United States. On Feb. 26, LAPSUS$ broke into graphics and computing chip maker <strong>NVIDIA</strong>. The group said it stole more than a terabyte of NVIDIA data, including source code and employee credentials.</p>
<p><strong>Dan Goodin</strong> at <em>Ars Technica</em> wrote about LAPSUS$&#8217;s <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/03/cybercriminals-who-breached-nvidia-issue-one-of-the-most-unusual-demands-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unusual extortion demand against NVIDIA</a>: The group pledged to publish the stolen code unless NVIDIA agreed to make the drivers for its video cards open-source. According to these chats, NVIDIA responded by connecting to the computer the attackers were using, and then encrypting the stolen data.</p>
<p>Like many high-tech firms whose value is closely tied to their intellectual property, NVIDIA relies on a number of technologies designed to prevent data leaks or theft. According to LAPSUS$, among those is a requirement that only devices which have been approved or issued by the company can be used to access its virtual private network (VPN).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-59502" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/mdm.png" alt="" width="368" height="264" />These so-called <strong>Mobile Device Management</strong> (MDM) systems retrieve information about the underlying hardware and software powering the system requesting access, and then relay that information along with any login credentials.</p>
<p>In a typical MDM setup, a company will issue employees a laptop or smartphone that has been pre-programmed with a data profile, VPN and other software that allows the employer to track, monitor, troubleshoot or even wipe device data in the event of theft, loss, or a detected breach.</p>
<p>MDM tools also can be used to encrypt or retrieve data from connected systems, and this was purportedly the functionality NVIDIA used to claw back the information stolen by LAPSUS$.</p>
<p>&#8220;Access to NVIDIA employee VPN requires the PC to be enrolled in MDM,&#8221; LAPSUS$ wrote in a post on their public Telegram channel. &#8220;With this they were able to connect to a [virtual machine] that we use. Yes, they successfully encrypted the data. However, we have a backup and it&#8217;s safe from scum!!!&#8221;</p>
<p>NVIDIA declined to comment for this story.</p>
<p>On March 7, consumer electronics giant <strong>Samsung</strong> confirmed what LAPSUS$ had bragged on its Telegram channel: That the group had stolen and leaked nearly 200 GB of source code and other internal company data.</p>
<p>The chats reveal that LAPSUS$ stole a great deal more source code than they bragged about online. One of White&#8217;s curious fascinations was <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/sascar" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SASCAR</a>, Brazil&#8217;s leading fleet management and freight security company. White had bought and talked his way into SASCAR&#8217;s systems, and had stolen many gigabytes worth of source code for the company&#8217;s fleet tracking software.</p>
<p>It was bad enough that LAPSUS$ had just relieved this company of valuable intellectual property: The chats show that for several days White taunted SASCAR employees who were responding to the then-unfolding breach, at first by defacing the company&#8217;s website with porn.</p>
<p>The messages show White maintained access to the company&#8217;s internal systems for at least 24 hours after that, even sitting in on the company&#8217;s incident response communications where the security team discussed how to evict their tormentors.</p>
<p>SASCAR is owned by tire industry giant <a href="https://www.michelin.com/en/press-releases/michelin-acquires-sascar-brazils-leading-digital-fleet-management-company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michelin</a>, which did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<h2>ENROLLMENT</h2>
<p>The leaked LAPSUS$ internal chats show the group spent a great deal of time trying to bypass multi-factor authentication for the credentials they&#8217;d stolen. By the time these leaked chat logs were recorded, LAPSUS$ had spent days relentlessly picking on another target that relied on MDM to restrict employee logins: <strong>Iqor</strong>, a customer support outsourcing company based in St. Petersburg, Fla.</p>
<p>LAPSUS$ apparently had no trouble using Russian Market to purchase access to Iqor employee systems. &#8220;I will buy login when on sale, Russians stock it every 3-4 days,&#8221; Amtrak wrote regarding Iqor credentials for sale in the bot shops.</p>
<p>The real trouble for LAPSUS$ came when the group tried to evade Iqor&#8217;s MDM systems by social engineering Iqor employees into removing multi-factor authentication on Iqor accounts they&#8217;d purchased previously. The chats show that time and again Iqor&#8217;s employees simply refused requests to modify multi-factor authentication settings on the targeted accounts, or make any changes unless the requests were coming from authorized devices.</p>
<div id="attachment_59489" style="width: 559px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59489" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59489" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/iqor-ftw.png" alt="" width="549" height="731" /><p id="caption-attachment-59489" class="wp-caption-text">One of several IQOR support engineers who told LAPSUS$ no over and over again.</p></div>
<p>After many days of trying, LAPSUS$ ultimately gave up on Iqor. On Mar. 22, LAPSUS$ announced it hacked <strong>Microsoft</strong>, and began leaking 37 gigabytes worth of Microsoft source code.</p>
<p>Like NVIDIA, Microsoft was able to stanch some of the bleeding, cutting off LAPSUS$&#8217;s illicit access while the group was in the process of downloading all of the available source code repositories alphabetically (the group publicized their access to Microsoft at the same time they were downloading the software giant&#8217;s source code). As a result, LAPSUS$ was only able to leak the source for Microsoft products at the beginning of the code repository, including Azure, Bing and Cortana.</p>
<h2>BETRAYAL</h2>
<p>LAPSUS$ leader White drew attention to himself prior to the creation of LAPSUS$ last year when he purchased a website called <strong>Doxbin</strong>, a long-running and highly toxic online community that is used to “dox” or post deeply personal information on people.</p>
<p>Based on the feedback posted by Doxbin members, White was not a particularly attentive administrator. Longtime members soon took to harassing him about various components of the site falling into disrepair. That pestering eventually prompted White to sell Doxbin back to its previous owner at a considerable loss. But before doing so, White leaked the Doxbin user database.</p>
<p>White’s leak triggered a swift counterpunch from Doxbin’s staff, which naturally responded by posting on White perhaps the most thorough dox the forum had ever produced &#8212; including videos filmed just outside his home where he lives with his parents in the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>The past and current owner of the Doxbin — an established cybercriminal who goes by the handle “<a href="https://www.twitter.com/kayte" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>KT</strong></a>” &#8212; is the same person who leaked these private LAPSUS$ Telegram chat logs to KrebsOnSecurity.</p>
<p>In early April, multiple news outlets reported that U.K. police had arrested seven people aged 15-21 in connection with the LAPSUS$ investigation. But it seems clear from reading these leaked Telegram chats that individual members of LAPSUS$ were detained and questioned at different times over the course of several months.</p>
<p>In his chats with other LAPSUS$ members during the last week in March, White maintained that he was arrested 1-2 months prior in connection with an intrusion against a victim referred to only by the initials &#8220;BT.&#8221; White also appeared unconcerned when Amtrak admits that the City of London police found LAPSUS$ Telegram chat conversations on his mobile phone.</p>
<p>Perhaps to demonstrate his indifference (or maybe just to screw with Amtrak), White responds by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/parentsknowisimswap.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leaking Amtrak&#8217;s real name and phone number to the group&#8217;s public Telegram channel</a>. In an ALL CAPS invective of disbelief at the sudden betrayal, Amtrak relates how various people started calling their home and threatening their parents as a result, and how White effectively outed them to law enforcement and the rest of the world as a LAPSUS$ member.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-59487" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/amtraxdox.png" alt="" width="745" height="206" /></p>
<p>The vast majority of noteworthy activity documented in these private chats takes place between White and Amtrak, but it doesn&#8217;t seem that White counted Amtrak or any of his fellow LAPSUS$ members as friends or confidants. On the contrary, White generally behaved horribly toward everyone in the group, and he particularly seemed to enjoy abusing Amtrak (who somehow always came back for more).</p>
<p>&#8220;<strong>Mox</strong>,&#8221; one of the LAPSUS$ members who shows up throughout these leaked chats, helped the group in their unsuccessful attempts to enroll their mobile devices with an airline in the Middle East to which they had purchased access. Audio recordings leaked from the group&#8217;s private Telegram channel include a call wherein Mox can be heard speaking fluently in Arabic and impersonating an airline employee.</p>
<p>At one point, Mox&#8217;s first name briefly shows up in a video he made and shared with the group, and Mox mentions that he lives in the United States. White then begins trying to find and leak Mox&#8217;s real-life identity.</p>
<p>When Mox declares he&#8217;s so scared he wants to delete his iCloud account, White suggests he can get Mox&#8217;s real name, precise location and other information by making <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/hackers-gaining-power-of-subpoena-via-fake-emergency-data-requests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a fraudulent &#8220;emergency data request&#8221; (EDR)</a> to <strong>Apple</strong>, in which they use a hacked police department email account to request emergency access to subscriber information under the claim that the request can&#8217;t wait for a warrant because someone&#8217;s life is on the line.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59515" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/edrtooapple.png" alt="" width="633" height="161" /></p>
<p>White was no stranger to fake EDRs. White was a founding member of a cybercriminal group called “<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210410013319/http://recursion.team/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Recursion Team,</a>” which existed between 2020 and 2021. This group mostly specialized in SIM swapping targets of interest and participating in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=swatting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“swatting” attacks</a>, wherein fake bomb threats, hostage situations and other violent scenarios are phoned in to police as part of a scheme to trick them into visiting potentially deadly force on a target’s address.</p>
<div id="attachment_59127" style="width: 768px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59127" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-59127" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion.png" alt="" width="758" height="630" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion.png 864w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion-768x638.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion-782x650.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 758px) 100vw, 758px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-59127" class="wp-caption-text">The roster of the now-defunct &#8220;Infinity Recursion&#8221; hacking team, from which some members of LAPSUS$ hail.</p></div>
<p>The Recursion Team was founded by a then 14-year-old from the United Kingdom who used the handle “<strong>Everlynn</strong>.” On April 5, 2021, Everlynn posted a new sales thread to the cybercrime forum cracked[.]to titled, “Warrant/subpoena service (get law enforcement data from any service).” The price: $100 to $250 per request.</p>
<div id="attachment_59126" style="width: 715px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59126" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59126" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinity-warrant.png" alt="" width="705" height="713" /><p id="caption-attachment-59126" class="wp-caption-text">Everlynn advertising a warrant/subpoena service based on fake EDRs.</p></div>
<p>Bringing this full circle, it appears Amtrak/Asyntax is the same person as Everlynn. As part of the Recursion Team, White used the alias &#8220;<strong>Peter</strong>.&#8221; Several LAPSUS$ members quizzed White and Amtrak about whether authorities asked about Recursion Team during questioning. In several discussion threads, White&#8217;s &#8220;Lapsus Jobs&#8221; alias on Telegram answers &#8220;yes?&#8221; or &#8220;I&#8217;m here&#8221; when another member addresses him by Peter.</p>
<p>White dismissed his public doxing of both Amtrak and Mox as their fault for being sloppy with operational security, or by claiming that everyone already knew their real identities. Incredibly, just a few minutes after doxing Amtrak, White nonchalantly asks them for help in stealing source code from yet another victim firm &#8212; as if nothing had just happened between them. Amtrak seems soothed by this invitation, and agrees to help.</p>
<p>On Mar. 30, software consultancy giant <strong>Globant</strong> was forced to acknowledge a hack after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/03/30/lapsus-globant-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LAPSUS$ published 70 gigabytes of data stolen from the company</a>, including customers&#8217; source code. While the Globant hack has been widely reported for weeks, the cause of the breach remained hidden in these chat logs: A stolen five-year-old access token for Globant&#8217;s network that still worked.</p>
<div id="attachment_59481" style="width: 647px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59481" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59481" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/globant-howtf.png" alt="" width="637" height="764" /><p id="caption-attachment-59481" class="wp-caption-text">LAPSUS$ members marvel at a 5-year-old stolen authentication cookie still working when they use it against Globant to steal source code.</p></div>
<p>Globant lists a number of high-profile customers on its website, including the U.K. Metropolitan Police, software house Autodesk and gaming giant <strong>Electronic Arts</strong>. In March, KrebsOnSecurity showed how <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/a-closer-look-at-the-lapsus-data-extortion-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">White was connected to the theft of 780 GB worth of source code from Electronic Arts last summer</a>.</p>
<p>In that attack, the intruders reportedly gained access to EA&#8217;s data after purchasing authentication cookies for an EA Slack channel from the dark web marketplace &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis</a>,&#8221; which offers more or less the same wares as the Russian Market.</p>
<p>One remarkable aspect of LAPSUS$ was that its members apparently decided not to personally download or store any data they stole from companies they hacked. They were all so paranoid of police raiding their homes that they assiduously kept everything &#8220;in the cloud.&#8221; That way, when investigators searched their devices, they would find no traces of the stolen information.</p>
<p>But this strategy ultimately backfired: Shortly before the private LAPSUS$ chat was terminated, the group learned it had just lost access to the Amazon AWS server it was using to store months of source code booty and other stolen data.</p>
<p>&#8220;RIP FBI seized my server,&#8221; Amtrak <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/fbiseizedmyserver.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote.</a> &#8220;So much illegal shit. It&#8217;s filled with illegal shit.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59496" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/somuchillegalshit.png" alt="" width="633" height="716" /></p>
<p>White shrugs it off with the dismissive comment, &#8220;U can&#8217;t do anything about ur server seized.&#8221; Then Amtrak replies that <em>they never made a backup of the server</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;FFS, THAT AWS HAD TMO SRC [T-Mobile source] code!&#8221; White yelled back.</p>
<p>The two then make a mad scramble to hack back into T-Mobile and re-download the stolen source code. But that effort ultimately failed after T-Mobile&#8217;s systems revoked the access token they were using to raid the company&#8217;s source code stash.</p>
<p>&#8220;How they noticed?&#8221; Amtrak asked White.</p>
<p>&#8220;Gitlab auto-revoked, likely,&#8221; White replied. &#8220;Cloning 30k repos four times in 24 hours isn&#8217;t very normal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ah, the irony of a criminal hacking group that specializes in stealing and deleting data having their stolen data deleted.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s remarkable how often LAPSUS$ was able to pay a few dollars to buy access to some hacked machine at a company they wanted to break into, and then successfully parlay that into the theft of source code and other sensitive information.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s even more remarkable is that anyone can access dark web bot shops like Russian Market and Genesis, which means larger companies probably should be paying someone to regularly scrape these criminal bot services, even buying back their own employee credentials to take those vulnerable systems off the market. Because that&#8217;s probably the simplest and cheapest incident response money can buy.</p>
<div id="attachment_58210" style="width: 774px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-58210" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-58210" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop.png" alt="" width="764" height="500" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop.png 1240w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop-768x503.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/genesisshop-782x512.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 764px) 100vw, 764px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-58210" class="wp-caption-text">The Genesis bot shop.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/leaked-chats-show-lapsus-stole-t-mobile-source-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conti’s Ransomware Toll on the Healthcare Industry</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/contis-ransomware-toll-on-the-healthcare-industry/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/contis-ransomware-toll-on-the-healthcare-industry/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 20:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Conti]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Emotet]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Emsisoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Errol Weiss]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[H-ISAC]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Health Information Sharing & Analysis Center]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Healthcare Information and Management Systems Society]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[proofpoint]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ryuk]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[sophos]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[U.S. Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zloader]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59446</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Conti -- one of the most ruthless and successful Russian ransomware groups -- publicly declared during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic that it would refrain from targeting healthcare providers. But new information confirms this pledge was always a lie, and that Conti has launched more than 200 attacks against hospitals and other healthcare facilities since first surfacing in 2018 under the name "Ryuk."]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conti</strong> &#8212; one of the most ruthless and successful Russian ransomware groups &#8212; publicly declared during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic that it would refrain from targeting healthcare providers. But new information confirms this pledge was always a lie, and that Conti has launched more than 200 attacks against hospitals and other healthcare facilities since first surfacing in 2018 under its earlier name, &#8220;<strong>Ryuk</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-53477" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/medsec.png" alt="" width="748" height="819" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/medsec.png 800w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/medsec-768x841.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></p>
<p>On April 13, Microsoft said it executed <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2022/04/13/zloader-botnet-disrupted-malware-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a legal sneak attack</a> against <strong>Zloader</strong>, a remote access trojan and malware platform that multiple ransomware groups have used to deploy their malware inside victim networks. More specifically, Microsoft <a href="https://noticeofpleadings.com/Zloader/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained a court order</a> that allowed it to seize 65 domain names that were used to maintain the Zloader botnet.</p>
<p>Microsoft&#8217;s civil lawsuit against Zloader names seven &#8220;John Does,&#8221; essentially seeking information to identify cybercriminals who used Zloader to conduct ransomware attacks. As the company&#8217;s complaint notes, some of these John Does were associated with lesser ransomware collectives such as <strong>Egregor</strong> and <strong>Netfilim</strong>.</p>
<p>But according to Microsoft and <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/alerts/aa21-265a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an advisory</a> from the <strong>U.S. Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA), Zloader had a special relationship with Ryuk/Conti, acting as <a href="https://threatpost.com/malsmoke-microsoft-e-signature-verification/177363/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a preferred distribution platform for deploying Ryuk/Conti ransomware</a>.</p>
<p>Several parties backed Microsoft in its legal efforts against Zloader by filing supporting declarations, including <strong>Errol Weiss</strong>, a former penetration tester for the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong> (NSA). Weiss now serves as the chief security officer of the <a href="https://www.h-isac.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Health Information Sharing &amp; Analysis Center</a> (H-ISAC), an industry group that shares information about cyberattacks against healthcare providers.</p>
<p>Weiss said ransomware attacks from Ryuk/Conti have impacted hundreds of healthcare facilities across the United States, including facilities located in 192 cities and 41 states and the District of Columbia.</p>
<p>&#8220;The attacks resulted in the temporary or permanent loss of IT systems that support many of the provider delivery functions in modern hospitals resulting in cancelled surgeries and delayed medical care,&#8221; Weiss said in <a href="https://noticeofpleadings.com/zloader/files/Application%20for%20TRO/TRO%2008%20-%20Weiss%20Decl%20with%20Ex%201%20ISO%20TRO%20and%20PI.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a declaration</a> (PDF) with the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Georgia.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hospitals reported revenue losses due to Ryuk infections of nearly $100 million from data I obtained through interviews with hospital staff, public statements, and media articles,&#8221; Weiss wrote. &#8220;The Ryuk attacks also caused an estimated $500 million in costs to respond to the attacks – costs that include ransomware payments, digital forensic services, security improvements and upgrading impacted systems plus other expenses.&#8221;<span id="more-59446"></span></p>
<p>The figures cited by Weiss appear highly conservative. A single attack by Ryuk/Conti in May 2021 against Ireland&#8217;s Health Service Executive, which operates the country’s public health system, resulted in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/12/inside-irelands-public-healthcare-ransomware-scare/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">massive disruptions to healthcare in Ireland</a>. In June 2021, the HSE’s director general said the recovery costs for that attack were likely to exceed USD $600 million.</p>
<p>Conti ravaged the healthcare sector throughout 2020, and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/conti-ransomware-group-diaries-part-i-evasion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leaked internal chats from the Conti ransomware group</a> show the gang had access to more than 400 healthcare facilities in the U.S. alone by October 2020.</p>
<p>On Oct. 28, 2020, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/10/fbi-dhs-hhs-warn-of-imminent-credible-ransomware-threat-against-u-s-hospitals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broke the news</a> that FBI and DHS officials had seen reliable intelligence indicating the group planned to ransom many of these care facilities simultaneously. Hours after that October 2020 piece ran, I heard from a respected H-ISAC security professional who questioned whether it was worth getting the public so riled up. The story had been updated multiple times throughout the day, and there were at least five healthcare organizations hit with ransomware within the span of 24 hours.</p>
<p>“I guess it would help if I understood what the baseline is, like how many healthcare organizations get hit with ransomware on average in one week?” I asked the source.</p>
<p>“It’s more like one a day,” the source confided.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://news.sophos.com/en-us/2022/02/28/conti-and-karma-actors-attack-healthcare-provider-at-same-time-through-proxyshell-exploits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report in February 2022</a> from <strong>Sophos</strong> found Conti orchestrated a cyberattack against a Canadian healthcare provider in late 2021. Security software firm <strong>Emsisoft</strong> <a href="https://blog.emsisoft.com/en/40813/the-state-of-ransomware-in-the-us-report-and-statistics-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> that at least 68 healthcare providers suffered ransomware attacks last year.</p>
<p>While Conti is just one of many ransomware groups threatening the healthcare industry, it seems likely that ransomware attacks on the healthcare sector are underreported. Perhaps this is because a large percentage of victims are paying a ransom demand to keep their data (and news of their breach) confidential. A <a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/newsroom/press-releases/proofpoints-2022-state-phish-report-reveals-email-based-attacks-dominated" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> published in February by email security provider <strong>Proofpoint</strong> found almost 60 percent of victims hit by ransomware paid their extortionists.</p>
<p>Or perhaps it&#8217;s because many crime groups have shifted focus away from deploying ransomware and toward stealing data and demanding payment not to publish the information. Conti shames victims who refuse to pay a ransom by posting their internal data on their darkweb blog.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of 2022, Conti has claimed responsibility for hacking a cancer testing lab, a medical prescription service online, a biomedical testing facility, a pharmaceutical company, and a spinal surgery center.</p>
<p>The <strong>Healthcare Information and Management Systems Society</strong> recently released its <a href="https://www.himss.org/sites/hde/files/media/file/2022/01/28/2021_himss_cybersecurity_survey.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2021 HIMSS Healthcare Cybersecurity Survey</a> (PDF), which interviewed 167 healthcare cybersecurity professionals and found 67 percent had experienced a &#8220;significant security incident&#8221; in the past year.</p>
<p>The survey also found that just six percent or less of respondent&#8217;s information technology budgets were devoted to cybersecurity, although roughly 60 percent of respondents said their cybersecurity budgets would increase in 2022. Last year, just 79 percent of respondents said they&#8217;d fully implemented antivirus or other anti-malware systems; only 43 percent reported they&#8217;d fully implemented intrusion detection and prevention technologies.</p>
<p>The FBI <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/News/2021/210521.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> Conti typically gains access to victim networks through weaponized malicious email links, attachments, or stolen Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP) credentials, and that it weaponizes Microsoft Office documents with embedded Powershell scripts &#8212; initially staging Cobalt Strike via the Office documents and then dropping <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/01/international-action-targets-emotet-crimeware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Emotet</a> onto the network &#8212; giving them the ability to deploy ransomware. The FBI said Conti has been observed inside victim networks between four days and three weeks on average before deploying Conti ransomware.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/contis-ransomware-toll-on-the-healthcare-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, April 2022 Edition</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/microsoft-patch-tuesday-april-2022-edition/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/microsoft-patch-tuesday-april-2022-edition/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 15:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Tools]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59439</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Microsoft on Tuesday released updates to fix roughly 120 security vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and other software. Two of the flaws have been publicly detailed prior to this week, and one is already seeing active exploitation, according to a report from the U.S. National Security Agency (NSA).]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="752" height="529" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 752px) 100vw, 752px" /></p>
<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> on Tuesday released updates to fix roughly 120 security vulnerabilities in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and other software. Two of the flaws have been publicly detailed prior to this week, and one is already seeing active exploitation, according to a report from the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong> (NSA).</p>
<p>Of particular concern this month is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-24521" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2022-24521</a>, which is a &#8220;privilege escalation&#8221; vulnerability in the Windows common log file system driver. In its advisory, Microsoft said it received a report from the NSA that the flaw is under active attack.</p>
<p>“It’s not stated how widely the exploit is being used in the wild, but it’s likely still targeted at this point and not broadly available,&#8221; assessed <strong>Dustin Childs</strong> with Trend Micro&#8217;s Zero Day Initiative. &#8220;Go patch your systems before that situation changes.”</p>
<p>Nine of the updates pushed this week address problems Microsoft considers &#8220;critical,&#8221; meaning the flaws they fix could be abused by malware or malcontents to seize total, remote access to a Windows system without any help from the user.</p>
<p>Among the scariest critical bugs is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-26809" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2022-26809,</a> a potentially &#8220;wormable&#8221; weakness in a core Windows component (<strong>RPC</strong>) that earned a CVSS score of 9.8 (10 being the worst). Microsoft said it believes exploitation of this flaw is more likely than not.</p>
<p>Other potentially wormable threats this month include <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-24491" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2022-24491</a> and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-24497" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2022-24497</a>, Windows <strong>Network File System</strong> (NFS) vulnerabilities that also clock in at 9.8 CVSS scores and are listed as &#8220;exploitation more likely by Microsoft.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;These could be the kind of vulnerabilities which appeal to ransomware operators as they provide the potential to expose critical data,&#8221; said <strong>Kevin Breen</strong>, director of cyber threat research at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong>. &#8220;It is also important for security teams to note that NFS Role is not a default configuration for Windows devices.&#8221;<span id="more-59439"></span></p>
<p>Speaking of wormable flaws, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/vulnerability/CVE-2022-24500" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2022-24500</a> is a critical bug in the <strong>Windows Server Message Block</strong> (SMB).</p>
<p>&#8220;This is especially poignant as we approach the anniversary of WannaCry, which famously used the EternalBlue SMB vulnerability to propagate at great pace,&#8221; Breen added. &#8220;Microsoft advises blocking TCP port 445 at the perimeter firewall, which is strong advice regardless of this specific vulnerability. While this won&#8217;t stop exploitation from attackers inside the local network, it will prevent new attacks originating from the Internet.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition, this month&#8217;s patch batch from Redmond brings updates for <strong>Exchange Server</strong>, <strong>Office</strong>, <strong>SharePoint Server</strong>, <strong>Windows Hyper-V</strong>, <strong>DNS Server</strong>, <strong>Skype for Business</strong>, <strong>.NET</strong> and <strong>Visual Studio</strong>, <strong>Windows App Store</strong>, and <strong>Windows Print Spooler</strong> components.</p>
<p>As it generally does on the second Tuesday of each month, <strong>Adobe</strong> released four patches addressing 70 vulnerabilities in <strong>Acrobat</strong> and <strong>Reader,</strong> <strong>Photoshop</strong>, <strong>After Effects</strong>, and <strong>Adobe Commerce</strong>. More information on those updates is available <a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/security.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>For a complete rundown of all patches released by Microsoft today and indexed by severity and other metrics, check out the <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft+April+2022+Patch+Tuesday/28542/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">always-useful Patch Tuesday roundup</a> from the <strong>SANS Internet Storm Center</strong>. And it’s not a bad idea to hold off updating for a few days until Microsoft works out any kinks in the updates: <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/2022/march-madness-patching-begins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskWoody.com</a> usually has the lowdown on any patches that may be causing problems for Windows users.</p>
<p>As always, please consider backing up your system or at least your important documents and data before applying system updates. And if you run into any problems with these patches, please drop a note about it here in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/microsoft-patch-tuesday-april-2022-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RaidForums Gets Raided, Alleged Admin Arrested</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Diogo Santos Coelho]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Europol]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[National Crime Agency]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Omnipotent]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Operation Tourniquet]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[RaidForums seizure]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SubVirt]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[T-Mobile breach]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[unrivaled@pm.me]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59419</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) said today it seized the website and user database for RaidForums, an extremely popular English-language cybercrime forum that sold access to more than 10 billion consumer records stolen in some of the world's largest data breaches since 2015. The DOJ also charged the alleged administrator of RaidForums -- 21-year-old Diogo Santos Coelho, of Portugal -- with six criminal counts, including conspiracy, access device fraud and aggravated identity theft.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> (DOJ) said today it seized the website and user database for <strong>RaidForums</strong>, an extremely popular English-language cybercrime forum that sold access to more than 10 billion consumer records stolen in some of the world&#8217;s largest data breaches since 2015. The DOJ also charged the alleged administrator of RaidForums &#8212; 21-year-old <strong>Diogo Santos Coelho</strong>, of Portugal &#8212; with six criminal counts, including conspiracy, access device fraud and aggravated identity theft.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-59420" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/raidforums-seized.png" alt="" width="750" height="484" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/raidforums-seized.png 1197w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/raidforums-seized-768x495.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/raidforums-seized-782x504.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>The &#8220;raid&#8221; in RaidForums is a nod to the community&#8217;s humble beginnings in 2015, when it was primarily an online venue for organizing and supporting various forms of electronic harassment. According to the DOJ, that early activity included &#8216;<strong>raiding</strong>&#8216; &#8212; posting or sending an overwhelming volume of contact to a victim&#8217;s online communications medium &#8212; and &#8216;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/swatting/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">swatting</a>,&#8217; the practice of making false reports to public safety agencies of situations that would necessitate a significant, and immediate armed law enforcement response.&#8221;</p>
<p>But over the years as trading in hacked databases became big business, RaidForums emerged as the go-to place for English-speaking hackers to peddle their wares. Perhaps the most bustling marketplace within RaidForums was its &#8220;<strong>Leaks Market</strong>,&#8221; which described itself as a place to buy, sell, and trade hacked databases and leaks.</p>
<p>The government alleges Coelho and his forum administrator identity &#8220;<strong>Omnipotent</strong>&#8221; profited from the illicit activity on the platform by charging &#8220;escalating prices for membership tiers that offered greater access and features, including a top-tier &#8216;God&#8217; membership status.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;RaidForums also sold &#8216;credits&#8217; that provided members access to privileged areas of the website and enabled members to &#8216;unlock&#8217; and download stolen financial information, means of identification, and data from compromised databases, among other items,&#8221; the DOJ said in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edva/pr/us-leads-seizure-one-world-s-largest-hacker-forums-and-arrests-administrator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a written statement</a>. &#8220;Members could also earn credits through other means, such as by posting instructions on how to commit certain illegal acts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prosecutors say Coelho also personally sold stolen data on the platform, and that Omnipotent directly facilitated illicit transactions by operating a fee-based “<strong>Official Middleman</strong>” service, a kind of escrow or insurance service that denizens of RaidForums were encouraged to use when transacting with other criminals.</p>
<p>Investigators described multiple instances wherein undercover federal agents or confidential informants used Omnipotent&#8217;s escrow service to purchase huge tranches of data from one of Coelho&#8217;s alternate user  identities &#8212; meaning Coelho not only sold data he&#8217;d personally hacked but also further profited by insisting the transactions were handled through his own middleman service.</p>
<p>Not all of those undercover buys went as planned. One incident described in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edva/press-release/file/1493601/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an affidavit by prosecutors</a> (PDF) appears related to the sale of tens of millions of consumer records stolen last year from <strong>T-Mobile</strong>, although the government refers to the victim only as a major telecommunications company and wireless network operator in the United States.</p>
<p>On Aug. 11, 2021, an individual using the moniker &#8220;<strong>SubVirt</strong>&#8221; posted on RaidForums an offer to sell Social Security numbers, dates of birth and other records on more than 120 million people in the United States (SubVirt would later edit the sales thread to say 30 million records). Just days later, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-breach-exposed-ssn-dob-of-40m-people/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">T-Mobile would acknowledge a data breach</a> affecting 40 million current, former or prospective customers who applied for credit with the company.</p>
<p>The government says the victim firm hired a third-party to purchase the database and prevent it from being sold to cybercriminals. That third-party ultimately paid approximately $200,000 worth of bitcoin to the seller, with the agreement that the data would be destroyed after sale. &#8220;However, it appears the co-conspirators continued to attempt to sell the databases after the third-party&#8217;s purchase,&#8221; the affidavit alleges.</p>
<p>The FBI&#8217;s seizure of RaidForums was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/a-closer-look-at-the-lapsus-data-extortion-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first reported by KrebsOnSecurity on Mar. 23</a>, after a federal investigator confirmed rumors that the FBI had been secretly operating the RaidForums website for weeks.<span id="more-59419"></span></p>
<p>Coelho landed on the radar of U.S. authorities in June 2018, when he tried to enter the United States at the <strong>Hartsfield-Jackson International Airport</strong> in Atlanta. The government obtained a warrant to search the electronic devices Coelho had in his luggage and found text messages, files and emails showing he was the RaidForums administrator Omnipotent.</p>
<p>&#8220;In an attempt to retrieve his items, Coelho called the lead FBI case agent on or around August 2, 2018, and used the email address <strong>unrivalled@pm.me</strong> to email the agent,&#8221; the government&#8217;s affidavit states. Investigators found this same address was used to register <strong>rf.ws</strong> and <strong>raid.lol</strong>, which Omnipotent announced on the forum would serve as alternative domain names for RaidForums in case the site&#8217;s primary domain was seized.</p>
<p>The DOJ said Coelho was arrested in the United Kingdom on January 31, at the United States&#8217; request, and remains in custody pending the resolution of his extradition hearing. A <a href="https://www.nationalcrimeagency.gov.uk/news/hacking-forum-taken-offline-and-uk-suspect-arrested" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from the <strong>U.K.&#8217;s National Crime Agency</strong> (NCA) said the RaidForums takedown was the result of &#8220;<strong>Operation Tourniquet</strong>,&#8221; an investigation carried out by the NCA in cooperation with the United States, <strong>Europol</strong> and four other countries that resulted in &#8220;a number of linked arrests.&#8221;</p>
<p>A copy of the indictment against Coelho is available <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edva/press-release/file/1493606/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a> (PDF).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Your-Crypto Scams Share Crypto Scam Host</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/double-your-crypto-scams-share-crypto-scam-host/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/double-your-crypto-scams-share-crypto-scam-host/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[+7.9914500893]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ARKinvest]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[crypto investment scams]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cryptohost]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[FinTelegram]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[lightning-network]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mark Tepterev]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Polkadot]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sergei Orlovets]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SmartApe]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ulanikirill52@gmail.com]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59326</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Online scams that try to separate the unwary from their cryptocurrency are a dime a dozen, but a great many seemingly disparate crypto scam websites tend to rely on the same dodgy infrastructure providers to remain online in the face of massive fraud and abuse complaints from their erstwhile customers. Here's a closer look at hundreds of phony crypto investment schemes that are all connected through a hosting provider which caters to people running crypto scams.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-59331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cryptopeople.png" alt="" width="766" height="501" /></p>
<p>Online scams that try to separate the unwary from their cryptocurrency are a dime a dozen, but a great many seemingly disparate crypto scam websites tend to rely on the same dodgy infrastructure providers to remain online in the face of massive fraud and abuse complaints from their erstwhile customers. Here&#8217;s a closer look at hundreds of phony crypto investment schemes that are all connected through a hosting provider which caters to people running crypto scams.</p>
<p>A security researcher recently shared with KrebsOnSecurity an email he received from someone who said they foolishly invested an entire bitcoin (currently worth ~USD $43,000) at a website called ark-x2[.]org, which promised to double any cryptocurrency investment made with the site.</p>
<p>The ark-x2[.]org site pretended to be a crypto giveaway website run by <a href="https://twitter.com/CathieDWood" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cathie Wood</a>, the founder and CEO of <strong>ARKinvest</strong>, an established Florida company that manages several exchange-traded investment funds. This is hardly the first time scammers have impersonated Wood or ARKinvest; <a href="https://twitter.com/cathiedwood/status/1313547340272340993?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a tweet from Wood in 2020 warned</a> that the company would never use YouTube, Twitter, Instagram or any social media to solicit money.</p>
<p>At the crux of these scams are well-orchestrated video productions published on YouTube and Facebook that claim to be a &#8220;live event&#8221; featuring famous billionaires. In reality, these videos just rehash older footage while peppering viewers with prompts to sign up at a scam investment site &#8212; one they claim has been endorsed by the celebrities.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was watching a live video at YouTube where Elon Musk, Cathy Wood, and Jack Dorsey were talking about Crypto,&#8221; the victim told my security researcher friend. &#8220;An overlay on the video pointed to subscribing to the event at their website. I&#8217;ve been following Cathy Wood in her analysis on financial markets, so I was in a comfortable and trusted environment. The three of them are bitcoin maximalists in a sense, so it made perfect sense they were organizing a giveaway.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Without any doubt (other than whether the transfer would go through), I sent them 1 BTC (~$42,800), and they were supposed to return 2 BTC back,&#8221; the victim continued. &#8220;In hindsight, this was an obvious scam. But the live video and the ARK Invest website is what produced the trusted environment to me. I realized a few minutes later, when the live video looped. It wasn&#8217;t actually live, but a replay of a video from 6 months ago.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ark-x2[.]org is no longer online. But a look at the Internet address historically tied to this domain (186.2.171.79) shows the same address is used to host or park <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1R3fZBzb75eQ3_RSxZ1Oq2DErZpkN-f5IMZj4i8IRs80/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hundreds of other newly-minted crypto scam domains</a>, including <strong>coinbase-x2[.]net </strong>(pictured below).</p>
<div id="attachment_59329" style="width: 777px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59329" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59329" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/coinbase-x2.png" alt="" width="767" height="407" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/coinbase-x2.png 1401w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/coinbase-x2-768x407.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/coinbase-x2-782x415.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 100vw, 767px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59329" class="wp-caption-text">The crypto scam site coinbase-x2[.]net, which snares unwary investors with promises of free money.</p></div>
<p>Typical of crypto scam sites, Coinbase-x2 promises a chance to win 50,000 ETH (Ethereum virtual currency), plus a &#8220;welcome bonus&#8221; wherein they promise to double any crypto investment made with the platform. But everyone who falls for this greed trap soon discovers they won&#8217;t be getting anything in return, and that their &#8220;investment&#8221; is gone forever.</p>
<p>There isn&#8217;t a lot of information about who bought these crypto scam domains, as most of them were registered in the past month at registrars that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/03/who-is-afraid-of-more-spams-and-scams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">automatically redact the site&#8217;s WHOIS ownership records</a>.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cryptohost-us.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">several dozen of the domains</a> are in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/.us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">.us domain space</a>, which is technically supposed to be reserved for entities physically based in the United States. Those Dot-us domains all contain the registrant name <strong>Sergei Orlovets</strong> from Moscow, the email address <strong>ulaninkirill52@gmail.com</strong>, and the phone number <strong>+7.9914500893</strong>. Unfortunately, each of these clues lead to a dead end, meaning they were likely picked and used solely for these scam sites.</p>
<p>A dig into the Domain Name Server (DNS) records for Coinbase-x2[.]net shows it is hosted at a service called <strong>Cryptohost[.]to</strong>. Cryptohost also controls several other address ranges, including 194.31.98.X, which is currently home to even more crypto scam websites, many targeting lesser-known cryptocurrencies like <strong>Polkadot</strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-59394" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/digcryptohostdotto.png" alt="" width="751" height="399" /></p>
<p>An ad posted to the Russian-language hacking forum BHF last month touted Cryptohost as a &#8220;bulletproof hosting provider for all your projects,&#8221; i.e., it can be relied upon to ignore abuse complaints about its customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why choose us? We don&#8217;t keep your logs!,&#8221; someone claiming to represent Cryptohost wrote to denizens of BHF.</p>
<p>Cryptohost says its service is backstopped by <strong>DDoS-Guard</strong>, a Russian company that has featured here recently for providing services to the sanctioned terrorist group <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/01/hamas-may-be-threat-to-8chan-qanon-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hamas</a> and to the conspiracy theory groups <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/10/qanon-8chan-sites-briefly-knocked-offline/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QAnon/8chan</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_59336" style="width: 771px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59336" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59336" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/polkadotscam.png" alt="" width="761" height="432" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/polkadotscam.png 1435w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/polkadotscam-768x436.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/polkadotscam-782x444.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 761px) 100vw, 761px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59336" class="wp-caption-text">A scam site at Cryptohost targeting Polkadot cryptocurrency holders.</p></div>
<p>Cryptohost did not respond to requests for comment.<span id="more-59326"></span></p>
<p>Signing up as a customer at Cryptohost presents a control panel that includes the IP address 188.127.235.21, which belongs to a hosting provider in Moscow called <strong>SmartApe</strong>. SmartApe says its main advantage is unlimited disk space, &#8220;which allows you to host an unlimited number of sites for little money.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to <strong>FinTelegram</strong>, a blog that bills itself as a crowdsourced financial intelligence service that covers investment scams, SmartApe is a &#8220;<a href="https://fintelegram.com/r4i-smartape-the-russian-israeli-hosting-company-for-cybercriminals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Russian-Israeli hosting company for cybercriminals</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>SmartApe CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-tepterev-97a16a18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Tepterev</a> declined to comment on the allegations from FinTelegram, but said the company has thousands of clients, some of whom have their own clients. </p>
<div id="attachment_59401" style="width: 602px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59401" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59401" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cryptohostpanel.png" alt="" width="592" height="686" /><p id="caption-attachment-59401" class="wp-caption-text">Cryptohost&#8217;s customer panel, which points to an IP address at Russian hosting provider SmartApe.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;Also we host other hostings that have their own thousands of customers,&#8221; Tepterev said. &#8220;Of course, there are clients who use our services in their dubious interests. We immediately block such clients upon receipt of justified complaints.&#8221;</p>
<p>Much of the text used in these scam sites has been invoked verbatim in similar schemes dating back at least two years, and it&#8217;s likely that scam website templates are re-used so long as they continue to reel in new investors. Searching online for the phrase &#8220;During this unique event we will give you a chance to win&#8221; reveals many current and former sites tied to this scam.</p>
<p>While it may seem incredible that people will fall for stuff like this, such scams reliably generate decent profits. When <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/twitter-hack/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Twitter got hacked in July 2020</a> and some of the most-followed celebrity accounts on Twitter started tweeting double-your-crypto offers, 383 people sent more than $100,000 in a few hours.</p>
<p>In Sept. 2021, the <strong>Bitcoin Foundation</strong> (bitcoin.org) was hacked, with the intruders placing <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/tech/2021/09/23/bitcoinorg-appears-hacked-by-giveaway-scam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a pop-up message on the site asking visitors to send money</a>. The message said any sent funds would be doubled and returned, claiming that the Bitcoin Foundation had set up the program as a way of &#8220;giving back to the community.&#8221; The brief scam netted more than $17,000.</p>
<p>According to the <strong>U.S. Federal Trade Commission</strong>, nearly 7,000 people lost <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2021/05/ftc-data-shows-huge-spike-cryptocurrency-investment-scams" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more than $80 million in crypto scams</a> from October 2020 through March 2021 based on consumer fraud reports. That&#8217;s a significant jump from the year prior, when the FTC tracked just 570 cryptocurrency investment scam complaints totaling $7.5 million.</p>
<p>A recent report from blockchain analysis firm <a href="https://blog.chainalysis.com/reports/2022-crypto-crime-report-introduction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chainalysis</a> found that scammers stole approximately $14 billion worth of cryptocurrency in 2021 &#8212; nearly twice the $7.8 billion stolen by scammers in 2020, the report found.</p>
<p>In March, Australia&#8217;s competition watchdog <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/australia-watchdog-sues-facebook-owner-meta-over-false-cryptocurrency-ads-2022-03-17/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">filed a lawsuit against Facebook owner Meta Platforms</a>, alleging the social media giant failed to prevent scammers using its platform to promote fake ads featuring well-known people. The complaint alleges the advertisements, which endorsed investment in cryptocurrency or money-making schemes, could have misled Facebook users into believing they were promoted by famous Australians.</p>
<p>In many ways, the crypto giveaway scam is a natural extension of perhaps the oldest cyber fraud in the book: Advanced-fee fraud. Most commonly associated with <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/scams-and-safety/common-scams-and-crimes/nigerian-letter-or-419-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigerian Letter or &#8220;419&#8221; fraud</a> and lottery/sweepstakes schemes, advanced fee scams promise a financial windfall if only the intended recipient will step up and claim what is rightfully theirs &#8212; and oh by the way just pay this small administrative fee and we&#8217;ll send the money.</p>
<p>What makes these double-your-crypto sites successful is not just ignorance and avarice, but the idea held by many novice investors that cryptocurrencies are somehow magical money-minting machines, or perhaps virtual slot machines that will eventually pay off if one simply deposits enough coinage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/double-your-crypto-scams-share-crypto-scam-host/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Actions Target Russian Govt. Botnet, Hydra Dark Market</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/actions-target-russian-govt-botnet-hydra-dark-market/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/actions-target-russian-govt-botnet-hydra-dark-market/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ars Technica]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ASUS]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Beserk Bear]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyclops Blink]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Dragonfly 2.0]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Federal Security Service]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Garantex]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[German Federal Criminal Police Office]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[GRU]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Hydra Market]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Main Intelligence Directorate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NotPetya]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russian FSB]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sandworm]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Trisis]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Triton]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Treasury]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Voodoo Bear]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VPNFilter]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[WatchGuard]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59305</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) says it has disrupted a giant botnet built and operated by a Russian government intelligence unit known for launching destructive cyberattacks against energy infrastructure in the United States and Ukraine. Separately, law enforcement agencies in the U.S. and Germany moved to decapitate "Hydra," a billion-dollar Russian darknet drug bazaar that also helped to launder the profits of multiple Russian ransomware groups.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation</strong> (FBI) says it has disrupted a giant botnet built and operated by a Russian government intelligence unit known for launching destructive cyberattacks against energy infrastructure in the United States and Ukraine. Separately, law enforcement agencies in the U.S. and Germany moved to decapitate &#8220;<strong>Hydra</strong>,&#8221; a billion-dollar Russian darknet drug bazaar that also helped to launder the profits of multiple Russian ransomware groups.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59311" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/botclops.png" alt="" width="505" height="446" /></p>
<p>FBI officials <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/pressrel/press-releases/director-christopher-wray-announces-actions-to-disrupt-and-prosecute-russian-criminal-activity-040622" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> Wednesday they disrupted &#8220;<strong>Cyclops Blink</strong>,&#8221; a collection of compromised networking devices managed by hackers working with the Russian Federation&#8217;s <strong>Main Intelligence Directorate</strong> (GRU).</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-court-authorized-disruption-botnet-controlled-russian-federation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> (DOJ) says the GRU&#8217;s hackers built Cyclops Blink by exploiting previously undocumented security weaknesses in firewalls and routers made by both <strong>ASUS</strong> and <strong>WatchGuard Technologies</strong>. The DOJ said it did not seek to disinfect compromised devices; instead, it obtained court orders to remove the Cyclops Blink malware from its &#8220;command and control&#8221; servers &#8212; the hidden machines that allowed the attackers to orchestrate the activities of the botnet.</p>
<p>The FBI and other agencies <a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/news/joint-advisory-shows-new-sandworm-malware-cyclops-blink-replaces-vpnfilter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned in March</a> that the Cyclops Blink malware was built to replace a threat called &#8220;<strong>VPNFilter</strong>,&#8221; an earlier malware platform that targeted <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/05/fbi-kindly-reboot-your-router-now-please/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vulnerabilities in a number of consumer-grade wireless and wired routers</a>. In May 2018, the FBI executed a similar strategy to dismantle VPNFilter, which had spread to more than a half-million consumer devices.</p>
<p>On April 1, ASUS <a href="https://www.asus.com/content/ASUS-Product-Security-Advisory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released updates</a> to fix the security vulnerability in a range of its Wi-Fi routers. Meanwhile, WatchGuard appears to have <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/04/watchguard-failed-to-disclose-critical-flaw-exploited-by-russian-hackers/?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_brand=ars&amp;utm_medium=social" target="_blank" rel="noopener">silently fixed its vulnerability in an update shipped almost a year ago</a>, according to <strong>Dan Goodin</strong> at <em>Ars Technica.</em><span id="more-59305"></span></p>
<h2>SANDWORM AND TRITON</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-36655" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/networktechnicians.png" alt="" width="748" height="495" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/networktechnicians.png 1212w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/networktechnicians-580x384.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/networktechnicians-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/networktechnicians-940x622.png 940w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></p>
<p>Security experts say both VPNFilter and Cyclops Blink are the work of a hacking group known as <strong>Sandworm</strong> or <strong>Voodoo Bear</strong>, the same Russian team blamed for disrupting Ukraine&#8217;s electricity in 2015.</p>
<p>Sandworm also has been implicated in the &#8220;<a href="https://collaborate.mitre.org/attackics/index.php/Software/S0001" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Industroyer</a>&#8221; malware attacks on Ukraine&#8217;s power grid in December 2016, as well as the 2016 global malware contagion &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petya_and_NotPetya" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NotPetya,</a>&#8221; which crippled companies worldwide using an exploit believed to have been developed by and then stolen from the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong> (NSA).</p>
<p>The action against Cyclops Blink came just weeks after the Justice Department <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/four-russian-government-employees-charged-two-historical-hacking-campaigns-targeting-critical" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unsealed indictments against four Russian men</a> accused of launching cyberattacks on power utilities in the United States and abroad.</p>
<p>One of the indictments named three officers of Russia&#8217;s <strong>Federal Security Service</strong> (FSB) suspected of being members of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berserk_Bear" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berserk Bear, a.k.a. Dragonfly 2.0, a.k.a. Havex</a>, which has been blamed for targeting electrical utilities and other critical infrastructure worldwide and is widely believed to be working at the behest of the Russian government.</p>
<p>The other indictment named Russians affiliated with a skilled hacking group known as <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2022/03/feds-allege-destructive-russian-hackers-targeted-us-oil-refineries/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;Triton&#8221; or &#8220;Trisis,&#8221;</a> which infected a Saudi oil refinery with destructive malware in 2017, and then attempted to do the same to U.S. energy facilities.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said that in Dragonfly&#8217;s first stage between 2012 and 2014, the defendants hacked into computer networks of industrial control systems (ICS) companies and software providers, and then hid malware inside legitimate software updates for such systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;After unsuspecting customers downloaded Havex-infected updates, the conspirators would use the malware to, among other things, create backdoors into infected systems and scan victims’ networks for additional ICS/SCADA devices,&#8221; the DOJ said. &#8220;Through these and other efforts, including spearphishing and “watering hole” attacks, the conspirators installed malware on more than 17,000 unique devices in the United States and abroad, including ICS/SCADA controllers used by power and energy companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>In Dragonfly&#8217;s second iteration between 2014 and 2017, the hacking group spear-phished more than 3,300 people at more than 500 U.S. and international companies and entities, including U.S. federal agencies like the <strong>Nuclear Regulatory Commission</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;In some cases, the spearphishing attacks were successful, including in the compromise of the business network (i.e., involving computers not directly connected to ICS/SCADA equipment) of the <strong>Wolf Creek Nuclear Operating Corporation</strong> (Wolf Creek) in Burlington, Kansas, which operates a nuclear power plant,&#8221; the DOJ&#8217;s account continues. &#8220;Moreover, after establishing an illegal foothold in a particular network, the conspirators typically used that foothold to penetrate further into the network by obtaining access to other computers and networks at the victim entity.&#8221;</p>
<h2>HYDRA</h2>
<div id="attachment_59309" style="width: 682px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59309" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-59309" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/federationtower.png" alt="" width="672" height="446" /><p id="caption-attachment-59309" class="wp-caption-text">Federation Tower, Moscow. Image: Evgeniy Vasilev.</p></div>
<p>Also this week, German authorities seized the server infrastructure for the Hydra Market, a bustling underground market for illegal narcotics, stolen data and money laundering that&#8217;s been operating since 2015. The <strong>German Federal Criminal Police Office</strong> (BKA) <a href="https://www.bka.de/DE/Presse/Listenseite_Pressemitteilungen/2022/Presse2022/220405_PM_IllegalerDarknetMarktplatz.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> Hydra had roughly 17 million customers, and over 19,000 vendors, with sales amounting to at least 1.23 billion euros in 2020 alone.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0701" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement on the Hydra takedown</a>, the <strong>U.S. Department of Treasury</strong> said blockchain researchers had determined that approximately 86 percent of the illicit Bitcoin received directly by Russian virtual currency exchanges in 2019 came from Hydra.</p>
<p>Treasury sanctioned a number of cryptocurrency wallets associated with Hydra and with a virtual currency exchange called &#8220;<strong>Garantex</strong>,&#8221; which the agency says processed more than $100 million in transactions associated with illicit actors and darknet markets. That amount included roughly $8 million in ransomware proceeds laundered through Hydra on behalf of multiple ransomware groups, including <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ryuk_(ransomware)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ryuk</a> and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/conti/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Conti</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today’s action against Hydra and Garantex builds upon recent sanctions against virtual currency exchanges SUEX and CHATEX, both of which, like Garantex, operated out of Federation Tower in Moscow, Russia,&#8221; the Treasury Department said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/actions-target-russian-govt-botnet-hydra-dark-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Original APT: Advanced Persistent Teenagers</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/the-original-apt-advanced-persistent-teenagers/</link>
      <comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/the-original-apt-advanced-persistent-teenagers/#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 17:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Advanced Persistent Teenagers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Amit Yoran]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[APT]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[LAPSUS$]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tenable]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Twitter hack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[vishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[voice phishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=59085</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Many organizations are already struggling to combat cybersecurity threats from ransomware purveyors and state-sponsored hacking groups, both of which tend to take days or weeks to pivot from an opportunistic malware infection to a full blown data breach. But few organizations have a playbook for responding to the kinds of virtual "smash and grab" attacks we've seen recently from LAPSUS$, a juvenile data extortion group whose short-lived, low-tech and remarkably effective tactics are putting some of the world's biggest corporations on edge.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many organizations are already struggling to combat cybersecurity threats from ransomware purveyors and state-sponsored hacking groups, both of which tend to take days or weeks to pivot from an opportunistic malware infection to a full blown data breach. But few organizations have a playbook for responding to the kinds of virtual &#8220;smash and grab&#8221; attacks we&#8217;ve seen recently from <strong>LAPSUS$,</strong> a juvenile data extortion group whose short-lived, low-tech and remarkably effective tactics have put some of the world&#8217;s biggest corporations on edge.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59260" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/apt.png" alt="" width="753" height="501" /></p>
<p>Since surfacing in late 2021, LAPSUS$ has <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/a-closer-look-at-the-lapsus-data-extortion-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gained access to the networks or contractors</a> for some of the world&#8217;s largest technology companies, including <strong>Microsoft</strong>, <strong>NVIDIA</strong>, <strong>Okta</strong> and <strong>Samsung</strong>. LAPSUS$ typically threatens to release sensitive data unless paid a ransom, but with most victims the hackers ended up publishing any information they stole (mainly computer source code).</p>
<p>Microsoft <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/03/22/dev-0537-criminal-actor-targeting-organizations-for-data-exfiltration-and-destruction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blogged about its attack</a> at the hands of LAPSUS$, and about the group targeting its customers. It found LAPSUS$ used a variety of old-fashioned techniques that seldom show up in any corporate breach post-mortems, such as:</p>
<p>-targeting employees at their personal email addresses and phone numbers;<br />
-offering to pay $20,000 a week to employees who give up remote access credentials;<br />
-social engineering help desk and customer support employees at targeted companies;<br />
-bribing/tricking employees at mobile phone stores to hijack a target&#8217;s phone number;<br />
-intruding on their victims&#8217; crisis communications calls post-breach.</p>
<p>If these tactics sound like something you might sooner expect from spooky, state-sponsored &#8220;Advanced Persistent Threat&#8221; or <a href="https://www.mandiant.com/resources/apt-groups" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>APT</strong> groups</a>, consider that the core LAPSUS$ members are thought to range in age from 15 to 21. Also, LAPSUS$ operates on a shoestring budget and is <a href="https://twitter.com/BillDemirkapi/status/1508527487655067660" target="_blank" rel="noopener">anything but stealthy</a>: According to Microsoft, LAPSUS$ doesn&#8217;t seem to cover its tracks or hide its activity. In fact, the group often announces its hacks on social media.</p>
<h2>ADVANCED PERSISTENT TEENAGERS</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59264" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/persistence.png" alt="" width="753" height="429" /></p>
<p>This unusual combination makes LAPSUS$ something of an aberration that is probably more aptly referred to as &#8220;<strong>Advanced Persistent Teenagers</strong>,&#8221; said one CXO at a large organization that recently had a run-in with LAPSUS$.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a lot of speculation about how good they are, tactics et cetera, but I think it’s more than that,&#8221; said the CXO, who spoke about the incident on condition of anonymity. &#8220;They put together an approach that industry thought suboptimal and unlikely. So it’s their golden hour.&#8221;</p>
<p>LAPSUS$ seems to have conjured some worst-case scenarios in the minds of many security experts, who worry what will happen when more organized cybercriminal groups start adopting these techniques.</p>
<p>&#8220;LAPSUS$ has shown that with only $25,000, a group of teenagers could get into organizations with mature cybersecurity practices,&#8221; said <strong>Amit Yoran</strong>, CEO of security firm <a href="https://www.tenable.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tenable</a> and a former federal cybersecurity czar, testifying last week before the <strong>House Homeland Security Committee</strong>. &#8220;With much deeper pockets, focus, and mission, targeting critical infrastructure. That should be a sobering, if not terrifying, call to action.&#8221;</p>
<p>My CXO source said LAPSUS$ succeeds because they simply refuse to give up, and just keep trying until someone lets them in.</p>
<p>&#8220;They would just keep jamming a few individuals to get [remote] access, read some onboarding documents, enroll a new 2FA [two-factor authentication method] and exfiltrate code or secrets, like a smash-and-grab,&#8221; the CXO said. &#8220;These guys were not <a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/2333149/are-you-l33t-.html#:~:text=The%20word%20%22l33t%22%20itself%20(,(also%20%22llama%22)." target="_blank" rel="noopener">leet</a>, just damn persistent.&#8221;<span id="more-59085"></span></p>
<h2>HOW DID WE GET HERE?</h2>
<p>The smash-and-grab attacks by LAPSUS$ obscure some of the group&#8217;s less public activities, which according to Microsoft include targeting individual user accounts at cryptocurrency exchanges to drain crypto holdings.</p>
<p>In some ways, the attacks from LAPSUS$ recall the <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=%22twitter+hack%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 2020 intrusion at Twitter</a>, wherein the accounts for Apple, Bill Gates, Jeff Bezos, Kanye West, Uber and others were made to tweet messages inviting the world to participate in a cryptocurrency scam that promised to double any amount sent to specific wallets. The flash scam netted the perpetrators more than $100,000 in the ensuing hours.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-59270" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/bezostweet.png" alt="" width="542" height="532" /></p>
<p>The group of teenagers who hacked Twitter hailed from a community that traded in hacked social media accounts. This community places a special premium on accounts with short &#8220;OG&#8221; usernames, and some of its most successful and notorious members were known to use all of the methods Microsoft attributed to LAPSUS$ in the service of hijacking prized OG accounts.</p>
<p>The Twitter hackers largely pulled it off by brute force, writes <em>Wired</em> on the July 15, 2020 hack.</p>
<p>&#8220;Someone was trying to phish employee credentials, and they were good at it,&#8221; Wired <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/inside-twitter-hack-election-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a>. &#8220;They were calling up consumer service and tech support personnel, instructing them to reset their passwords. Many employees passed the messages onto the security team and went back to business. But a few gullible ones—maybe four, maybe six, maybe eight—were more accommodating. They went to a dummy site controlled by the hackers and entered their credentials in a way that served up their usernames and passwords as well as multifactor authentication codes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Twitter <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/an-update-on-our-security-incident.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> that a key tactic of the group was &#8220;phone spear phishing&#8221; (a.k.a. &#8220;voice phishing&#8221; a.k.a. &#8220;vishing&#8221;). This involved calling up Twitter staffers using false identities, and tricking them into giving up credentials for an internal company tool that let the hackers reset passwords and multi-factor authentication setups for targeted users.</p>
<p>In August 2020, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/08/voice-phishers-targeting-corporate-vpns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned that crooks were using voice phishing</a> to target new hires at major companies, impersonating IT employees and asking them to update their VPN client or log in at a phishing website that mimicked their employer&#8217;s VPN login page.</p>
<p>Two days after that story ran, the <strong>FBI</strong> and the <strong>Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA) <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/08/fbi-cisa-echo-warnings-on-vishing-threat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">issued their own warning on vishing</a>, saying the attackers typically compiled dossiers on employees at specific companies by mass-scraping public profiles on social media platforms, recruiter and marketing tools, publicly available background check services, and open-source research. The joint FBI/CISA alert continued:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Actors first began using unattributed Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) numbers to call targeted employees on their personal cellphones, and later began incorporating spoofed numbers of other offices and employees in the victim company. The actors used social engineering techniques and, in some cases, posed as members of the victim company’s IT help desk, using their knowledge of the employee’s personally identifiable information—including name, position, duration at company, and home address—to gain the trust of the targeted employee.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The actors then convinced the targeted employee that a new VPN link would be sent and required their login, including any 2FA [2-factor authentication] or OTP [one-time passwords]. The actor logged the information provided by the employee and used it in real-time to gain access to corporate tools using the employee’s account.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Like LAPSUS$, these vishers just kept up their social engineering attacks until they succeeded. As KrebsOnSecurity wrote about the vishers back in 2020:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It matters little to the attackers if the first few social engineering attempts fail. Most targeted employees are working from home or can be reached on a mobile device. If at first the attackers don’t succeed, they simply try again with a different employee.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And with each passing attempt, the phishers can glean important details from employees about the target’s operations, such as company-specific lingo used to describe its various online assets, or its corporate hierarchy.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Thus, each unsuccessful attempt actually teaches the fraudsters how to refine their social engineering approach with the next mark within the targeted organization.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>SMASH &amp; GRAB</h2>
<p>The primary danger with smash-and-grab groups like LAPSUS$ is not just their persistence but their ability to extract the maximum amount of sensitive information from their victims using compromised user accounts that typically have a short lifespan. After all, in many attacks, the stolen credentials are useful only so long as the impersonated employee isn&#8217;t also trying to use them.</p>
<p>This dynamic puts tremendous pressure on cyber incident response teams, which suddenly are faced with insiders who are trying frantically to steal everything of perceived value within a short window of time. On top of that, LAPSUS$ has a habit of posting screenshots on social media touting its access to internal corporate tools. These images and claims quickly go viral and create a public relations nightmare for the victim organization.</p>
<p>Single sign-on provider <strong>Okta</strong> experienced this firsthand last month, when LAPSUS$ posted screenshots that appeared to show Okta&#8217;s Slack channels and another with a Cloudflare interface. Cloudflare <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/cloudflare-investigation-of-the-january-2022-okta-compromise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">responded</a> by resetting its employees&#8217; Okta credentials.</p>
<p>Okta quickly <a href="https://threatpost.com/lapsus-data-kidnappers-claim-snatches-from-microsoft-okta/179041/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">came under fire</a> for posting only a brief statement that said the screenshots LAPSUS$ shared were connected to a January 2022 incident involving the compromise of &#8220;a third-party customer support engineer working for one of our subprocessors,&#8221; and that &#8220;the matter was investigated and contained by the subprocessor.&#8221;</p>
<p>This assurance apparently did not sit well with many Okta customers, especially after LAPSUS$ began <a href="https://twitter.com/BillDemirkapi/status/1506339927935569928" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posting statements that disputed some of Okta&#8217;s claims</a>. On March 25, Okta <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2022/03/25/okta-on-handling-of-lapsus-breach-we-made-a-mistake/#:~:text=Okta%20has%20released%20an%20apology,impacted%20hundreds%20of%20its%20customers." target="_blank" rel="noopener">issued an apology</a> for its handling of the January breach at a third-party support provider, which ultimately affected hundreds of its customers.</p>
<p>My CXO source said the lesson from LAPSUS$ is that even short-lived intrusions can have a long-term negative impact on victim organizations &#8212; especially when victims are not immediately forthcoming about the details of a security incident that affects customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It does force us to think about insider access differently,&#8221; the CXO told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;Nation states have typically wanted longer, more strategic access; ransomware groups want large lateral movement. LAPSUS$ doesn&#8217;t care, it’s more about, &#8216;What can these 2-3 accounts get me in the next 6 hours?&#8217; We haven’t optimized to defend that.&#8221;</p>
<p>Any organizations wondering what they can do to harden their systems against attacks from groups like LAPSUS$ should consult <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/03/22/dev-0537-criminal-actor-targeting-organizations-for-data-exfiltration-and-destruction/#Detections" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft&#8217;s recent blog post on the group&#8217;s activities, tactics and tools</a>. Microsoft&#8217;s guidance includes recommendations that can help prevent account takeovers or at least mitigate the impact from stolen employee credentials.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/the-original-apt-advanced-persistent-teenagers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 255/255 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached (User agent is rejected) 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2022-05-03 19:57:25 by W3 Total Cache
-->