<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Security - Cisco Blogs</title>
    <atom:link href="https://blogs.cisco.com/security/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://blogs.cisco.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 14:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2020/03/8c630e69-cropped-b44a9049-cropped-screen-shot-2019-11-08-at-12.24.33-pm-32x32.png</url>
      <title>Security - Cisco Blogs</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Targeted Attacks on Public Cloud Services with Cisco Secure Cloud Analytics</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/detecting-targeted-attacks-on-public-cloud-services-with-cisco-secure-cloud-analytics</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/detecting-targeted-attacks-on-public-cloud-services-with-cisco-secure-cloud-analytics#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Harris]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 14:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[network security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Secure Cloud Analytics]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=399298</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Secure Analytics Targeted Attack Denonia AWS Lambda Detection Security]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Public Cloud and Security Responsibility</p>
<p>Across many businesses, leveraging services offered and hosted by public cloud providers such as AWS proves to be extremely advantageous for both improving operational efficiencies, cost savings, scaling, and for security.</p>
<p>For AWS customers, Lambda functions are a great example of this advantage in providing a useful way to execute only the code you need to execute when you need to execute it, saving businesses money on hosting costs and reducing operational overhead.  This allows customers to scale to their needs and only pay for what they need to run their tasks and applications that drive their business.</p>
<p>Another business benefit is with security.  The infrastructure security for running these services is covered by the cloud provider, which means less overhead and worry for the business using these services.  However, this does not mean customers of public cloud providers have zero security responsibility.  Per the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/shared-responsibility-model/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared responsibility model</a> from AWS, customers are still responsible for security <em>in the cloud</em>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Enter Denonia</span></h2>
<p>Denonia is a cryptocurrency mining software that is specifically designed to run on AWS Lambda, recently discovered by Cado Security on April 6th, 2022. It is likely that Denonia has been running prior to this date, so adjust your investigations accordingly.</p>
<p>According to Cado, the software could be delivered by leveraging DNS over HTTPS to avoid detection at the network access layer and using compromised credentials to execute the software designed for Lambda environments.</p>
<p>In the case of this software targeting AWS Lambda, customers are responsible for securing the functions themselves including who and what has access, network connections, and securing the code that runs on the functions.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Analyzing Denonia</span></h2>
<p>Our research team at Cisco Talos tested the Denonia package using a Lambda Function in our lab. Upon executing we monitored AWS CloudWatch Logs and behavior in Secure Cloud Analytics, we noticed several interesting insights about how it functions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Several console log messages that resembled HTTP GET requests were logged to various domains with spoofed user agents including that of the Baidu web spider, Archive.org bot, and Android 4.1.2 browser.</li>
<li>Running the strings command on the malware binary shows that these system log messages are hard coded in the binary, including the HTTP response codes, and are apparently printed to the console upon execution.</li>
<li>We found console log messages printed by XMRig, an example of which would be time=&#8221;2022-04-13T16:20:44Z&#8221; level=info msg=&#8221;User [14.705882], System [0.000000], Idle [85.294118]&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcghchgchg-300x27.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcghchgchg-768x68.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' class="aligncenter wp-image-399301 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcghchgchg-768x68.png"   alt="" width="640" height="57" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Once we updated the Lambda to use a VPC in our test lab, the function exited with status 1, and the logs showed an error &#8220;panic: doh: all query failed&#8221;. This potentially indicates that DNS over HTTPS was not supported either by the Lambda or the VPC.</li>
<li>We found similar results to above when tested on EC2 with root privileges and using lamb-ci’s Docker Lambda project to run the Lambda environment locally in Docker containers, Denonia was successfully executed.</li>
</ul>
<p>So far, there have not been any known successful deployments, but they key takeaway is attackers are targeting specific resources from cloud providers and becoming increasing sophisticated in the public cloud, so this just may be the start of targeted attacks on serverless functions and other public cloud services</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Continuous Monitoring and Threat Detection in the Public Cloud using Cisco Secure Cloud Analytics</span></h2>
<p>Cisco Secure Cloud Analytics is a SaaS based security product that provides broad visibility and detection within public cloud services across AWS, Azure, and GCP leveraging APIs and logs from the providers, all without deployment of agents.</p>
<p>When looking at Denonia as a potential attack targeting services and applications running in the public cloud, Secure Cloud Analytics provides a wide array of detection capabilities to see an attack at many stages of its lifecycle.</p>
<p>Working with our research team at Cisco Talos, we have identified several methods for detecting Denonia and attacks like it in the public cloud using Secure Cloud Analytics.</p>
<p>With Secure Cloud Analytics deep ability to baseline normal behavior, behavior seen by Denonia or other software or malware that triggers an unusually large number of Lambda functions will trigger the alert “AWS Lambda Invocation Spike” due to the typically short default timeouts of a Lambda function and the need for many of those resources to leverage the functions to execute the attack and leverage the resources for the goal.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcgfcgfcfg-300x25.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcgfcgfcfg-768x64.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399381 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcgfcgfcfg-768x64.png"   alt="" width="640" height="53" /></p>
<p>Additionally, if devices connect with a known bad domain or IP from Denonia, Secure Cloud Analytics will trigger a ““Talos Intelligence Watchlist Hits” alert which indicates a device on the network communicated with a known bad domain or IP from Cisco Talos.  Domain or IP matching is not always guaranteed in cases like Denonia where DNS over HTTPS is used, therefore it’s important to look at malicious behavior in conjunction with known IOCs for complete visibility and detection capability.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/gvhgvghvg-300x25.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/gvhgvghvg-768x64.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399382 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/gvhgvghvg-768x64.png"   alt="" width="640" height="53" /></p>
<p>Domains:</p>
<ul>
<li class="p1">denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">ctrl.denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">gw.denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">1.gw.denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">www.denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">xyz.denonia[.]xyz</li>
<li class="p1">mlcpugw.denonia[.]xyz</li>
</ul>
<p>IP Addresses:</p>
<ul>
<li class="p1">116.203.4[.]0</li>
<li class="p1">162.55.241[.]99</li>
<li class="p1">148.251.77[.]55</li>
</ul>
<p>Further our researchers indicated other common attacker techniques may be seen with the rich behavioral visibility of Secure Cloud Analytics in the public cloud that may be correlated with the above finding for Denonia or other like threats.</p>
<p>“New AWS Region” alert which can be used to detect defense evasion targeting unused regions.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fwdfsdfqwgw-300x24.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fwdfsdfqwgw-768x62.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399383 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fwdfsdfqwgw-768x62.png"   alt="" width="640" height="52" /></p>
<p>“Geographically Unusual AWS API Usage” alert which can highlight initial access through valid identity and access management accounts.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/sdfsgsfger-300x28.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/sdfsgsfger-768x72.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399385 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/sdfsgsfger-768x72.png"   alt="" width="640" height="60" /></p>
<p>“AWS Mulifactor Authentication Change” alert which can identify disabling MFA.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/efewfwer-300x26.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/efewfwer-768x66.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-399388 size-medium_large aligncenter" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/efewfwer-768x66.png"   alt="" width="640" height="55" /></p>
<p>“AWS Temporary Token Persistence” alert which identifies temporary tokens created by other temporary credentials.</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcfgcgfg-300x40.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcfgcgfg-768x102.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399390 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/fcfgcgfg-768x102.png"   alt="" width="640" height="85" /></p>
<p>Although the above alerts are specific to AWS, we have expanded our coverage to other common cloud providers such as Azure and GCP as customer utilization has grown for similar detection outcomes.</p>
<p>In addition to public cloud specific detection, Secure Cloud Analytics offers a wide range of threat detection across an organization&#8217;s private network, all within a single pane of glass.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Protect Your Public Cloud Today</span></h2>
<p>To learn more, go to <a href="https://www.cisco.com/go/secure-cloud-analytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.cisco.com/go/secure-cloud-analytics</a> and start a free risk free 60 day trial.</p>
<p>For more up to date threat information, follow the <a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cisco Talos blog</a>, including other recent threats targeting the public cloud by <a href="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/2022/04/teamtnt-targeting-aws-alibaba.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TeamTNT</a>.</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/shared-responsibility-model/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/shared-responsibility-model/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.cadosecurity.com/cado-discovers-denonia-the-first-malware-specifically-targeting-lambda/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.cadosecurity.com/cado-discovers-denonia-the-first-malware-specifically-targeting-lambda/</a></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/detecting-targeted-attacks-on-public-cloud-services-with-cisco-secure-cloud-analytics/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISE business value and ROI uncovered in Forrester study</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/ise-business-value-and-roi-uncovered-in-forrester-study</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/ise-business-value-and-roi-uncovered-in-forrester-study#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Burdette]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 06:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NAC]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Network Access Control]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[network segmentation]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SD-Access]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[secure network access]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=399291</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Looking to deploy ISE? Forrester conducted a study to uncover the business value and ROI of Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) and revealed a 191% return.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.forrester.com/marketing/about/about-us.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Forrester Consulting</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> recently conducted an independent analysis of five organizations using Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE), the industry-leading network access control solution, to uncover the business value of ISE. The commissioned study conducted by Forrester Consulting on behalf of Cisco, “The Total Economic Impact<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> of Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE),” published in March 2022, highlighted a total payback period of only 11 months within a composite organization that was built from data compiled across the participants in the research. The study showed that the composite organization received a 191% ROI over the first three years use of use, with a current returned value of $1.03 million across many categories, including:</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<ul>
<li data-leveltext="" data-font="Symbol" data-listid="2" aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-posinset="1" data-aria-level="1"><b><span data-contrast="auto">Improved security</span></b><span data-contrast="auto"> impact from breaches: 44% of total </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></li>
<li data-leveltext="" data-font="Symbol" data-listid="2" aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-posinset="2" data-aria-level="1"><b><span data-contrast="auto">Reduced IT costs</span></b><span data-contrast="auto"> with automation: 33% of total </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></li>
<li data-leveltext="" data-font="Symbol" data-listid="2" aria-setsize="-1" data-aria-posinset="3" data-aria-level="1"><b><span data-contrast="auto">Improved business outcomes</span></b><span data-contrast="auto">, such as employee productivity: 23% of total </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">The research by Forrester into customer utilization and the related business value comes at a time when organizations are looking to gain a more strategic focus on resources amidst unprecedented global uncertainty. In a world where everything is connected and boundaries are blurred, the report highlights how ISE is improving organizational resilience across three areas related to maintaining business continuity and securing network access: improved security, reduced IT costs, and improved business outcomes. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>NAC and security resilience </b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">The Forrester study states that, “Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) is a network access control (NAC) solution that streamlines secure network management and gives users and devices segmented access to corporate resources.” Having the level of visibility and control that ISE supplies has allowed organizations to be resilient and withstand change. One of the five organizations that were studied to compile the singular composite used in determining the final ROI is a media company in Europe with 7000 users. The director interviewed stated that, “The greatest challenge we faced during the pandemic was having 7000 people start working from home the next day. What we had in place was not good enough. We needed to add ISE, and we needed to add Software-Defined Access to handle the changes.” In an ever-changing world, ISE is providing the access controls needed to respond to change with confidence and limit organizational risk. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Improved security </b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">The Forrester study noted that cost savings from improved security were the single greatest factor in the overall 191% return on investment. This was due not only to a reduction in the number of security incidents, which was 50%, but also to the business impact of the staff resources needed to respond to access-related security events, which would have required increasing security personnel by 25%. The study stated that, “Together, these benefits are worth $442,000 over three years. This benefit does not include other potential costs of a breach such as lost revenue, fines, and brand reputation damage because it varies greatly depending on the size and nature of a breach and on company specifics such as industry and size.” </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Reduced IT costs</b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">In addition to improved security, the study by Forrester found that, “Cisco ISE streamlined and automated activities related to network management and user and device access.” This helped IT avoid hiring additional full-time staff and equated to considerable direct savings, 34% of the total ROI. To achieve the same level of value with manual methods, the study noted that the organization would have had to increase staffing by 66%. The study stated, “Contributing factors to the time savings include better automation, less time to diagnose potential problems, fewer user-access help desk tickets, and fewer security false alerts.” </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-05-02-at-11.26.10-PM-2-300x153.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-05-02-at-11.26.10-PM-2-768x391.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399489 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/05/Screen-Shot-2022-05-02-at-11.26.10-PM-2-768x391.png" alt="" width="640" height="326" /></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">“Without ISE, we would be spending a lot more time helping people connect. Now, we can diagnose 90% of the problems in 10 minutes. Doing it the old-school way would have taken a lot more time.” </span><span data-contrast="auto">—</span><span data-contrast="auto">Network engineering services assistant director, higher education organization</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">From the commissioned study conducted by Forrester Consulting on behalf of Cisco, “The Total Economic Impact<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> of Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE),” March 2022</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Improved business outcomes</b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Organizations need to supply fast, secure access to network resources. When they do, end users are more productive, and they can also increase collaboration with customers, partners, and suppliers. Forrester noted in the study that aligning to these business-driven outcomes created $236,000 in value, or 23% of total ROI. Forrester also noted that the increase in innovation and speed can deliver “improved business outcomes such as faster time to market, increased revenues, and higher customer satisfaction.” The value was achieved at scale across the different organizations included in the study. The director at the European media organization said that its “7000 employees were all more productive, which ‛is extremely important because TV productions are on a tight timeline.’” And an enterprise architect at the European higher education organization said it “onboards 45,000 to 55,000 devices per year and that 96% of the time it is a fully self-service and near-instantaneous experience.” ISE is increasing business value for organizations of all sizes and across all industries. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Flexibility and SD-Access</b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Companies are also looking to increase the value of existing solutions. A few of the organizations included in the report have matured their secure network access strategies by layering on Cisco DNA Center to deploy Software-Defined Access (SD-Access). SD-Access brings additional savings through improved policy creation and enforcement. The study cited benefits across all categories, including reducing applicable threats by 40%, reducing business user downtime, and avoiding hiring additional full-time employees. SD-Access, layered onto ISE, completes zero trust within the self-managed infrastructure, adding an additional 88% uplift and boosting a 3-year present value of $906,205. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>ISE: Trusted – Proven – Resilient </b> </span></h2>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Two things have remained constant in a world of uncertainty. The first is that change is constant, and the second is that controlling access to ensure that only trusted users and devices can gain access to trusted network resources is and will remain a top concern as organizations look to be resilient and protect the integrity of their business. Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) has been providing this trusted service with mature technology for over 10 years. The independent review of ISE has quantified this benefit, aligning secure network access to business outcomes and risk reduction. To learn more, </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/products/collateral/security/identity-services-engine/total-economic-impact-ise.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">download and read the entire study</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">ISE social media kit for Forrester TEI study </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Use this go-to-market kit, and study to help move your Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) Network Access Control discussions toward the quantitative benefits and ROI of deploying ISE for secure network access control.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Use this kit and study to help move your Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) network access and control conversations toward a more strategic one focused on zero trust for the self-managed infrastructure, or Workplace.</span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forrester.com/marketing/about/about-us.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Forrester Consulting</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> conducted an analysis of five organizations to uncover the business value and ROI of Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE), the industry-leading network access control solution. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Looking to deploy ISE? Forrester conducted a study to uncover the business value and ROI of Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) and revealed a 191% return. </span><span data-ccp-props="{}"> </span></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/ise-business-value-and-roi-uncovered-in-forrester-study/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The More You Know: Job Searching &amp; Interviewing</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/the-more-you-know-job-searching-interviewing</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/the-more-you-know-job-searching-interviewing#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Kate Schmermund]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Career Advice]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Interviewing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398553</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Recruiters and hiring managers at Cisco and Duo Security share useful tips for those job searching and interviewing in the cybersecurity and tech industries.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the midst of global change and virtual hiring, the landscape of job searching has changed. We sat down (via WebEx) with recruiting leaders, accessibility experts and career changers at Cisco Secure and Duo Security to find out the<strong> top 10 ways to make the virtual job search, application and interview process as easeful as possible. </strong>Stay tuned for future topics in this series including advice for career changers and environmental aspects to consider for long-term fulfillment at work.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">1. Keep up with career pages and other career posting sites.</span></strong></h2>
<p><strong>Cisco Secure Talent Acquisition Lead Jeff Edwards</strong> says, “Check the <a href="https://jobs.cisco.com/jobs/SearchJobs/?source=Cisco+Jobs+Career+Site&amp;tags=CDC+Browse+all+jobs+careers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cisco.com careers page</a> consistently, because new roles are opening up daily. Cisco’s always hiring and looking for strong talent. We fill the roles quickly, so don&#8217;t get discouraged if you aren&#8217;t considered for the first role you apply to.”</p>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcfctctddyt-300x169.jpg 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcfctctddyt-768x433.jpg 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-398993 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/gcfctctddyt-768x433.jpg"   alt="" width="640" height="361" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dice.com/company/CXCISCO" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dice</a>, <a href="https://www.indeed.com/cmp/Cisco" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indeed</a>, <a href="https://hired.com/company/cisco" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hired</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/cisco/jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn</a>, <a href="https://builtin.com/company/duo-security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Built In</a>, and <a href="https://www.themuse.com/profiles/duosecurity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Muse</a> are other go-to sources for jobs at Cisco Secure and Duo. “Follow companies on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/duo-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn</a>, and look at the jobs they’ve posted. You may learn more details about the kind of work they&#8217;re doing and what they&#8217;re striving for,” shares <strong>Duo Security Lead Recruiter Shannon Curran</strong>.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">2. Consider a company’s evolution.</span></strong></h2>
<p>Articles, interviews with company leaders, and acquisition history offer “a good snapshot of how a company’s evolved over time and what it’s trying to accomplish going forward. For example when Cisco got started, it was highly focused on hardware. Now we’re wanting to be the top security company in the world,” reports Edwards.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">3. Understand what the company is looking for.</span></strong></h2>
<p>By reviewing multiple job posts, you can get a better understanding of the skills and qualities the company values most in candidates. <strong>Kelly Davenport, manager of the Global Knowledge and Communities team</strong>, “look(s) for folks who are curious, love to learn, like to ask questions, and understand our customer-centered mission where we’re accountable to the people who we provide this service to and we want to do right by them.”</p>
<p>Conversely, in security and engineering, Edwards explains, “We want strategic thinkers who can work independently and collaboratively. We’re looking for candidates who have a passion for the next generation of cutting-edge products for our customers. We’re focusing on many different skill sets, from DevOps to site reliability engineers, product managers, program managers, software developers, UI and UX developers, and engineers with skill sets like Java, AWS, Golang, Python, etc.”</p>
<p>Curran adds, <strong>“A candidate may not have all of the check marks of experience and skills, but if they worked on some of the areas that we are looking for and are </strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>kinder than necessary </strong></span><strong>when we talk to them, we share that with our hiring managers.” </strong></p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">4. Update your resume and showcase your relevant skills.</span></strong></h2>
<p>To develop an impactful resume, Edwards suggests: “<strong>Highlight your skills and experience as they relate to the role you’re interviewing for.</strong> So if you’re interviewing for a back end or front end Java developer role, call out all the different programs that you’re working on or the things you’re doing, or the level of development that you’re involved with from a project standpoint. That allows a hiring manager to really focus in on, ‘Well, you&#8217;re doing this and we definitely work on that program quite a bit. Can you give me your level of expertise, your comfort level, how hands-on you are with that specific program?’”</p>
<p>When reviewing a resume, Curran considers, “Do they have other relevant skills that can be applied to other roles that we’re recruiting for? As a recruiter, you may be working to fill 10 to 12 roles, and they may not all be the same. So we keep in mind if they’re not a match for this role, where else might they be a match. If we don&#8217;t have a role, could we share their profile with other recruiters on the team to see if they have a match?”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">5. Connect with recruiters on LinkedIn.</span></strong></h2>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/ergewrgerg-300x169.jpg 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/ergewrgerg-768x433.jpg 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-398994 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/ergewrgerg-768x433.jpg"   alt="" width="640" height="361" /></p>
<p>When reaching out to recruiters on LinkedIn, Curran advises to say something along the lines of, “Hey, I’d like to connect. I’m a software engineer. I’ve worked in these technologies and would like to see if there’s anything you have that may be relevant with my background,” or, “Hey, I’ve looked at the job site. I thought this job was interesting, and I’ve applied to it. Is there any way that you would be open to speaking with me or can share more details about the role, or connect me with somebody that may be able to help?”</p>
<p>Edwards shares, “<strong>I love proactive candidates who know what they want. The key is, send your resume or your LinkedIn profile with that initial message, because that allows us as recruiters to immediately provide feedback.</strong> Like, ‘Hey, thanks so much, I don&#8217;t think this is the right role for you, but let me forward you to a couple of my colleagues who have roles that I think you’d be a great fit for.’ It allows us to collaborate faster and shows that you&#8217;ve done your research and know what you want and you&#8217;re interested in this company, this role, and working on these types of products.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">6. Learn about accessibility resources during and beyond the interview process.</span></strong></h2>
<p><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/sdvdwfrw-300x169.jpg 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/sdvdwfrw-768x433.jpg 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-398995 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/sdvdwfrw-768x433.jpg"   alt="" width="640" height="361" /></p>
<p><strong>Julie Kramer, a Marketing Specialist</strong> focused on employee experience and accessibility, states, “Review the company’s site to see if they have a statement about accommodations, disability, and what they include for the environment. Find a place that meets your interest, education, and experience. <strong>Review the company policies when it comes to inclusion and demand the best fit for yourself.</strong> Cisco has been accommodating, providing whatever we&#8217;ve needed including closed captioning and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b3hYODBg53c" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign language interpreters</a>.”</p>
<p>In terms of accessibility while interviewing, discuss any accommodation requests with your recruiter or point of contact. Kramer says, “Be yourself. <strong>Don’t be afraid to ask for the accommodations that you need, including during the interviewing process.</strong> Just let them know that you do need accommodations and what your specific needs are. Human Resources have to provide that because in the United States we have the Americans with Disabilities Act. In other countries, candidates need to make sure that they provide what their language needs are as far as an interpreter, for example.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">7. Know what to expect in the interview process.</span></strong></h2>
<p>Curran describes a potential interview on the Duo side of things: “As a recruiter, we prep candidates on what to expect for an interview. For example, they may speak with a recruiter and then we’ll communicate with the hiring manager, and if they’re interested, the candidate will have a phone interview with the hiring manager. If it’s on the engineering side and that goes well, then they’ll have a technical interview. They would be given a programming language of their choice. There’s no right or wrong answer, we just like to see the solution that they come up with.”</p>
<p>In terms of the Product team, “First, they’ll have a phone interview with the hiring manager. Then if there’s interest, there’s a case study which they would review and then discuss as part of the next interview steps. We do our best to explain the interview process so that candidates know what to expect in terms of how long the interviews might last and who they may be speaking with.”</p>
<p>Edwards describes the process at Cisco: “<strong>We’ve gotten pretty good at operating a virtual interviewing process. It doesn’t hurt that we own all these collaborative tools like WebEx Teams.</strong> Depending on the role, the interview process and the number of interviews can vary. Typically there’s a recruiter screen first, then a conversation with the hiring manager for what we would call a first-round interview. If the hiring manager wants to move the candidate forward, a second round usually consists of two to four interviews, and a couple of those could be technical interviews where there could be a panel.”</p>
<p>With some of the technical roles, Edwards shares, “There can be live coding challenges using virtual whiteboards where we can bounce stuff back and forth and really gauge the knowledge. The rest of the two to four interviews might be more behaviorally based. Typically, on the average, it would be three to five interviews total plus a recruiter screen in the beginning. We try to stay in constant communication with the candidates throughout the interview process, whether through email, calls or texts. Candidates are interviewing us just as much as we&#8217;re interviewing them to see if this is the right place.”</p>
<p>Edwards explains further, “<strong>We&#8217;re striving for interview standardization as it brings out objectivity and equality to our process.</strong> We have a certified interviewer training that all of our interviewers go through before they can interview candidates.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">8. Be Prepared, Especially Virtually.</span></strong></h2>
<p>To ensure a smooth virtual interview, Edwards advises, “Make sure to download WebEx or other tools way ahead of time so when it comes time for your interview, it’s an easy, quick login. Test the systems beforehand and make sure your mics are working so that you can be heard clearly. If your computer speakers are bad, call in.”</p>
<p>Many in-person interview guidelines apply for virtual interviews. Edwards says, “Be there early. Promptness is important in interviews.” In terms of dress, for Cisco interviews Edwards recommends business casual: “You don&#8217;t need to wear a suit, but don&#8217;t show up in a T-shirt either. It’s a California company, we&#8217;re pretty laid-back, you don’t need to get dressed to the nines, just look presentable. Bring a list of questions for the interviewer, as well as examples of projects or experiences in your current or past roles that highlight the impact that you’ve made.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">9. Don’t be afraid to own your accomplishments or interview for multiple roles.</span></strong></h2>
<p>Edwards elaborates, “You can say, ‘Well, <em>we</em> did this and <em>we</em> did that,’ but that’s not what the hiring manager’s looking for in an interview. <strong>A hiring manager wants to know what <em>you</em> did. This is the time where you get a pass to brag on yourself.</strong> Talk about the ‘I.’ ‘What did I do?’ ‘I did this, I was involved in that, I managed that project.’ If you keep saying ‘we,’ the hiring manager can’t discern how involved you were.”</p>
<p>While it may not be the case at other companies, Edwards shares that “Cisco is very supportive of candidates interviewing for multiple roles at the same time. Just let your recruiters know so we can coordinate behind the scenes. We&#8217;re all one big team. We all want to bring great talent into Cisco and I don&#8217;t care if the recruiter over there gets the offer, or if I get the offer, we&#8217;re not measured that way. We don&#8217;t get paid commissions. <strong>We do this because we love the job, we love helping people advance their careers and change their lives</strong>. Keep us in the loop, it’s encouraged here at Cisco to interview for more than one role, apply to more than one role and stay in touch with those recruiters if they don’t work out, because most likely they’re going to have those roles open back up again.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">10. When approaching behavioral and technical Interviews, it’s all about S-A-R.</span></strong></h2>
<p>If behavioral interviews are part of the interview process, to prepare, Edwards suggests, “Start thinking about different projects and experiences you&#8217;ve had and look at it from the angle of <strong>S-A-R: Situation, Action steps and Results</strong>. And once again, focus on the ‘I.’” — what you specifically did, or how you specifically made an impact.</p>
<p>A question could be, “‘Tell me about a time when you had a project or deadline and a difficult obstacle to overcome to meet that deadline.’ You want to describe the situation, then describe the action steps that you took to overcome that obstacle to meet that deadline. And then, what was the end result? If you can remember S-A-R and think through that with different projects as you’re preparing for your interview, even in technical interviews, sometimes those examples of the projects and that S-A-R method can still be beneficial as you’re describing a project before you&#8217;re diving into the actual technical side of things. So it can be very, very beneficial across the board from an interviewing standpoint.”</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Come Build With Us</span></strong></h2>
<p>At Cisco Secure and Duo, we protect our customers so they can pursue their passions. We’re looking for enthusiastic, proactive people who are driven to help others, make the world a better place through technology, and cultivate their career path along the way. If you get a kick out of collaborating with inspiring teammates, creating and supporting products that really make a difference, we want you.</p>
<p><a href="https://jobs.cisco.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Cisco-Secure-General_Role-Promo-Small_02-300x169.gif 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Cisco-Secure-General_Role-Promo-Small_02.gif 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-399068 size-full" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Cisco-Secure-General_Role-Promo-Small_02.gif"   alt="" width="768" height="432" /></a></p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/the-more-you-know-job-searching-interviewing/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Duo Security Completes Australia’s Information Security Registered Assessors Program (IRAP) Assessment</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-duo-security-completes-australias-information-security-registered-assessors-program-irap-assessment</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-duo-security-completes-australias-information-security-registered-assessors-program-irap-assessment#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Morgan Mann]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[security assessment]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398860</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Cisco Duo Security Completes Australia’s Information Security Registered Assessors Program (IRAP) Assessment. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Cyber Security Centre (ACSC) leads its government’s efforts to monitor threats and improve cyber security for individuals and families, small and medium businesses, major organizations and vital infrastructure, and government entities. Keeping watch 24 hours a day, seven days a week, the ACSC is dedicated to helping Australia be the most secure place to thrive and connect online.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>What is IRAP?</strong></span></h2>
<p>There are several programs that the ACSC administers to safeguard the country from cyber incidents. One of particular significance is the <em>Information Security Registered Assessors Program (IRAP)</em>, a program that certifies qualified individuals to perform security assessments against the <em>Information Security Manual (ISM), </em>which is a comprehensive framework for information security requirements that are applied against government systems, cloud services, and cloud service providers. It is noteworthy to mention that  recently announced the completion of this important assessment. <a href="https://duo.com/blog/duo-new-data-centers-australia-singapore-japan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Following a data center expansion to Australia</a> last year, the Duo IRAP assessment came at an opportune time, enabling us to better serve our regulated customers in the country’s various sectors.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>What was the process to complete Duo’s IRAP assessment?</strong> </span></h2>
<p>According to the ACSC on their website, “<em>Cloud computing offers a range of potential cyber security benefits for cloud consumers to leverage, providing access to advanced security technologies, shared responsibilities, fine-grained access management, comprehensive monitoring and highly redundant geographically dispersed cloud services.” </em>To address requirements in the assessment, Duo was evaluated in multiple phases in accordance with the methodology process, which you can see in more detail in the <a href="https://www.cyber.gov.au/acsc/view-all-content/publications/anatomy-cloud-assessment-and-authorisation" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Anatomy of a Cloud Assessment and Authorisation</em></a>.</p>
<p>Upon the successful completion of the IRAP evaluation, a <a href="https://trustportal.cisco.com/c/r/ctp/trust-portal.html?search_keyword=duo#/9230214252266970" target="_blank" rel="noopener">security assessment letter</a> and the <a href="https://trustportal.cisco.com/c/r/ctp/trust-portal.html?search_keyword=duo#/9970104683115361" target="_blank" rel="noopener">assessment report</a> were issued. For your information, both documents are available for you, as well as Cisco customers, to view via the <a href="https://trustportal.cisco.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trust Portal</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>What security classification was Duo assessed for?</strong> </span></h2>
<p>Within IRAP, and under the Australian Government Protective Security Policy Framework, there are four classifications that the ISM defines the applicability of information sensitivity and security. They are: OFFICIAL, PROTECTED, SECRET and TOP SECRET. Duo completed an assessment against the PROTECTED controls.</p>
<p>Given the occurrences of cyber security threats and attacks in our world’s digital ecosystem, it is imperative that countries take steps to safeguard their citizens, businesses, infrastructure and more. We are on a journey to provide secure access, mitigate security risks and empower everyone to safely and confidently connect online. Cisco remains intently committed to complying with governments’ additional security measures and assuring the delivery of a user-friendly zero-trust security platform for all users, all devices and all applications.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-duo-security-completes-australias-information-security-registered-assessors-program-irap-assessment/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvise, Adapt, Overcome: Building Security Resilience in a World of Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/improvise-adapt-overcome-building-security-resilience-in-a-world-of-uncertainty</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/improvise-adapt-overcome-building-security-resilience-in-a-world-of-uncertainty#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Hazel Burton]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security resilience]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security Stories Podcast]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398639</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Which practices have the greatest impact when building security resilience? We asked industry experts to share their success stories.
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For my very first interview for the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/securitystories-archives.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Security Stories podcast</a>, I met a wonderful person called Mick Jenkins, MBE. Mick is sadly no longer with us, but his story will stay with me forever. One of Mick’s philosophies was centred around the importance of cyber resilience. “Improvise, adapt, overcome” are the words he used.</p>
<p>This philosophy helped him when he got lost in the wilderness at age 14. It helped him when he became a bomb disposal expert in the military. It helped him when he took on the CISO role at Brunel University London, at a time when cybersecurity wasn’t embedded into the organization’s culture. Mick was instrumental in leading the organization to proactively defend against targeted attacks on the university’s intellectual property.</p>
<p>Improvise. Adapt. Overcome. I’ve been thinking about those words a lot lately, and what they mean (for me, at least):</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>Improvise.</strong> </span>When I’m going through a tough time, I think about how I can change the story. Make it about something else. Helping others with their ideas. Saying yes to new opportunities. (I’m an improviser by trade too, so it’s always, “Yes, and…”)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>Adapt.</strong></span> Finding stillness in chaos and opportunities in the most unlikely of circumstances.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><strong>Overcome.</strong> </span>Becoming focused. Getting through it, with the support of those around me.</p>
<p>What has become clear, now more than ever, is that our vulnerability and resilience go hand-in-hand. It’s not one or the other. Having both side-by-side is what makes us human.</p>
<p>In these moments, we can feel stronger. We can see chances for change that never rose to the surface before.</p>
<h2><strong>New eBook on Building Security Resilience</strong></h2>
<p>I recently spoke with 13 industry leaders to get their perspectives on the concept of <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html?CCID=cc000160&amp;DTID=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">security resilience</a>, and which practices have the greatest impact on an organization’s ability to adapt to change. How can we structure security, so we can spot opportunities we’ve never seen before?</p>
<p>We featured their stories and advice in a new interactive eBook, called <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html?CCID=cc000160&amp;DTID=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><em>Building Security Resilience: Advice and Stories from Cybersecurity Leaders,</em></strong></a> that we released today.</p>
<p>A few key themes emerged from our contributors:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can’t have a resilient security posture without making people your top priority. Making sure they have everything they need for their role, and not overburdening them.</li>
<li>Use threat intelligence and maintain strong visibility of your assets, so you can prioritize dealing with incidents and vulnerabilities that are the greatest risk to your organization.</li>
<li>Communication is everything. Staying close to the needs of the business and the overall future direction will mean that you’re in a better position to build security resilience that can adapt to change.</li>
<li>There are new opportunities to be had, and new ideas can appear even in the toughest of times. As one of our contributors, Christos Sarris from Sainsbury’s said, “Nonstop business transformation at the time of a crisis is a key strategy for building enterprise resilience.”</li>
</ul>
<p>Do take a look at our new eBook for inspiration on how to build security resilience.</p>
<h2><strong>#CiscoChat on Security Resilience</strong></h2>
<p>I’ve also invited contributors from the eBook to join me for a #CiscoChat live discussion that we’re hosting: <a href="https://video.cisco.com/video/6301077161001?CCID=cc000160&amp;OID=wbrsc029058&amp;DTID=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Detect, Respond, Recover: Moving Toward Security Resilience</a>. We kick things off at 1pm ET/10am PT and hope to see you there.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="//players.brightcove.net/1384193102001/41XYD7gTx_default/index.html?videoId=6301077161001" allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen width="640" height="360"></iframe></p>
<p>I’ll leave the last word to another of our contributors, Christos Syngelakis, CISO and Data Privacy Officer at Motor Oil Group, who will be joining us for the #CiscoChat:</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 40px;">“I want to end by acknowledging that one of the biggest challenges for CISOs is burnout. In an always-on environment where there is always something new to learn, as well as a tremendous expansion of technology and requests for new projects, the challenge of finding balance is one of the top issues. Invest in your people and prioritize their mental health.”</p>
<blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Get more insights like this in our interactive eBook, <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html?CCID=cc000160&amp;DTID=oblgcdc000651">Building Security Resilience</a>.</em></strong></h3>
</blockquote>
<h2>More on Security Resilience</h2>
<p>Find this blog helpful? View our other blogs on <a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/tag/security-resilience">security resilience</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/security/enabling-security-resilience-in-the-face-of-unpredictable-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Enabling Security Resilience in the Face of Unpredictable Change</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/security/the-5-dimensions-of-security-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener">5 Dimensions of security resilience</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/security/continuity-and-recovery-on-the-path-towards-resiliency" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Continuity and recover on the path to resiliency</a></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Learn more about Cisco’s approach to security resilience for your business: </strong></h3>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html">Protect Your Business with Security Resilience</a></strong></h2>
</blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/improvise-adapt-overcome-building-security-resilience-in-a-world-of-uncertainty/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security resilience from the classroom to the cloud</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-from-the-classroom-to-the-cloud</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-from-the-classroom-to-the-cloud#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristina Errico]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cisco Gateway]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cisco SecureX]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cisco Talos]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[network security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security resilience]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398416</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Security resilience is crucial for all organizations. Learn how the Shawnee Heights School District stays cyber safe and ready for the future.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong><i>A conversation with Shawnee Heights School District </i> </strong></h3>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">You have likely heard us talking more about </span><a href="https://blogs.cisco.com/security/the-5-dimensions-of-security-resilience" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">security resilience</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> in recent weeks. Resilience has always been a key part of cybersecurity, but the last few years have really highlighted its importance. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">At Cisco, we define security resilience as: </span><b><span data-contrast="auto">The ability to protect the integrity of every aspect of your business to withstand unpredictable threats or changes, and then emerge stronger. </span></b><span data-contrast="auto">Depending on the business, this will look a bit different for every organization. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">For the </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/case-studies-customer-success-stories/shawnee-heights-securex.html?ccid=cc001528&amp;oid=vorsc028952&amp;dtid=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Shawnee Heights School District in Kansas</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">, it means empowering roughly 3,700 K-12 students with modern education technology including laptops and iPads, while still maintaining the security and integrity of the district’s data and infrastructure. Shawnee Heights has about 5,500 devices on its network every day, three-quarters of which go home with staff and students each night. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">We recently spoke with Shawnee Heights IT Director and Cisco Gateway Cybersecurity Ambassador, </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/blairpanderson/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Blair Anderson</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">, to hear about how the district keeps these educational devices secure as they travel back and forth to unprotected networks. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: How are you able to let so many devices leave your network each day and still feel safe? </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair: </b></span><span data-contrast="auto">With Cisco, we have the security in place to keep our devices secured no matter where they go. I know that when they leave, we still have visibility into what’s happening and the threats they could be bringing into our district. We can remediate the threats before they even hit our network the next day. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: How have recent changes in technology impacted your security? </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair:</b></span><span data-contrast="auto"> Digitalization has had a huge impact on Shawnee Heights. We have moved away from textbooks and deployed devices to all our students. That’s a big change. We’ve also seen a substantial increase in the amount of documents and data going up into the cloud. That creates a need for us to make sure all this information is secure, and that our users don’t get compromised. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: What exactly were you looking for in a security solution? </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair:</b></span><span data-contrast="auto"> Several years ago, we did not have the security in place to keep these devices protected. They were coming back into the district with all kinds of threats, and we had to constantly reimage them. When we started looking at a security architecture, we wanted something that was in the cloud and that could keep our staff and students safe 24/7, 365 days a year.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">We also wanted something that would run in the background. We didn’t want security pop-ups and alerts impacting our users and their day-to-day routine. At the same time, it was crucial for our IT staff to have in-depth visibility into what was happening on each device to easily detect, track, and mitigate attacks. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: How does Cisco help you safeguard the transition to digital learning? </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair:</b></span><span data-contrast="auto"> Through a combination of technologies including </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/products/security/endpoint-security/secure-endpoint/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco Secure Endpoint</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> and </span><a href="https://umbrella.cisco.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco Umbrella</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">, we can see and block attacks from multiple vectors </span>— <span data-contrast="auto">including the internet and email </span>— <span data-contrast="auto">whether a device is on or off the network. Most importantly, it’s all integrated through the </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/products/security/securex-platform/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco SecureX</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> platform, so we get a unified view into our systems and potential risks, and can also automate and accelerate our response. </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/talos.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco Talos</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> is the brains behind it all. We learn so much from Cisco and the resources they make available to us.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: How has Cisco helped you become more cyber resilient? </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair:</b></span><span data-contrast="auto"> Before Cisco, we didn’t know whether malware was on our devices until staff and students brought it to our attention. We didn’t have the insight to be proactive and prevent significant damage. Our staff and students were bogged down with continual security disruptions, and it was very stressful because it took away from what they needed to get done in the classroom.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Now, we know exactly when threats hit our district, and can keep our staff and students safe before they even notice something has happened. Since integrating </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/products/security/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco security products</span></a><span data-contrast="auto">, we haven’t had any major threats affect our staff and students. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">In security, you always have to be thinking about what’s next. Cisco frees up time for our IT staff to focus on higher-level projects that will move us forward from a technology standpoint.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Q: In addition to deploying the right technology, what else can organizations do to be more security resilient?  </b></h2>
<p><span style="color: #6abf4b;"><b>Blair:</b></span><span data-contrast="auto"> Everyone has a role to play in security. My colleagues and I often communicate with staff and students about what we’re seeing and the security we have in place. It’s critical that everyone knows what we’re doing and why, so they can work alongside us to protect themselves, each other, and the district from cyberattacks. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">I am always learning too. Being involved in the </span><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/about/peer-networking-communities/gateway.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span data-contrast="none">Cisco Gateway</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> community has allowed me to gain valuable knowledge to help keep Shawnee Heights cyber resilient </span>— <span data-contrast="auto">while also sharing my experience with others. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Watch the new video for more security insights from Shawnee Heights:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="//players.brightcove.net/1384193102001/41XYD7gTx_default/index.html?videoId=6302876281001" allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen width="640" height="360"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b><i><span data-contrast="auto">Visit our </span></i></b><a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b><i><span data-contrast="none">security resilience page</span></i></b></a><b><i><span data-contrast="auto"> to discover how to defend your business against current and future disruptions. </span></i></b><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-from-the-classroom-to-the-cloud/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Resilience in EMEA</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-in-emea</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-in-emea#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cindy Valladares]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cisco Security Outcomes Report]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security resilience]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398096</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[How do organizations across the EMEA region fare when it comes to security resilience?]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What makes a successful cybersecurity program and how can organizations improve their resilience in a world that seems increasingly unpredictable? How do we know what actually works and what doesn’t in order to maximize success?</p>
<p>These are the types of burning questions guiding Cisco’s <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-outcomes-study-vol-2.html?ccid=cc000160&amp;oid=rptsc027923&amp;dtid=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Security Outcomes Study</a> series. In the second edition of the study, Cisco conducted an independent, double-blind survey of over 5,100 IT professionals in 27 countries. This article highlights data from the latest volume to focus on security resilience in the region spanning Europe, Middle East and Africa (EMEA).</p>
<p>The study focuses on a dozen outcomes that contribute to overall security program success. Four of them in particular are crucial for building resilience:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keeping up with the business <em>(Security should enable, not impede)</em></li>
<li>Avoiding major incidents <em>(&#8230;And their business impacts)</em></li>
<li>Maintaining business continuity <em>(&#8230;Even when disaster strikes)</em></li>
<li>Retaining talented personnel <em>(You can’t stay on top when top staff won’t stay)</em></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Assessing Security Resilience in EMEA</span></strong></h2>
<p>We calculated an overall resilience score for each surveyed organization based on their ratings for the outcomes listed above. The chart below compares that score across the three global regions. Organizations in the Americas scored a scant 1.7% better than the global average, while EMEA organizations landed about 2% below that mark. And the width of the gray error bars further diminishes those differences. Overall, we simply don’t see huge discrepancies in security resilience at the regional level.</p>
<figure id="attachment_398103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398103" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfdsfdsfsd-300x55.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfdsfdsfsd-768x140.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398103 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfdsfdsfsd-768x140.png"   alt="" width="640" height="117" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398103" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Regional comparison of mean security resilience score</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>When examining resilience at the country level, however, differences begin to emerge. </strong>The next chart shows the proportion of organizations in each country reportedly “excelling” in each of the four outcomes related to security resilience. In other words, about 48% of firms in Saudi Arabia say their security program is doing a great job keeping up with the business. About 37% excel at maintaining business continuity, and so on. So, pick your country of interest and trace its success level across each outcome.</p>
<figure id="attachment_398106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398106" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/vbcbcvcvb-300x181.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/vbcbcvcvb-768x462.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398106 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/vbcbcvcvb-768x462.png"   alt="" width="640" height="385" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398106" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Country-level comparison of reported success levels for security resilience outcomes</em></figcaption></figure>
<hr />
<p>Interested in comparing countries in the EMEA region across all 12 security outcomes beyond those shown here for resilience? Download the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/products/collateral/security/2020-outcomes-study-emear-mini-report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EMEA spinoff</a> of the Security Outcomes Study, Volume 1.</p>
<hr />
<p>Perhaps the most interesting aspect of this chart is the comparison it provides among countries. The reported success rates by security professionals in the countries at the top are roughly twice that of those on the bottom. And for the most part, each country maintains its relative position across all outcomes.</p>
<p>The obvious question here is what lies behind these apparent differences in security resilience among countries? Is Saudi Arabia really that much more resilient than Germany? Might German organizations have a more realistic grasp of what it means to be resilient and know there’s a lot of work left to do? Perhaps it’s somewhere between those possibilities or something else altogether.</p>
<p><strong>Whatever the reason, the key takeaway here is that success rates for all countries indicate that organizations aren’t as successful as they’d like to be in the area of security resilience.</strong></p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Improving Security Resilience in EMEA</span></strong></h2>
<p>How can organizations in the EMEA region improve those outcomes, thereby making their firms more resilient? That’s an excellent question and one we were eager to explore in the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-outcomes-study-vol-2.html?ccid=cc000160&amp;oid=rptsc027923&amp;dtid=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Security Outcomes Study</a>. The study revealed five security practices—affectionately referred to as the Fab Five—that boost security program success more than any others. If you’d like a lot more information about the Fab Five and how to maximize their effectiveness, the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/products/collateral/security/security-outcomes-study-vol-2-report.pdf?ccid=cc000160&amp;oid=rptsc027923&amp;dtid=oblgcdc000651">latest edition of the Security Outcomes Study</a> is the place to go.</p>
<figure id="attachment_398107" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398107" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/cfcgcf-300x69.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/cfcgcf-768x177.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398107 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/cfcgcf-768x177.png"   alt="" width="640" height="148" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398107" class="wp-caption-text"><em>The Fab Five: Highly effective practices for achieving security program outcomes</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Before we examine how these practices improve resilience, let’s first check how well each country has implemented each of the Fab Five. The chart below mimics the one above for outcomes and is interpreted similarly. Once again, we see Saudi Arabia reporting the strongest implementation of these practices and Germany reporting the lowest. Countries shift around quite a bit beyond that.</p>
<figure id="attachment_398108" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398108" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dsfssfsd-300x162.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dsfssfsd-768x415.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398108 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dsfssfsd-768x415.png"   alt="" width="640" height="346" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398108" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Country-level comparison of reported success levels for five leading security practices</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>As with the outcomes chart, reasons behind these country-level differences are difficult to pinpoint. We suspect there’s a mix of maturity, cultural, and organizational factors at play. But hey, if you have thoughts, we’d love to hear them. Use #SecurityOutcomes on LinkedIn or Twitter to get our attention.</p>
<p>Remember that security resilience score we shared above for the regions? Great, because it’s coming back into play in this next chart. We wanted to test whether practicing the Fab Five actually improved resilience among EMEA organizations participating in our study. As seen in the chart below, that’s a definitive “Yes!”</p>
<p><strong>Organizations that don’t do any of these practices well ranked in the bottom 25% for resilience, whereas those strong in all five reversed that standing and rose into the top 25%!</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_398109" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398109" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfffsdfsd-300x172.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfffsdfsd-768x440.png 768w' sizes='(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398109 size-medium_large" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/dfffsdfsd-768x440.png"   alt="emea" width="640" height="367" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398109" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Effect of implementing five leading security practices on overall resilience score</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Resilience has always been critical for cybersecurity. However, the last several years have really driven home the point that organizational defenders must be ready for anything. We hope this analysis demonstrates two things: 1) Organizations in the EMEA region have room for improving security resilience, and 2) It is actually possible to do so.</p>
<p>If you’d like more data-driven insights and tips on <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-resilience.html?CCID=cc000160&amp;DTID=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">how to build a more resilient organization</a> in EMEA or anywhere else in the world, please check out the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/security-outcomes-study-vol-2.html?ccid=cc000160&amp;oid=rptsc027923&amp;dtid=oblgcdc000651" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Security Outcomes Study</a> today or join us on April 26<sup>th</sup> when we will be discussing the highlights of the study and what they mean for successful hybrid work strategies. <a href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3614211/C58CF9D4CFDBFF8838D83F0D67090C70?partnerref=CiscoTVSOSUmbrella?CCID=cc001713&amp;DTID=oemzzz000233&amp;OID=evvsc028623" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Register today</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/security-resilience-in-emea/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Secure Endpoint Shines in the 2022 MITRE® Engenuity ATT&amp;CK Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-secure-endpoint-shines-in-the-2022-mitre-engenuity-attck-evaluation</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-secure-endpoint-shines-in-the-2022-mitre-engenuity-attck-evaluation#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Bethea]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Behavioral Protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cisco Secure Endpoint]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MITRE ATT&CK]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Orbital Advanced Search]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sandworm]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Wizard Spider]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=398176</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The 2022 MITRE® Engenuity ATT&#038;CK Evaluation results are in, and Cisco Secure Endpoint proved it can stop Wizard Spider and Sandworm attack campaigns early in the kill chain and provide analytic detections.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently MITRE Engenuity released the results from its fourth round of the ATT&amp;CK Evaluations. This round focused on threat actors Wizard Spider and Sandworm.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no surprise that both hacking groups have made their presence felt. For example, between 2019 and 2020, Wizard Spider, a Russian-speaking cybercriminal group, extorted $61 million from ransomware attacks, including notable attacks that included <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/uhs-hospitals-hit-by-reported-country-wide-ryuk-ransomware-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Universal Healthcare System Hospitals,</a> and state government administrative offices <a href="https://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2019/07/08/Ransom-hackers-hit-Georgia-courts-after-cities-pay-1M/4111562116580/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in both Georgia and Florida</a>. In 2017, Sandworm infiltrated Ukrainian accounting software MeDoc and hijacked the company’s update mechanism which resulted in malicious software being introduced to copies of the MeDoc software used by its customers.</p>
<p>After participating in the 3rd round of MITRE Engenuity Evaluations, Cisco was excited to engage again to show our improvements over last year.</p>
<p><strong>These evaluations are not a competitive analysis. MITRE shows the detections it observed without providing a “winner.” Because there is no singular way for analyzing, ranking, or rating the solutions, MITRE instead shows how each vendor approaches threat defense within the context of ATT&amp;CK.</strong></p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Cisco delivered strong results in the 2022 Evaluation</span></h2>
<p>Overall, Cisco Secure Endpoint proved it can stop Wizard Spider and Sandworm attack campaigns early in the kill chains and provided analytic detections at the MITRE ATT&amp;CK technique level across each step of its respective kill chains.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Summary of Cisco&#8217;s Results:</span></h2>
<table style="width: 70%; margin-left: 15%; margin-right: 15%; border-collapse: collapse; height: 267px;" cellpadding="5;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">
<h3><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Protection Test</span></strong></h3>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">
<h3><strong><u>Detection Test</u></strong></h3>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">Wizard Spider</p>
<ul>
<li>Blocked 5 of 6 Tests</li>
<li>Technique level Detections across all 6 of 6 Tests</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">Wizard Spider</p>
<ul>
<li>Analytic Coverage with Technique level detections across 10 of 10 Steps</li>
<li>Visibility within the first substep in 9 of 10 Steps</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">Sandworm</p>
<ul>
<li>Blocked 2 of 3 Tests</li>
<li>Technique level Detections across all 3 of 3 Tests</li>
</ul>
</td>
<td style="border: 1px solid #000000;">Sandworm</p>
<ul>
<li>Analytic Coverage with Technique level Detections across 9 of 9 Steps</li>
<li>Visibility within the first substep in 8 of 9 Steps</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>What’s important to know:</p>
<ul>
<li>Day 1 and 2 of the MITRE Evaluation were for the Detection Test and Protection tests were conducted on Day 4.</li>
<li>Of the 30 vendors that participated in the evaluation all but eight do not offer a comprehensive solution and did not have a Linux agent.</li>
<li>Of the 30 vendors that participated eight of them did not participate in the protection test.</li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Protection Kill Chains Overlayed with Detections</span></h2>
<figure id="attachment_398191" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398191" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1-300x129.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1-768x331.png 768w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1-1024x442.png 1024w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1.png 1080w' sizes='(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398191" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture1-1.png"   alt="Display of Wizard Spider test results from the 2022 MITRE® Engenuity ATT&amp;CK Evaluation" width="800" height="345" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398191" class="wp-caption-text">Wizard Spider Test Results</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_398192" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-398192" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img srcset='https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1-300x67.png 300w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1-768x171.png 768w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1-1024x228.png 1024w, https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1.png 1080w' sizes='(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px' loading="lazy" class="wp-image-398192" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/blogs-images/ciscoblogs/1/2022/04/Picture2-1.png"   alt="Diagram of Sandworm test results from the 2022 MITRE® Engenuity ATT&amp;CK Evaluation" width="800" height="178" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-398192" class="wp-caption-text">Sandworm Test Results</figcaption></figure>
<p>When it comes to protection, Cisco Secure Endpoint stopped both attack campaigns early in the kill chains and provided analytic detection at the MITRE ATT&amp;CK level across each step of their respective kill chains. With real-time protection and analytics, a security analyst can remediate the threat with a reduced mean time to detection and response. Cisco Secure Endpoint blocked Wizard Spider at the start of the kill chain, however, an Active Directory database dump test was executed in Test 4. It’s important to remember that the protection tests are executed as independent unit tests; in this case it&#8217;s assumed the earlier tests were unsuccessfully blocked.</p>
<p>Cisco Secure Endpoint Analytic Coverage significantly improved in the 2022 Evaluation, allowing us to see the tactic or technique used at a more granular level. Cisco Secure Endpoint’s improved insights on the threat&#8217;s specific technique helped accelerate the mean time to detection and response.</p>
<p>Cisco Secure Endpoint had a significant number of detections at the first substeps of each phase in the Wizard Spider and Sandworm kill chain emulated in the MITRE Evaluation. Alert on potential threat actor activity was immediate quite early in the kill chain, which helped reduce attacker dwell time on the endpoint.</p>
<p>Cisco Secure Endpoint Behavioral Protection again played a critical role in identifying threats. We will continue to expand and develop Behavioral Protection for customers.</p>
<p>Links to Cisco’s MITRE Engenuity ATT&amp;CK results:</p>
<ul>
<li>Scenario 1: <a href="https://attackevals.mitre-engenuity.org/enterprise/participants/cisco?view=results&amp;adversary=wizard-spider-sandworm&amp;scenario=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wizard Spider</a></li>
<li>Scenario 2: <a href="https://attackevals.mitre-engenuity.org/enterprise/participants/cisco/?adversary=wizard-spider-sandworm&amp;scenario=2&amp;view=results" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sandworm</a></li>
<li><a href="https://attackevals.mitre-engenuity.org/enterprise/participants/cisco/?adversary=wizard-spider-sandworm&amp;scenario=protections&amp;view=results" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Protection Test</a></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Cisco Secure Endpoint and MITRE ATT&amp;CK: Why it matters to CISOs right now</span></h2>
<p>Securing your endpoints has never been more critical, and you need endpoint security you can trust. Cisco Secure Endpoint is designed for those seeking endpoint resilience. Meeting security head-on requires adopting a comprehensive cloud-based endpoint protection solution for your <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/products/collateral/security/amp-for-endpoints/esg-wp-evolution-modern-security.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">secure remote worker, SASE, XDR, and Zero Trust architecture</a>. We are the only endpoint security solution to deliver a cloud-native, built-in platform, Cisco SecureX, delivering XDR capabilities and more for better threat visibility, more intelligent investigations, and faster response.</p>
<p>Cisco has been recognized as a leader in endpoint security</p>
<ul>
<li>Strategic Leader in the 2nd annual <a href="https://www.av-comparatives.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/EPR_Comparative_2021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AV-Comparatives EPR testing</a></li>
<li>First Place in Radacti’s 2021 <a href="https://www.radicati.com/?p=17608" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Endpoint Security Market Quadrant</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.av-comparatives.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/avc_biz_2021_12.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Approved Business Product Award</a> by AV-Comparatives</li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="color: #6abf4b;">See it for yourself</span></h2>
<p>We know what you are facing, a world where malware is constantly evolving, and threats are becoming harder and harder to detect. The most advanced and riskiest threats that will eventually enter and wreak havoc in your network could potentially go undetected. Secure Endpoint provides comprehensive protection against any threat. This security software prevents breaches, blocks malware at the point of entry, and continuously monitors and analyzes file and process activity to rapidly detect, contain, and remediate threats that can evade front-line defenses.</p>
<p>To learn more about Cisco Secure Endpoint and see for yourself how it protects you against today’s threats, join our <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/threat-hunting-workshop.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">virtual threat hunting workshop</a> or sign up for a <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/amp-for-endpoints/free-trial.html?utm_medium=web-referral&amp;utm_source=blog&amp;utm_campaign=amp-free-trial&amp;utm_term=pgm&amp;utm_content=amp-free-trial" target="_blank" rel="noopener">free trial</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p class="p1" style="text-align: center;"><i>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</i></p>
<p class="p1" style="text-align: center;"><b>Cisco Secure Social Channels</b></p>
<p class="p1" style="text-align: center;"><b><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a><br />
</b><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="s1"><b>Facebook</b></span></a><b><br />
</b><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="s1"><b>Twitter</b></span></a><b><br />
</b><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="s1"><b>LinkedIn</b></span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/cisco-secure-endpoint-shines-in-the-2022-mitre-engenuity-attck-evaluation/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Router Spring Cleaning – No MOP Required — Again</title>
      <link>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/router-spring-cleaning-no-mop-required-again</link>
      <comments>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/router-spring-cleaning-no-mop-required-again#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Oxman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 16:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[network security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.cisco.com/?p=393569</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[DECNET MOP in Cisco IOS/IOS-XE allows remote login via VTY by default, and ignores much of the configuration in the "line vty" configuration stanzas. 
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="section">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>Way back in May 18, 2010, Dario Ciccarone of The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) published a blog post called <em><strong>Router Spring Cleaning – No MOP Required</strong></em>. It has since been <a href="//blogs.cisco.com/security/router_spring_cleaning_-_no_mop_required/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">archived</a>, but the key points of that blog are captured below:</p>
</div>
</div>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>When looking over the recommendations in the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/ip/access-lists/13608-21.html#anc18">Cisco Guide to Harden Cisco IOS Devices</a>, time and again people are puzzled by this line: “Issue the no mop enabled command in interface configuration mode in order to disable the Maintenance Operation Protocol (MOP) service.”</p>
<p>And they come back to us with questions like, “What is MOP, why do I have to disable it, and is it even relevant if I’m not running DECnet?”</p>
<p>Well, the thing is, the MOP functionality is decoupled from the DECnet protocol stack, so even if your device isn’t configured for DECnet, <strong>you will still be able to establish a MOP RC session to the device, as long as MOP hasn’t been explicitly disabled</strong>.</p>
<p>So, some key points to note from all of this:</p>
<ul>
<li>The MOP protocol (RC and remote load functionality) is still being shipped as part of Cisco IOS 15.x</li>
<li>MOP RC is <strong>enabled by default</strong> on ethernet interfaces (and yes, that includes FastEthernet and GigabitEthernet)</li>
<li>MOP (RC and dump/load) data packets are directly encapsulated on Ethernet L2 frames (Ethertype is 0x6002 for RC)</li>
<li>MOP packets can’t be routed but can be bridged</li>
<li>There is a readily available MOP RC client for Linux</li>
<li>You do have to provide valid credentials for authentication before being allowed interactive access to the device</li>
<li>A <strong>show users</strong> WILL show anyone connected to a Cisco IOS device over a MOP RC session</li>
<li>MOP RC packets are neither encrypted nor authenticated</li>
<li>Removing <strong>transport input mop</strong> from the VTY lines will not disable the MOP RC functionality</li>
</ul>
<p>So, now you’re wondering, “Why is Cisco bring this old stuff back up again?” Well&#8230;</p>
<p>This topic recently came up again in an external forum. I hope this blog will clear up some inconsistencies and outline a clear mitigation path for customers. The contents below pertain to any router or switching platform that is running Cisco IOS Software or Cisco IOS-XE Software.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Identifying MOP on Platforms</span></strong></h2>
<p>Over the years, support for MOP has been completely removed and can’t be enabled or configured in some releases and in some license level sets. For those platforms that have not removed support, some have left it enabled by default, while others ship with it disabled by default. We can use the following steps to determine if the protocol is both present and enabled on the running image.</p>
</div>
</div>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 3">
<div class="section">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p><strong>Step 1: Determine Whether the Platform Supports MOP</strong></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>To see if the software image on the platform you are running supports MOP, enter<br />
the <strong>show subsys | include mop</strong> CLI command. If the platform supports MOP, it will show a line with <strong>mop Protocol</strong>, as shown in the following example:</p>
<pre>   Router#show subsys | include mop
   mop Protocol 1.000.001
   Router#
</pre>
<p>If the device doesn’t support MOP, it will return nothing as shown in the following example:</p>
<pre>   Router#show subsys | include mop
   Router#
</pre>
<p>If a platform doesn’t support MOP, then the commands to disable MOP won’t be visible in the command help and you will get an error if you try to configure it, as shown in the following examples:</p>
<pre>Router(config)#interface gigabitEthernet 1 
Router(config-if)#no mop ? 
% Unrecognized command 
Router(config-if)#no mop enabled 
                      ^ 
% Invalid input detected at '^' marker.
Router(config-if)#</pre>
<p><strong>Step 2: Determine Whether the Platform is Running MOP</strong></p>
<p>If you have confirmed that the platforms supports MOP, use the <strong>show</strong> <strong>processes | include</strong><br />
<strong>MOP</strong> CLI command to see if the MOP process is actually running on the device. If the platform has MOP enabled (either by default or by a configuration), it will show the <strong>MOP Protocols</strong> in the output, as shown in the following example:</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<pre>Router#show processes | include MOP
208 Mwe 5632C4164FCE 7 66 10622408/24000 0 MOP Protocols
Router#</pre>
<p>If the device isn’t running MOP, it will return nothing as shown in the following example:</p>
<pre>   Router#show processes | include MOP
   Router#
</pre>
<p>The platform will accept MOP RC sessions only if it is running MOP.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Controlling MOP RC Sessions on the VTY Lines</span></strong></h2>
<p>Once we have determined that the image supports MOP and that the MOP process is running, how do we control MOP usage and access? The following question came up on the external forum, and it was mentioned in the original blog: Why is MOP RC traffic even accepted when the VTY lines were configured with <strong>transport input ssh</strong>, which should drop all management protocols other than SSH over the VTY lines, especially when <strong>transport input</strong> does include the keyword option of mop?</p>
<p>The answer is that this is a bug and it has been addressed with Cisco Bug ID <a href="https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCwa57951" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSCwa57951</a>. The fix will be included in Cisco IOS XE Software releases 17.9(1) and later. After you implement the fix, if you do have the recommended configuration of transport input ssh on the VTY lines, then even if MOP is running, no connections that use MOP RC will be permitted.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> MOP RC sessions still are subject to whatever authentication options are configured on the VTY lines.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Recommendations for MOP</span></strong></h2>
<p>The current advice really hasn’t changed from what was recommended way back in 2010 and as per the hardening guide. Go ahead and disable MOP on all interfaces; unless your business requires it to be enabled.</p>
<p>Recently, the MOP protocol has been disabled by default in Cisco IOS XE releases but, unfortunately, that varies from platform type to platform type and even license levels.</p>
<p>Regardless of how you are configuring the device – via templates, API, scripts, or manually – ensure that you apply <strong>no mop enable</strong> on all interfaces. The command will be rejected if the release or license level doesn’t support MOP, but it won’t impact to the device.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 5">
<div class="section">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>At this point you may ask, “Hang on&#8230; isn’t there a global command to just disable MOP? Something similar to the <strong>no cdp run</strong> command?” The short answer is no. But a feature request has been raised for the support of this command via Cisco Bug ID <a href="https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCwa91505" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSCwa91505</a>.</p>
<p>Also, ensure that you have your VTY and TTY lines configured in accordance with the <a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/docs/ip/access-lists/13608-21.html#anc45" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cisco Guide to Harden Cisco IOS Devices</a>. Doing so will ensure that once you upgrade your Cisco IOS XE release beyond 17.9(1), you will be protected regardless of the MOP configuration status.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">What About MOP sysid?</span></strong></h2>
<p>This blog and the previous one focused on <strong>no mop enable</strong>. You will likely also see the <strong>no mop sysid</strong> interface configuration command. When MOP is enabled, the MOP server will periodically multicast a system ID message out to the Ethernet interfaces if <strong>mop sysid</strong> is enabled.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>So if you see frames on your network with the Ethertype 0x6002, then there’s a good chance you not only have MOP enabled but mop sysid enabled as well. Disabling MOP with the no mop enable interface configuration command also disables sending MOP periodic system ID.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #6abf4b;">Final Concerns</span></strong></h2>
<div class="page" title="Page 5">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>What if you disabled MOP with the <strong>no mop enable</strong> interface command on all interfaces, then issued the <strong>show processes | include MOP</strong> and you still see the MOP process being active? Be patient. In the background, a process runs every 8 to 12 minutes to check if MOP is disabled on all supported interfaces. If it is, then it fully shuts down the MOP process and you will no longer see it in the <strong>show processes | include MOP</strong> output. If you wait 15 minutes and still see the MOP process in the output of <strong>show processes | include MOP,</strong> then you still have MOP enabled on a supported interface.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>We’d love to hear what you think. Ask a Question, Comment Below, and Stay Connected with Cisco Secure on social!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Cisco Secure Social Channels</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/CiscoSecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ciscosecure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://twitter.com/CiscoSecure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong><br />
<strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/cisco-secure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blogs.cisco.com/security/router-spring-cleaning-no-mop-required-again/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>