<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:event="https://www.brookings.edu/events/">
  <channel>
    <title>International Affairs</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/international-affairs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.brookings.edu</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:38:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Germany has a special responsibility to stop Putin’s evil</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/04/26/germany-has-a-special-responsibility-to-stop-putins-evil/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Constanze Stelzenmüller]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 15:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1602470</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A merciless war is being waged in the middle of Europe — on Germany’s ruling Social Democratic Party (SPD). That, at least, is what a casual observer of German politics might conclude. Rolf Mützenich, the head of the SPD’s parliamentary faction, has denounced demands by his Green and Free Democratic coalition partners for heavy weapons&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Constanze Stelzenmüller</p><p>A merciless war is being waged in the middle of Europe — on Germany’s ruling Social Democratic Party (SPD). That, at least, is what a casual observer of German politics might conclude.</p>

<p>Rolf Mützenich, the head of the SPD’s parliamentary faction, <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/russland-ukraine-krieg-marie-agnes-strack-zimmermann-kritisiert-rolf-muetzenich-a-76eb4adb-9f54-4062-a844-0e17de11bff8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has denounced</a> demands by his Green and Free Democratic coalition partners for heavy weapons deliveries to Ukraine as “irresponsible.” His colleague Ralf Stegner toggles between angry tweets and accusatory <a href="https://www.facebook.com/login/?next=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F480641715335370%2Fposts%2F5119978991401596%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook screeds</a> against critics of his party’s past policy towards Russia.</p>
<p>Sigmar Gabriel, a former foreign minister, has <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/sigmar-gabriel-wir-brauchen-zumindest-einen-kalten-frieden-gastbeitrag-a-411895f4-557e-42e7-9453-c62baa490d82" target="_blank" rel="noopener">inveighed</a> against “dangerous conspiracy theories” about German-Russian networks of influence. The maudlin self-pity is unedifying. Its stridency suggests that the criticism is hitting home.</p>
<p>Chancellor Olaf Scholz himself is becoming thin-skinned. He has <a href="https://www.rnd.de/politik/olaf-scholz-an-jungs-und-maedels-kanzler-interview-sorgt-fuer-unmut-VBSMMZEUMJEMZGBDNYCCNTNN24.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dismissed</a> three Bundestag members who had visited Ukraine and called for more military support, as “boys and girls.” In a recent interview, he suggested sending heavy weapons would make Germany and NATO <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/international/germany/interview-with-german-chancellor-olaf-scholz-there-cannot-be-a-nuclear-war-a-d9705006-23c9-4ecc-9268-ded40edf90f9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“parties to the war.”</a></p>
<p>The cold truth is that there is much to criticize. It is way past time for the SPD to expel its top Russian gas lobbyist, former Chancellor Gerhard Schröder. It is also essential that German courts should investigate the links between <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6560170c-95f5-478e-860f-eec683c049af" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Manuela Schwesig</a>, premier of the eastern state of Mecklenburg West-Pomerania, and the pipeline operator Nord Stream 2, fully owned by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/exclusive-nord-stream-2-owner-considers-insolvency-after-pipeline-halt-sanctions-2022-03-01/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gazprom</a>.</p>
<p>But Germany’s self-serving Russia policy and its self-inflicted energy dependence — part willfully naïve, part deeply corrupt — found eager supporters across the political party spectrum. They emboldened the Kremlin, and they enabled Vladimir Putin’s war.</p>

<p>It is, however, missing the point <a href="https://www.rnd.de/politik/deutsche-russland-politik-wadephul-fordert-auseinandersetzung-A5DAZNZ5Q5BBFLH46W7ZBZKMF4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to call for</a> Frank-Walter Steinmeier, the president and another former foreign minister, or former chancellor Angela Merkel to be hauled in front of a parliamentary commission of inquiry. When they held power, they and other German politicians shrewdly assessed that they were doing exactly what the business sector and the general public wanted.</p>
<p>At least Steinmeier has publicly <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/german-president-steinmeier-admits-mistakes-over-russia-policy/a-61362153" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declared</a> that he was wrong. But as for Russia’s war of annihilation and its relentless atrocities against Ukrainians, they are on all of us.</p>
<p>To Scholz’s credit, he and his government took power with an ambitious domestic transformation agenda. Four days after Russia’s invasion, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ffc46030-51c6-4d87-b81b-457a31fbcdc9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the chancellor acknowledged</a> the need for a <em>Zeitenwende</em>, or turning point, in German energy and security policy as well, and he promised to support Ukraine. It is hard to imagine Merkel, his Christian Democratic predecessor, doing either. Unfortunately, none of Germany’s short-term options for helping Kyiv and preventing a Kremlin victory is good.</p>
<p>Because <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c95634ad-e01a-4af5-b7e8-4616618b7431" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Germany’s hydrocarbon imports</a> fuel the Russian war machine, Berlin wants to stop importing coal by the summer, and oil by the end of the year. But it <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/e82b11a1-cf1f-4543-9f9f-6ab70da6b746" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fears</a> that cutting off gas imports now — instead of in 2024, as initially planned — could create a massive recession and political turmoil. On that point <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7e1307f8-6ec6-4a12-a7f1-a97c23a6167e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Janet Yellen</a>, the U.S. treasury secretary, seems to agree.</p>
<p>Ukraine is begging for heavy weapons, as Russia steps up <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4351d5b0-0888-4b47-9368-6bc4dfbccbf5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its offensive in Donbas</a>. But on this question Scholz has dithered, prevaricated and thrown up smoke, to mounting anger among Germany’s allies and his coalition partners. The shortfall of usable German military kit is real, and so is pressure from the SPD’s intransigently pacifist left wing. In a belated compromise, Berlin is acting <a href="https://www.thedefensepost.com/2022/04/21/germany-east-european-weapons-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to backfill weaponry</a> provided to Kyiv by other NATO allies.</p>
<p>Scholz is not helped by a speaking style that runs the gamut from stoical to gnomic. Some of his ministers are weaker than others. But his real problem lies elsewhere. As a parliamentary democracy, Germany has a federal executive that is weak by design. The chancellery staff is tiny compared with those of other major democracies. Scholz’s most senior advisers are spreading themselves thin. It shows.</p>
<p>For Scholz’s volatile “traffic light” coalition to survive and wield power effectively, it must change the way it governs. The foreign ministry is working on <a href="https://www.tagesschau.de/inland/innenpolitik/nationale-sicherheitsstrategie-101.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a national security strategy</a>, Germany’s first such document. In principle this will help articulate strategic goals more coherently.</p>
<p>But even more urgently, the chancellery needs a proper national security staff that can advise and assist the head of government to weather an age of continual disruptions. It matters all the more because Germany has a special responsibility to put a stop to the evil unleashed by Putin.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-25T151204Z_186991290_RC2EUT9JHD8U_RTRMADP_3_GERMANY-POLITICS.jpg?w=283" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" label="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/russias-invasion-of-ukraine/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much popular support does Tunisia’s president really have?</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/opinions/how-much-popular-support-does-tunisias-president-really-have/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sharan Grewal, Mohamed Dhia Hammami]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=opinion&amp;p=1603621</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Sharan Grewal, Mohamed Dhia Hammami</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-10T020603Z_1212598309_RC22KT9XVLPV_RTRMADP_3_TUNISIA-POLITICS-PIX.jpg?w=292" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Tunisia" label="Tunisia" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/tunisia/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-Japan relations in an era of economic statecraft</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/events/us-japan-relations-in-an-era-of-economic-statecraft/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=event&amp;p=1598564</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[National security and economic globalization are increasingly intertwined. Amid rapid technological change and increased tension in the international system, the United States and Japan are each honing their own economic policies with a new emphasis on industrial policy to nurture advanced manufacturing and science and innovation, strengthening supply chains, and reducing dependence on China. In&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>National security and economic globalization are increasingly intertwined. Amid rapid technological change and increased tension in the international system, the United States and Japan are each honing their own economic policies with a new emphasis on industrial policy to nurture advanced manufacturing and science and innovation, strengthening supply chains, and reducing dependence on China. In addition to the renewed focus on economic security, Japan and the U.S. are also promoting economic connectivity through shared activities in the Quad and the proposed Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, while Japan continues to play a leadership role in the Comprehensive and Progressive Trans-Pacific Partnership. More recently, the two allies have engaged in an unprecedented coordination of economic sanctions against Russia for its invasion of Ukraine. How do Japanese and American visions of economic statecraft overlap, and what are the future opportunities for the allies to work together in this space?</p>
<p>On May 4, the Center for East Asia Policy Studies at the Brookings Institution will host a panel of policy practitioners from Japan and Washington, D.C.-based experts to discuss how the United States and Japan can coordinate their industrial policies effectively and promote science and tech collaboration. Panelists will discuss the challenges of reconciling economic security with economic connectivity, and the contours of a redefined relationship with China at a time when deglobalization trends are strengthening.</p>
<p>After the discussion, panelists will take questions from the audience. Online viewers can submit questions via e-mail to <a href="mailto:events@brookings.edu">events@brookings.edu</a> or via Twitter at <strong>#USJapan</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong>Brookings requires all staff and visitors to show proof that they are </strong><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/stay-up-to-date.html?s_cid=11747:fully%20vaccinated%20guidelines"><strong>fully vaccinated</strong></a><strong> against COVID-19 via vaccines approved by the FDA or WHO. After submitting your registration, please proceed to the provided link on the confirmation page to complete the registration process by verifying your vaccination information.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2015-04-28T000000Z_1510607227_TB3EB4S14251T_RTRMADP_3_USA-JAPAN.jpg?w=265" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Japan" label="Japan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/japan/" />
      <event:locationSummary>Washington, DC</event:locationSummary>
      <event:type>upcoming</event:type>
      <event:startTime>1651674600</event:startTime>
      <event:endTime>1651679100</event:endTime>
      <event:timezone>America/New_York</event:timezone>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Biden, don’t pass up the opportunity for a reset with Shahbaz Sharif’s Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/04/22/president-biden-dont-pass-up-the-opportunity-for-a-reset-with-shahbaz-sharifs-pakistan/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Bruce Riedel, Madiha Afzal]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1598644</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The end of American involvement in Afghanistan and the change in leadership in Pakistan presents the United States with an opportunity to reset its long-troubled relationship with the world’s fifth most populous country. President Joe Biden should initiate a high-level dialogue with new Prime Minister Shahbaz Sharif, who will be in power for up to&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Bruce Riedel, Madiha Afzal</p><p>The end of American involvement in Afghanistan and the change in leadership in Pakistan presents the United States with an opportunity to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/25/opinion/pakistan-biden-khan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reset its long-troubled relationship</a> with the world’s fifth most populous country. President Joe Biden should initiate a high-level dialogue with new Prime Minister Shahbaz Sharif, who will be in power for up to a year before the next election is held.</p>

<p>For most of the last 40 years, American policy toward Pakistan <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/deadly-embrace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revolved around our interests in the wars in Afghanistan</a>. In the 1980s, we partnered with the military dictator Zia ul-Haq to <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/what-we-won/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arm the Afghan mujahideen against the Soviets</a>. Then we sought Pakistani cooperation to fight al-Qaida and the Taliban, often with mixed results. Karachi port was crucial in both wars to get supplies to our Afghan allies and NATO forces in Afghanistan. Pursuing these wars was Washington’s top priority, edging out all other issues.</p>
<p>Because our policy was focused on fighting wars in Afghanistan, our primary partners in Pakistan were the intelligence service and the military. Less attention was devoted to the civilian government. Unintentionally this helped destabilize the always fraught civil-military balance in Pakistan, bolstering Pakistan’s military at the expense of its civilian governments.</p>
<p>The withdrawal of American and NATO forces from Afghanistan last August, a badly flawed operation, has essentially freed up American policy toward this important nuclear-armed Muslim country of <a href="https://www.census.gov/popclock/world" target="_blank" rel="noopener">243 million people</a>. Now Washington can engage with Islamabad without prioritizing Afghanistan issues at the expense of our broader interests in regional stability with India and China, encouraging development in South Asia, and supporting the strengthening of the elected democratic forces in Pakistan. America also has an interest in balancing somewhat the influence of China, Pakistan’s closest ally, on decisionmaking in Islamabad.</p>
<p>The Biden administration, and in particular the White House, has given Pakistan a relative cold shoulder to date — <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/10/13/post-afghanistan-us-pakistan-relations-stand-on-the-edge-of-a-precipice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">irked</a> by the war in Afghanistan <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/08/24/pakistans-problematic-victory-in-afghanistan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ending with a Taliban takeover</a> and ostensibly with then-Prime Minister Imran Khan <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/u-s-really-messed-it-up-in-afghanistan-says-pakistan-prime-minister-imran-khan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">publicly criticizing the U.S.</a> as it happened; more broadly, Pakistan has <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/04/12/under-biden-pakistan-and-the-us-face-a-dilemma-about-the-breadth-of-their-relationship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">simply not been high on the priority list</a> of an administration aiming to counter China via its relationships in the Indo-Pacific and now focused on Russia’s war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>Biden did not call Khan while he was prime minister. Last fall, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/events/the-future-of-us-pakistan-relations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we argued</a> he should. Khan in turn <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/12/13/pakistan-skipped-the-us-summit-for-democracy-why/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declined to attend</a> Biden’s Summit for Democracy. The White House should call Shahbaz Sharif. Sharif is a three-time former chief minister of Punjab, Pakistan’s largest and most prosperous province, and brother of three-time former Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif. The Sharifs have been marred by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/11/pakistan-prime-mininster-shehbaz-sharif/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">corruption allegations</a>, key to Imran Khan’s arguments against them, but they are also pragmatic men eager to develop Pakistan’s infrastructure and economy. (One of us, Bruce, has known them for over 30 years.) They have generally refrained from foreign adventures and <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/avoiding-armageddon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conflict with India</a>. Their (belated) opposition to the reckless military operation in Kargil in 1999 is what led to the overthrow of Nawaz’s administration later in 1999.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Imran Khan is an ideologue. He relied on anti-American rhetoric both in his rise to power as well as in his recent fall, <a href="https://www.thechicagocouncil.org/commentary-and-analysis/podcasts/after-khan-pakistans-political-instability-meets-great-power" target="_blank" rel="noopener">denouncing alleged American interference</a> in Pakistani politics this spring first to try to stay in power and now to try to get back in charge. He has been an outspoken critic of American operations against al-Qaida and the Taliban.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, American warnings that supporting the Afghan Taliban would lead to a stronger threat from the Pakistani Taliban to Pakistan have proven to be all too accurate. Pakistan’s <a href="https://responsiblestatecraft.org/2022/04/18/deadly-pakistan-strikes-in-afghanistan-reflect-growing-cross-border-tensions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clashes with both have intensified</a> in recent days. The Afghan Taliban has ignored Pakistan’s entreaties to control their Pakistani Taliban allies.</p>
<p>The Afghan people could be a beneficiary of improved relations between America and Pakistan. Washington has shown no real leverage on the new regime in Kabul. Afghan girls are <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/03/23/1088202759/taliban-afghanistan-girls-school" target="_blank" rel="noopener">barred from attending secondary school</a> and <a href="https://www.economist.com/asia/2022/04/02/the-taliban-are-pushing-females-out-of-public-life" target="_blank" rel="noopener">increasingly constrained</a> in the workplace. Islamabad has more influence in Kabul than any outside player, albeit within limits. For example, it controls the importation of oil to its neighbor. Pakistan has been at the forefront of <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/10/13/post-afghanistan-us-pakistan-relations-stand-on-the-edge-of-a-precipice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">calling for engagement</a> with the Taliban regime. Working with Islamabad may help ease the misery of the Afghan people over time. It’s worth exploring.</p>
<p>The Sharif government has a moderate military leadership to work with in the months ahead. Chief of Army Staff General Qamar Javed Bajwa has <a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/pakistan-army-chief-blasts-russia-aggression-against-ukraine/6512372.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">openly criticized</a> Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, a marked shift from Khan’s posture of “neutrality” on the war. Khan was coincidentally <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/03/09/imran-khan-pakistan-picks-terrible-time-make-friends-with-vladimir-putin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in Moscow</a> when the invasion began. Given that his relationship with the Biden administration was non-existent, Khan’s relationship with Russian President Vladimir Putin — who <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamNoahWho/status/1496147475597602828?s=20&amp;t=bJhpDQeyhEYwXvTIy9027Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">called him three times</a> since August — and Chinese President Xi Jinping looked like a leaning away from America toward Russia and China. With his reliance on a U.S. conspiracy narrative as his government was about to fall, he solidified that position. On the other hand, Bajwa has <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1683055" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spoken publicly</a> about improving <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/defence/pakistan-army-chief-general-qamar-javed-bajwas-remarks-on-us-may-affect-pak-russia-ties/articleshow/90650134.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">relations with America</a>, as has <a href="https://twitter.com/MadihaAfzal/status/1514229194066120707?s=20&amp;t=HAdmFUQSZrfWdZMm0NZGMw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shahbaz Sharif</a>. They will have to walk a delicate balance in engaging with the United States given Khan’s U.S. conspiracy narrative, which the army and Sharif have rebuffed but which Khan’s supporters buy wholesale.</p>
<p>The opportunity for the Biden administration for this engagement is not open ended. Shahbaz Sharif inherits a weak economy which is now his primary problem, and his runway is limited. Imran Khan, meanwhile, is determined to get back in power. His support is substantial; he has led <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/15/world/asia/imran-khan-rally-pakistan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">huge rallies</a> in Pakistan’s major cities, relying on demagoguery and anti-American rhetoric. He is trying to undermine the new government’s legitimacy by calling it an “imported government” and railing about the corruption cases against its members. His party has <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1684501" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resigned</a> from parliament. In the end, the prize for both the Sharifs and Khan is the next election. Pakistan’s politics is increasingly uncertain; it’s an urgent time to open a dialogue.</p>
<p>A major priority for sustained presidential engagement with Pakistan should be to strengthen the democratic process in the second-largest Muslim country in the world. No elected prime minister has served out five years in office; too often the military has intervened to bring down the elected government. By underscoring American support for civilian rule by engaging primarily with Sharif and his foreign minister, Hina Rabbani Khar, Biden’s team would belatedly make Pakistan a part of the president’s policy of strengthening democracy against autocracy. This should usher in a new era of stability in the U.S.-Pakistan relationship, that has seen too many highs and lows — essentially because the relationship has been predicated on America’s goals in Afghanistan. That would mean engaging with civilian governments regardless of which leader is in power — which will benefit Pakistan itself and the U.S.-Pakistan relationship in the long-run.</p>
<p>In terms of what should be on the immediate agenda, first would be the notion that the relationship with Pakistan can no longer be focused solely on security, though that would be one necessary dimension, with the Taliban in power in Afghanistan, a rise in attacks by the Islamic State Khorasan group and the Pakistani Taliban, and given Islamabad’s nuclear arsenal and difficult relationship with New Delhi. Another aspect of the agenda could be to explore avenues for strengthening the economic relationship in a way that uses Pakistan’s untapped economic potential (ultimately to both Pakistan and America’s benefit), for instance with Pakistan’s small but growing tech sector. An important effect is that this gives Pakistan something other than the <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/at-all-costs-how-pakistan-and-china-control-the-narrative-on-the-china-pakistan-economic-corridor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">China-Pakistan Economic Corridor</a> to look to in terms of investment; a stronger economy also loosens the military’s hold on the country. It’s a big opportunity to fundamentally alter U.S.-Pakistan relations.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Sharif_001.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Pakistan" label="Pakistan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/pakistan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trans-Atlantic Scorecard — April 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/research/trans-atlantic-scorecard-april-2022/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=research&amp;p=1597887</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Welcome to the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s Center on the United States and Europe (CUSE). To produce the Scorecard, we poll Brookings scholars and other experts on the present state of U.S. relations with Europe — overall and in the political, security, and economic&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/center/center-on-the-united-states-and-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center on the United States and Europe (CUSE)</a>. To produce the Scorecard, we poll Brookings scholars and other experts on the present state of U.S. relations with Europe — overall and in the political, security, and economic dimensions — as well as on the state of U.S. relations with five key countries and the European Union itself. We also ask about several major issues in the news. The poll for this edition of the survey was conducted from April 5 to April 8, 2022. The experts’ analyses are complemented by CUSE Director <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/experts/thomas-wright/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas Wright</a>’s take on what to watch in the coming months.</p>
<div class="size-article-fullbleed" title="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/FP_20220421_bbti_survey_responses.csv">

<div id="bbti-snapshot" class="bbti__tab">
<h2>What to Watch</h2>
<h3 class="accordion__title active">A message from CUSE Director Thomas Wright</h3>
<div class="accordion__content">
<p><em>Center on the United States and Europe Director <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/experts/thomas-wright/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas Wright</a> lays out events, issues, and potential developments to watch for in the months ahead.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am delighted to share with you the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/center/center-on-the-united-states-and-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center on the United States and Europe</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The first quarter of 2022 in trans-Atlantic relations has been dominated by the Russian troop buildup on the border with Ukraine and launch of the invasion on February 24. This iteration of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard offers a snapshot of the impact of the war on U.S.-Europe relations to date, as well as other developments from the quarter.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By the end of the quarter, five weeks into Russia’s war in Ukraine, U.S.-European relations had significantly improved since the end of the fourth quarter of 2021, from an average of 6.5 on a 1-10 scale to 8.1 at the end of the first quarter of 2022. Political and security relations are also up roughly 1.5 points each at 8, while economic relations increased more modestly to an average of 7. 85% of our survey pool saw U.S.-Europe relations trending positively overall, and respondents unanimously agreed that U.S.-European security relations had improved. Bilateral relations between the US and Germany, the US and France, the US and the U.K., the US and Turkey, and the US and EU all increased by over 1 point since the end of 2021, while US-Russia relations suffered a 0.6-point decrease, from the already quite low 1.9 to 1.3.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the questions specific to events and developments of this quarter, respondents unanimously disagreed that there would be a full Russia-Ukraine ceasefire before April 30, 2022. 85% believe that the war in Ukraine will expedite Europe’s green energy transition, while 80% agreed that China’s position on Russia would damage EU-China relations (10% were neutral and 10% disagreed). 89% thought that U.K.-EU relations had improved since the Russian invasion of Ukraine. On the question of whether Macron would face widespread discontent, weakening his capacity for reforms, even if reelected, respondents were divided. 60% agreed, while 10% disagreed and 30% were neutral.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the second quarter of 2022, our attention remains fixed on Russia and Ukraine. We will continue to closely follow trans-Atlantic security relations in the coming months, including how Germany’s historic shift in defense policy influences European security debates and possible Finnish and Swedish accession to NATO. With the French two days away from going to the polls to choose between the incumbent Emmanuel Macron and the far-right populist Marine Le Pen at the time of writing, we will also be watching the outcome of the election and impact on Europe and the world. Finally, as we look ahead to late spring and early summer, we will be watching the G-7 and NATO summits in June.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thank you again for reading the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-08T000000Z_584036144_MT1ABCPR805556006_RTRMADP_3_ABACA-PRESS.jpg?w=258" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Europe" label="Europe" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/europe/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Khan, Pakistan’s political instability meets great power competition</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/podcast-episode/after-khan-pakistans-political-instability-meets-great-power-competition/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Madiha Afzal, Brian Hanson]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=podcast-episode&amp;p=1598639</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Madiha Afzal, Brian Hanson</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-21T211701Z_2014705611_RC2XRT9BUNZV_RTRMADP_3_PAKISTAN-POLITICS.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Pakistan" label="Pakistan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/pakistan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politicians need to square with the American people on gasoline prices</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/planetpolicy/2022/04/20/politicians-need-to-square-with-the-american-people-on-gasoline-prices/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Gross]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1598187</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Members of Congress from both parties are politicizing and spreading bad information on the energy crisis resulting from Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. Given the acrimony in U.S. politics today, this isn’t surprising, but misinformation on the real cause of high gasoline prices is a disservice to U.S. citizens. Democrats blame the oil and gas industry&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Samantha Gross</p><p>Members of Congress from both parties are politicizing and spreading bad information on the energy crisis resulting from Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. Given the acrimony in U.S. politics today, this isn’t surprising, but misinformation on the real cause of high gasoline prices is a disservice to U.S. citizens. Democrats blame the oil and gas industry and Republicans blame President Joe Biden, but global market forces are the real culprit. Better understanding of the energy system, among policymakers and ordinary people, is crucial as the United States and world strive to transition to a system with net-zero greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>Rising U.S. gasoline prices are the result of global oil market conditions. U.S. gasoline prices reached their <a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/LeafHandler.ashx?n=PET&amp;s=EMM_EPM0_PTE_NUS_DPG&amp;f=W" target="_blank" rel="noopener">highest average level ever</a> (in nominal terms) of $4.41 per gallon in March, but prices have been <a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/LeafHandler.ashx?n=PET&amp;s=EMM_EPM0_PTE_NUS_DPG&amp;f=W" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rising steadily</a> since they bottomed out in April 2020. Global and U.S. oil production decreased during the COVID-19 pandemic, as demand and prices plummeted. Now demand is recovering faster than production, leading to rising prices even before the Ukraine crisis. Since the invasion, Russian oil production generally is not sanctioned (except by the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/fact-sheet-united-states-bans-imports-of-russian-oil-liquefied-natural-gas-and-coal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">United States</a> and <a href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/business/canada-to-ban-russian-oil-imports-1.5800473" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Canada</a>, which are not large buyers). However, buyers are shunning Russian oil because of difficulty obtaining tankers for shipment, fear of running afoul of banking sanctions, and reputational risk in buying Russian oil. As a result, <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/energy-russia-europe-oil-gas-lng-51649449573?tesla=y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2% to 3%</a> of global oil supply is off the market today and global oil prices have risen accordingly, with the European benchmark Brent crude reaching <a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/RBRTED.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$133 a barrel</a> in early March. President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/fact-sheet-president-bidens-plan-to-respond-to-putins-price-hike-at-the-pump/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">describes</a> this as “Putin’s price hike.”</p>
<p>However, in a <a href="https://energycommerce.house.gov/committee-activity/hearings/hearing-on-gouged-at-the-gas-station-big-oil-and-americas-pain-at-the" target="_blank" rel="noopener">House Energy and Commerce Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations</a> hearing on April 6, neither Democrats nor Republicans focused on the real issues at hand. Instead, they grilled six executives from the oil and gas industry on their party’s pet issues.</p>
<p>Rep. Frank Pallone Jr. summarized the majority Democrats’ position when he <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/06/business/energy-environment/gas-prices-executives-congress.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accused</a> the oil companies of “ripping off the American people” and “at a time of record profits… refusing to increase production.” But oil is a globally fungible good with a price set on the global market. None of the U.S. oil companies is large enough to have much influence on these prices. Furthermore, these companies make production decisions based on business criteria, including expected future prices, availability of capital, and the company’s appetite for risk. Since the U.S. companies cannot influence the global oil price, whether the new production will reduce prices is not one of these criteria. Members of the OPEC+ group could make up for much of the oil missing today, but are thus far <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/opec-technical-committee-replaces-iea-with-wood-mackenzie-rystad-secondary-2022-03-30/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">refusing</a> to increase production, in part for their own economic self-interest and in part because Russia is a member of the group and they don’t want to be involved in the geopolitics of the Ukraine invasion.</p>
<p>Several factors are limiting growth in U.S. oil production today. Capital availability is a challenge for the industry. Investors were burned during the price drops of 2014 and 2020 and are now <a href="https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news/2292744-shale-discipline-gears-up-for-biggest-test-yet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demanding fiscal discipline and higher returns</a>, instead of plowing profits into increasing production. Oil production decreased during the COVID-19 pandemic, as demand and prices plummeted. Now supply chain and labor challenges are slowing U.S. production recovery, as in many other industries. Scott Sheffield, CEO of Pioneer Natural Resources Company, noted that some <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/big-oil-tell-congress-markets-not-companies-set-fuel-prices-testimony-2022-04-05/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">drilling rigs and hydraulic fracturing equipment were decommissioned</a> over the past two years amid low oil prices, adding a shortage of equipment to drillers’ woes.</p>
<p>For their part, Republicans blamed the Biden administration’s policies, from cancelling the Keystone XL pipeline to pausing oil and gas leases on federal lands, for reducing U.S. oil production. Rep. Morgan Griffith <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/big-oil-tell-congress-markets-not-companies-set-fuel-prices-testimony-2022-04-05/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that “It is impossible to generate confidence or invest in production today when future production is clearly being blocked by this administration.” Rep. Cathy McMorris Rodgers <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/06/business/energy-environment/gas-prices-executives-congress.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">added</a>, “This is not the Putin price hike. This is the Biden price hike.”</p>
<p>In reality, none of President Biden’s moves have reduced today’s oil production. Any lease that had been established during his administration would not be producing yet, so the pause on leasing has had no effect on today’s oil production or gasoline prices. A lease to produce oil and gas is only the first step; obtaining permits, building infrastructure, and establishing the best places to drill can take years in a new production area. Additionally, only about <a href="https://www.cpr.org/2021/01/27/what-bidens-pause-on-oil-and-gas-leases-on-federal-lands-means-for-colorado/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one-quarter</a> of U.S. oil production takes place on federal lands; the rest occurs on private property. Federal lands are not the only choice for expanded production. Timing is also an issue in the case of the Keystone XL pipeline. Since the pipeline was not yet operating, its cancellation did not change U.S. oil supply from Canada. Even if construction had continued, the pipeline <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/could-the-keystone-pipeline-help-limit-rising-gas-prices-oil-cbs-news-explains/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">would not yet be completed</a>. Finally, the pipeline would not have carried new oil production, especially in its early days. Oil that might have been carried through the pipeline is reaching the market through other means, and thus already having its small impact on global oil prices.</p>
<p>A final complaint about Biden’s energy policy from both sides of the political spectrum is that it is <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/04/13/biden-gas-supply-climate-change-00024776" target="_blank" rel="noopener">incoherent</a> or “<a href="https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2021/aug/17/bidens-two-faced-energy-policies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two-faced</a>,” asking for more oil supply now while at the same time discouraging fossil fuel use and focusing on greener energy. This isn’t policy confusion, but a recognition of the challenging situation of today’s tight oil market that may become even tighter if countries further strengthen their sanctions on Russia and Russian energy. We must feed the energy system we have today, which runs on fossil fuels, while also working toward the future transition away from such fuels. The energy system cannot stop using fossil fuels overnight. As Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm said in a <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/secretary-granholm-ceraweek-keynote-luncheon-and-11-fireside-chat-sp-globals-dan-yergin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">speech</a> in March, we need to “walk and chew gum at the same time.”</p>
<p>President Biden has not changed his overall stance on climate change and fossil fuels so much as reacted to current conditions in the global oil market. The key to understanding these policies is timing — with goals of increasing short-term oil supply while still decreasing long-term demand.</p>
<p>There’s very little that an administration can do to increase supply in the short term, but selling oil from the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) is a useful step. On April 1, the Department of Energy <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-announces-second-emergency-notice-sale-crude-oil-strategic-petroleum-reserve-address" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/what-is-spr-emergency-oil-stash-biden-is-tapping-2022-03-31/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">largest sale ever</a> from the SPR, averaging one million barrels of oil per day over the next six months, amounting to about 1% of global demand. The United States has plenty of oil to undertake this action — the SPR currently contains more than <a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/LeafHandler.ashx?n=PET&amp;s=WCSSTUS1&amp;f=W" target="_blank" rel="noopener">560 million</a> barrels of oil. In collaboration, member countries of the International Energy Agency announced a release of an additional <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/iea-release-120-mln-barrels-over-six-month-period-2022-04-07/#:~:text=The%20total%20release%20of%20240,this%20is%2060%20million%20barrels." target="_blank" rel="noopener">60 million barrels</a>, furthering the goal of increasing oil supply immediately and reducing prices somewhat.</p>
<p>Despite today’s push to increase supply, the way to reduce fossil fuel use over the long term, and thus greenhouse gas emissions, is to decrease demand for the fuels. Decreasing domestic production <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/policy2020/bigideas/the-united-states-can-take-climate-change-seriously-while-leading-the-world-in-oil-and-gas-production/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">isn’t particularly helpful</a> since oil and gas are produced globally. The United States will just import whatever it doesn’t produce domestically, often from countries with worse environmental standards than our own. Biden administration policy recognizes this timing challenge by releasing more supply to the market today while rolling out policies to reduce demand — like support for <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/president-biden-doe-and-dot-announce-5-billion-over-five-years-national-ev-charging" target="_blank" rel="noopener">electric vehicles</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/12/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-races-to-deploy-clean-energy-that-creates-jobs-and-lowers-costs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">renewable electricity</a>, and <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-bipartisan-infrastructure-laws-95-billion-clean-hydrogen-initiatives" target="_blank" rel="noopener">low-carbon hydrogen production</a> — that will deliver future decreases in emissions.</p>
<p>The administration’s policy makes sense, but is difficult to explain in a sound bite. Congress is focused more on scoring points in the political game than on informing the American people. High gasoline prices anger Americans like those for no other product. Gasoline prices are apparent to all as they drive and see the price in lights along the road, and gasoline is a crucial component in many family budgets. But the American public doesn’t understand who to blame in a market that is global, nuanced, and complex. And particularly in Congress, politicians aren’t helping.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/McMorrisRodgers_001.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Energy Security" label="Energy Security" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/energy-security/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus on interests, not ideology, to strengthen Taiwan’s standing</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/04/18/focus-on-interests-not-ideology-to-strengthen-taiwans-standing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Hass]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1597796</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[As images of Russian brutality against innocent Ukrainians shock the conscience of the world, there is a natural impulse to frame the struggle in Europe as part of a global contest between democracies and autocracies. Taiwan’s leaders would be wise to restrain those impulses. Drawing analogies between Ukraine today and Taiwan tomorrow risks generating more&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Ryan Hass</p><p>As images of Russian brutality against innocent Ukrainians shock the conscience of the world, there is a natural impulse to frame the struggle in Europe as part of a global contest between democracies and autocracies. Taiwan’s leaders would be wise to restrain those impulses. Drawing analogies between Ukraine today and Taiwan tomorrow risks generating more costs than benefits for Taiwan’s future.</p>

<p>Yes, Taiwan faces a serious and growing threat from the People’s Republic of China. China’s leaders provide regular reminders of their bloody-minded determination to annex Taiwan. Chinese fighter jets and naval vessels exercise their capabilities near Taiwan with growing frequency and audacity. Chinese diplomats are becoming more brazen in their efforts to thwart Taiwan’s international space and deny the Taiwan people the dignity they deserve on the world stage. Beijing actively obstructs Taiwan’s efforts to enter regional trade blocs as it seeks to push Taiwan to integrate its economy more with the mainland and less with the rest of the world. Chinese efforts to interfere in Taiwan’s political system also are well-documented.</p>
<p>Taiwan’s leaders do not need to carry too heavy of a burden in drawing attention to the threats Taiwan faces, though. Beijing’s bullying already is doing the job of raising global awareness. A growing chorus of countries and regional groupings, such as the <a href="https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/front/archives/2021/06/14/2003759130" target="_blank" rel="noopener">G-7</a> and the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-quad-leaders-discuss-ukraine-thursday-white-house-2022-03-03/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quad</a> countries (Australia, India, Japan, and the United States), have been raising their voice about the importance of preserving peace in the Taiwan Strait.</p>
<p>In facing challenges from Beijing, Taipei is strengthened by its capacity to develop deep, strong, enduring partnerships with key countries around the world. These partnerships often are nurtured by shared democratic values, but they are fundamentally propelled forward by shared interests.</p>
<p>The drafters of the Biden administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/U.S.-Indo-Pacific-Strategy.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indo-Pacific Strategy</a> understood this imperative for grounding America’s approach to the region in tangible interests. The Biden team could have written a strategy focused on China, or on the global contest between democracy versus autocracy, but they wisely understood that such an approach would have limited appeal in the region. Instead, the Biden administration recognized that America needs to attract coordination and contribution from partners to advance its vision for an open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient region. Thus, through its Indo-Pacific strategy, Washington designed as big a tent as possible for as many countries as possible to feel comfortable working alongside the U.S.</p>
<p>In other words, the broad trendline of American policy in Asia is toward generating collective capacity to confront common problems, including with countries like Vietnam, who are strategically important but non-democratic. This trendline often is obscured by headlines around President Joe Biden’s views on the sharpening struggle between democracies and autocracies.</p>
<p>The truth is that President Biden is comfortable holding seemingly contradictory thoughts at once. He is capable of channeling his deep reservoirs of sympathy and emotion into the most powerful language he can reach, which often leads him toward ideologically infused rhetoric. At the same time, Biden also is practiced at making cold-eyed calculations about America’s national interests. He did so in deciding upon America’s withdrawal from Afghanistan. He similarly has imposed discipline about limiting risk of direct conflict between American and Russian forces in Ukraine.</p>

<p>President Biden will continue to talk about an intensifying global struggle between democracies and autocracies, and at the same time, the United States will continue to work with illiberal states when it serves American interests to do so. America is not going to limit its capacity to cooperate with non-democratic states on pressing challenges, and neither should Taiwan.</p>
<p>The coming months and years likely will demand greater coordination between democratic and non-democratic states, not less. The world is confronting conflict, economic shocks, and a continuing pandemic. Given the scale of these foreseeable challenges, the opportunity cost of splitting the world into rival <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/182adfa1-daae-449a-bdd9-8fe4265c20ed" target="_blank" rel="noopener">democratic and authoritarian blocs</a> is high and rising.</p>
<p>The growing strain on the global economy should lend greater global awareness to the importance of preserving Taiwan’s security. Taiwan is arguably the <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2022/4/1/silicon-shield-why-taiwan-is-not-the-next-ukraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most critical node</a> in global supply chains, accounting for 92% of global production of semiconductor process nodes below 10 nanometers. Major semiconductor companies like TSMC and MediaTek are trusted by international markets and are viewed as critical to the healthy functioning of the global economy.</p>
<p>Drawing analogies between Taiwan and Ukraine, on the other hand, spooks investors, compels caution about Taiwan in corporate boardrooms, and ultimately generates pressure for countries to de-globalize by re-shoring more production from Taiwan as a hedge against risk of Chinese invasion. All these reflexes run counter to Taiwan’s long-term economic interests.</p>
<p>President Tsai Ing-wen has provided calm, steady <a href="https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/editorials/archives/2020/08/10/2003741401" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leadership</a> through previous crises, including most recently during the COVID-19 pandemic. Those same skills will need to be summoned again to guide Taiwan through this current period of global turbulence. In so doing, President Tsai and her advisors can place Taiwan in a stronger position by emphasizing Taiwan’s central contributions to global economic growth, its generous responses to global challenges, and its geostrategic significance than by stressing Taiwan’s role in a global contest between democracy and autocracy.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-15T072934Z_281486708_RC2JNT9MH90C_RTRMADP_3_TAIWAN-USA.jpg?w=290" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Taiwan" label="Taiwan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/taiwan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20220415 Al Jazeera Madiha Afzal</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/media-mentions/20220415-al-jazeera-madiha-afzal/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicki Sullivan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 19:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=media-mention&amp;p=1597756</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Nicki Sullivan</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <atom:category term="Pakistan" label="Pakistan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/pakistan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20220414 Los Angeles Times Constanze Stelzenmüller</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/media-mentions/20220414-los-angeles-times-constanze-stelzenmuller/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Agneska Bloch]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=media-mention&amp;p=1597763</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Agneska Bloch</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-18T120000Z_1657101432_MT1YOMIUR000QA7KWE_RTRMADP_3_UKRAINE-CRISIS-PEOPLE-IN-LVIV.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" label="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/russias-invasion-of-ukraine/" />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>