<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Stories by Josue Martins on Medium]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[Stories by Josue Martins on Medium]]></description>
    <link>https://medium.com/@josue-martins?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/1*o2cqUdmTbwIIu6SG3H1iVg.jpeg</url>
      <title>Stories by Josue Martins on Medium</title>
      <link>https://medium.com/@josue-martins?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Medium</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:24:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://medium.com/@josue-martins/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub" />
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[How Mobile Operators should Thousands of Dollars because of SMS Malware.]]></title>
      <link>https://infosecwriteups.com/how-mobile-operators-should-thousands-of-dollars-because-of-sms-malware-2a4d7ac1e3a2?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2a4d7ac1e3a2</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 12:47:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-04-18T13:34:51.265Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>How Mobile Operators Lost Thousands Of Dollars Because Of An SMS Malware</h3><h3>SMS Malware Analysis — Write Up By Josue Martins</h3><p>This write-up is about an android malware that affected multiple mobile operators and subscribers, it is commonly found on pirate sites where subscribers download songs, games, and other content.</p><p>I have presented my finds on this SMS Malware at the <strong>GSMA Fraud and Security Group</strong> meeting in Paris 2019, This malware affected operators in Africa, Europe, and the Middle East, and the victims of this malware were often left with huge bills on their telephone number.</p><blockquote><strong>Let&#39;s break down this malicious piece of code…………………</strong></blockquote><h3>MALWARE FILE INFORMATION</h3><p><em>File Name: </em>smartworld_-_WIN_-_5001283180632240_-_.apk</p><p><em>Size: </em>1.76MB</p><p><em>MD5:</em>7b63adc6100ee6c7b703ba637882dd17</p><p><em>SHA1:</em>054e5d6569cfdc631bb1c722cc91b2dd6ae8e32c</p><p><em>SHA256:</em>5db5b4a563106e9a1b7c502e271f40224bb40cdbe678553dd90fc0335204af7e</p><p><em>App Name : Package Name : </em>contradecirte.preciosas.escasez</p><h3>STATIC ANALYSIS OF THE MALWARE</h3><p>When conducting a mobile malware analysis for the android OS, it is always good to look first at the manifest file, because it helps to identify the most important activity of the malware.</p><h4>ANDROID MANIFEST FILE ANALYSIS</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ifEOISwo_qii9a7oBEE2Hg.png" /><figcaption>Android Manifest File</figcaption></figure><h4>The malware request the following permissions:</h4><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.ACCESS_WIFI_STATE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to view the information about the status of Wi-Fi.</p><p>One can assume that his malware wants to use the internet to connect to a server to receive commands from cybercriminals.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.GET_ACCOUNTS”/&gt;</strong><br> — Allows an application to access the list of accounts known by the phone.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.ACCESS_NETWORK_STATE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to view the status of all networks.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.RECEIVE_BOOT_COMPLETED”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to start itself as soon as the system has finished booting. This can make it take longer to start the phone and allow the application to slow down the overall phone by always running.</p><h4>All the permission below are dangerous permissions and are used very often by malware.</h4><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.READ_PROFILE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to read the user’s personal profile data.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.INTERNET”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to create network sockets.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.READ_PHONE_STATE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows the application to access the phone features of the device. An application with this permission can determine the phone number and a serial number of this phone, whether a call is active, the number that calls is connected to, and so on.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.CHANGE_WIFI_STATE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to connect to and disconnect from Wi-Fi access points and to make changes to configured Wi-Fi networks.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.GET_TASKS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to retrieve information about currently and recently running tasks. May allow malicious applications to discover private information about other applications.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to write to the SD card.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.READ_EXTERNAL_STORAGE”/</strong>&gt;</p><p>— Allows an application to read from SD Card.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.MODIFY_PHONE_STATE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows the application to control the phone features of the device. An application with this permission can switch networks, turn the phone radio on and off and the like, without ever notifying you.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.BLUETOOTH”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to view the configuration of the local Bluetooth phone and to make and accept connections with paired devices.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.install_packages”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Install other applications on the device and applications from unknown sources.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.delete_packages”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Delete installed applications on the device.<br><br><strong> &lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.LOCAL_MAC_ADDRESS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Gets the MAC ADDRESS of the device.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.SEND_SMS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to send SMS messages. Malicious applications may cost you money by sending messages without your confirmation.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.WRITE_SMS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to write SMS messages stored on your phone or SIM card. Malicious applications may delete your messages.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.READ_CONTACTS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to read all of the contact (address) data stored on your phone. Malicious applications can use this to send your data to other people.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”com.google.android.c2dm.permission.RECEIVE”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allow the attacker server to send messages to the application using Google cloud messaging for Android.</p><p><strong>&lt;uses-permission android:name=”android.permission.USE_CREDENTIALS”/&gt;</strong></p><p>— Allows an application to request authentication tokens.</p><p>Just reading at all the twenty plus permissions requested by this malware, one can see that this malware has multiple functionalities.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Cwf9JR6-FiBkpRcN3OrsCQ.png" /><figcaption>Android Manifest file</figcaption></figure><p>We can see that the manifest file shows that the application will ask to be the administrator of the smartphone and the name of the activity is called “fraude”, fraude means fraud in Portuguese and Spanish. In my point of view, the malware writer is a Spanish individual or a group.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*O4_zPc3jZAyRWNlgTCSP3w.png" /><figcaption>Android Manifest</figcaption></figure><p>This code on the manifest file “ <strong><em>&lt;intent-filter android:priority=”999&quot;&gt;</em></strong> “ is used to make the service run with high priority in the background once installed and when the smartphone reboots too.</p><h4>JAVA FILE ANALYSIS</h4><p>The Java source code shows the following instructions coded into the malware.</p><p><strong>Extract sensitive information such as:</strong></p><ul><li>Smartphone operator</li><li>The country where the smartphone is located</li><li>The version of the Android Operating system running on the device</li><li>Date the malware was installed.</li></ul><p><strong>Additional functionalities coded into the malware:</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/756/1*sZMj9AxogS36NF43ok7sOg.png" /><figcaption>Request for admin access</figcaption></figure><p>Presents the user with entertainment content such as mobile games and adult content.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*T7FTVP9g84ZD1LHstN-I1Q.png" /><figcaption>Entertainment content such as mobile games and adult content.</figcaption></figure><p>Contact the <strong>Command and Control Centre</strong> to receive the <strong>number to send the SMS to</strong>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Hpfi2cOoB5PQs5GlebFYkg.png" /><figcaption>Request information from the malware creator.</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/783/1*n0QfOw9MdaxZrB18dvARmQ.png" /><figcaption>Collecting smartphone and user information</figcaption></figure><p>Request the date to repeat sending the SMS if there is an error or not.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*u-rZVQoM1dA3IwUZrWHHKQ.png" /><figcaption>The repeat date to send the SMS</figcaption></figure><p>Allows also the installation of additional mobile applications.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8rlhGB0Tj9BoyNjmc3bJPA.png" /><figcaption>Installation of the Apk file.</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/870/1*EB09r2nO5mIs4qSthH7dkg.png" /><figcaption>Location of the APK file</figcaption></figure><h4>DYNAMIC ANALYSIS OF THE MALWARE</h4><p>When conducting a dynamic analysis, it requires that one infects the test device with the malware and watches its behaviour.</p><p><strong>The malware was installed on test smartphones and displayed the following behaviour, once installed:</strong></p><ul><li>Hides by not using an icon, if you are not careful you will miss the malware in the main menu.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/444/1*RDinMejiKXx84MKaIs-C0A.png" /><figcaption>The App shows without an icon</figcaption></figure><ul><li>Presents the user with entertainment content such as mobile games and adult content, to view adult context one has to give the app administrative permissions and that is when the malware controls the device.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/443/1*aqjcm1ucpJs3PeRYhqJWSA.png" /><figcaption>Terms and conditions</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/447/1*c9ImaWHfwQS-mvSKmKCiZg.png" /><figcaption>The main menu</figcaption></figure><ul><li>The malware request Administrative rights on the smartphones.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/443/1*rT9jKQHuDc2uuGoykmO5vg.png" /><figcaption>Requesting administrator permission or access to the device.</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/969/1*8jjfmcFYJPE3WZXjSc3ULw.png" /><figcaption>Source code behind the screenshot</figcaption></figure><ul><li>Collects sensitive information highlighted in the static analysis</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Pc1_G17G-u1Dn7htHJ4uQw.png" /><figcaption>information collection</figcaption></figure><ul><li>It communicates with a Command and control centre via the domain “App.in-spicy.com”, and alerts that the malware has been installed successfully. It also asks the Command and control centre to send the number that will receive the SMS as the source code shows in the static analysis.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*RyxqFx7v_xkADKoJm3IslQ.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_IeCdSL6I-VqTPnXMRmgNw.png" /><figcaption>Contents of the SMS</figcaption></figure><p><strong>The SMS was sent to the number “<em>0079585388749</em>”, which is normally a premium number(A number with a high tariff).</strong></p><h3>Recap of the Malware</h3><ul><li>The malware hides by not using icons and runs in the background.</li><li>Presents the user with entertainment content to be interpreted as an entertainment mobile application.</li><li>Ask the user to allow it to run as a device administrator to allow the user to view additional adult content.</li><li>Once permitted to run as an administrator, it extracts sensitive information and sends SMS to premium numbers.</li><li>The malware can install additional software.</li></ul><h3><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3><p>SMS Malware is an interesting piece of software that cybercriminals are using more often because most smartphone users don&#39;t install antivirus software and they want to get free access to the contents on the internet.</p><p>Moreover, cybercriminals are also using Mobile malware as an enabler of telecommunication fraud and security attacks because they are aware that mobile operators are not deploying adequate security defences when it comes to mobile malware detection and SMS fraud.</p><p>Smartphones users should be very careful and should not install software outside of the Google Play or App Store from Apple. The above Command and Control centre should be blocked in your networks as soon as possible to avoid multiple types of telecom fraud that impact the reputation of mobile operators.</p><p><strong><em>PS — Don’t create mobile malware because it is a crime and this content is purely for educational purposes only.</em></strong></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2a4d7ac1e3a2" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://infosecwriteups.com/how-mobile-operators-should-thousands-of-dollars-because-of-sms-malware-2a4d7ac1e3a2">How Mobile Operators should Thousands of Dollars because of SMS Malware.</a> was originally published in <a href="https://infosecwriteups.com">InfoSec Write-ups</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Triad Of Information Security A Mobile Application]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/the-triad-of-information-security-a-mobile-application-39f68dd42f52?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/39f68dd42f52</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[integrity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[confidentiality]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[availability]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[owasp-top-10]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile-security]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 12:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-04-18T12:32:02.126Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*acGxR-RP5ey-Iej07AQkjA.jpeg" /></figure><h3>The Triad Of Information Security In A Mobile Application</h3><h4>Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability — By Example</h4><p>In my previous article in January. I wrote about “ <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/the-triad-of-information-security-in-mobile-networks-by-example-106bc3775969"><strong>The Triad Of Information Security In Mobile Networks By Example</strong></a>”, but this time I will focus on mobile applications security to give an end to end security perspective.</p><p>In Mobile Application security, the concept of TRIAD of Information Security is important because Mobile applications ingest and carry sensitive information about their users. Therefore, When building and deploying mobile applications it is essential that one takes these concepts below into consideration to ensure that the subscriber’s information is protected.</p><h4>The TRIAD of Information Security consists of the following items:</h4><blockquote>Confidentiality</blockquote><blockquote>Integrity</blockquote><blockquote>Availability</blockquote><h3><strong>Confidentiality</strong></h3><p>According to NIST, confidentiality is</p><blockquote>Preserving authorized restrictions on information access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information.</blockquote><p>In the absence of the encryption by using the PKI such as public and private keys to encrypt and decrypt data in motion a bad actor can intercept the traffic and modify or extract sensitive information</p><h4><strong><em>Case 1</em></strong></h4><p>— Leakage of sensitive information in cleartext.</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>In this exercise, the end-user login credentials, and all other traffic are sent over an unencrypted channel. All end-user traffic should be sent over an encrypted channel and hashed to prevent abuse.</p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><p><strong>iOS Application allows HTTP Traffic, therefore all the traffic is unencrypted. Multiple contents of the user session were intercepted and extracted.</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/968/1*437YwU95xpqQV_iJKazMFA.png" /><figcaption>iOS app code to accept traffic in cleartext.</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/641/1*MAAz2bAs1EDv6fKCY6np_Q.png" /><figcaption>Downloaded a whole album without an account and via the terminal from the streaming app</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>Integrity</strong></h3><p>According to NIST, Integrity is</p><blockquote>guarding against improper information modification or destruction, and includes ensuring information non-repudiation and authenticity.</blockquote><h4>Case 2</h4><p>— Lack of Signature validation and authenticity of the application send traffic to the server.</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>In this exercise, The bad actor was enabled to reverse engineer the application, sign it with its own signature, and still communicate with the backend server.</p><p><strong>The server failed to restrict the communication only to a legitimate application.</strong></p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><p><strong>Android Application was reversed engineered and new code was added to it, but the backend server still allowed this application to exchange sensitive traffic with it.</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*qKSHjx2o5YjLkCMLLckNbA.png" /><figcaption>Multiple permissions were added to the modified App</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>Availability</strong></h3><p>According to NIST, Availability is</p><blockquote>Ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information.</blockquote><h4><strong><em>Case 3</em></strong></h4><p>— No rate limiting and Time out for OTP.</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>In this exercise, there was no rate limit or time out on the number of OTPs that users can request from the app servers and no timeout is enforced after multiple requests.</p><p>If the app does not have the above protection and even distributed denial of service solution, this could be exploited to overwhelm the server and cause downtime, which will result in revenue loss and negatively impact the reputation of the provider.</p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><p><strong>3 OTP was requested and provided within 60 seconds, from 17:39 to 17:40, therefore 114216, 759089 and 992431.</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/620/1*3X_UioQsbuF3QoE_77Zjew.png" /><figcaption>Three OTP were requested in less than 60 seconds/1 minute</figcaption></figure><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability play a critical role in information security. It is very important to protect the end-users from cybercrime by applying multiple security layers in every stage of software development.</p><p>PS — This information is being shared for educational purposes only, therefore please don’t use it to commit a crime.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=39f68dd42f52" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/the-triad-of-information-security-a-mobile-application-39f68dd42f52">The Triad Of Information Security A Mobile Application</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Triad Of Information Security In Mobile Networks By Example]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/the-triad-of-information-security-in-mobile-networks-by-example-106bc3775969?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/106bc3775969</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 20:46:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2022-01-16T08:32:11.752Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Wy_zD1XfQm7k4ODF6Enr5A.jpeg" /></figure><h4>Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability</h4><p>In Mobile networks security, the concept of TRIAD of Information Security is important because these networks carry sensitive information. Therefore, When building and deploying these systems it is essential that one takes these concepts below into consideration to ensure that the subscriber&#39;s information is protected.</p><p>In this is article, I will explain the TRIAD of Information security and how it affects Mobile networks regardless of the generations.</p><h4>The TRIAD of security consists of the following items:</h4><blockquote><em>- Confidentiality</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>- Integrity</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>- Availability</em></blockquote><h4>Confidentiality</h4><p>According to NIST, confidentiality is</p><blockquote>“Preserving authorized restrictions on information access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information.”</blockquote><p>In the absence of the encryption algorithms, which uses the Symmetric and Asymmetric keys to encrypt and decrypt data in motion a bad actor can intercept the traffic and modify or extract sensitive information</p><p><strong><em>Case 1</em></strong></p><p>— HTTP Header Enrichment</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>A service that has been HTTP enriched in the Mobile Core Network to use subscriber&#39;s <strong>Personal Identifiable Information, </strong>such as MSISDN, IMSI or even IP address to facilitate authentications for value-added services such as operator portals, online gaming portals, shopping portals, and other services launched by the partners of the Mobile Operator.</p><p>When Mobile operators configure HTTP header enrichment, they often applied it in HTTP and not HTTPS, Therefore sending all the information in clear text as stated in the article “<a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/your-information-has-been-leaked-for-years-287b60256f6d">Your Information Has Been Leaked For Years</a>”. Information such as MSISDN and IMSI should never be sent on the clear because it can be used by attackers to launch further attacks.</p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*nrHGLDc6Bi2rWFtE.png" /><figcaption>Exposed MSISDN</figcaption></figure><p>Once an MSISDN has been exposed, an attacker can use SS7 vulnerabilities such as Map Anytime Interrogation to extract the location of a subscriber and Map Send Routing for SM to extract the IMSI that was not exposed over HTTP Header Enrichment.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*eDH30B8zW7j5l0Fz-EZ22Q.jpeg" /></figure><p>Therefore, the lack of encryption enables the bad actors to conduct location tracking attacks and once your location has been extracted criminals can use this information to commit burglary, kidnapping, and other types of crimes</p><h4>Integrity</h4><p>According to NIST, Integrity is</p><blockquote>“Guarding against improper information modification or destruction, and includes ensuring information non-repudiation and authenticity.”</blockquote><p><strong><em>Case 2</em></strong></p><p>— The absence of User Plane traffic integrity</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>The absence of User Plane traffic integrity enables the attacker to modify/redirect or impersonate the IP traffic and receiving party will not have a way to validate the authenticity of the sender.</p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><p>The IMP4GT vulnerability is spotted in 4G networks and this vulnerability also affects 5G if UPIP is not applied. Bad actors exploit this vulnerability using a fake BTS as stated in this article “<a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/catching-imsis-with-a-simple-imsi-catcher-a0c5cba5b8b0">Catching IMSIS With A Simple Imsi Catcher</a>”.</p><p>The researchers that discovered this vulnerability used the IMP4GTP and HTTP head enrichment to log in into the value-added service web portal by impersonating a legitimate subscriber.</p><blockquote>“The service site authenticates a user only based on his/her IP address (header enrichment). Eventually, we access the service site without user interaction and fully impersonate the victim against the network. Accessing the service site can be a stepping stone for further attacks. For example, an attacker can book data plans (fraud attacks), use the data volume, or retrieve personal information, e.g., phone number.”</blockquote><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/839/0*dXXEo1Kxl-jk7U52" /><figcaption>IMPersonation Attacks in 4G NeTworks using a Fake BTS</figcaption></figure><h4>Availability</h4><p>According to NIST, Availability is</p><blockquote>“Ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information.”</blockquote><p><strong><em>Case 3</em></strong></p><p>— Distributed Denial Of Service via SIP Flood Attack</p><p><strong><em>Issue</em></strong></p><p>In the absence of a Denial Of Service solution to protect the I-SBC or A-SBC from international or national links, these nodes are exposed to multiple attacks. A Distributed denial of service via SIP flood can result in downtime for Mobile Networks. Therefore, if the Mobile Network is bombarded with SIP flood or SIP register attacks the I-SBC could be overwhelmed and start dropping legitimate traffic and preventing subscribers from receiving calls over the interconnect or the I-SBC stop responding at all.</p><p><strong><em>Example:</em></strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ThfHcXNrcpRhQpjtKo71ZQ.png" /><figcaption>Multiple SIP invite Flood Attack</figcaption></figure><p>This attack happened in a VoIP provider from Canada and caused a major downtime in their services, moreover, the best way to launch a SIP attack is via a botnet for example the Sality botnet.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*PsXdvqGPhILCMCGituvoLg.png" /><figcaption>Logs from SIP attack</figcaption></figure><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability play a critical role in Information Security and Mobile networks security. Therefore, it is very important to protect subscribers and the networks that provide services to them from cybercrime by understanding these concepts and applying them rigorously.</p><p><strong>PS — This information is being shared for educational purposes only, therefore please don&#39;t use it to commit crime.</strong></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=106bc3775969" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/the-triad-of-information-security-in-mobile-networks-by-example-106bc3775969">The Triad Of Information Security In Mobile Networks By Example</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Your Information Has Been Leaked For Years]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/your-information-has-been-leaked-for-years-287b60256f6d?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/287b60256f6d</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[http-headers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[https]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[information-leak]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 13:03:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2021-11-02T13:08:42.710Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*w3aWL_gKTmULfDwoFefyrQ.jpeg" /></figure><h4>Information Leakage Of Subscribers &amp; Mobile Network Identifiers Via HTTP Header Enrichment</h4><p>When the third and fourth generations of mobile technology, which are 3G and 4G respectively were introduced to the public it was a tech buzz like the current 5G era. It enabled faster speeds and reliable access to services with smartphones, and Mobile Operators thought of various ways of generating revenue with data and other value-added services.</p><p>In the quest to generate revenue, Mobile Operators introduced a new type of authentication method of subscribers, which seemed easy, user-friendly, functional, and like other services with no security and privacy in mind. This authentification method is enabled by HTTP header Enrichment.</p><h4>What is HTTP Header Enrichment?</h4><p><em>it is the ability to add subscribers&#39; identifiers and the core network elements identifiers to the HTTP header of a Smartphone web session towards a webserver on the internet for the purpose of seamless authentication or identification of the subscribers/website user. This is usually done to websites or mobile applications of companies that have partnerships with the Mobile Operator.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*YYTS7Wr0deRbhBMAE8Yofw.png" /><figcaption>HTTP Header Enrichment flow</figcaption></figure><p>The additional information that can be added in the HTTP headers are MSISDN(Telephone number), IMSI, IMEI, and Core Network elements IP addresses, remember this information is all needed by cybercriminals to conduct attacks described in the article “Embedded Mobile Malware — The greatest cyber weapon” <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/embedded-mobile-malware-the-greatest-cyber-weapon-30aa8092d1b7">https://medium.com/josue-martins/embedded-mobile-malware-the-greatest-cyber-weapon-30aa8092d1b7</a>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/909/1*flMvLhiaGv6lFWQfTd-Atg.jpeg" /><figcaption>Example of MSISDN in an Enriched HTTP header</figcaption></figure><h4>How can cybercriminals extract this information and conduct attacks?</h4><ul><li><em>Set up a rogue access point by using your smartphone hotspot or 4G handheld router, with the hotspot name of the most popular Mobile Operator in the country or well-known free Wifi Hotspot.</em></li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZsoLtd7KFd6qJxdPtloKgg.jpeg" /><figcaption>Mobile Hotspot In Android</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/522/1*qTISTbthSpE3bNnXnp1tjg.jpeg" /><figcaption>4G Handheld Router</figcaption></figure><ul><li><em>The cybercriminal will connect their laptop to the hotspot network.</em></li><li><em>Run a man in the middle attack and Wireshark in the background, as soon as the targets connect to the network, then the cybercriminal will start to filter on the HTTP traffic, and search for parameters like MSISDN, IMSI, and others such as email address associated with the MSISDN so that it can be used for further attacks or even passwords since the traffic is over HTTP. Remember most of the end-users reuse their passwords on multiple sites.</em></li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gJIya3i4lPFLmGtsVrp5Vg.png" /><figcaption>Man In The Middle Attack</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*46fj1yFl_y_U1CSAc1fnqw.png" /><figcaption>Wireshark trace</figcaption></figure><ul><li><em>A cybercriminal can now conduct further attacks with information collected.</em></li></ul><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>Solutions for Mobile Operators and Subscribers</p><ol><li><em>Make use of HTTPS instead of HTTP. If it is hard to implement HTTP header enrichment over HTTPS, then hash sensitive information is sent over HTTP, which requires additional work.</em></li><li><em>Limit the sensitive information sent over HTTP.</em></li><li><em>Recommend the subscribers not to browse websites using HTTP or any random hotspots.</em></li><li><em>Discontinue HTTP header enrichment.</em></li></ol><p>The threats are not only the cybercriminals, who are external threats. It is also a disgruntled Mobile Operator employee, but that is content for another article…</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=287b60256f6d" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/your-information-has-been-leaked-for-years-287b60256f6d">Your Information Has Been Leaked For Years</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Catching IMSIS With A Simple Imsi Catcher]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/catching-imsis-with-a-simple-imsi-catcher-a0c5cba5b8b0?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/a0c5cba5b8b0</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile-security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[3g]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[telecommunication]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[4g]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 09:22:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2021-03-30T09:22:36.888Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*nqMlYU_qYsb6TB6-_E05fw.png" /></figure><p>In recent years the Mobile Telecommunication networks gained attention from the media due to signaling security attacks, one of the critical components of these attacks became the most important security information to be concealed and it is called the IMSI.</p><h4>So, What is an IMSI?</h4><p>An International Mobile Subscriber Identity (IMSI) is a unique number associated with all Global System for Mobile Communications (GSM) and Universal Mobile Telecommunications System (UMTS) network mobile phone users used for identifying a GSM subscriber.</p><h4>The IMSI has two parts which are :</h4><ol><li>Mobile Country Code + Mobile Network code</li></ol><ul><li>The mobile country code — Points to the country where the operator is based for example the UK or the US</li><li>The mobile network code — Point to the operator to which the SIM card or the subscriber belongs too, for example, Telefonica Spain or Verizon US.</li></ul><p>2. Mobile Subscription Identification Number — Any number assigned by the mobile network operator</p><p>These two parts make up the IMSI, which is the most important part of the Home Location Register(HLR ), and even the home subscriber server(HSS) lookup the process in routing signaling traffic.</p><h3>Why do hackers want your IMSI?</h3><p>Hackers need your IMSI to conduct all sorts of attacks that as stated in the article called <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/embedded-mobile-malware-the-greatest-cyber-weapon-30aa8092d1b7">Embedded Mobile Malware the greatest Cyber Weapon</a>.</p><h3>How can the hackers get your IMSI?</h3><p>The three most commonly used methods to harvest or extract IMSIs are the following:</p><ol><li><em>The IMSI catchers or Stingray as commonly called in the US.</em></li><li><em>Mobile malware</em></li><li><em>Signaling attacks</em></li></ol><p>Let&#39;s focus on the first method;</p><p><strong>To catch IMIS you will need the following equipment:</strong></p><ol><li><strong>Computer running Linux, I normally prefer Ubuntu 20+ or Kali Linux 2019+.</strong></li></ol><p><em>Ubuntu and Kali Linux can be downloaded respectively from the following links:</em></p><ul><li><a href="https://ubuntu.com/">https://ubuntu.com/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.kali.org/">https://www.kali.org/</a></li></ul><p><strong>2. Software Defined Radio.</strong></p><p><em>It can be purchased from the Amazon website.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/434/1*IPVoRggxROg8ZqDcTyoR3Q.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/546/1*wN3rISpAD46astdoOWSowg.png" /><figcaption>Software-Defined Radios</figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://github.com/Oros42/IMSI-catcher"><strong>3. The IMSI catcher source code on Github</strong></a></p><h4>How to install and run it?</h4><p><em>1.Clone the IMSI-catcher from GitHub to your computer by following the steps below:</em></p><pre>git clone https://github.com/Oros42/IMSI-catcher.git<br># or wget https://github.com/Oros42/IMSI-catcher/archive/master.zip &amp;&amp; unzip -q master.zip</pre><pre>sudo apt install python3-numpy python3-scipy python3-scapy</pre><p><em>2.Install gr-gsm for Ubuntu 20.04+</em></p><pre>sudo apt-get install -y \<br>    cmake \<br>    autoconf \<br>    libtool \<br>    pkg-config \<br>    build-essential \<br>    python-docutils \<br>    libcppunit-dev \<br>    swig \<br>    doxygen \<br>    liblog4cpp5-dev \<br>    gnuradio-dev \<br>    gr-osmosdr \<br>    libosmocore-dev \<br>    liborc-0.4-dev</pre><pre>git clone -b maint-3.8 https://github.com/velichkov/gr-gsm.git<br>cd gr-gsm<br>mkdir build<br>cd build<br>cmake ..<br>make -j 4<br>sudo make install<br>sudo ldconfig<br>echo &#39;export PYTHONPATH=/usr/local/lib/python3/dist-packages/:$PYTHONPATH&#39; &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc</pre><p><em>3.Run the following commands in three separate windows in your terminal.</em></p><p>In terminal 1 — running the IMSI catcher code in python</p><pre>sudo python3 simple_IMSI-catcher.py --sniff</pre><p>You can add -h to display options.</p><p>In terminal 2 — Search a frequency to listen by running the two commands below:</p><pre>grgsm_scanner</pre><p>Next, ask grgsm_livemon to use one of these frequencies:</p><pre>grgsm_livemon -f &lt;your_frequency&gt;M</pre><p>In terminal 3 — One can also capture the traffic by running Wireshark.</p><pre>wireshark</pre><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*xxheRuBj2vwGGiWqR7QuxQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>IMSI capture on Wireshark</figcaption></figure><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>IMSI catchers are not legal in most countries, it is not advisable to use them with criminal intent, therefore only apply the knowledge shared in this post for education reasons or to contribute to better security for smartphone users.</p><p><strong>PS: Stay out of trouble</strong></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=a0c5cba5b8b0" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/catching-imsis-with-a-simple-imsi-catcher-a0c5cba5b8b0">Catching IMSIS With A Simple Imsi Catcher</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[USSD Top 10 Security Risk For Mobile Payments]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/ussd-top-10-security-risk-for-mobile-payments-bcd64d0a34dc?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/bcd64d0a34dc</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ussd]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 18:48:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2020-12-28T19:11:53.400Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bKyW1NMPAnSbL7fEOk-IWA.png" /></figure><h3><a href="https://medium.com/p/bcd64d0a34dc?source=post_stats_page-------------------------------------">USSD Top 10 Security Risks For Mobile Payments</a></h3><p>Mapping of USSD Top 10 Security Risks</p><p>Security should be at the heart of software systems, especially when there is money involved. In mobile money or mobile payment ecosystems which enable USSD feature are exposed to some risks can affect the credibility of the service and can be detrimental for the organization&#39;s revenue, if they are not taken into account and prevented before launching a mobile money service. Below are the most prevalent risks for mobile money payments related to USSD and the recommendations to mitigate them.</p><h4>01. INSECURE COMMUNICATION</h4><p>A cybercriminal can tamper with USSD command requests and responses by conducting man-in-the-middle attacks<strong> </strong>by using fake base stations and forcing the smartphone to connect to the using 2G or 3G. which are easier to decrypt the traffic and tamper it.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>All the traffic leaving the smartphone to the core network should be encrypted by using the A5/3 or A5/4 cryptographic algorithm and IPsec to avoid man in the middle attacks.</li><li>By all means necessary do not use A5/0 to A5/2 cryptographic algorithms.</li></ul><h4>02. SIGNALLING ATTACKS</h4><p>A cybercriminal can conduct a USSD based attack by sending spoofed USSD requests from the roaming interfaces or even target SIM Cards with vulnerable SIM Tool Kit software such as S@t Browsers and WIB.</p><p>If the cybercriminal sends a well crafted binary SMS with instruction to send a USSD command, the Smartphone can send a USSD request from the victim&#39;s device and the request will appear to be legitimate and it will be processed by the mobile money solution.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*HUeBeWGQXiH4WJA5L9KVbg.png" /><figcaption>SimJacker Attack</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*lRJLawGPwP-W8rPBeI_Hmw.png" /><figcaption>The functionalities of an S@T Browser</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>Apply velocity check and rate-limiting of USSD requests towards the home network for mobile money related USSD requests.</li><li>Restrict account reset via USSD request from roaming interfaces.</li><li>Block binary SMS from roaming interfaces or at the SMS center that are targeting SIM cards with S@T browser vulnerability.</li></ul><h4>03. <strong>INSECURE</strong> AUTHENTICATION</h4><p>Insecure Authentication happens when authentication controls and protocols are by bypassed due to poor implementation or absence of it. For example, If the USSD menu for user authentication is not masked, an attacker can view the credentials of the end-user by conducting social engineering attacks such as shoulder surfing.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/288/0*PRRIPd_bbEt-MI_V.jpeg" /><figcaption>Mobile money USSD menu</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>All users accessing a mobile money menu should be forced to authenticate by entering an MSISDN followed by PIN or PASSWORD, if needed an OTP can be used as two-factor authentication.</li><li>Do not allow concurrent sessions.</li><li>In the usage of OTP, apply OTP rate limiting.</li><li>The input field for the password or PIN should be masked.</li><li>Mask sensitive information.</li></ul><h4><strong>04.</strong> <strong>USING TECHNOLOGY WITH KNOWN VULNERABILITY</strong></h4><p>The usage of technology with public known vulnerabilities such as the SIM-Jacker can pose a great security risk to the apps running on the SIM Tool Kit.</p><p>Using binary SMS as stated in the previous risk, a cybercriminal can force the device to send a USSD request to the home network.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><p>· Avoid using SIM cards with the SIM-Jacker vulnerability or similar, SIM Cards with these vulnerabilities are the ones that support the S@T browser and WIB.</p><ul><li>If these SIM cards are present in the mobile network already, request the vendor to provide an appropriate software update via OTA.</li><li>Provide software updates via OTA continuously to patch know vulnerabilities.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*lRJLawGPwP-W8rPBeI_Hmw.png" /><figcaption>SEND USSD via S@T Browser</figcaption></figure><h4><strong>05.</strong> WEAK <strong>PIN</strong></h4><p>Weak pins leave the USSD based menu vulnerable to brute-forcing and guessing attacks.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>All the pins should have at least a minimum of 6 Digits for the sake of equilibrium between security and usability.</li></ul><h4><strong>06.</strong> <strong>LACK OF INPUT AND DATA VALIDATION</strong></h4><p>Improper data validation in the USSD can lead to injection attacks that can leak sensitive information. An attacker may insert specifically crafted text in the user input to perform malicious actions in the back-end server.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>All the input inserted by the end-user in the smartphone should be considered as untrusted data and should be validated before processed by the backend server.</li><li>The above should also be applied for USSD related strings from roaming interfaces.</li></ul><h4><strong>07.</strong> <strong>BROKEN ACCESS CONTROL</strong></h4><p>Broken access control occurs due to the lack of appropriate access control, and allows the user to access unauthorized resources, such as features and information.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>The agent should not send USSD strings related to the customer&#39;s features and customers should not also send USSD strings related to the agent’s features, this prevents either one of them to access unauthorized resources.</li><li>There should be a clear separation of duty and profile features between customers and agents.</li></ul><h4>08. INSUFFICIENT LOGGING AND MONITORING</h4><p>Insufficient logging and monitoring in conjunction with a non-existent or insufficient incident response allow fraudulent transactions to occur and no sufficient information will available for further investigation or even to stop the ongoing attacks.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>Monitor all the USSD request coming from roaming interfaces.</li><li>Log all attempts of account and OTP brute force attacks.</li><li>Correlate transaction location with user location either in the home or foreign network.</li><li>Validate if a SIM SWAP occurred in less than 24 hours before processing a transaction.</li></ul><h4>09. <strong>INSECURE AUTHORIZATION</strong></h4><p>Insufficient authorization can occur when an attacker is able to conduct a successful SIM SWAP fraud and logs into a mobile money account as legitimate users if the security controls are not in place at the mobile operator stores.</p><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>Prevent USSD based or any mobile money transactions(account reset and transfers) after a SIM SWAP done conducted during the last 24 hours.</li><li>Notify the end-users that a SIM SWAP was requested on their behalf via alternative contacts such as email addresses or others.</li></ul><h4>10. MISCONFIGURATION</h4><p>Security Misconfiguration occurs due to a lack of alignment between system administrators, security administrators, and other non-technical staff.</p><p>Common examples of incorrect settings are:</p><ul><li>Weak password/PIN or standard credentials that are easily guessed.</li><li>Poor error handling and error response.</li></ul><p><strong>Recommendation:</strong></p><ul><li>Force the end-user to change passwords/PIN in the USSD menu every 3 months.</li><li>Disable default passwords/PIN and force the end-user to create a new password/PIN after the first login.</li><li>Do not issue a response that gives away that the end-user is registered on the mobile money service. For example for failed login attempts, an error message should display “ Your user ID or PIN is incorrect”. This message should be available for registered and non-registered users.</li></ul><h3>CONCLUSION</h3><p>It is recommended that mobile money solution should be immune to the risks, vulnerabilities, attacks that are presented in this article at the same time it is expected that it provides the triad of security, which are confidentiality, integrity, and availability.</p><h3>REFERENCES</h3><ol><li><a href="https://www.methics.fi/2019/09/simjacker-wibattach-all-security-lost/">https://www.methics.fi/2019/09/simjacker-wibattach-all-security-lost/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.adaptivemobile.com/blog/simjacker-next-generation-spying-over-mobile">https://www.adaptivemobile.com/blog/simjacker-next-generation-spying-over-mobile</a></li><li><a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/521.html">https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/521.html</a></li><li><a href="https://www.troopers.de/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/TROOPERS13-Dirty_use_of_USSD_codes_in_cellular-Ravi_Borgaonkor.pdf">https://www.troopers.de/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/TROOPERS13-Dirty_use_of_USSD_codes_in_cellular-Ravi_Borgaonkor.pdf</a></li><li><a href="https://securityaffairs.co/wordpress/52666/hacking/gsm-crypto-hacking.html">https://securityaffairs.co/wordpress/52666/hacking/gsm-crypto-hacking.html</a></li><li><a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/blog/gsm-hijacking/11660/">https://www.kaspersky.com/blog/gsm-hijacking/11660/</a></li><li><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/gsm-decrypt-calls/">https://www.wired.com/story/gsm-decrypt-calls/</a></li></ol><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=bcd64d0a34dc" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/ussd-top-10-security-risk-for-mobile-payments-bcd64d0a34dc">USSD Top 10 Security Risk For Mobile Payments</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Top Five Technical Books And Why?]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/top-five-technical-books-and-why-1978111da8c?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1978111da8c</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[python]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 10:55:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2020-12-19T10:55:34.841Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*io9_oSJHFl2zZxiwA67B5g.png" /></figure><p>Some of the top 5 technical books I have read — December 2020 to February 2021 edition.</p><p>In my quest to become the security professional that I am today, I have learned from multiple sources and one of these key sources are the technical books that I read, apart from the RFC, online courses, and of course the articles on Medium published by very skilled security professionals.</p><p>I would like to share some of the top 5 technical books and I will continue to share more.</p><h3>1. Black Hat python, 1st Edition.</h3><p>The book is written by Justin and Tim Arnold and foreword by one of the greatest hackers in history Charlie Miller aka the guy that hacked Jeep.</p><p>The book is rich in examples of source code, showing step by step how to create tools in python and also explains the theory behind the attack and the tools that are being created. Example ARP CACHE POISONING WITH SCAPY.</p><p>This is the book that you want to use to become a skilled hacker and not a script kiddie forever. There is the second version coming out and I look forward to it.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/962/1*UfUKTxipwjb-G74IBEwUsg.png" /><figcaption>Book Cover</figcaption></figure><h3>2.CCNA Cyber OPS</h3><p>This is a Cisco certification book is written by Omar Santos and Joseph Muniz both CISSPs and Stefano De Crescenzo(CCIE), beyond being a certification guide, the book is also rich in contents related to security operation centers in short a SOC.</p><p>The books cover a topic related to threat analysis, incident response, and another topic that opens the door for one to get a job in a security operations center, and trust me it changed my life in terms of threat hunting skills.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/595/1*UKSBGWhFBiwrXbuTuRppVg.png" /><figcaption>Book Cover</figcaption></figure><h3>3. The C programming Language</h3><p>This the book for C and written by creators of C themselves Dr. Brian W Kernighan and late Dr. Dennis M. Ritchie. It is the easiest book to read and to learn C. This book gave me my degree and the programming skills to survive the computer science operating system course at University.</p><blockquote>Remember if you want to learn, learn from the best and from the purest source. — Josue Martins</blockquote><p>Above all, there wouldn’t be a Unix or C without these two brilliant minds. Therefore thank you, Dr. Brian and Dr. Dennis.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/608/1*_PouxmeEAma_wMaH2lvoUA.png" /><figcaption>Book Cover</figcaption></figure><h3>4. From GSM to LTE-Advanced Pro and 5G</h3><p><strong>An Introduction to Mobile Networks and Mobile Broadband</strong></p><p>Written by Dr. Martin Sauter. This book is one of the most resourceful books for those who are new to telecommunications or even experience engineers that would like to learn about all the mobile network generations and the protocols that govern them.</p><p>The book is rich in call flows illustrating, how the traffic from one generation affects the other and it even covers the security aspects of mobile networks with a brief introduction to 5G.</p><p>If you are a core network engineer, security professional or someone seeking a career in telecommunications, then this is the book to read.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/676/1*X4O2RuMxzcCAIZFa5FLxiA.png" /><figcaption>Book Cover</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>5. Metasploit — The Penetration Tester’s Guide</strong></h3><p>Written by David Kennedy, Jim O’Gorman, Devon Kearns, and Mati Aharoni and a foreword by HD More, This book has the in and outs of the Metasploit framework developed by the great hacker HD Moore.</p><p>The Metasploit framework is the most widely adopted tool by the most security professional and this book will guide you on how to use this tool to its fullest. The Metasploit Framework can be integrated with other great tools such as Nessus, Nmap, and others.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/734/1*5xq3j73ahfGM97-qvKJclA.png" /><figcaption>Book Cover</figcaption></figure><h3>Bring It Altogether</h3><p>These books have influenced my career and also provided me with a lot of knowledge about the topic they cover. Until today I use them as reference books, and I hope that you have fun reading them. P.S Don&#39;t be a script kiddie.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1978111da8c" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/top-five-technical-books-and-why-1978111da8c">Top Five Technical Books And Why?</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Avoid Getting Hacked By Following These Simple Steps]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/avoid-getting-hacked-by-following-these-simple-steps-da6410a801ae?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/da6410a801ae</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[hacked]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[passwords]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 16:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2020-12-06T15:10:02.215Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the digital era, we find ourselves connected to the internet all the time and from multiple devices. All these connected devices can be compromised by cybercriminals to steal sensitive data such as credit card numbers, passwords, and others.</p><p>To increase the level of difficulty for a criminal who seeks to compromise your devices and stealing your information, one can adopt the following preventive measures.</p><h3><strong>1. Enable Automatic Updates By Default</strong></h3><p>Enabling automatic updates can save you from a lot of trouble. if your devices are not running the latest software then it is vulnerable to multiples attacks that can happen when you browse a website, open malicious software, or even when you lose your device a cybercriminal can log in by finding a loophole in outdated software.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0mHHuKiqtOcaQb5_oAyGPA.png" /><figcaption>Enable automatic updates</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>2. Install Paid Antivirus</strong></h3><p>An antivirus is the first line of defense for your devices, as soon as you purchase any device make sure that you install antivirus from a legitimate source and not antivirus downloaded from torrent sites.</p><p>If you can afford to pay for antivirus go for it because paid antivirus comes with more security features that can protect your information.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/610/1*7Xjo50ZSukU6mUB3YbWNfQ.png" /><figcaption>Checkpoint Sandblast Antivirus</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>3. Use A Password Manager</strong></h3><p>Cybercriminal usually studies their targets so that they can perform social engineering attacks to extract as much information as possible. The most successful attack conducted by cybercriminals is phishing, even with sophisticated technologies the end-users still end up giving up their passwords, and with <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/understanding-sms-phishing-attacks-e617932296d2">SMS phishing</a> the cybercriminals found a new way to get the password when you are not using company devices that are protected by security professionals, therefore your smartphone.</p><p>Skilled cybercriminals are aware that most users reuse passwords and if they get the password, they get all your other accounts. The solution to this problem is to use a password manager and multifactor authentication. Most of the antivirus solutions come with a password manager but I personally prefer 1password, which is easy to use across all your devices and very affordable.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Lb293z4IPlNmwZqzbSvM8Q.png" /><figcaption>1Password</figcaption></figure><h3>4. Use Multifactor Authentification</h3><p>To improve the overall security of your accounts, you should make use of multifactor authentication, the most common authenticator apps are Google authenticator or Microsoft authenticator. The usage of multifactor authentication can add more complexity or even frustrate a cybercriminal.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/400/1*cY7nbaZLOTPKDQALxtlXKQ.png" /><figcaption>Google Authenticator app</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>5. Change The Default Passwords</strong></h3><p>As soon as you buy a new device, you should always change the default password, especially for Wifi router, cameras and other gadgets are commonly available on Amazon or eBay.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*GDkMAiSKxg8MNcFTqSkpTg.png" /><figcaption>Changing the default password</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>6. Avoid Public Wifi</strong></h3><p>Most of the cybercriminals connect to public wifi to conduct traffic interception attacks and strip the secure connection from your device to the internet to extract sensitive information or even redirect you to malicious sites under their control.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CqIoDtcS_DX_xywTwg0gPA.jpeg" /><figcaption>Free Wifi</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>7. Avoid Pirated Software</strong></h3><p>Avoid pirated software, most pirated software comes with built-in malicious software or functionality that pretends to be legitimate software with the intent to harm the end-user.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/934/1*jvSCOa2oYS3TIgTQi3G0fA.png" /><figcaption>Malicious software that steals passwords</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>8. Use Browser Extensions</strong></h3><p>Not all extensions are secure, when installing a browser extension in your browser make sure that they are verified extensions.</p><h4>The most useful extensions are :</h4><p><strong>Extensions that block’s scripts running on the web sites</strong></p><ul><li>Blocker extensions will prevent you from being hacked when you visit a compromised website that runs malicious computer code. Most of these malicious are codes run automatically and can infect your devices with malware, steal your login information, or even perform actions without you being aware of what is happening.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-Wdzvw8SQaZ9XyzKUNB2zw.png" /><figcaption>Popup Blocker</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Use Antivirus Extension</strong></p><p>Avast, Avira, and Eset have great antivirus extensions available for Chrome, Firefox, and other browsers. When using the browser with these extensions, secure websites will be marked with a green arrow, while unsecured or untrusted sites with an X.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/307/1*1ncl-HKs1ltu2dDAuasl3w.png" /><figcaption>Avast Online security extension</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/654/1*l2B1a9TGB8so2Ba6G621oA.png" /><figcaption>Secure websites</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/632/1*ICRgqJMmsMWqTFkbmJFzyA.png" /><figcaption>Untrusted website</figcaption></figure><h3><strong>9. Avoid Inserting Your Credit Card Numbers In Multiple Websites</strong></h3><p>Avoid inserting your credit card into every website that you want to use, instead, use Paypal with multifactor authentification enabled, which is much easier to control all the payments towards your credit card.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*kYwDtMNfY4y4Ed6TwuwBLw.png" /><figcaption>Paypal</figcaption></figure><h3>10. Avoid Public Charging Stations</h3><p>Cybercriminals are very creative and innovative, one of the new tactics developed by them is called Juice Jacking.</p><p>Juice jacking happens when you connect your smartphone to a charging station in the airport or in a coffee shop that hackers hooked their computer to it and hack your smartphone via the USB cable connection.</p><p>One can buy a power bank and charge your power bank in the charging stations. Once it is fully charged then you can connect your smartphone to your power bank.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/486/1*X7MYKhY5lc1XnOHW1idFmw.png" /><figcaption>Charging stations.</figcaption></figure><h3>11.Consult A Security Professional</h3><p>If you still find difficulties in following the above advice, you can always contact the security professional or continue to read the mobile security publication, which has great articles about cybersecurity.</p><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>Following the above steps won&#39;t make you hackproof in other words impossible to get hacked but it will most definitely increase the level of difficulty for a cybercriminal who intends to compromise your devices and stealing your data.</p><blockquote>Remember! if you can not beat them, frustrate them until they give up. — Josue Martins</blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=da6410a801ae" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/avoid-getting-hacked-by-following-these-simple-steps-da6410a801ae">Avoid Getting Hacked By Following These Simple Steps</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Embedded Mobile Malware — The greatest cyber weapon]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/embedded-mobile-malware-the-greatest-cyber-weapon-30aa8092d1b7?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/30aa8092d1b7</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[espionage]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[attack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[gdpr]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 17:07:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2020-12-05T21:19:41.653Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Embedded Mobile Malware — The greatest cyber weapon</h3><p>The cybersecurity and enterprise world have deep knowledge of attacks towards computers and servers running Linux or windows but not towards mobile operating systems such as Android and iOS and others.</p><p>In the digital era, most people use their smartphone to browse the internet, and bring your own device has become the norm in the workplace, but these smart devices are the victims of embedded malware developed by skilled hackers, who are willing to extract as much as information for their own financial benefit.</p><p>Most of the mobile malware creators are interested in the following information from your smartphone:</p><blockquote><strong><em>MSISDN</em></strong><em>/</em>t<em>elephone number</em></blockquote><blockquote>International Mobile Subscriber Identity/IMSI</blockquote><blockquote><em>IMEI</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Email Address</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>List of software installed in your smartphone</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>SMS(Messages) to read your Transfer authorization numer(TAN) or One time password(OTP)</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Location</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Passwords</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Documents and other personal information</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Credit card numbers</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Administrator access or privileges in the smartphones.</em></blockquote><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/866/1*DtVPTHpzPskbzktwx2RmYw.png" /><figcaption>Pieces of information that are extracted by an embedded malware</figcaption></figure><p>The above information is critical for cybercriminals to conduct all orchestrated attacks and the common types of attacks that can be conducted with the above information are:</p><blockquote><em>- Account take over</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>- Financial fraud</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>- Espionage such as location extraction, interception of calls and all texts messages towards the device</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>- Telecommunications fraud</em></blockquote><blockquote>- Selling Information of users in the Darkweb or Marketing companies</blockquote><blockquote><em>- Botnets</em></blockquote><h3>Account take over</h3><p>By collecting all the above information by using an embedded mobile malware, the attacker can use the information in the following way.</p><ol><li>Request a password request from your yahoo or email account and choosing the verification by a telephone number(MSISDN), extracted by the malware too.</li></ol><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/838/1*ohSR_6jcaOBpzegY2yKmKQ.png" /><figcaption>Google verification code, which can be read by an embedded malware</figcaption></figure><ol><li>Using the vulnerabilities in the SS7(Map ) protocol the attacker can intercept your SMS and insert it in the two-factor authentication input field in the website host your email address.</li></ol><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/674/1*yxWc8wLgoCzO9c3BSdnmfw.png" /><figcaption>Two-factor authentification with Telephone number</figcaption></figure><h3>Financial fraud</h3><p>Once a cybercriminal has the information needed to perform an account take over as explained in Account over, the cybercriminal can then proceed into transferring funds from one account to another or even extract credit card numbers to purchase goods online or sell the credit numbers on the Darkweb.</p><p>Cybercriminals normally also lock you out of all your devices to prevent you from calling your bank once your financial information has been sold or used by them.</p><h3>Espionage</h3><p>There are various ways that an individual can be spied on.</p><p>The most common methods being used are :</p><h4>Signaling Attacks</h4><p>Signaling attacks are performed by sending signaling messages from one mobile network to another to extract sensitive information from the mobile user connected to a mobile operator network.</p><p><em>SS7(MAP) Any Time Interrogation and Provide Subscribers Information to extract the location of the user in a mobile network.</em></p><p><em>SS7 (MAP) RegisterSS and other MAP messages to intercept the voice call or SMS.</em></p><p><em>Silent SMS can also be used to extract the location of a subscriber and other vulnerabilities such as the SimJacker.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/937/1*y96bJ9r6ERHdLQOMpzOYDA.png" /><figcaption>SS7 vulnerabilities reported by BBC News</figcaption></figure><p>These methods might not be as efficient as in the past due to the fact that many mobile operators are deploying a Signalling firewall to block these messages from malicious actors.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*E2Bd47lj7PfSMDbLBVDK6Q.png" /><figcaption>SS7 attacks for sale on the dark web</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hL5rs2r26qpHRmFiBYofiA.png" /><figcaption>SS7 attacks for sale in the dark web and payment is done with bitcoins</figcaption></figure><h4>Mobile Malware</h4><p>Using mobile malware is a very good method because it extracts GPS coordination of the device has the victim moves around and it is accurate as the signaling attacks and the mobile operators are not actively blocking them.</p><p>The use of mobile malware is also very active to cybercriminals because the normal smartphone users do not install antivirus solution and mobile malware can offer more that is why is the greatest weapon in by security.</p><p>The most advanced mobile malware has the following features.</p><blockquote>Recording audio and video live without the knowledge of the end user.</blockquote><blockquote>Intercepting Text,Calls and other social media software contents.</blockquote><blockquote>Provide full remote control of the device to the attacker.</blockquote><blockquote>Read the notification in the smartphone.</blockquote><blockquote>Extract location of the device continuosly in realtime or not.</blockquote><blockquote>Installing new malware on the devices.</blockquote><p>The application called Mobile Tracker Free <a href="https://mobile-tracker-free.com/">https://mobile-tracker-free.com/</a> are used for this purposes and it very cheap with a great user interface.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*l6EwANPMAs9qt161GiGCzA.png" /><figcaption>Malware extracting the location of the user</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*HGoMe8aY4cqHIrBBYjXslg.png" /><figcaption>The exact location of the user extracted by the malware</figcaption></figure><h3>Telecommunications fraud</h3><p>Apart from mobile malware being a great weapon to extract sensitive information from a smartphone, it can also be used to commit telecommunication fraud.</p><p>The most common are known as international revenue-sharing fraud.</p><p>Malware can have an SMS feature that sends SMS to or even make calls to international numbers without the knowledge of the smartphone user, most of these international numbers are associated with high charging fees.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Dw3n5GpCLDi2UZ1WKwyL3w.png" /><figcaption>SMS Malware traffic</figcaption></figure><h3>Botnets</h3><p>Mobile malware can also be used to create a botnet, and these smartphones can be controlled remotely to send all sorts of Distributed denial of service attacks(DDOS) and some of those attacks are :</p><blockquote>1.DNS Amplification attacks(DNS DDOS)</blockquote><p><em>DNS amplification is a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack in which the attacker exploits vulnerabilities in domain name system (DNS) servers to turn initially small queries into much larger payloads, which are used to bring down the victim’s servers.</em></p><blockquote>2.SIP flood atttack or SIP DDOS</blockquote><p>Is an application layer attack on the Session Initiation Protocol- SIP(in use in VoIP services), targeted <a href="https://security.radware.com/ddos-knowledge-center/DDoSPedia/dos-attack/">denial of service</a> to SIP servers. Common attack vectors include SIP invite and register floods.</p><p>This type of attack can be confused with Wangiri or Single Ring solicitation attacks because they have the same pattern in volume and the same SIP messages are used for the attack, to read more about Wangiri visit — <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/detecting-wangiri-single-ring-solicitation-calls-in-isup-traffic-411f9bff8e6a">https://medium.com/josue-martins/detecting-wangiri-single-ring-solicitation-calls-in-isup-traffic-411f9bff8e6a</a></p><blockquote>3. HTTP flood attacks</blockquote><p>An HTTP flood attack is a type of volumetric distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack designed to overwhelm a targeted server with HTTP requests. These requests can either be a GET or POST request towards the server.</p><p>Once the target has been saturated with (GET or POST)requests and it is unable to respond to normal traffic, denial-of-service will occur for additional requests from actual users.</p><h3>Bring It Altogether</h3><p>To fully protect smartphone users from all sorts of attacks mobile operators and other entities should providing end to end security solutions.</p><p>If the mobile operator has a signaling firewall in place, they should also install the Gi Firewall to block all the malicious traffic from a smartphone in the network who are trying to connect to the cybercriminal’s servers in the public internet.</p><p>In the enterprise environment companies should invest in the antivirus suite that covers both Android and iOS to actively block or prevent the end-users from being infected by malware.</p><p>Above all, let&#39;s remember that the weakest link in cybersecurity is always the human. Therefore educating smartphone users about malware and security features that everything smartphones operating systems comes with is a very important topic and should not be ignored.</p><h3>References</h3><p><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/en-gb/learning/ddos/http-flood-ddos-attack/">https://www.cloudflare.com/en-gb/learning/ddos/http-flood-ddos-attack/</a></p><p><em>DDoSPedia is a glossary that focuses on network and application security terms with many distributed denial-of-service…</em>security.radware.com</p><p><a href="https://www.computer.org/csdl/journal/tq/2014/06/06720187/13rRUwbJD6h">CSDL | IEEE Computer Society</a></p><p><a href="https://positive-tech.com/knowledge-base/research/ss7-network-security-analysis-2020/">https://positive-tech.com/knowledge-base/research/ss7-network-security-analysis-2020/</a></p><ul><li><a href="https://mobile-tracker-free.com/">Mobile Tracker Free | Cell Phone Tracker App | Monitoring App for Android Smartphone</a></li><li><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-53903436">Chinese phones with built-in malware sold in Africa</a></li><li><a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/7701227.stm">Trojan virus steals banking info</a></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-6473185586139271169-RCww">https://www.linkedin.com/posts/activity-6473185586139271169-RCww</a></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=30aa8092d1b7" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/embedded-mobile-malware-the-greatest-cyber-weapon-30aa8092d1b7">Embedded Mobile Malware — The greatest cyber weapon</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[iOS versus Android — Qual sistema operativo que é mais suscetível a infecções de vírus?]]></title>
      <link>https://medium.com/josue-martins/ios-versus-android-qual-sistema-operativo-que-%C3%A9-mais-suscet%C3%ADvel-a-infec%C3%A7%C3%B5es-de-v%C3%ADrus-5f92a1166bce?source=rss-3052ca503325------2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/5f92a1166bce</guid>
      <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[operating-systems]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile-security]]></category>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Josue Martins]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 20:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <atom:updated>2020-07-03T12:05:54.745Z</atom:updated>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*VZoaHswm3c7PWPfMnkY8xQ.jpeg" /></figure><h3>iOS versus Android — Qual sistema operativo que é mais suscetível a infecções de vírus?</h3><p>Quando fala-se de virus moveis muita gente ainda pensa que é um mito e que esses tipos de virus não existem, mas esses virus são muitos comuns e afectam todas as plataformas ou sistemas operativos.</p><p>Antes de explicar qual sistema mas suscetível a infecçōes de virus, primeiro vou falar sobres os sistemas operativos e a segurança que eles oferecem para prevenção contra esses virus.</p><h3><strong>Sistemas operativo Android</strong></h3><p>O Android é um sistema operativo de código aberto da Google, a Google permite que os fabricantes de smartphones façam alterações e personalizem a parencia do sistema operativo.<br>O Android é baseado no Linux, mas trata a comunicação entre o aplicativo e o sistema operativo de uma maneira diferente da abordagem tradicional do Linux, porque ele emprega a máquina Virtual DALVIK.</p><h3>Sistemas operativo<strong> iOS</strong></h3><p>O sistema operativo iOS é da empresa Apple ou Apple Computers que é baseado no Mac OSX . Esse sistema operativo não é de código aberto, mas é proprietário da Apple e é executado apenas em dispositivos desta empresa.</p><h4><strong>Como é que os smartphones são infectados por um vírus?</strong></h4><p><strong>Existem quatro métodos, que são :</strong></p><ul><li>Via lojas oficiais.</li><li>Lojas não oficiais ou sites piratas.</li><li>Exploração remota de um invasor que instala virus no dispositivo.</li><li>Dispositivo com virus embutidos.</li></ul><p><strong>1.Via App Stores oficiais</strong></p><p>Devido às fraquezas detectadas por cibercriminosos no processo de verificação de aplicativos móveis da Apple e da Google, alguns desenvolvedores ou criadores de virus usam códigos tão bem criado que o aplicativo malicioso consegue escapar do processo de verificação das lojas oficias , e um dos virus mais famoso com essa habilidade foi o Anubis Malware e o famoso programa Tik-Tok.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/722/1*iPX4s5U_rQoFMBKMQxwbcA.png" /><figcaption>Tik-Tok</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/603/1*NQLaJisoDpBwR8qFYYA6fQ.png" /><figcaption>Virus para Android e iOS</figcaption></figure><p><strong>2. App Stores que não são oficiais ou sites piratas</strong></p><p>Os sites piratas são famosos por oferecer jogos grátis, conteúdo adulto e aplicativo com recursos premium.</p><p>A maioria esses aplicativos e conteúdos foram infectados com malware que explorará as fraqueza dos smarphones de todas as maneiras possíveis, como fazer chamadas, enviar SMS para números internacionais, transformar o seu smartphone em um robó controlado por criminosos ciberneticos, ler os seus códigos de autenticação/ código de dois fatores (2FA), roubar suas credenciais de varias contas e outras informações pessoais que podem ser usadas para ataques contra a tua pessoa.</p><p>As imagens abaixo são do viru chamado smartworld, este é o hash do viru 5db5b4a563106e9a1b7c502e271f40224bb40cdbe678553dd90fc0335204af7e.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/517/1*Bz2vJHMsmWFecn3WrYPwjQ.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/525/1*zpQcTdwpxcNtjyjFq9nRHw.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/532/1*tQgPP7VHOdUmZxevh7_FDg.png" /><figcaption>Imagens do virus smartworld</figcaption></figure><p><strong>3. A exploração remota de invasor/criminosos ciberneticos que instalam um virus no dispositivo</strong></p><p>Devido a muitas vulnerabilidades no Android e o iOS, os dispositivos são explorados remotamente por falta de atualizações de software e sistemas operativos fornecidas pelos fabricantes e os criadores de aplicativos móveis.<br>Uma das ferramentas mais usadas para infectar ou invadir remotamente o smartphone é o Metasploit framework desenvolvido por HD Moore.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*JHht1mmjQG9pvL7drSReHA.png" /><figcaption>Metasploit</figcaption></figure><p><strong>4. Dispositivo com virus embutidos</strong></p><p>Muitos fabricantes, empresas ou grupos do crime organizado procuram explorar e infectar smartphones para realizar vários tipos de ataques e extrair informações confidencias para vender a empresas de publicidade ou intidades governamentais; portanto, eles encontram maneiras de embutir virus nos dispositivos na fábrica ou interceptam os caminhões de entrega de smartphones para inserir esses programas maliciosos antes de ser vendido ao usuário final.<br>Apos da compra do smartphone nas lojas, os usuários não percebem que são proprietários de dispositivos infectados.Essa prática tem sido muito comum nos smartphones proveniente da China ou o mercado negro.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*ZIT11WLwwgvE-d1zMLboCg.png" /><figcaption>Google Protect dectando o programa malicioso embutido no dispositivo</figcaption></figure><p><strong>No proximo artigo vou falar mais sobre dispositivo com programa maliciosos embutidos.</strong></p><h3><strong>Conclusão</strong></h3><p>O Android é o sistema operativo que é mais suceptivel a infecções de vírus devido à sua natureza de codigo aberto e ao processo de verificação de aplicativos menos rigoroso em comparação com o processo de verificação da Apple.</p><p>O processo de verificação da Google melhorou nos dois últimos anos com a adesão do Google protect que examina peoridicamente os smartphone Android em busca de virus e, além disso, A Google fez uma parceira com as seguintes empresas: Lookout, Zimperium e Eset a fim de criar a App Defense Aliance que tem a missão de melhorar a detecção de virus no Google Playstore.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/790/1*dgKT-CuT4xcO7BQw6m8oGw.png" /><figcaption>Google Play Protect</figcaption></figure><p>Acima de tudo gostaria de realçar que os dois sistemas operativos ​​ oferecem proteções embutidas como o ASRL, encripção de dados , permissões para aceder certas funções , fornecem actualizações de softwares com frequência e muito mais.</p><p><strong>Segundo a empresa Zimperium as estatisticas de 2019 diz que </strong>“ <em>A Apple corrigiu 185 CVEs (Vulnerabilidades e Exposições Comuns), um aumento de 120 durante o mesmo período do ano passado. Cerca de 62% dos CVEs foram considerados riscos “críticos” à segurança, enquanto 25% foram considerados riscos moderados e 13% foram considerados de baixo risco.<br>O Android corrigiu 255 CVEs na primeira metade do ano, uma redução em relação aos 492 do ano anterior, segundo o relatório. Apenas 20% dos CVEs do Android foram classificados como “críticos”, enquanto 79% foram considerados de alto risco e 2% foram considerados de baixo risco</em>.”</p><p><strong>A segurança do seu smartphone depende do fabricante e de ti , abaixo estão algumas medidas que tu deves tomar para garantir tua segurança:</strong></p><ol><li>Active as actualizações automáticas dos sistemas operativo do seu smartphone, independentemente de ser Android ou iOS.</li><li>Habilite actualizações automáticas para todos os aplicativos em execução no teu smartphone.</li><li>Use antivírus para smartphones.</li><li>Não use estação de carregar smartphones pública/ public smartphones charging station.</li><li>Não use Wifi público/ Ponto de acesso publico.</li><li>Não faça root ou Jailbreak o teu smartphone.</li></ol><p>Os cibercriminosos estão muito interessados em atacar os smartphones de políticos, celebridades, CEOs e outros pessoas com informações de valores financeiros ou do interesse deles. Portanto seja seguro e cauteloso.</p><p>Referencias</p><ol><li>( <a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/google-play-protect-eset-lookout-zimperium-app-defense-alliance-store/">https://www.xda-developers.com/google-play-protect-eset-lookout-zimperium-app-defense-alliance-store/</a>).</li><li><a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/ios-and-android-patched-440-security-vulnerabilities-in-2019-so-far/">https://www.techrepublic.com/article/ios-and-android-patched-440-security-vulnerabilities-in-2019-so-far/</a></li><li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/06/tiktok-and-53-other-ios-apps-still-snoop-your-sensitive-clipboard-data/">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/06/tiktok-and-53-other-ios-apps-still-snoop-your-sensitive-clipboard-data/</a></li></ol><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=5f92a1166bce" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins/ios-versus-android-qual-sistema-operativo-que-%C3%A9-mais-suscet%C3%ADvel-a-infec%C3%A7%C3%B5es-de-v%C3%ADrus-5f92a1166bce">iOS versus Android — Qual sistema operativo que é mais suscetível a infecções de vírus?</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/josue-martins">Mobile Security</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>