<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
    <description>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</description>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rawstory.com/feeds/world.rss" rel="self">
    </atom:link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:12:08 -0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNDk4MDQwMC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTcwODk2ODc0NH0.CAuDKCrYnLogkIrRCoHwZj7vOQ_5oq7DyFBijbdG0dE/image.jpg?width=210</url>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
      <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Trump suggested 'secret' missile strike on Mexico in 2020: Former Pentagon chief</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/trump-suggested-firing-missiles-into-mexico-in-2020-former-pentagon-chief/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/trump-tries-to-take-credit-for-firing-top-adviser-who-said-he-quit-over-megyn-kelly-food-fight.jpg?id=24720193&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C15%2C0%2C15&height=600"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/mark-esper-book-blocked/">The forthcoming book</a> by Trump-era Secretary of Defense Mark Esper reveals a discussion of attacking Mexico late in the administration.</p><p>"Former President Donald J. Trump asked Mark T. Esper, his defense secretary, about the possibility of launching missiles into Mexico to 'destroy the drug labs' and wipe out the cartels, maintaining that the United States’ involvement in a strike against its southern neighbor could be kept secret, Mr. Esper recounts in his upcoming memoir," Maggie Haberman <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/05/us/politics/mark-esper-book.html" target="_blank">reported</a> for <em>The New York Times. </em>"Those remarkable discussions in 2020 were among several moments that Mr. Esper described in the book, <em>A Sacred Oath</em>, as leaving him all but speechless when he served the 45th president."</p><p>The book says Trump asked at least twice if the military could "shoot missiles into Mexico to destroy the drug labs."</p><p>Esper served as secretary of defense until Nov. 9, 2020 when Trump announced in a tweet he had been "<a href="https://www.rawstory.com/2020/11/trump-abruptly-fires-defense-secretary-mark-esper-after-reports-surface-about-his-resignation-letter/" target="_blank">terminated</a>."</p><p>"Mr. Esper, the last Senate-confirmed defense secretary under Mr. Trump, also had concerns about speculation that the president might misuse the military around Election Day by, for instance, having soldiers seize ballot boxes. He warned subordinates to be on alert for unusual calls from the White House in the lead-up to the election," the newspaper reported. "Mr. Esper describes an administration completely overtaken by concerns about Mr. Trump’s re-election campaign, with every decision tethered to that objective. He writes that he could have resigned, and weighed the idea several times, but that he believed the president was surrounded by so many yes-men and people whispering dangerous ideas to him that a loyalist would have been put in Mr. Esper’s place."</p><p>Esper says Trump even knew the exact missile he wanted to use, although he listed one from America's missile defense system. And Trump also suggested just brazenly lying about the military strike.</p><p>"When Mr. Esper raised various objections, Mr. Trump said that 'we could just shoot some Patriot missiles and take out the labs, quietly,' adding that 'no one would know it was us.' Mr. Trump said he would just say that the United States had not conducted the strike, Mr. Esper recounts, writing that he would have thought it was a joke had he not been staring Mr. Trump in the face," the newspaper reported. "Mr. Esper writes that he never believed Mr. Trump’s conduct rose to the level of needing to invoke the 25th Amendment. He also strains to give Mr. Trump credit where he thinks he deserves it. Nonetheless, Mr. Esper paints a portrait of someone not in control of his emotions or his thought process throughout 2020."</p><p>The book is scheduled to hit bookstore shelves on Tuesday.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/trump-suggested-firing-missiles-into-mexico-in-2020-former-pentagon-chief/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Bob Brigham</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/trump-tries-to-take-credit-for-firing-top-adviser-who-said-he-quit-over-megyn-kelly-food-fight.jpg?id=24720193&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three killed in attack in central Israel's Elad</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/three-killed-in-in-central-israel-s-elad/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766234&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C50&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>At least three people were killed in an attack in the central Israeli city of Elad as the Jewish state marked its independence day on Thursday, following a brief lull in deadly unrest.</p><p>The Magen David Adom emergency response service, which confirmed the deaths, said two others were in a serious condition after the incident, which comes following a series of fatal attacks committed by Palestinians and Israeli Arabs in recent weeks.</p><p>Two others suffered moderate or light injuries, according to the MDA, which is Israel's version of the Red Cross.</p><p>Police said a manhunt had been launched, including helicopters and roadblocks, to find a vehicle that had fled the scene, without providing details on the alleged perpetrators.</p><p>Police said that it appeared the attack had played out at several spots in one area.MDA Paramedic Alon Rizkan, a first responder, described it as a "complex scene," identifying all of the dead as men in their early 40s.</p><p>Those who suffered serious injuries men aged between 35-60, according to the MDA.</p><p>The majority of Elad's 50,000 residents are members of Israel's ultra-Orthodox Jewish community, known as haredim.</p><p>Another majority haredi city, Bnei Brak, which also lies on the outskirts of the coastal city of Tel Aviv, was targeted in March.</p><p>It was one of the areas hit in the string of attacks since March 22 that, prior to Thursday's incident, had killed 15 people including an Arab-Israeli police officer and two Ukrainians, in separate attacks inside Israel.</p><p>Two of the deadly attacks were carried out in the Tel Aviv area by Palestinians.</p><p>A total of 27 Palestinians and three Israeli Arabs have died during the same period, among them perpetrators of attacks and those killed by Israeli security forces in West Bank operations.</p><p>For Palestinians, the anniversary of Israel's 1948 declaration of independence marks the Nakba, or "catastrophe", when more than 700,000 fled or were expelled during the war surrounding Israel's creation.</p><p>Hamas Islamists who control the Gaza strip and Islamic Jihad, another Palestinian armed group, praised the Elad attack as a consequence of unrest at Jerusalem's Al-Aqsa mosque compound.</p><p>Fresh clashes broke out at earlier Thursday at Al-Aqsa, which is also the holiest site in Judaism, where it is known as the Temple Mount.</p><p>The latest morning violence at the flashpoint site came following a tense April, in which nearly 300 people were injured in clashes between police and Palestinians at Al-Aqsa.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/three-killed-in-in-central-israel-s-elad/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766234&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombian drug lord 'Otoniel' pleads not guilty in US court</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/colombian-lord-otoniel-pleads-not-guilty-in-us-court/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766230&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C50&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>One of Colombia's most notorious drug lords pleaded not guilty to trafficking charges in a New York court Thursday following his extradition to the United States.</p><p>Dairo Antonio Usuga, known as "Otoniel," did not ask for bail during the arraignment in Brooklyn.</p><p>The 50-year-old Usuga was the leader of Colombia's largest narco-trafficking gang, known as the Gulf Clan.</p><p>The United States accuses Usuga and the Gulf Clan of illegally bringing at least 73 tons of cocaine into the country between 2003 and 2012.</p><p>He was the most-wanted person in Colombia until he was arrested last October in the northwest of the country after a massive military operation.</p><p>On Wednesday afternoon, a convoy of five bulletproof police vehicles transported him from a prison in the capital Bogota to a military airport, where he was handed over to US Drug Enforcement Administration officials.</p><p>He landed in New York around 11:30 PM (0330 GMT Thursday).</p><p>Usuga wore orange prison garb and was handcuffed during his first appearance in the Brooklyn federal court.</p><p>He has been charged with criminal enterprise and international cocaine manufacturing and distribution.</p><p>Usuga asked to be held in detention until his trial and judge Vera Scanlon set a date of June 2 for the defendant's next court appearance.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/colombian-lord-otoniel-pleads-not-guilty-in-us-court/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766230&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia probably won't use nukes — but it looks more likely they might now: Harvard professor</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-russia-nuclear-possibilities/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C109%2C0%2C110&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The Russian invasion of Ukraine took a turn on Feb. 27 when President Vladimir Putin put Russia’s nuclear forces on alert. International and military experts were cautious but dismissive that he would go that far.  </p><p>"I don't think that the Russian leadership and Putin are irrational actors," John Erath, senior policy director for the Center for Arms Control and Non-Proliferation, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/putin-still-rational-man-who-wont-use-nuclear-weapons-top-experts-say-1687297" target="_blank">told Newsweek on March 12</a>. "The use of a nuclear weapon would lead to the possibility of a response that would be disastrous for all."</p><p>"In my opinion, he is rational. Given that he is rational, I strongly believe he will not intentionally use nuclear weapons against the West. I say intentionally because indiscriminate shelling near a nuclear power plant can cause an unintentional nuclear disaster in Ukraine," said former Russian Minister of Foreign Affairs Andrei Kozyrev, who served from 1990 to 1996. <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/putin-isnt-insane-and-wont-use-nuclear-weapons-says-ex-russian-foreign-minister-161816208.html" target="_blank">That was on March 7. </a></p><p>Just under two months later, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/05/03/russia-ireland-nuclear-weapons-video-ukraine/" target="_blank">Russia pushed out a video</a> showing Britain and Ireland being blown up by a nuclear bomb. </p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/trump-loving-candidate-blames-special-state-house-election-loss-on-coup-from-rino-establishment/" target="_self">Trump-loving candidate blames election loss on 'coup' from 'RINO establishment'</a></em></strong></p><p><span></span>It prompted Harvard international affairs <a href="https://twitter.com/stephenWalt/status/1522297673587605504" target="_blank">Professor Stephen Walt to say</a> that he still doesn't believe that Putin will break out the nukes, "but I am more worried about it than I was a couple of months ago."</p><p>Writing for <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/05/05/why-washington-should-take-russian-nuclear-threats-seriously/?tpcc=recirc_latest062921" target="_blank">ForeignPolicy.com he explained</a> that when he was speaking about the war back in February that he found the idea difficult to believe. "To its credit, the Biden administration has been somewhat mindful of the risk of escalation," he wrote on Thursday. </p><p>The initial thought was that as long as the United States keeps troops from going into a ground war and shooting at Russian soldiers, Putin wouldn't be triggered into a fury. Now it seems he might be crazier than was anticipated. </p><p>"To be clear: I have no idea if anyone in the Kremlin is thinking seriously along those lines, and this point is <em>not</em> an argument for sending U.S. troops to Ukraine as a deterrent shield," wrote Walt. "My point is that keeping American personnel out of the fight does not eliminate all incentives to escalate, and it might make nuclear use appear less risky if those other incentives began to loom large in Moscow’s calculations."</p><p><strong><em>READ MORE: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ted-cruz-and-sheldon-whitehouse-clash/" target="_self">Ted Cruz and Sheldon Whitehouse clash at hearing: ‘If you’re going to criticize my brief – read it!’</a></em></strong></p><p>There's also a concern because of Putin's tendency to make good on his threats. There was his 2008 demand Ukraine and Georgia never be part of NATO. An attack broke out and it's kept Georgia away ever since. He went on to threaten Ukraine in 2014 and ultimately invaded and took over Crimea. In 2021, he warned Ukraine they better not take weapons from the west, and when they did he staged his troops on the border. </p><p>The U.S. cowboy bravado is easy. "Just blow him up" is emotionally appealing as the horrifying images and videos roll in from Ukraine. </p><p>"Many would like to punish Putin for the suffering he’s inflicted on Ukraine," Walt explained. "Unfortunately, trying to inflict a decisive defeat on Russia creates precisely the circumstances that would encourage a rational leader to contemplate other options, such as a demonstration strike with a small nuclear weapon. The purpose of such an action would be what the late theorist Thomas Schelling <a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300246742/arms-and-influence/" target="_blank">called</a> a 'competition in risk-taking': one side takes an obviously dangerous action in order to demonstrate how much it cares about the issue at hand, and to persuade its opponent(s) to back off."</p><p>There's an ongoing concern that if Putin thinks he's losing, his willingness to go to the extreme deepens. After all, if he's going to be removed from power or Russia is about to collapse, why wouldn't a man with nothing left to lose embrace mutually assured destruction? </p><p><strong><em>RELATED: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/putin-apologized-for-russia-hitler-claims-israel-pm-s-office/" target="_self">Putin apologized for Russia Hitler claims</a></em></strong></p><p>"It would be a gamble for sure, but he’s gambled before," wrote Walt. "And he probably cares more about avoiding those outcomes than the opposing coalition cares about inflicting them on him. He won’t order a large-scale nuclear attack, because that would be suicidal, but a demonstration strike against a non-nuclear adversary, though not without serious risks, is another matter."</p><p><a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/05/05/why-washington-should-take-russian-nuclear-threats-seriously/" target="_blank">Read the full column at ForeignPolicy.com. </a></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-russia-nuclear-possibilities/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sarah K. Burris</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin apologized for Russia Hitler claims: Israel PM's office</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-apologized-for-russia-hitler-claims-israel-pm-s-office/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/putin-urges-better-us-russia-ties-then-vilifies-west.jpg?id=24837417&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C52%2C0%2C53&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Israel's Prime Minister Naftali Bennett said Thursday that Russian leader Vladimir Putin has apologized for remarks made by Moscow's top diplomat, Sergei Lavrov, who claimed Adolf Hitler may have had "Jewish blood".</p><p>The comments had sparked outrage in the Jewish state.</p><p>"The Prime Minister accepted President Putin's apology for Lavrov's remarks and thanked him for clarifying his attitude towards the Jewish people and the memory of the Holocaust," Bennett's office said in a statement.</p><p>A Kremlin summary of the Bennett-Putin call, which came as Israel marked 74 years since the creation of the Jewish state, made no mention of a Putin apology.</p><p>It did, however, note that the leaders discussed the "historic memory" of the holocaust.</p><p>In an interview with an Italian media outlet released on Sunday, Lavrov claimed that Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky "puts forward an argument of what kind of Nazism can they have if he himself is Jewish".</p><p>Lavrov, according to a transcript posted on the Russian foreign ministry website, then added: "I could be wrong, but Hitler also had Jewish blood".</p><p>Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid labelled the comments "an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error."</p><p>Bennett denounced the comments as "lies"that he said effectively "accuse the Jews themselves of the most awful crimes in history", perpetrated against themselves.</p><p>Russia's ambassador to Israel was summoned to "clarify" the remarks.</p><p>Israel has sought to tread a delicate line since Russia invaded Ukraine in February, with Bennett stressing Israel's close ties to both Moscow and Kyiv.</p><p>Bennett has in particular sought to preserve Russian cooperation with Israeli strikes in Syria, where Russian forces are on the ground.</p><p>Israel has so far refused Ukraine's requests for military support, instead suppling bullet proof vests and helmets for medical workers, as well as an Israeli field hospital.</p><p>Bennett has attempted to mediate in the conflict and is among a handful of world leaders to meet with Putin since the invasion, traveling to Moscow in early March.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-apologized-for-russia-hitler-claims-israel-pm-s-office/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/putin-urges-better-us-russia-ties-then-vilifies-west.jpg?id=24837417&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Armed gang robs Chanel boutique in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/armed-gang-robs-chanel-boutique-in-paris/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-chanel-outlet-is-one-of-many-high-end-jewelry-stores-in-the-place-vendome-neighborhood-bertrand-guay-afp-file.jpg?id=29764878&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C93%2C0%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>An armed gang on Thursday robbed a Chanel watch and jewelry store near the swanky Place Vendome in central Paris in broad daylight, police told AFP.</p><p>Nobody was hurt during the heist, and there was no immediate indication of the bounty's value.</p><p>Police said at least one of the four, who were all masked and wore helmets, carried an assault rifle, with a witness saying that the others also had automatic weapons.</p><p>They made their getaway on two motorbikes in a scene that was filmed by a bystander and widely shared on social media.</p><p>The clip shows three people dressed in black leaving the boutique while a fourth, carrying an assault rifle on a shoulder strap, waited on a motorcycle.</p><p>A witness, 26-year-old Anastasia Martino who works in a clothes store across from Chanel said she was on a cigarette break when she noticed "a man with a Kalashnikov on a motorbike", at around 2:30 pm (1230 GMT).</p><p>"Two minutes later, three other men left the boutique carrying big black bags. They, too, had automatic weapons, got on two motorbikes and left in a hurry."</p><p><img alt="Police cordoned off the area shortly after the robbery" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"/>Police cordoned off the area shortly after the robbery Bertrand GUAY AFP</p><p>Her colleague, 31-year-old Cyril Ngo, said the heist lasted a full 10 minutes. "These weren't professionals," he said.</p><p>The Chanel shop is located on Rue de La Paix, close to Place Vendome, an area with a high concentration of luxury jewelry stores.</p><p>Police cordoned off the area shortly after the robbery, and the store was shuttered.</p><p>Chanel, founded in 1910 by Coco Chanel, is one of France's leading fashion houses, selling haute couture and ready-to-wear clothes, perfumes, accessories and other luxury items.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/armed-gang-robs-chanel-boutique-in-paris/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-chanel-outlet-is-one-of-many-high-end-jewelry-stores-in-the-place-vendome-neighborhood-bertrand-guay-afp-file.jpg?id=29764878&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plane turns around after pilot reveals he's not qualified</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/airlines-pilots-training-problems/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/airline-pilots.jpg?id=27282314&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C25%2C0%2C25&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>A pilot was reportedly flying a Virgin Atlantic aircraft from London to New York City when he turned around mid-flight after revealing to coworkers that he was not qualified to fly.</p><p><a href="https://www.tmz.com/2022/05/05/virgin-atlantic-jet-turns-back-co-pilot-unqualified-to-fly/" target="_blank">TMZ posted the story </a>Thursday saying that the transatlantic flight was packed with passengers when, after the jumbo jet took off and the copilot revealed he hadn't actually taken his final test.</p><p>"Virgin Atlantic has made us aware of the incident. Both pilots were suitably licensed and qualified to undertake the flight," said the company. </p><p>Three hours later, the airline found an alternate pilot, which also wouldn't have been necessary if the airline believed the pilot was "suitably licensed and qualified."</p><p><strong>READ MORE: </strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/christian-smalls-senate/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Watch: Amazon union organizer schools Lindsey Graham after he complains about US businesses being mistreated"><strong>Watch: Amazon union organizer schools Lindsey Graham after he complains about US businesses being mistreated</strong></a></p><p>There's currently a pilot shortage, <a href="https://skift.com/2022/05/03/u-s-transportation-secretary-pitches-federal-support-to-ease-pilot-shortage/" target="_blank">which Secretary Pete Buttigieg addressed</a> earlier this week when speaking to a Senate committee.</p><p>“There won’t be a quick fix but we’ve got to work on shoring up that domestic aviation workforce," he explained.</p><p>It isn't a new problem, but the pandemic certainly <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/millions-travel-across-us-as-airlines-cancel-flights-over/" target="_blank">made things worse</a>. </p><p>“We think it’s related to a number of issues from the pipeline in to the thinning out of workforces that happened during the worst periods of Covid-related <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/over-4500-flights-cancelled-by-christmas-day-as-omicron-hits-holiday-travel/" target="_blank">flight cancellations</a>, to some questions about pay and conditions,” he said.</p><p><strong>IN OTHER NEWS: </strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/mcconnell-roe-v-wade/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Republicans worked for years to overturn Roe -- but now they're afraid to talk about it: analysis"><strong>Republicans worked for years to overturn Roe -- but now they're afraid to talk about it: analysis</strong></a></p><p>Flight hour requirements for an airline transport pilot certification in the United States is currently set at 1,500, which some companies think is excessive. It's one of the main reasons that Air Force pilots are heavily recruited in the airlines, because they have documented training and flight requirements already. </p><p>The hour requirement was once set at 250, but was changed after the 2009 crash of <a href="https://buffalonews.com/news/local/12-years-after-flight-3407-crash-that-killed-50-pilot-record-database-gets-approval/article_4dca461a-bd69-11eb-a63f-3b22149326c2.html" target="_blank">Colgan Air Flight 3407</a> near Buffalo, in which killed all passengers and crew were killed, as well as one person on the ground.</p><p>Southwest, American and United are all heavily recruiting new pilots with websites specifically citing "<a href="https://careers.southwestair.com/pilots" target="_blank">first officer opportunities</a>." United particularly, said that they intend to hire more than <a href="https://unitedaviate.com/" target="_blank">10,000 new pilots</a> over the decade.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/airlines-pilots-training-problems/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sarah K. Burris</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/airline-pilots.jpg?id=27282314&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African students fleeing Ukraine endure hardship in France</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/african-students-fleeing-ukraine-endure-hardship-in-france/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/ukrainians-and-foreign-residents-wait-for-trains-inside-lviv-railway-station-on-february-28-2022-in-lviv-west-ukraine-c-bernat-armangue-ap.jpg?id=29764632&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C14%2C0%2C141&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Since the start of the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, more than 5.5 million people have fled the country of which more than 50,000 have been welcomed by France. These refugees have been granted temporary status that entitles them to work and receive social and medical assistance.</p><p>However, foreign students who were living in <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/tag/ukraine/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ukraine</a> and who were also forced to flee have been exempted from this scheme – and they now find themselves in a complicated situation that risks jeopardizing their university studies and, possibly, their professional careers.</p><p>When he fled the port city of Odesa a few days after the start of the war in Ukraine, Merdi couldn’t have imagined his journey would turn into an obstacle course with the goal being to stay in France. “We thought <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/tag/france/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">France</a> would welcome us, but that is not the case. They tell us we don't have a nationality – that we were in Ukraine only to study and now we have to go home,” said the 26-year-old Congolese student, who arrived in France on March 11. </p><p>Merdi's case is not an isolated one. According to the Union des étudiants exiles (Union of exiled students) and the France Fraternités union, there are around 1,000 foreign students who have fled Ukraine and are experiencing the same difficulties staying in France.</p><p>The crux of the problem is administrative and dates back to early March, when many European Union countries pledged to move quickly to help those fleeing the conflict in Ukraine. France decided to implement the EU’s <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/FR/ALL/?uri=celex:32001L0055" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">“temporary protection directive”</a>, aimed at aiding displaced persons. Valid for three months, it grants several protections to refugees, including the right to a place of residence as well as access to jobs, education, and social and medical assistance.</p><p>But the foreign students living in Ukraine were excluded from this emergency measure.</p><p>“France excluded foreign students from the temporary protection measures by giving them a one-month residence permit instead,” said Pierre Henry, president of the France Fraternités union. The rationale being that, “their countries are not at war, so they can go home”.</p><p>Sabar, an Algerian student who fled Lviv when the war started, also found himself in difficulty upon his arrival in France. “The prefecture gave me just a one-month residence permit. Now, they want me to return to Algeria. But I don't want to – I spent a lot of money to go to Ukraine, study and get my diploma,” the 25-year-old said.</p><h2><strong>‘The Kafkaesque option’</strong></h2><p>After arriving in Paris on March 14, Sabar endured two days of hardship before finding a hotel that welcomed refugees. “I slept outside near a train station,” he said. </p><p>Now trapped in an administrative quagmire, he just wants to continue his studies in France. “I tried to enroll in several universities in Paris, Marseille, Lyon, Strasbourg and Bordeaux. But they didn't reply.”</p><p>“They are going to tell me that if I want a six-month residence permit to be able to stay, I will have to be registered at a university or have a guarantee of employment. My problem is that I haven't found anything in a month. But I don't want to leave,” Sabar said.</p><p>The same goes for Merdi, who just wants to continue his studies abroad. “I am afraid that I will be told to go back to Congo. If I can, I would like to continue my studies at a university here. That’s the only thing I want.”</p><p>The plight of African students who have fled Ukraine has spurred many in France to action. Among them is a group of university presidents and lecturers who are alarmed by their circumstances. </p><p>In a contribution published in “Le Monde” newspaper in April, the academics called for France to “continue educating the students that Ukraine chose to welcome”. Leftist student political organizations, such as Le Poing Levé (Raised Fist), are trying to increase the pressure on university presidents to enroll these students who find themselves caught in the middle of world affairs.</p><p>"It is an absurd situation,” Henry said. “We have chosen the Kafkaesque option rather than offering protection for all.”</p><p>He said these students, who have no intention of returning home, will soon find themselves in very precarious circumstances on French territory.</p><p>“It is a real waste, because these are French-speaking students. Since half of their education is already complete and considering their professional prospects have been totally destroyed by the war, the logical thing would be to allow them to register in France and continue their studies,” he added.</p><p>Some universities are, however, beginning to change their position and accept foreign students. “Twenty or so are in the pre-registration phase and taking applications,” Mathieu Schneider, president of the <a href="https://www.campusfrance.org/en/migrants-higher-education-french-education-network" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Migrants in Higher Education network</a> of French institutions, told “Les Echos Start” media on April 19.</p><h2><strong>‘Everyone is a victim of this war’</strong></h2><p>The administrative status of students caught up in this situation remains up in the air. France’s prefectures, which handle immigration applications, favor taking a case-by-case approach, with decisions seeming to vary from one regional administration to another. </p><p>Several people, including a Congolese student living in Aveyron, said they had received provisional residence permits good for several months instead of for just one (which remains the official rule). </p><p>So which requirements currently prevail? Contacted by FRANCE 24, the French ministry of the interior detailed the arrangements available to people eligible for temporary protection, notably through <a href="https://www.campusfrance.org/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Campus France</a>, which allows eligible people to apply to enroll in French higher education.</p><p>Regarding the situation being faced by foreign students in France, the ministry said the treatment of third-country nationals is part of the EU Council’s temporary protection directive, noting: “If a third-country national is not eligible for temporary protection, he or she should return to his or her country of origin.” </p><p>However, other countries, including Portugal and Spain, have chosen to adapt the EU framework and welcome all those fleeing Ukraine.</p><p>The Council of Europe has been alarmed by the varied treatments displaced people are getting in EU member states. A report published at the beginning of April referred to a “double standard” in the reception of refugees, asylum seekers and migrants depending on their country of origin.</p><p>Foreign students thus either have to relocate to those countries that have decided to universally welcome those fleeing Ukraine or return to their countries of origin. The other option is to apply for asylum or a residence permit, provided they meet the required conditions, and hope for the best.<br/></p><p>Sabar and Merdi have an appointment at the prefecture in the next few days to find out what their future holds. The young Algerian says continuing his studies and staying in France is “the best thing that can happen”.</p><p>Merdi still does not understand why he is being treated differently from another refugee: “No one wanted to leave Ukraine to come to France. It's not our fault. It's the war that caused all of these problems. Everyone is a victim of this war.”</p><p>“It’s the Ukrainians’ country, but we also lived there,” he said. “We paid for university. We have the right to be treated like them. There should be no difference.”</p><p><em>This article has been translated from the <a href="https://www.france24.com/fr/france/20220504-une-situation-absurde-la-gal%C3%A8re-des-%C3%A9tudiants-africains-en-france-apr%C3%A8s-avoir-fui-l-ukraine" target="_blank">original in French</a>.</em> </p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 16:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/african-students-fleeing-ukraine-endure-hardship-in-france/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/ukrainians-and-foreign-residents-wait-for-trains-inside-lviv-railway-station-on-february-28-2022-in-lviv-west-ukraine-c-bernat-armangue-ap.jpg?id=29764632&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin's military slammed by retired general on CNN: 'Ukrainians are beating them in every possible way!'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657269957/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-president-vladimir-putin-c-yuri-kochetkov-afp.jpg?id=29546190&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C32%2C0%2C33&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The Russian military last month shifted tactics in its <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-ukraine-putin/" target="_blank">war against Ukraine</a> to focus more on the eastern part of the country -- but American intelligence reports indicate they're seeing setbacks there as well.</p><p>Appearing on CNN Thursday, Ret. Brig. Gen. Steve Anderson broke down just why Russia still hasn't found its footing in Ukraine two months into its unprovoked invasion.</p><p>"The Russians have a flawed strategy," he said. "They're attacking along an 800-mile front, and not just a couple of main axes of advance, to which they could overwhelm with artillery and their superior numbers in tanks and mechanized vehicles... he who attacks everywhere attacks nowhere. They essentially have flawed logistics, flawed strategy."</p><p>Anderson then went on to compare the state of Russia's military to Ukraine's -- and the comparison was not flattering.</p><p><strong>RELATED: </strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-spy-ukraine/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: He 'drove himself into a dead end': Ukraine's top spy makes bold prediction about Vladimir Putin"><strong>He 'drove himself into a dead end': Ukraine's top spy makes bold prediction about Vladimir Putin</strong></a></p><p>"Their soldiers, morale, and leadership is poor," he said. "<a href="https://www.rawstory.com/american-intel-used-to-russian-generals-in-ukraine-us-officials/" target="_blank">The generals are getting killed</a>. The Ukrainians are beating them in every possible way, with their will to fight, their superior logistics, their superior leadership, and their superior execution of an active mobile defense, which thus far is carrying the day."</p><p>Later in the segment, former national security official Andrea Kendall-Taylor predicted that Putin at some point in the future realize he has no way of holding Ukraine and would instead use state media to hype up some kind of "shambolic victory" that he could tout despite having failed to achieve his main objectives.</p><p><em>Watch the video below or <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657269957/" target="_blank">at this link</a></em><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657269957/"></a>.<br/></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b6be84fdf4c146a7a4373bb8cbb47b48" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QzFdKzNNFqg?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Putin's military torched by retired general</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QzFdKzNNFqg" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 15:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657269957/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Brad Reed</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-president-vladimir-putin-c-yuri-kochetkov-afp.jpg?id=29546190&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>He 'drove himself into a dead end': Ukraine's top spy makes bold prediction about Vladimir Putin</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-spy-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin.jpg?id=29548571&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C25%2C0%2C25&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The head of Ukraine's intelligence forces said on Monday that Russian President Vladimir Putin 'drove himself into a dead end' and that his war in Ukraine will end with his demise.</p><p>In an extensive interview with <em><a href="https://nv.ua/ukr/ukraine/politics/gur-minoboroni-shcho-vidomo-pro-herson-i-donbas-interv-yu-nv-novini-ukrajini-50238690.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The New Voice of Ukraine</a></em><a href="https://nv.ua/ukr/ukraine/politics/gur-minoboroni-shcho-vidomo-pro-herson-i-donbas-interv-yu-nv-novini-ukrajini-50238690.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"></a>, Major-General Kyrylo Budanov, the chief of the Central Intelligence Agency (GUR) of the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense, said that Putin chose the "path of genocide" and that "all the problems of the Russian army have just emerged."</p><p>Putin's failures, Budanov said, began on the day that his forces entered Ukraine, according to a <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/ukraines-defense-intelligence-chief-kyrylo-budanov-predicts-the-war-in-ukraine-will-end-with-putin-dead" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">translation provided by </a><em><a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/ukraines-defense-intelligence-chief-kyrylo-budanov-predicts-the-war-in-ukraine-will-end-with-putin-dead" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Daily Beast</a>.</em></p><p>"It was a great PR. All they spent money on was to show the greatness of the Russian army in the world. Now everyone has seen - there is no greatness," Budanov remarked on Putin's pre-invasion bluster. "It is impossible to compare the military potential of Russia and Ukraine before the start of this phase of the war, which began on February 24: it is a ten-fold, and in some respects twenty-fold advantage of the Russian Federation. However, real hostilities have shown real problems: they have a quantitative indicator, of course, but no qualitative one. Secondly, rather low motivation. The losses they have suffered during this time have a strong impact on them."</p><p>Budanov foresees increasingly brash decisions being jettisoned out of the Kremlin, including a potential surge of false-flag terrorist attacks inside Russia's borders.</p><p>"Look what's happening. Many explosions, many destroyed objects - and Russia blames only Ukraine for everything. Look at the situation with Transnistria, for example. Of course, this is a good position - to blame Ukraine for everything. And how is all this possible? Can anyone explain?" he posited.</p><p>Timing, Budanov continued, is not on Putin's side either. He noted that Russia's upcoming World War II Victory Day celebrations on May 9th will arrive far too soon for Putin to have accomplished anything in Ukraine.</p><p>Budanov also pointed out that "the Russian army is completely demotivated. However, there is a military vertical - commands come to them, and they will be forced to carry them out. Whether you like it or not, there is an order, and you will carry it out. If you don't do it, you go to prison, there are many different options. Therefore, their moral condition is not significant. They will carry out the order."</p><p>Incidentally, <em>The Daily Beast</em> reported on Monday that Putin has been "<a href="https://www.alternet.org/2022/05/kremlin-sneaky-downplay-ukraine-casualties/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">transporting the corpses" of fallen Russian fighters "back to Russia</a> in small groups in order to avoid suspicion that Russia’s invasion is sustaining massive losses or faltering in Ukraine."</p><p>Estimates of Russian casualties in Ukraine <a href="https://www.cnn.com/europe/live-news/russia-ukraine-war-news-05-01-22/h_9c8808827bce42c5e27deca12af8f1ef" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">range from 7,000 to 23,000</a>, although independent verification of those figures has been elusive.</p><p>Russia Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, meanwhile, has insisted that May 9th <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russias-lavrov-says-may-9-not-relevant-date-ukraine-operations-2022-05-01/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">has nothing to do with Ukraine</a>.</p><p>Nevertheless, given how poorly Russia has performed, Putin is staring at certain defeat, even if he deploys strategic atomic bombs as a last-ditch means to claim a win, Budanov explained.<br/></p><p>"The chance to use tactical nuclear weapons has always been. There is no point in using strategic nuclear weapons, because we are close enough to each other. But tactical nuclear weapons and their use will simply hasten the end of Russia," he said. "This war is over."</p><p>Budanov then laid out two scenarios that he believes will mark the end of the conflict.</p><p>"The unofficial one," Budanov said, will be orchestrated by Russia's heavily-sanctioned oligarchy.</p><p>"They are afraid of losing their wealth. And they understand how it will end very quickly for them," he said. This approach, however, presumes that Putin manages to negotiate his way out of the crisis.<br/></p><p>The more likely conclusion, Budanov predicted, is that Putin is eliminated altogether.</p><p>"Leaving him a way to retreat is one of the strategies, but it is almost unrealistic. He is a war criminal for the whole world. This is his end," Budanov said. "He drove himself into a dead end."</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 14:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-spy-ukraine/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Brandon Gage, Alternet</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin.jpg?id=29548571&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy launches security probe as tempers fray over Russians on TV</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/italy-launches-security-probe-as-tempers-fray-over-russians-on-tv/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29763268&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Gavin Jones ROME (Reuters) - An Italian parliamentary panel has opened an investigation into "disinformation" on television amid a heated debate over the frequent appearance of Russian guests on the country's news programmes during the war in Ukraine. The Parliamentary Committee for the Security of the Republic (Copasir) which oversees the intelligence services, said on Wednesday it had summoned the heads of Italy's state TV network, state security agency and communications watchdog. The panel said it was looking into "foreign interference and disinformation activity ... with particular ref...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/italy-launches-security-probe-as-tempers-fray-over-russians-on-tv/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29763268&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugee who paints with a toothbrush nominated for Australian art prize</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/2657268460/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/a-refugee-held-for-eight-years-in-australia-s-hardline-immigration-system-has-won-a-place-as-a-finalist-for-the-nation-s-top-art-prize-saeed-khan-afp.jpg?id=29763055&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C21%2C0%2C40&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>A refugee held for eight years in Australia's hardline immigration system earned a finalist spot in the nation's top art prize on Thursday -- for a self-portrait he painted with a toothbrush.</p><p>For artist Mostafa Azimitabar, a Kurd who fled persecution in Iran, the honor came just over a year after he was released from one of Australia's notorious immigration hotels.</p><p>He told AFP a finalist berth for the Archibald -- a portrait prize worth AUD$100,000 ($72,192), which has been awarded to some of Australia's most esteemed artists -- was "one of the best moments of my life".</p><p>Azimitabar's self-portrait was painted using a toothbrush, a technique he began experimenting with in 2014, soon after being put into one of Australia's offshore immigration detention camps on Manus Island, Papua New Guinea.</p><p>"I asked one of the officers on Manus: 'Can I have some paint?'... I would like to do some artwork because I don't want to give up'," he recalled.</p><p>After the officer said he might eat the paint to inflict self-harm, a frustrated Azimitabar returned to the room he shared with dozens of men.</p><p>On a table, he spotted a cup of coffee and a toothbrush.</p><p>"I don't know what happened... that moment was so special for me. I grabbed the toothbrush and I put it in the coffee and I just dragged it (on some paper)," he said, describing this as his "moment of victory".</p><h2>KNS088</h2><p>Azimitabar's self-portrait is entitled "KNS088", the government identification number he was given during his eight years in detention.</p><p>He said painting was a reminder that he was a person, not a number.</p><p>"Art and painting helped me to be strong, to continue. Because when I paint, I don't feel any trauma," he said.</p><p>The UNHCR has repeatedly called on Australia to close its offshore camps, saying they "undermined the rights of those seeking safety and protection and significantly harmed their physical and mental health".<br/></p><p>But when he was moved to Australia's mainland for medical care and placed in a detention hotel, Azimitabar found it difficult to make art.</p><p>Australia's detention hotels, which made global headlines earlier this year when tennis star Novak Djokovic was held in one during his visa stoush, were "worse than Manus", he said.</p><p>Then, on January 21, 2021, with little warning or explanation, he was released.</p><h2>Life after detention</h2><p>Azimitabar was given a six-month bridging visa, which allowed him to work, but not study, access welfare or claim support for accommodation.</p><p>Since his release into the community, he has tried to build a life in Australia, working at a charity called ReLove.</p><p>"We provide free furniture to people (fleeing) domestic violence, or people who have been through a lot of trauma," he said.</p><p>He has also painted, a lot, but found traditional tools didn't inspire him as much as the toothbrush.</p><p>"This toothbrush is a very good friend of mine," he said.<br/></p><p>Azimitabar wanted his self-portrait to capture the "suffering, sadness and strength" of life as a refugee.</p><p>He hoped that being named as an Archibald finalist will allow more Australians to understand that refugees are capable of anything.</p><p>"I believe that people look at me as a survivor," he said.</p><p>The winner of this year's Archibald Prize will be announced on May 13.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/2657268460/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/a-refugee-held-for-eight-years-in-australia-s-hardline-immigration-system-has-won-a-place-as-a-finalist-for-the-nation-s-top-art-prize-saeed-khan-afp.jpg?id=29763055&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Queen Elizabeth II to miss summer garden parties: palace</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/queen-elizabeth-ii-to-miss-summer-garden-parties-palace/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/queen-elizabeth-ii.jpg?id=29707333&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C60%2C0%2C60&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Queen Elizabeth II, who has cut back on public appearances due to poor health and old age, will not attend this summer's royal garden parties, Buckingham Palace said on Thursday.</p><p>Every summer, up to three parties take place with invited members of the public in the Buckingham Palace Garden in central London, and another at the Palace of Holyroodhouse in Edinburgh.</p><p>Since she became queen in 1952, more than 1.45 million people have attended her annual garden parties.</p><p>But a royal official said: "Her Majesty The Queen will be represented by other members of the royal family at this year's garden parties, with details on attendance to be confirmed in due course."</p><p>The monarch recently returned to Windsor Castle after a week-long break on her Sandringham estate in Norfolk, eastern England, where she marked her 96th birthday in private on April 21.</p><p>Royal tradition since the 18th century has also seen the monarch have a second, official birthday, typically celebrated in warmer weather in June.</p><p>This year's official birthday coincides with four days of public events from June 2 to 5 to mark her record-breaking 70th year on the throne.</p><p>Since an unscheduled overnight stay in hospital last October, she has cut down massively on public appearances on doctor's orders.</p><p>A back complaint and difficulties standing and walking have seen her cancel a number of engagements, while a bout of Covid-19 in February left her "very tired and exhausted", she admitted.</p><p>But her grandson Prince Harry told US broadcaster NBC in a recent interview that she was "on great form".<br/></p><p>The queen was last seen in public at Westminster Abbey in central London on March 29 at a memorial service for her late husband Prince Philip, who died last year aged 99.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 11:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/queen-elizabeth-ii-to-miss-summer-garden-parties-palace/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/queen-elizabeth-ii.jpg?id=29707333&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian PM urges calm after Solomons leader cites 'invasion' threat</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/australian-pm-urges-calm-after-solomons-leader-cites-invasion-threat/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/italy-blocks-eu-vaccine-delivery-to-australia.jpg?id=25738006&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C66%2C0%2C67&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Australian Prime Minister Scott Morrison urged a calm response Thursday after the Solomon Islands' leader cited an "invasion" threat and said his nation was being treated like an infant wielding a handgun.</p><p>Morrison, who faces federal elections May 21, has been battling criticism of his government's foreign policy after the Pacific island nation signed a security pact with China last month.</p><p>The China deal raised alarm in Australia and the United States, which fear it may give Beijing a military foothold in the South Pacific less than 2,000 kilometers (1,200 miles) from Australia's coast.</p><p>"We need to be calm and composed when we deal with these issues," Morrison told journalists Thursday.</p><p>The Australian leader said he was concerned for the security of the Solomons and the Pacific after Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare signed the "secret arrangement" with Beijing.</p><p>Morrison insisted his government treated the Pacific "family" as an equal.</p><p>But Sogavare was irritated by US and Australian criticism of the deal.</p><p>"We deplore the continued demonstration of lack of trust by the concerned parties," Sogavare told parliament Tuesday, adding there was "nothing to be concerned about" with the pact.</p><h2>'We are insulted'</h2><p>Without naming countries, Sogavare said there had been a "warning of military intervention" if other countries' interests were undermined in the Solomons.</p><p>"In other words, Mr Speaker, we are threatened with invasion. And that is serious," the prime minister said.<br/></p><p>"We are being treated as kindergarten students walking around with Colt 45s in our hands, and therefore we need to be supervised," he added.</p><p>"We are insulted."</p><p>Sogavare's government severed ties with Taiwan in September 2019 in favor of diplomatic relations with China, a switch that unlocked investment but stoked inter-island rivalries.</p><p>Last November, protests against Sogavare's rule flared into riots in the capital Honiara, during which much of the city's Chinatown was torched.</p><p>Australia deployed about 100 police and military peacekeepers in response to a request by the Solomon Islands. They were joined by forces from New Zealand, Fiji and Papua New Guinea.</p><p>But Sogavare said a "personal envoy" of Morrison had briefed him at the time that the peacekeepers would not protect Chinese businesses or China's embassy.</p><p>Chinatown could not be saved "because our police were overwhelmed", Sogavare said, adding the "rules of engagement" precluded peacekeeper involvement.</p><p>The prime minister said Solomon Islands police were unable to assure the Chinese embassy's protection during the Honiara riots.</p><p>China's ambassador had asked the Solomons government to allow it to bring in 10 "special police protection personnel", he said, to help secure the embassy.</p><p>"Under the UN conventions, we are fully obliged to grant that request," Sogavare said.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/australian-pm-urges-calm-after-solomons-leader-cites-invasion-threat/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/italy-blocks-eu-vaccine-delivery-to-australia.jpg?id=25738006&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq sandstorm sends more than 1,000 to hospital</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/iraq-sandstorm-sends-more-than-1000-to-hospital/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/iraq-is-yet-again-covered-in-a-thick-sheet-of-orange-as-it-suffers-the-latest-in-a-series-of-dust-storms-that-have-become-increasingly-common-sabah-arar-afp.jpg?id=29762681&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C26%2C0%2C26&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>More than 1,000 Iraqis were rushed to hospital with respiratory ailments on Thursday due to a sandstorm, the seventh to hit the country in the past month, state media said.</p><p>Residents of six of Iraq's 18 provinces, including Baghdad and the vast western region of Al-Anbar, awoke once again to a thick cloud of dust blanketing the sky.</p><p>Authorities in Al-Anbar and Kirkuk provinces, north of the capital, urged people to stay indoors, said the official INA news agency.</p><p>Hospitals in Al-Anbar province had received more than 700 patients with breathing difficulties, said Anas Qais, a health official cited by INA.</p><p>The central province of Salaheddin reported more than 300 cases, while the central province of Diwaniya and the province of Najaf, south of Baghdad, each recorded about 100 cases, the news agency added.</p><p>Iraq is particularly vulnerable to climate change, having already witnessed record low rainfall and high temperatures in the past few years.</p><p>Experts have said these factors threaten to bring social and economic disaster in the war-scarred country.</p><p>In November, the World Bank warned Iraq could suffer a 20-percent drop in water resources by 2050 due to climate change.</p><p>In early April, a government official warned Iraq could face "272 days of dust" a year in coming decades.</p><p>The environment ministry said the weather phenomenon could be addressed by "increasing vegetation cover and creating forests that act as windbreaks".</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/iraq-sandstorm-sends-more-than-1000-to-hospital/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/iraq-is-yet-again-covered-in-a-thick-sheet-of-orange-as-it-suffers-the-latest-in-a-series-of-dust-storms-that-have-become-increasingly-common-sabah-arar-afp.jpg?id=29762681&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legendary Morozov art collection back in Russia after hit show in Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/legendary-morozov-art-collection-back-in-russia-after-hit-show-in-paris/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-morozov-collection-drew-a-near-record-breaking-1-25-million-visitors-to-the-swish-louis-vuitton-foundation-in-the-bois-de-boulogne-between-september-22-and-april-3-geoffroy-van-der-hasselt-afp-file.jpg?id=29762664&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C66%2C0%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Russia said Thursday that a sprawling collection of artworks by the likes of Van Gogh, Cezanne, Matisse and Monet -- the so-called Morozov Collection -- has been safely returned after the show proved a runaway success in Paris.</p><p>Nevertheless, the French government said that two key paintings had been held back due to Western sanctions against Russia over its military operation in Ukraine.</p><p>The Morozov Collection drew a near record-breaking 1.25 million visitors to the swish Louis Vuitton Foundation in the Bois de Boulogne between September 22 and April 3.</p><p>In fact, the show proved such a success that it was extended from its initial end-date of February 22, two days before Russia sent in troops to its pro-Western neighbor.</p><p>"The Morozov Collection has returned to Russia. At the moment, the exhibits have already been delivered to state museums," Culture Minister Olga Lyubimova said on messaging app Telegram.</p><p>It took nearly 20 days to secure the return of the artworks, Lyubimova said, praising a "great team effort", and the entire collection would now go on show this summer at Moscow's Pushkin Museum.</p><p>The collection, built up by brothers Mikhail and Ivan Morozov during the late 19th and early 20th century, had never before been seen as a whole outside Russia.</p><p>In April, the French culture ministry said that two pictures were to remain in France -- a self-portrait by Russian artist Pyotr Konchalovsky owned by sanctioned Russian oligarch Petr Aven; and a work by Russian painter Valentin Serov, which belongs to the Fine Arts museum in the Ukrainian city of Dnipro.</p><p>The Ukrainian authorities had asked for the latter painting to remain in France until the situation improves.</p><p>After Russian President Vladimir Putin sent troops to Ukraine on February 24, the EU adopted a series of sanctions including those prohibiting the sale, supply, transfer or export of luxury goods -- including works of art -- to Russia.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/legendary-morozov-art-collection-back-in-russia-after-hit-show-in-paris/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-morozov-collection-drew-a-near-record-breaking-1-25-million-visitors-to-the-swish-louis-vuitton-foundation-in-the-bois-de-boulogne-between-september-22-and-april-3-geoffroy-van-der-hasselt-afp-file.jpg?id=29762664&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine leader appeals for truce to dig out civilians trapped under steel plant</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-leader-appeals-for-truce-to-dig-out-civilians-trapped-under-steel-plant/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762624&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b04688455e13c73760e9dd7302c5a77e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9af28" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762626&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Natalia Zinets</p>
<p>KYIV (Reuters) -Civilians will need to be dug from bunkers under a steel works that is the last holdout of resistance in Ukraine's Mariupol, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Thursday, after a Russian bombardment that has littered the area with concrete debris.</p>
<p>Having failed to capture the capital Kyiv in the early weeks of an invasion that has killed thousands and flattened towns and villages, Russia has accelerated attacks in southern and eastern Ukraine, including on the Azovstal steel works in Mariupol.</p>
<p>Ukraine's resistance at the plant underscores Russia's failure to capture major cities in a war that has united Western powers in arming Kyiv and punishing Moscow with sanctions. Sweden and Finland are expected to decide very soon whether to join NATO, in what would be a major historical shift.</p>
<p>Russia's military promised to pause its activity in Azovstal during Thursday daytime and the following two days to allow civilians to leave, after what Ukrainian fighters described as "bloody battles" prevented evacuations on Wednesday. The Kremlin said humanitarian corridors from the plant were in place.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials believe around 200 civilians remain trapped along with fighters in the network of underground bunkers at the sprawling Soviet-era Azovstal complex.</p>
<p>In an early morning address, Zelenskiy said Ukraine stood ready to ensure a ceasefire in Mariupol, a port city that after a weeks-long siege Russia controls - apart from the steel works.</p>
<p>"It will take time simply to lift people out of those basements, out of those underground shelters. In the present conditions, we cannot use heavy equipment to clear the rubble away. It all has to be done by hand," Zelenskiy said.</p>
<p>Ukrainian fighters inside Azovstal are fighting "difficult, bloody battles," Denis Prokopenko, a commander with Ukraine's Azov regiment, said late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ukraine's military general staff said the assault on the plant included air support, and pictures released by Russian-backed fighters appeared to show smoke and flames enveloping it.</p>
<p>"God forbid more shells hit near the bunkers where the civilians are," said Tetyana Trotsak, an Azovstal evacuee among dozens who reached a Ukraine-controlled town this week, describing her two-and-a-half hour walk to get across a short stretch of ground strewn with rubble at the plant.</p>
<p>Mariupol has been an important target in Russia's efforts to cut Ukraine off from its Black Sea grain and metals export routes, as well as to link Russian-controlled territory in the east of the country to Crimea, seized by Moscow in 2014.</p>
<p>The United Nations and Red Cross evacuated hundreds of people from the city and other areas this week.</p>
<p>Nobody from Azovstal was among more than 300 civilians evacuated on Wednesday from Mariupol and other areas in southern Ukraine, the U.N. humanitarian office said.</p>
<p>We "stand ready to help" any trapped civilians, Jens Laerke, spokesperson for the office, said in an email.</p>
<p>SWEDEN EYES NATO</p>
<p>Sweden and neighbour Finland stayed out of NATO during the Cold War, but Russia's invasion of Ukraine has prompted them to rethink their security arrangements.</p>
<p>Sweden received U.S. assurances that it would receive support during the period that a potential application to join NATO is processed by the 30 nations in the alliance, Foreign Minister Ann Linde said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir embarked on the war partly to counter the expansion of the NATO alliance, which Ukraine also wants to join.</p>
<p>Sweeping sanctions from the United States and its European allies have hobbled Russia's $1.8 trillion economy while billions of dollars worth of military aid has helped Ukraine frustrate the invasion.</p>
<p>The United States has provided details on the location of Russia's mobile military headquarters, allowing Ukrainian forces to strike those targets and kill Russian generals, the New York Times reported on Wednesday, citing senior U.S. officials.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials said they have killed about 12 Russian generals on the battlefield, the newspaper said. The Pentagon and the White House did not immediately respond to Reuters' requests for comment on the report.</p>
<p>A source said EU envoys could reach a deal as early as Thursday on a plan to phase out imports of Russian crude oil within six months and refined products by the end of this year. It requires agreement by all 27 EU governments.</p>
<p>The plan also targets Russia's top bank, its broadcasters, and hundreds of individuals. It would follow U.S. and British oil bans and be a watershed for the EU, the world's largest trading bloc, which remains dependent on Russian energy.</p>
<p>The Kremlin said Russia was weighing responses to the EU plan, which it said would be costly for European citizens.</p>
<p>BATTLES</p>
<p>Ukraine and Russia said fighting had been heavy across the south and east over the past day.</p>
<p>Ukrainian authorities reported shelling of towns near a frontline that divides territory it holds in the Donetsk and Luhansk regions from land held by Russian-backed separatists.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian air force claimed to have downed three Russian cruise missiles and four aircraft, including two Sukhoi fighter jets.</p>
<p>Russia said it had killed 600 Ukrainian soldiers overnight. Reuters could not independently verify the battlefield reports by either side.</p>
<p>Pavlo Kyrylenko, governor of the eastern Donetsk region in which Mariupol is located, said at least 25 civilians were wounded as Russian forces shelled Kramatorsk, a town that in April suffered a missile strike on a train station that killed dozens of evacuating civilians.</p>
<p>A school and a kindergarten were damaged in the new attack, the town's mayor said.</p>
<p>Russian missile strikes in recent days have included railway stations in an attempt to target Western arms transfers and fuel depots.</p>
<p>More than five million Ukrainians have fled abroad since Putin launched the invasion on Feb. 24. Millions more are displaced inside Ukraine.</p>
<p>Russia calls its actions a "special operation" to disarm Ukraine and protect it from fascists. Ukraine and the West say the fascist allegation is baseless and that the war is an unprovoked act of aggression.</p>
<p>(Additional reporting by Emma Farge in Geneva and Reuters bureaus; Writing by Frank Jack DanielEditing by Gareth Jones)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="faf5930f0c5b2b935c8cee15ab37d289" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="325ab" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762631&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="01ca33fa0e7692c1bf96bdfe4fd4907d" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5a8c5" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762636&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ad60c3f44ecfe2114a6e67a061262470" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="4c308" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762638&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="97a7ebc45fbda6b3f4ab098348cc7dd9" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="550ba" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762644&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="5c187502178205a37a11d10bd2bde3f0" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3a050" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762646&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ee1a30bc1b48c29070dc62491dfe307a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="f5fbb" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762651&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b0fe99c53ce7dde2d23ab15cfbc558f3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="2260b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762654&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-leader-appeals-for-truce-to-dig-out-civilians-trapped-under-steel-plant/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29762624&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombia extradites drug lord 'Otoniel' to US</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/colombia-extradites-lord-otoniel-to-us/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761592&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="03c1142e8456dd9fd907d442fa949943" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="4283b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761593&width=980"/><figcaption>Colombian drug lord and former head of the Gulf Clan, 'Otoniel' Usuga was extradited to the United States on May 4, 2022</figcaption></figure></div><p>Bogota (AFP) - One of Colombia's most notorious drug lords was extradited Wednesday to the United States to face drug trafficking charges, announced President Ivan Duque.</p>
<p>"I want to reveal that Dairo Antonio Usuga, alias 'Otoniel' has been extradited," Duque said on Twitter, calling him "the most dangerous drug trafficker in the world."</p>
<p>Usuga, 50, was the most wanted person in Colombia until he was arrested last October in the northwest of the country after a massive military operation.</p>
<p>Duque described Usuga as a "murderer of social leaders and police, an abuser of boys, girls and teenagers."</p>
<p>"Today legality, the rule of law, the security forces and justice triumphed," he added.</p>
<p>On Wednesday afternoon, a convoy of five bulletproof police vehicles transported Usuga from a prison in the capital Bogota to a military airport, where he was handed over to US Drug Enforcement Administration officials.</p>
<p>Images shared by local media showed a handcuffed Usuga seated in an airplane alongside Colombian police and an Interpol official.</p>
<p>Usuga was the leader of Colombia's largest narco-trafficking gang, known as the Gulf Clan.</p>
<p>He was captured near the border with Panama following a military operation involving 500 soldiers backed by 22 helicopters, in which one police officer was killed.</p>
<p>His arrest was one of the biggest blows to Colombia's drug trafficking business since the assassination of Pablo Escobar in 1993.</p>
<p>Usuga was indicted in 2009 in the United States, which had offered a $5 million bounty for information leading to his arrest.</p>
<p>The United States accuses Usuga and the Gulf Clan of illegally bringing at least 73 tons of cocaine into the country between 2003 and 2012.</p>
<p>Following Usuga's arrest and that of another 90 suspected gang members, Duque declared the "end" of the Gulf Clan.</p>
<p>However, four Colombian soldiers were killed in attacks blamed on the gang just days after Usuga's arrest.</p>
<p>The Gulf Clan was believed to be responsible for 30 percent of cocaine exports from Colombia, the world's largest producer and supplier of the drug.</p>
<h1>'Who is afraid of Otoniel?'</h1>
<p>Since his capture, Usuga has been held in a high-security prison in Bogota, and has been at the heart of multiple controversies.</p>
<p>Recordings of testimony "Otoniel" gave to the Truth Commission -- an extrajudicial body investigating the decades-long conflict between the government and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) -- were stolen, the perpetrators unknown.</p>
<p>Colombian police also halted one of Usuga's Truth Commission hearings, saying the Gulf Clan had organized an escape attempt.</p>
<p>"Who is afraid of Otoniel?" read a headline on Cambio, an independent online news outlet, which charged that some people in the Colombian government sought to silence the drug lord.</p>
<p>The site reported Usuga would have said during his hearings that the army continued to work in complicity with right-wing paramilitaries in some parts of the country.</p>
<p>Citing a leaked Truth Commission document, the outlet said "Otoniel" had implicated 63 people as linked to the Gulf Clan, including a former minister, a former national director of intelligence, six former governors and four former members of parliament.</p>
<p>Family members of Usuga's victims had asked for the courts to suspend his extradition, arguing that he should stand trial in Colombia for "crimes against humanity."</p>
<p>But the Colombian justice system ultimately gave the green light for his extradition, Usuga's defense team told AFP.</p>
<p>Duque vowed that Usuga would still face justice in Colombia. </p>
<p>"This criminal was extradited to serve drug trafficking sentences in the United States," the president said.</p>
<p>"But I want to be clear that once those are served, he will return to Colombia to pay for the crimes committed against our country."</p>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 01:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/colombia-extradites-lord-otoniel-to-us/</guid>
      <category>Colombia</category>
      <category>Us</category>
      <category>Drugs</category>
      <category>Extradition</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>AFP</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761592&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American intel used to kill Russian generals in Ukraine: US officials</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/american-intel-used-to-russian-generals-in-ukraine-us-officials/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/president-joe-biden-participates-in-a-press-conference-thursday-march-24-2022-at-nato-headquarters-in-brussels.jpg?id=29761427&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C50&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Unnamed "senior American officials" revealed to <em>The New York Times</em> that the U.S. has provided intelligence that helped Ukrainians target "many" of the Russian generals killed during Putin's invasion.</p><p>"Ukrainian officials said they have killed approximately 12 generals on the front lines, a number that has astonished military analysts. The targeting help is part of a classified effort by the Biden administration to provide real-time battlefield intelligence to Ukraine," the newspaper <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/04/us/politics/russia-generals-killed-ukraine.html?referringSource=articleShare" target="_blank">reported</a>. "The administration has sought to keep much of the battlefield intelligence secret, out of fear it will be seen as an escalation and provoke President Vladimir V. Putin of Russia into a wider war."<span></span></p><p>Both classified and commercial satellites have been part of the intelligence gathering operation.</p><p>"The Biden administration is also supplying new weaponry that should improve Ukraine’s ability to target senior Russian officers. The smaller version of the Switchblade drone, which is now arriving on the battlefield, can be used to identify and kill individual soldiers, and could take out a general sitting in a vehicle or giving orders on a front line," the newspaper reported. "Although the administration remains wary of inflaming Mr. Putin to the point that he further escalates his attacks — President Biden has said he will not send American troops to Ukraine or establish a 'no-fly zone' there — current and former officials said the White House finds some value in warning Russia that Ukraine has the weight of the United States and NATO behind it."</p><p><u>REVEALED: </u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-ukraine-putin/" target="_self"><u>Top US general reveals the 'worst thing the Russians did' before the Ukraine invasion </u></a></p><p>Russian generals still fighting the war have grown "<a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/" target="_blank">extremely frustrated</a>" </p><p>Frederick B. Hodges, the former top U.S. Army commander in Europe, said Russian generals have also made mistakes by talking over unsecured lines of communication.</p><p>“It shows poor discipline, lack of experience, arrogance and failure to appreciate Ukrainian capabilities,” he said. “It is not hard to geo-locate someone on a phone talking in the clear.”</p><p><span></span>Read the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/04/us/politics/russia-generals-killed-ukraine.html?referringSource=articleShare" target="_blank">full report</a>.</p><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IlhvktyRX2w" target="_blank">Marjorie Taylor Greene gets confronted by a veteran for her 'craziness'</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="11033b17c602e9c6a769fb89b46a1250" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IlhvktyRX2w?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Marjorie Taylor Greene gets confronted by a veteran for her 'craziness'</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IlhvktyRX2w" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/american-intel-used-to-russian-generals-in-ukraine-us-officials/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Bob Brigham</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/president-joe-biden-participates-in-a-press-conference-thursday-march-24-2022-at-nato-headquarters-in-brussels.jpg?id=29761427&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top US general reveals the 'worst thing the Russians did' before the Ukraine invasion</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-ukraine-putin/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C109%2C0%2C110&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>On Wednesday, Fox News <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/world/us-european-command-ukraine-training-soldiers-russia-war" target="_blank">reported</a> that Brig. Gen. Joseph E. Hilbert, the commanding general in charge of joint training exercises between U.S. and Ukrainian troops in Germany, revealed what he believed is "the worst thing the Russians did" that ensured they would struggle to seize control in their invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>Specifically, Hilbert argued, the problem is that Russia telegraphed its intentions early — giving Ukraine "eight years to prepare" for the attack.</p><p>"Hilbert, the commanding general for the 7th Army Training Command, also said Ukraine has participated in more than a dozen large exercises with U.S. troops in Germany since 2015," reported Greg Norman and Liz Friden. "'The Ukrainian soldiers are motivated, they are professional,' Hilbert added, noting that the U.S. is currently training 50 to 60 Ukrainian soldiers on how to operate M777 howitzer artillery in Grafenwoehr, Germany."</p><p>"Hilbert also said the U.S. has trained more than 23,000 members of Ukraine's armed forces from 17 different battalions and 11 different brigades, spending a total of $126 million on this program," said the report. "He added that the U.S. was planning for Ukrainian troops to lead a division-level exercise across the country before over 160 Florida National Guard troops pulled out of Ukraine in February, days before the invasion began."</p><p><u><em><strong>RELATED: </strong><strong></strong></em></u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/vladimir-putin-doesnt-realize-how-badly-the-ukraine-war-is-going-for-russian-forces-us-official/" target="_self"><u><em><strong>Vladimir Putin doesn’t realize how ‘badly’ the Ukraine war is going for Russian forces: US official </strong></em></u></a> </p><p>The invasion of Ukraine was launched on the pretense of Russia providing security to two so-called "independent republics" declared in the east of Ukraine by separatist rebels backed by the Kremlin.</p><p>Military experts initially feared that the capital city of Kyiv would fall fairly quickly. However, <a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/2975508/russian-forces-invading-ukraine-suffer-low-morale/#:~:text=Russian%20forces%20invading%20Ukraine%20are,Kirby%20said.&text=Reports%20out%20of%20Ukraine%20indicate,a%20Pentagon%20news%20conference%20yesterday" target="_blank">the Pentagon has claimed</a> Russian troops have been plagued with low morale and face a fierce level of resistance from Ukraine. This has forced them to retreat from Kyiv and to focus on shoring up their position in the east.</p><p>Watch the original report <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/world/us-european-command-ukraine-training-soldiers-russia-war" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qmwzceEZ_sM" target="_blank">MSNBC’s Mika busts Republicans for pointing fingers over SCOTUS leak — when they probably know who did it</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="774495567744b303077c5a6e4aa8a2c7" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qmwzceEZ_sM?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">MSNBC busts Republicans for pointing fingers over SCOTUS leak, when they probably know who did it</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qmwzceEZ_sM" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 22:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-ukraine-putin/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook parent to slow hiring as costs mount</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/facebook-parent-to-slow-hiring-as-costs-mount/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761043&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="99f99ea7e8ab09a53854e000e5e5b38e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0c3a2" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761045&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>(Reuters) - Meta Platforms Inc is slowing the growth of its workforce as the Facebook parent looks to rein in costs, the company said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>"We regularly re-evaluate our talent pipeline according to our business needs and in light of the expense guidance given for this earnings period, we are slowing its growth accordingly," a Meta spokesperson said in an e-mailed statement.</p>
<p>Business Insider, citing an internal note to employees, reported that the company was lowering hiring targets and had temporarily stopped hiring for the remainder of the year.</p>
<p>Meta Platforms last week recorded its slowest revenue growth in a decade, with Chief Executive Officer Mark Zuckerberg also saying the company would scale back costs.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Praveen Paramasivam and Tiyashi Datta in Bengaluru; Editing by Anil D'Silva)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 21:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/facebook-parent-to-slow-hiring-as-costs-mount/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29761043&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky: Withdrawal of Russian troops a prerequisite for peace deal</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/zelensky-withdrawal-of-russian-troops-a-prerequisite-for-peace-deal/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29760470&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="508c3ce1f773343d08b88d5c622ddd5b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b763a" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29760475&width=980"/><figcaption>UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson, connected via videoconference, and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky observe the Ukrainian national anthem at the Verkhovna Rada before Johnson addressed the Ukrainian parliament. -/Verkhovna Rada via PA Media/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky reiterated his refusal to cede any territory to Russia and stated some conditions for any peace deal with Moscow.</p>
<p>"The goal of every Ukrainian is the restoration of territorial integrity within international borders," Zelensky said during an event hosted by the Wall Street Journal, according to a statement. "We will not enter into a frozen conflict."</p>
<p>He said Russian troops would have to withdraw and that Russian President Vladimir Putin would have to agree to a ceasefire "if possible, publicly."</p>
<p>This is the prerequisite for a peace agreement, he said, although he conceded that restoring Ukraine's territorial integrity would be "difficult," especially concerning Crimea, which was annexed by Russia in 2014.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 18:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/zelensky-withdrawal-of-russian-troops-a-prerequisite-for-peace-deal/</guid>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29760470&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian supporters rally behind embattled far-right Azov regiment</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ukrainian-supporters-rally-behind-embattled-far-right-azov-regiment/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29759318&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C50&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Valentyna Ocheretna has waited in vain for weeks for a call from her son Sasha. In March, he was wounded in battle against Russian troops in the strategic city of Mariupol. Since then, there's been silence.</p><p>For eight years, Sasha has fought with Ukraine's Azov regiment -- a far-right volunteer battalion turned Ukrainian national guard unit renowned for the mettle of its fighters and links to extremists.</p><p>"He chose to defend his country. And no one can fault him for doing so," Ocheretna told AFP in the Ukrainian capital.</p><p>The regiment has long been fodder for Russian President Vladimir Putin during his lengthy rants against Kyiv and repeated vows to rid Ukraine of Nazis.</p><p>But in Ukraine, the Azov regiment has largely enjoyed a solid reputation and been showered with praise for its years-long commitment to fight Russian incursions into the country.</p><p>This week, demonstrators gathered in Kyiv to rally public support for Azov and their fellow defenders of Mariupol, as the Russians launched another withering assault on a sprawling steel plant where Ukrainian forces in the southern city are taking a final stand.</p><p>Many of the participants had family and friends in the Azov Regiment, with some brandishing its yellow and blue flag featuring the infamous "Wolfsangel" logo that draws a striking similarity to insignia used by German Nazi SS units in World War II.</p><p>But despite criticism mostly from abroad of the regiment, Azov's backers in Ukraine insist that their forces are fighting fascists, not supporting them.</p><p>"If they had radical beliefs, they would have been pushed out of the army. I don't see any far-right radicalism or extremism in them," said Taras Tokovyi, a 32-year-old entrepreneur in Kyiv.</p><p>"They are simply Ukrainian heroes," he added.</p><p>Mariupol resident Svitlana Mitroshchenko agreed, citing the vital support -- including food and supplies -- Azov fighters provided to civilians in the war-torn port city following the Russian invasion.</p><h2>'Get out alive'</h2><p>"If not for these Azov guys, this would probably have been another Bucha," said Mitroshchenko, 47, fighting back tears as she referred to the Kyiv suburb where Ukraine and the West have accused Moscow's forces of killing civilians.</p><p>"It's the Russians who should really be called Nazis," she added.</p><p>Azov rose to prominence when it took up arms to beat back pro-Russian separatists in the Donbas in 2014, when Ukraine was in disarray following Moscow's lightning capture and later annexation of the Crimean peninsula.</p><p>Its founding members embraced a host of neo-Nazi symbols while maintaining links to a network of far-right movements before watering down its hard-line ideology and falling under the command of the Ukrainian military.</p><p>"The Azov Regiment is part of the national guard of Ukraine, it is not an independent paramilitary unit anymore. The connection with right-wing, radical politicians remains in history," said Volodymyr Fesenko, a Kyiv-based political analyst.</p><p>Since Russia invaded Ukraine in February, Azov's defence of Mariupol -- where their fighters and Ukrainian military units remain outgunned and outnumbered by Russian forces -- has only crystalised their popularity, giving them a status reserved for the bravest of the brave.</p><p>"They have big hearts for standing up in such a difficult situation," said Khrystyna Shemchuk, 21.</p><p>"Only a person with a big heart can stay there and fight in such conditions -- probably staying there to die."</p><p>But for 51-year-old Svitlana Prypyshna whose son is an Azov soldier based in Mariupol, the survival of the regiment's remaining forces is what matters most.</p><p>"My heart is breaking apart. My soul is crying out. But I cannot do anything about it," said Prypyshna.</p><p>"Of course, I feel proud, but I hope they get out alive."</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 16:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/ukrainian-supporters-rally-behind-embattled-far-right-azov-regiment/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29759318&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French left agrees rare coalition deal to take on Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/french-left-agrees-rare-coalition-deal-to-take-on-macron/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29759001&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Elizabeth Pineau, Michel Rose and Ingrid Melander PARIS (Reuters) - France's Socialist Party and the hard-left La France Insoumise (LFI) agreed in principle on Wednesday to run together in June parliamentary elections and try to deprive newly re-elected President Emmanuel Macron of a majority. If confirmed, the coalition pact, which the Greens and Communists approved earlier this week, will be the first time the French left has united in 20 years - but under the helm of the eurosceptic, leftist LFI this time around. "We want to have lawmakers in a majority of constituencies, to prevent Emma...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/french-left-agrees-rare-coalition-deal-to-take-on-macron/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29759001&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Francis calls out Russian Orthodox Church leader for acting like 'Putin's altar boy'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pope-francis-russia-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29758816&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C30&height=600"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/pope-wants-to-visit-moscow-to-meet-putin-over-ukraine-paper/" target="_blank">Pope Francis</a> says that he has told the leader of the Russian Orthodox Church, Patriarch Kirill, not to "transform himself into Putin's altar boy" by continuing to justify the Russian president's <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/un-chief-calls-russia-ukraine-war-unwinnable/" target="_blank">unprovoked attack on Ukraine</a>.</p><p>In an interview published on Tuesday by the Italian daily Corriere della Sera and reported by <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/04/europe/pope-francis-patriarch-kirill-ukraine-invasion-intl/index.html" target="_blank">CNN</a>, the Pope revealed that he had spoken to Kirill March 16. The Catholic leader sharply criticized the patriarch for parroting Putin's justifications for the brutal assault.</p><p>"I spoke to him for 40 minutes via Zoom," the Pope said. "The first 20 minutes he read to me, with a card in hand, all the justifications for war. I listened and told him: I don't understand anything about this. Brother, we are not clerics of state, we cannot use the language of politics but that of Jesus."</p><p>Francis said that during the conference call he and the Patriarch had agreed to postpone a meeting they had scheduled for June 14 in Jerusalem. </p><p>"It would be our second face-to-face meeting, nothing to do with the war," the Pope said. "But now, he too agrees: let's stop, it could be an ambiguous signal."</p><p><strong>READ MORE: </strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/greg-lopez-colorado/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Watch: 'Pro-life' GOP candidate grilled by reporter about past arrest for assaulting his pregnant wife"><strong>Watch: 'Pro-life' GOP candidate grilled by reporter about past arrest for assaulting his pregnant wife</strong></a></p><p>Kirill has echoed Putin's stated justifications for invading Ukraine, saying the war is an extension of a fundamental culture clash between the Russian world and Western liberal values. The Russian cleric has said he fully supports Putin's efforts to reestablish a Russian empire in which the Orthodox religion plays a pivotal role.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pope-francis-russia-ukraine/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Timothy Evans</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29758816&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia bans entry to Japanese prime minister, dozens of others</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-bans-entry-to-japanese-prime-minister-dozens-of-others/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757859&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="47fb6870f7ae84a7cc492234da1368e5" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="fc34c" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757862&width=980"/><figcaption>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz (not pictured) hold a joint press conference. Kay Nietfeld/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Kremlin retaliated on Tuesday against sanctions imposed by Japan for Russia's invasion of Ukraine, by placing an entry ban on 63 Japanese citizens, including Prime Minister Fumio Kishida.</p>
<p>Kishida's government was accused by the Russian Foreign Ministry of launching an "unprecedented anti-Russian campaign" and "allowing itself to use improper rhetoric against the Russian Federation, including slander and direct threats."</p>
<p>Tokyo's actions are destroying "good neighbourly relations" and damaging Russia's economy and image, it added.</p>
<p>In addition to the Japanese prime minister, Russia's blacklist includes Foreign Minister Yoshimasa Hayashi, parliamentarians, owners of media outlets and journalists.</p>
<p>The entry ban is in effect indefinitely.</p>
<p>Japan joined Western partners in slapping sanctions on Russia for its war in Ukraine. But tensions between two countries have also flared due to competing claims to the Kuril Islands, which Tokyo calls its Northern Territories.</p>
<p>Moscow terminated talks on a partial return of the archipelago in March. Tokyo subsequently described these islands as "illegally occupied" in April for the first time in years.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-bans-entry-to-japanese-prime-minister-dozens-of-others/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Japan</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757859&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU proposes Russian oil ban to make Putin 'pay high price' for Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-proposes-russian-oil-ban-to-make-putin-pay-high-price-for-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757785&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Jan Strupczewski and Kate Abnett STRASBOURG (Reuters) -The European Union's chief executive on Wednesday proposed a phased oil embargo on Russia, sanctions on its top bank and a ban on Russian broadcasters from European airwaves in its toughest measures yet to punish Moscow for its war in Ukraine. The EU's sixth round of sanctions, if agreed by member states, would be a watershed for the world's largest trading bloc, which is dependent on Russian oil and gas and must find alternative supplies just as energy prices are spiking. Reluctance to deliver sanctions that will hurt EU economies as w...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-proposes-russian-oil-ban-to-make-putin-pay-high-price-for-ukraine/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757785&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea mobilizes office workers to fight drought amid food shortages</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/n-korea-mobilises-office-workers-to-fight-drought-amid-food-shortages/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757037&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="12fa3ed923a0dc8e4f517afe6ac0efa3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5aafe" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757039&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Hyonhee Shin</p>
<p>SEOUL (Reuters) - North Korea's office workers and factory labourers have been dispatched to farming areas around the country to join a fight against drought, state media reported on Wednesday, amid concerns over prolonged food shortages.</p>
<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un had called for measures to improve a tense food situation caused by the coronavirus pandemic and typhoons, despite slight improvements early last year.</p>
<p>Drought and floods have long posed a seasonal threat to North Korea, which lacks irrigation systems and other infrastructure, and any serious natural hazards could cripple its reclusive economy already reeling from international sanctions and a near halt of trade.</p>
<p>The North's Rodong Sinmun newspaper said government officials and company and factory workers joined hands with farmers nationwide in distributing pumping equipment and developing water resources in drought-prone regions.</p>
<p>It did not specify any damages so far, but said those efforts are aimed at countering an ongoing dry spell and bracing for an upcoming drought.</p>
<p>"Systematic, aggressive efforts are under way to raise public awareness and mobilise all available capabilities to prevent crop damages from drought in advance," the paper said.</p>
<p>North Korea's weather authorities on Tuesday warned of prolonged dry weather across the country until early next week, according to the official KCNA news agency.</p>
<p>The weather agency said last week that the average temperature for April was 2.3 Celsius (36.1 Fahrenheit) degrees higher than usual, with just 44 percent of its average rainfall nationwide.</p>
<p>In Anju and Kaechon, north of the capital Pyongyang, people created ponds, added fertiliser and growth enhancer to crops, and sent tractors, trucks and cultivators to carry water to farms, Rodong said.</p>
<p>Another dispatch said young labour units, which are called dolgyeokdae or youth brigades and usually mobilised in major infrastructure projects, have recently built waterways in the eastern port city of Hamhung as part of efforts to modernise and expand irrigational facilities.</p>
<p>In March, the United Nations urged Pyongyang to reopen its borders to aid workers and food imports, saying its deepening isolation may have left many facing starvation.</p>
<p>North Korea has not officially confirmed any COVID-19 cases, but it had closed borders and travel restrictions, before briefly resuming trade with China early this year.</p>
<p>The World Food Program estimated that even before the pandemic hit, 11 million, or more than 40 percent of the population, were undernourished and required humanitarian assistance.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Hyonhee Shin; Editing by Michael Perry)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/n-korea-mobilises-office-workers-to-fight-drought-amid-food-shortages/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757037&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope wants to visit Moscow to meet Putin over Ukraine: report</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pope-wants-to-visit-moscow-to-meet-putin-over-ukraine-paper/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757158&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="aaad4fc7b62b59b9723c0b9941a4d40f" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="e7d05" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757164&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Philip Pullella and Francesca Piscioneri</p>
<p>VATICAN CITY (Reuters) -Pope Francis said in an interview published on Tuesday that he asked for a meeting in Moscow with Russian President Vladimir Putin to try to stop the war in Ukraine but had not received a reply.</p>
<p>The pope also told Italy's Corriere Della Sera newspaper that Patriarch Kirill of the Russian Orthodox Church, who has given the war his full-throated backing, "cannot become Putin's altar boy".</p>
<p>Francis, who made an unprecedented visit to the Russian embassy when the war started, told the newspaper that about three weeks into the conflict, he asked the Vatican's top diplomat to send a message to Putin.</p>
<p>The message was "that I was willing to go to Moscow. Certainly, it was necessary for the Kremlin leader to allow an opening. We have not yet received a response and we are still insisting".</p>
<p>"I fear that Putin cannot, and does not, want to have this meeting at this time. But how can you not stop so much brutality? Twenty-five years ago in Rwanda we lived through the same thing," he was quoted as saying, appearing to equate the killings in Ukraine to the genocide in the African country in 1994.</p>
<p>Before the interview, Francis, 85, had not specifically mentioned Russia or Putin publicly since the start of the conflict on Feb. 24. But he has left little doubt which side he has criticised, using terms such as unjustified aggression and invasion and lamenting atrocities against civilians.</p>
<p>The pope said that perhaps Putin reacted because of "NATO's barking at Russia's gate .. I wouldn't know if this provoked an ire but perhaps it facilitated it".</p>
<p>Asked about a trip to the Ukrainian capital Kyiv, which Francis last month said was a possibility, the pope said he would not go for now.</p>
<p>"First, I have to go to Moscow, first I have to meet Putin ... I do what I can. If Putin would only open a door," he said.</p>
<p>STRAINED RELATIONS</p>
<p>The war in Ukraine has strained relations between the Vatican and the Russian Orthodox Church, and caused a split among Orthodox Christians around the world.</p>
<p>Reuters reported on April 11 that the Vatican was considering extending the pope's trip to Lebanon on June 12-13 by a day so he could meet with Kirill on June 14 in Jerusalem. But Francis later decided against it.</p>
<p>In the interview, Francis said that when he had a 40-minute video conference with Kirill on March 16, the patriarch spent half of it reading from a sheet of paper "with all the justifications for the war".</p>
<p>Moscow describes its action in Ukraine as a "special operation" to demilitarise and "denazify" its neighbour. Kirill, 75, sees the war as a bulwark against a West he considers decadent, particularly over the acceptance of homosexuality.</p>
<p>"We (the pope and Kirill) are pastors of the same people of God. That is why we have to seek paths of peace, to cease the fire of weapons. The patriarch cannot become Putin's altar boy," Francis was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The pope also said that when he met Viktor Orban on April 21, the Hungarian prime minister told him "the Russians have a plan, that everything will end on May 9", referring to the anniversary of Russia's liberation at the end of World War II.</p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov has said the anniversary would have no bearing on Moscow's military operations in Ukraine.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Francesca Piscionieri and Philip Pullella; Editing by Jacqueline Wong, Nick Macfie and Ed Osmond)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 04:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pope-wants-to-visit-moscow-to-meet-putin-over-ukraine-paper/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757158&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea fires projectile towards sea off east coast,  says South Korea</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/n-korea-fires-projectile-towards-sea-off-east-coast-says-s-korea/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757075&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="0cb796e63279b262783709466bc627a0" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="2cd32" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757079&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>SEOUL (Reuters) - North Korea has fired an unidentified projectile towards the sea off its east coast, South Korea's military said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Soo-hyang Choi; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 03:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/n-korea-fires-projectile-towards-sea-off-east-coast-says-s-korea/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29757075&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>