<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>VISTA InfoSec</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com</link>
    <description>Vista Infosec</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>ISO27001 Checklist of the Main Security Control Domain</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/iso27001-checklist-of-the-main-security-control-domain/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/iso27001-checklist-of-the-main-security-control-domain/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 11:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[ISO 27001]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4578</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Information Security Management System is an international standard designed to &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/iso27001-checklist-of-the-main-security-control-domain/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Information Security Management System is an international standard designed to manage the security of sensitive information. At the core, ISMS is about managing the people, processes, and technology through a risk management program. While there are many standards under the ISO2000 family, the<a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/everything-you-need-to-know-about-iso-27001-standards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> ISO27001 Standard</a> is the most popular and widely accepted standard in the industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ISO 27001 standard provides a framework for implementing ISMS and securing information assets. The Information Security Standard and Framework help organizations implement security controls that ensure Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability of sensitive data. Elaborating on the standard in detail, we have in the article also share a compliance checklist with a list of security controls that must be implemented for those looking to achieve <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/benefits-of-iso-27001-certification/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ISO27001 Certification</a>. But before getting into the details of the security control list, let&#8217;s understand in brief the ISO27001 Standard and framework. </span></p>
<h2><b>What is ISO27001 Standard?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">ISO/IEC 27001 is an international standard for managing data security through an information security management system (ISMS). The standard which was first published in 2005 by the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) and the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) had last been updated the standard in 2013. The Standard comprises 10 management system clauses and 14 Annex A Security Control Domain which lists 114 Information Security Controls that are designed to support the implementation and maintenance of ISMS. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While there is no mandate that all 114 Annex A controls be implemented by the organization, it is however recommended that risk assessment should be conducted to determine which controls are required and provide details explaining why other controls are excluded from the ISMS. So, for the understanding of our reader, we have today shared an ISO 27001 checklist to help an organization approach its implementation plan efficiently and prepare for certification. But this again would depend on the controls applicable to the organization based on the risk assessment findings and outcomes. </span></p>
<h2><b>ISO27001 Checklist and Security Controls</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Achieving ISO 27001 certification helps organization prove their implementation and adoption of industry best security practices to potential customers in the industry. So, achieving the ISO27001 Certification will provide the organization with a competitive edge in the industry. That said, ISO 27001 Annex A  comprises  114 controls that are grouped into 14 security control categories. Each of the 14 categories has been explained in the article. Referring to this checklist will help organizations successfully implement an Information Security Management System (ISMS) according to the standard, and prepare the organization for the audit of ISMS to obtain ISO 27001 certification.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>ISO27001 Annex A contains 14 Main categories of Security Controls</strong></h3>

<table id="tablepress-17" class="tablepress tablepress-id-17">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">Annex A.5</th><th class="column-2">Information Security Policies</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.6</td><td class="column-2">Organization of Information Security<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.7 </td><td class="column-2">Human Resource Security</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.8 <br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Asset Management</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.9<br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Access Control</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-6 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.10</td><td class="column-2">Cryptography<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-7 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.11 </td><td class="column-2">Physical and Environmental Security</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-8 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.12</td><td class="column-2">Operations Security</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-9 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.13<br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Communications Security<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-10 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.14</td><td class="column-2">System Acquisition, Development, and Maintenance<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-11 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.15</td><td class="column-2">Supplier Relationships<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-12 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.16 </td><td class="column-2">Information Security Incident Management<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-13 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.17</td><td class="column-2"> Information Security Aspects of Business Continuity Management</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-14 even">
	<td class="column-1">Annex A.18 </td><td class="column-2">Compliance</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-17 from cache -->
<h3><b>Control Category A.5 – Information Security Policies</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This section guides the management in implementing information security measures in alignment with the industry standards, regulations, and the organization&#8217;s security requirements. Organizations can achieve this by establishing and documenting Information Security Policies and by regularly reviewing them from time to time. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.6 – Organization of Information Security</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This section guides the management to set an Information Security Framework that facilitates the implementation of Information Security within the organization, across verticals and operations. This requires organizations to define information security roles and responsibilities, segregation duties maintain appropriate contact details with ICO and ISACA, and ensure information security in project management, irrespective of the project type. Organizations are also required to ensure security in remote working including the security of mobile devices and teleworking. For this organizations are required to establish and maintain a stringent security policy supporting the security measures to manage risk associated with remote working including protection of information accessed, processed, stored remotely, and use of mobile devices. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.7 – Human Resource Security</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category is about setting security measures and prerequisites for employment to ensure that the employees are aware of their responsibilities and they are suitable for the role they are hired for. This requires organizations to conduct appropriate background checks on candidates. It further requires organizations to have in place information security policies, procedures, and contracts that define the employee’s information security roles and responsibility and documented signature of acknowledgment for the same from the candidate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The organization must also ensure the employees receive adequate training and are regularly updated on the policy changes if any concerning information security. There must also be a well-defined, formal disciplinary process in place to ensure necessary actions are taken against any individual who does not adhere to the information security breach.   In addition to this, the organization needs to even have an Employee Termination Policy that defines the process for terminating or changing employee duties that are defined and enforced. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4487 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06.png" alt="Free Consulting" width="1070" height="543" /></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.8 – Asset Management</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This section is about asset security and management. Organizations are expected to maintain an inventory of all assets associated with information and information processing facilities. The asset must be classified and the inventory must include information about the assets and their designated asset owners. The organization must document the policies, procedures, and rules for the acceptable use and handling of assets. There shall also be policies and procedures in place to manage and prevent unauthorized disclosure, modification, removal, or destruction of information stored on media.  The policies and procedures must include details on how the media should be handled, rules for disposal of media or systems containing information, and protection of data in transit. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.9 – Access control</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The organization must have in place Access Control Policies and Procedures to support the implementation of restricted access to information and information processing facilities. Further, the policy must define roles and responsibilities to ensure only authorized individuals are granted access based on their roles. Organizations are expected to make the policies accessible to their employees to know their roles and responsibilities concerning their access to sensitive data or systems. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Further, organizations must define and establish user access management for formal user access provisioning, management of privilege access rights, and removal of access rights for users who leave the organization. Necessary measures should be implemented to ensure users are accountable for securing their passwords and preventing unauthorized access to systems and applications. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.10 – Cryptography</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations are expected to use the Cryptography technique to ensure confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of the information. For this, the organization needs to establish and enforce a cryptography policy which should include details such as the use of cryptography controls, and cryptography key management. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.11 – Physical and Environmental Security</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category is about ensuring the prevention of unauthorized physical access, damage, and interference to information and systems and facilities comprising information. So security measures must be implemented to secure systems and information and prevent data compromise and interruption to operations. For this, organizations need to implement physical security, for securing offices, rooms, and facilities with necessary access controls in place. They are further required to establish security policies and procedures that support the implementation of these physical security measures. This is to ensure protection against the external environmental threat.</span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.12 – Operations Security</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category is about ensuring operational security within the organization. The organization needs to ensure that information processing facilities are operated appropriately and securely. So, to ensure safe and secure operations,  the organization needs to establish operational procedures and make them available to all. The procedure must include change management to control changes to business processes, information processing systems, and operations. It should also include capacity management to highlight the capacity requirements. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations must also ensure enforcement of segregation of development, test, and operational environment. This is to reduce risks of unauthorized access or changes to operational environments. Further, to ensure security, necessary controls against malware should be established to detect, alert and prevent malware attacks. So, organizations are expected to implement anti-malware software for effective detection and prevention of attacks. Organizations are also expected to maintain a backup of information to protect against loss of data</span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.13 – Communications Security</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category focuses on maintaining the security of Information when transferred internally or externally. The organization must for these reasons have a Network Management process in place which includes risk management, and ensuring network segmentation where applicable to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive networks and data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This can be achieved by organizations by having in place agreements, and contracts with security-related SLAs mandated. For securing the data transition, the organization must have data transfer policies and procedures including details such as how the data should be transferred and made available to employees and the implementation of technical controls to prevent unauthorized data transfer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This requires organizations to implement security controls to protect information transferred  through emails, social media, and other communication platforms.  the organization is also expected to maintain an agreement contract between third parties involved, specifying their responsibility in ensuring the security of data when transferred. There should also be in place Confidentiality or Nondisclosure Agreements that should be subject to regular review and maintenance of such records. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.14 – System Acquisition, Development, and Maintenance</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The category focuses on ensuring the systems and operations within the environment are secured and the security implementations are an integral part of the systems and operations lifecycle. The organization must ensure information security requirements are specified when new systems are introduced or when systems are being enhanced or upgraded. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The organizations are expected to secure applications sending information over public networks against fraudulent activities, unauthorized access, and modification of data. The organizations must have in place technical security measures to prevent instances of incomplete transmission, unauthorized modification, disclosure of data, misrouting, or duplication of data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The organization must also have in place a secure development policy, system change control procedures, and processes for secure software development, system engineering, secure development environment. The organization must also ensure system security testing is performed on outsourced developments.</span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.15 – Supplier Relationships</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category focuses on ensuring the security of information accessed by suppliers. For this organizations should have in place documented policies and procedures concerning supplier management with details of all suppliers and information they have access to. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The organization must also develop an agreement or contract with suppliers mentioning their responsibilities and security requirements, addressing the information security risks associated with information and communications technology services and the supply chain. This should be in line with the security management policy. The Agreement or Contract must also include and mention the agreed level of information security and delivery of service in line with the Supplier Agreement.</span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.16 – Information Security Incident Management </b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category focuses on ensuring consistent and effective enforcement of Information Security Incident Management. This includes communication security incidents and weaknesses in systems and processes. For this, organizations must define roles responsibilities, and a clear process for reporting incidents, information security weaknesses, assessment, and response to information security incidents. </span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.17 – Information Security Aspects of Business Continuity Management</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category focuses on ensuring Information Security and Business Continuity Management. The organizations are expected to have in place policies, procedures, and processes in place to facilitate Information Security and Business Continuity in case of an incident. This further needs to be documented for future use, reference, and audit purpose. Organizations are expected to evaluate review and verify the effectiveness of Information Security and Business Continuity Management.  The organization must also maintain information on whether the information processing facilities have sufficient redundancy to meet the organization&#8217;s availability requirements.</span></p>
<h3><b>Control Category A.18 – Compliance</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This category focuses on ensuring compliance with the legal, statutory, regulatory, or contractual obligations related to information security and security requirements.  Organizations are expected to identify and document applicable legislation and contractual requirements for compliance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Further, it is a mandate to maintain records of all intellectual property rights and the use of proprietary software products. All records and documents should be secured against unauthorized access, destruction, and modification as per the legislative, regulatory, contractual, and business requirements. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations must maintain the security and privacy of personally identifiable information (PII) and use cryptography controls in line with relevant agreements, legislation, and regulations. Organizations must also regularly conduct audit reviews and implementation of security controls. Further compliance with security policies and standards should be regularly reviewed and verified. </span></p>
<h3><b>Final Thought</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/iso-27001-consulting-audit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ISO 27001</a> is an international standard that helps organizations understand the various requirements of an Information Security Management System (ISMS). The standard comprises multiple policies, procedures, processes, and systems that an organization must establish and implement that help manages information security risks. Achieving and Demonstrating the ISO/IEC 27001 certification implies that the organization followed the ISO 27001 guidelines and implemented the best practices of information security processes. It reflects the organization&#8217;s commitment to building and maintaining high-level security standards within the organization and thereby gaining customer confidence in them. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4578"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/iso27001-checklist-of-the-main-security-control-domain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Cybersecurity is Worth the Cost for Your Business</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-cybersecurity-is-worth-the-cost-for-your-business/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-cybersecurity-is-worth-the-cost-for-your-business/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 08:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4575</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[You probably have some form of cybersecurity program already in &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-cybersecurity-is-worth-the-cost-for-your-business/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You probably have some form of cybersecurity program already in place. Maybe a Norton app that scanned this page for you before you opened it. While that may be good but yet not be enough to tackle or address the evolving cyber threats in the industry. We live in an era of rampant cyber security threats.  Mistakes are as easy to make as they are punishing. In this article today let us take a look at why developing a cybersecurity program is worth the cost for your business. </span></p>
<h2><b>Breaches are Expensive</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we talk about breaches it is hard to even quantify the true cost of the incident of a security breach. Even in scenarios where no actual money has been stolen, you will still probably be facing fines and fees. Some of the popular examples of breaches would be Marriot which was wound up on the hook for many millions of dollars in fines, Yahoo having faced similar forms of fines and a class action lawsuit following their infamous breaches. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then there comes the time cost which is equally critical in business. It can take years for a bad actor to be noticed in your system, and many months to recover even after the cyberthreat has been identified. Cybersecurity can be expensive, yes, but like insurance, it’s an expense you have to accept to do business in the modern world. </span></p>
<h2><b>A Bigger Threat</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hackers and other cyber threats are now more common than ever before. Thanks to the proliferation of computer skills, it is now easier than ever for bad actors to get the skills they need to perform an attack and achieve their malicious objectives. There are more than 30,000 cyber-attacks directed toward businesses every single day. Such cyber threats often have a huge impact on the business financially and non-financially. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In worst-case scenarios, businesses also end up shutting down for the financial and reputational impact that it ends up having on the business. So, today the most important question to be asked is whether your business is capable of dealing with such cyber threats. Developing and establishing robust cyber security systems goes a long way in managing threats and preventing the impact of a breach. It is indeed a great way of also keeping you and your customer’s information safe in the bargain. </span></p>
<h2><b>Your Customers are Counting On You</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Virtually every business deals with some form of customer data. If you are an online store, you probably have many customers’ personal and financial data including the billing information on record. If you are a subscription service, you almost certainly keep customer credit cards on file.  Even local coffee shops maintain customer data, through email lists, customer surveys, and more. This is the age of information, and information is everywhere. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When your customers do business with you, they usually assume that there is no degree of personal risk involved. Unfortunately, all of the data breaches that frequently splash their way into the headlines tell a different story.  From Yahoo to Marriot, big businesses have shown us time and time again that simple mistakes can jeopardize vast swaths of customer data.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not only does a breach hurt the customer, but chances are it will hurt you as well. So, with an incident of data breach and its repercussions on customers as well, how many customers out of that lot do you think are going to continue doing business with the company that mishandled their information?</span></p>
<h2><b>Business Reputation </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we talk about customer confidence in business, it is also seen as a reputation built in the market about your brand and business safety on the whole. For instance, achieving PCI Compliance certification is a reflection of your business taking all the necessary steps and measures to protect customers’ credit card information. </span><b> </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">While achieving PCI DSS Compliance may not be legally mandatory, achieving compliance is valuable for businesses and their customers in several ways. For one thing, taking the steps towards PCI compliance will legitimately make your transactions safer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It can also make your business more marketable. You can use your PCI status in your branding to describe yourself as a safe company that cares about your customers.  Though not guaranteed, it’s also worth mentioning that some credit card companies may give you a small but worthwhile break on fees if you can prove you are taking steps towards ensuring safe transactions. They want to incentivize businesses to invest in cybersecurity because when they do, it means fewer customer-challenged transactions for the credit card company over time. </span></p>
<h2><b>Getting It Done</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider hiring a cyber security professional to help you with your online protection needs. </span><a href="https://onlinedegrees.unr.edu/blog/master-in-cybersecurity-salary/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber security</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and related fields such as </span><a href="https://onlinedegrees.und.edu/blog/forensic-accounting-career/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">forensic accounting</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are in high demand now, thanks to the big shift towards digital business that has occurred over the last several years.  Now is the perfect time to rethink your cyber security needs with the help of a knowledgeable professional. Investing in a good cyber security program is definitely worth the spending than the risk of bearing the brunt of a breach incident. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4575"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-cybersecurity-is-worth-the-cost-for-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is the Impact of the GDPR on Online Transactions?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/impact-of-the-gdpr-on-online-transactions/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/impact-of-the-gdpr-on-online-transactions/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 09:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[EU GDPR]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[UK GDPR]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4562</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[&#160; From the first online transaction in 1994, we have &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/impact-of-the-gdpr-on-online-transactions/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('audio');</script><![endif]-->
<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-4562-1" preload="none" style="width: 100%;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/66398215.mp3?_=1" /><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/66398215.mp3">https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/66398215.mp3</a></audio>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the first online transaction in 1994, we have seen online transactions evolve faster than anticipated. With this also came an evolution of rules and regulations to avoid the abuse of personal data. The GDPR is one such regulation that has an important role in regulating the whole structure of online transactions. It has also led to the development of specialized </span><a href="https://snyk.io/learn/fintech-cybersecurity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">fintech cybersecurity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what exactly is the impact of the GDPR, and how is it helping? Let us understand all of this in detail and put things into perspective.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is the GDPR?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The General Data Protection Regulation came into force in 2018. It is a regulation applicable to businesses around the globe dealing with the Personal data of citizens of the European Union. It is an international data privacy law that has brought transformation in the way businesses and organizations process and use personal data. The main aim of the regulation is to ensure the protection of personal data from any form of misuse.</span></p>
<h2><b>Who Does It Affect?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any business that operates be it online or offline is affected by the GDPR. Even if a business isn&#8217;t directly operating in the EU, it might still have to fulfill the requirements of the GDPR. If you fall under any of the following categories, you are required by law to operate in line with the regulations of GDPR.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You deal with the personal data of customers who are residents of the EU.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visitors from the EU access your website and collect/store personal data.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your emails are addressed to EU citizens.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bottom line is that if the business is handling or dealing with the personal data of <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/infographic-implication-of-gdpr-compliance-on-eu-citizen-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EU citizens,</a> then they need to comply with the GDPR.</span></p>
<h2><b>How Does It Work?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The guidelines of GDPR are pretty straightforward, ensuring businesses maintain the highest level of data privacy and protection. It works by defining certain requirements for organizations to maintain data protection and privacy while processing, storing, and transmitting Personal Data.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following is a list of all the things covered by this regulation.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The GDPR regulation clearly defines what is personal data.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How companies should process and protect personal data is one of the core elements of the GDPR.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It covers the rights of customers whose personal data are stored processed and used.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also outlines the way how personal data should be secured online.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Impact of the GDPR on Online Transactions</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that we know what the GDPR Regulation is, let us move on to understanding how the GDPR regulation impacts online transactions. </span></p>
<h2><b>What Data is Protected by the GDPR?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online businesses receive lots of information about their users through online transactions. Out of all this data, only the information that may potentially reveal the customer&#8217;s identity is protected by GDPR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This means companies need to be careful about the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">names, IP addresses, contact details, credit card numbers, cookies tracking</span><b>,</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> etc. Even unimportant things like gender, age, and the user&#8217;s ethnicity are considered sensitive personal data and need to be secured.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the seller wants to process any of the said data, they need &#8216;consent&#8217; from the users. If the user provides consent for the processing of their information, then the business is allowed to use it whatever way it prefers.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is Data Processing Consent?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whenever we sign up for websites or simply open a website, we encounter pop-ups requesting consent in one form or the other. It could be a website asking for cookie tracking or a detailed consent form. But that is just one-way organizations ask for consent according to the GDPR.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The standard has set other merits for granting consent as well. Whenever a customer makes an online purchase, they consent to the use of their information; even if there isn&#8217;t any special consent form that needs to be filled, this data can legally be used by the seller. Because according to GDPR guidelines placing an order itself is an automatic consent.</span></p>
<h2><b>Which Data can be Processed?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every piece of information that allows the user complete anonymity can be processed by the seller. Apart from this, the information acquired after the user&#8217;s consent, whether explicit or automatic, can be used by the business.</span></p>
<h2><b>What Does Data Processing Mean?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When a company receives data that the users consent to, it is allowed to do whatever it wants with that information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They can save that data in their database, use it to send emails, or even display it. As long as the organization receives prior consent from the user, it can use the information however it wants.</span></p>
<h2><b>Does This Regulation Apply to Marketing Emails?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As far as the question of marketing emails goes, they are exempted from </span><a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=LEGISSUM:310401_2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GDPR</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rules. This means that the seller doesn&#8217;t need consent to send marketing emails.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Article (6) of the General Data Protection Regulations stipulates that companies possess the right to use customer information for legitimate use. Recital 47 has deemed marketing a &#8216;legitimate interest.&#8217; However, there&#8217;s one catch. This exemption holds only if emails are sent to existing customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the business chooses to send </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">marketing emails to new customers, they need consent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A simple checkbox requesting them to be a part of the e-mail list is sufficient. However, the company has to make sure to keep a record of this consent to avoid potential legal action.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, businesses using customer data for marketing purposes don&#8217;t need to worry about the regulations of GDPR too much.</span></p>
<h2><b>How Do Organizations Protect Data?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online businesses store a lot of information, including any details a customer provides for purchase in an online transaction. This information needs to be protected due to its sensitive nature.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For this reason, companies are willing to go to all lengths to protect this data. They have special divisions that work in collaboration with cybersecurity companies to ensure data security. These cybersecurity companies specialize in data protection and use elaborate measures to ensure no data leaks occur.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/gdpr-compliance-consulting-services/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VISTA InfoSec</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a widely renowned reputable company that provides cybersecurity consultation to top-notch companies. VISTA InfoSec provides its services to many notable enterprises like HP, IBM, Novartis, Toyota, and Walt Disney, among others.</span></p>
<h2><b>Final Words</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GDPR is a revolutionary set of regulations that ensures customer data isn&#8217;t misused. It is clearly defined to make sure no ambiguity or confusion arises in terms of maintaining the security and privacy of data. It is because of regulations like the GDPR that companies take extra measures to ensure data security. With GDPR enforced, companies and customers enjoy a trustworthy and safe relationship.</span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4562"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/impact-of-the-gdpr-on-online-transactions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide on Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification (CMMC 2.0)</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-cybersecurity-maturity-model-certification-cmmc-2-0/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-cybersecurity-maturity-model-certification-cmmc-2-0/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 11:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CMMC Service]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4545</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[CMMC 2.0 Model is the latest upgraded version of CMMC &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-cybersecurity-maturity-model-certification-cmmc-2-0/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>CMMC 2.0 Model </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">is the latest upgraded version of CMMC v 1.0 established back in 2020.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">The Department of Defense (DoD) in a bid to mitigate the growing risk of cyber security threats, released the Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification (CMMC) framework in January 2020. The objective behind establishing this framework was to ensure that businesses maintain an appropriate level of cybersecurity to protect Federal Contact Information (FCI) and Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to the enforcement of CMMC, contractors were responsible for implementing and monitoring their own cybersecurity best practices. However, these contractors were never audited and verified for their level of security maintained. This is because they were allowed to self-attest to their level of security. But with the establishment of CMMC, there was an entire shift in the paradigm of cybersecurity in the industry among contractors serving the DoD. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the DoD worked on the model of “</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">trust but verify”</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> rather than simply relying on the self-attestation approach. Unlike most cybersecurity frameworks, CMMC was designed and established to specifically address the issue of supply chain cyber security threats. The framework provides an excellent foundation for establishing a strong cybersecurity program to effectively manage cyber threats. Over a year after enforcing CMMC, the federal government 2021 issued a new version of the framework, </span><b>CMMC 2.0</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which is designed to simplify compliance requirements for contractors. Let us today learn about the </span><b>CMMC 2.0 model</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and understand the 3 levels and their different controls. </span></p>
<h2><b>What is CMMC Compliance?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification is a cybersecurity program developed by the United States Department of Defense (DoD). It is a standard and an industry best practice that organizations dealing with the Department of Defense (DoD) are required to comply with. The framework is designed to measure the defense contractor’s capability, and readiness, in mitigating cybersecurity threats prevailing in the industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CMMC Compliance framework is a collection of processes and security implementations of various cybersecurity standards such as NIST, FAR, and DFARS. Achieving CMMC Certification of Compliance simply suggests the level of maturity an organization’s current cybersecurity initiative stands at in the industry. The primary objective of attaining the certification is to improve the security of Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) and Federal Contract Information (FCI) that is in the possession and use of their federal contractors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CMMC or CMMC v1.0 was designed with 5 maturity levels ranging from the basics of cyber hygiene at Level 1 to the progressive and advanced level at Level 5. So, while an organization operating with non-classified DoD data was expected to meet Level 3 or a level below that for<a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/cmmc-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> CMMC Compliance</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations operating with high-value information were expected to achieve Level 4 or higher. However, last year in 2021 the Federal Government issued a new version of the framework, </span><b>CMMC 2.0</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. As per the updated version of CMMC 2.0, there are just levels in this version of compliance. So, now achieving</span><b> CMMC 2.0 compliance</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> requirements vary depending on the contract, with some requiring only Level 1 or Level 2, Level 3. Elaborating this in detail, let us learn </span><b>what the CMMC 2.0 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">is for a better understanding of the standard and the compliance program.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is CMMC 2.0?</b></h2>
<p><b>CMMC 2.0 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">is the latest version or rather an upgraded version of CMMC Compliance introduced earlier last year in 2021. So,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">the </span><b>CMMC 2.0 changes</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> currently included reducing the number of compliance “levels” from five to three, and changes in terms of making it easier for contractors to self-certify their compliance. Elaborating more on the latest version and explaining the </span><b>CMMC 2.0 controls</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we have outlined </span><b>CMMC 2.0 vs 1.0 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">changes introduced in the table below.  The table broadly outlines the key changes introduced in the latest version of the </span>CMMC 2.0 model<span style="font-weight: 400;"> by the DoD.</span></p>
<h4><b>CMMC 2.0 vs CMMC 1.0</b></h4>

<table id="tablepress-14" class="tablepress tablepress-id-14">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">Titles <br />
<br />
</th><th class="column-2">CMMC1.0<br />
<br />
</th><th class="column-3">CMMC2.0</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">Levels </td><td class="column-2">1. CMMC 1.0 included 5 progressive levels from Basic to Advanced. <br />
<br />
2. CMMC Levels 2 and 4 intended as transition stages between Levels 1, 3, and 5<br />
</td><td class="column-3">CMMC 2.0  includes 3 progressive levels:<br />
Foundational Level 1 (same as the CMMC 1.0 level 1)<br />
Advanced Level 2 (same as CMMC 1.0 level 3)<br />
Expert Level 3 (same as CMMMC 1.0 level 5)<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Requirements at each level <br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">1. Requirements include cybersecurity standards and maturity processes at each level. <br />
<br />
2. Cybersecurity standards consist of certain requirements from NIST SP 800-171 as well as CMMC-unique standards. <br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-3">1. Eliminates all maturity processes<br />
2. Eliminates all CMMC unique security practices:<br />
Advanced  Level 2 will mirror NIST SP 800-171 (110 security practices)<br />
Expert Level 3 will be based on a subset of NIST SP 800-172 requirements<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">Additional Changes </td><td class="column-2"></td><td class="column-3">1. Allows annual self-assessments with an annual affirmation by DIB company leadership for CMMC Level <br />
2. Bifurcate CMMC Level 3 requirements to identify prioritized acquisitions that require independent assessment, non-prioritized acquisitions that require annual self-assessment, annual company affirmation<br />
3. Development of a time-bound and enforceable Plan of Action and Milestone process. <br />
4. Development of a selective, time-bound waiver process, if needed and approved. <br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-14 from cache -->
<h2><b>Who needs to be CMMC Certified?</b></h2>
<p><b>CMMC 2.0</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is meant for any organization planning to do business with the DoD. This requirement applies to prime contractors, subcontractors, and any other supplier across the supply chain involved in the process. CMMC compliance requirements may vary depending on the contract, with some contracts requiring Level 1 or Level 2 compliance while other contracts may require up to Level 5. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The DoD contract specifies the level of compliance the contractor needs to meet. That said, for those businesses not working with the government or DoD does not mean they need not comply with CMMC 2.0. CMMC compliance, in general, is seen as an industry best practice so every organization should be able to achieve CMMC compliance.</span></p>
<h3><b>CMMC 2.0 Model</b></h3>
<p><b>CMMC 2.0 Model</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is the latest version of the standard designed to protect Federal Contract Information (FCI) and Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) that is shared with contractors and subcontractors of the Department. </span><b>CMMC Model </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">of</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">framework outlines the best cybersecurity practices at the highest level by domains that are segmented into different </span><b>CMMC 2.0 controls</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The contractors looking to work with DoD are required to demonstrate compliance by adhering to those controls and processes segmented across the 3 maturity levels of CMMC namely Level 1 Foundational, Level 2 Advanced, and Level 3 Expert. Let us learn about the 3 levels of the </span><b>CMMC 2.0 Model</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a bit in detail. </span></p>
<h3><b>CMMC 2.0 Model In a Glance</b></h3>

<table id="tablepress-15" class="tablepress tablepress-id-15">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">CMMC Model 2.0</th><th class="column-2">Controls/ Practices</th><th class="column-3">Assessment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">Level 1 Foundation</td><td class="column-2">17 practices </td><td class="column-3">Annual Self-Assessment </td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Level 2 Advanced</td><td class="column-2">110 practices aligned with NIST 800-171</td><td class="column-3">Triennial Third Party Assessment</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">Level 3 Expert</td><td class="column-2">110 + practices based on NIST 800-172<br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-3">Triennial Government led Assessment <br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-15 from cache -->
<h2><b>3 Levels of CMMC 2.0</b></h2>
<h3><b>Foundational Level 1</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CMMC 2.0 Level 1 is the foundational level comprising 17 controls of CMMC 1.0 Level 1, a limited subset of NIST 800-171. The CMMC Level1 applies to organizations handling and focused on protecting Federal Contract Information (FCI). These controls are meant for basic cyber hygiene to protect covered contractor information systems and engage contractors in developing a strong cybersecurity posture. Level 1 which is the foundational level of CMMC 2.0 allows self-assessment.</span></p>
<h3><b>Advanced Level 2</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CMMC 2.0 Level 2 is the advanced level comprising 110 controls of NIST 800-171. The Level 2 CMMC 2.0 is comparable to the Level3 of CMMC 1.0 requirements that reflect 14 domains and 110 controls of NIST SP 800-171 and eliminate all practices and maturity processes that were unique to CMMC. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It applies to those organizations handling Controlled Unclassified Information that is deemed critical to National Security Information.  Achievement and maintenance of compliance to this level require audit and assessment by a third party every three years. So, any contractor with a Defense Federation Acquisition Regulation (DFAR) clause in their contract will need to at least meet Level 2 requirements. Further, it is important to note that DFARS clause 252.204-7012 applies and specifies additional requirements beyond NIST SP 800-171 security requirements such as incident reporting. </span></p>
<h3><b>Expert Level 3</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CMMC 2.0 Level 3 focuses on protecting sensitive information against Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs) and is meant for organizations dealing with or handling Controlled Unclassified Information which is DoD’s top priority. Level 3 is similar or rather comparable to the CMMC 1.0 Level 5. Currently, the requirement for this level is still being developed but officially lists out 110 controls based on NIST 800-172. Any contractor with a DFARS clause in their contract will meet Level 3 requirements. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meeting this requirement will require going beyond NIST SP 800-171 security requirements and including incident reporting. It is also important to note that the assessment of CMMC Level 3 will be completed by the government and not CMMC Third Party Assessment Organization (C3PAO).</span></p>
<h2><b>NIST 800-171 14 Domains Covered in CMMC 2.0</b></h2>

<table id="tablepress-16" class="tablepress tablepress-id-16">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">Access Control</th><th class="column-2">Media Protection</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">Awareness and Training<br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Personnel Security</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Audit and Accountability</td><td class="column-2">Physical Protection</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">Configuration Management</td><td class="column-2">Risk Assessment</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Identification and Authentication</td><td class="column-2">Security Assessment<br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-6 even">
	<td class="column-1">Incident Response</td><td class="column-2">System and Communications Protection</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-7 odd">
	<td class="column-1">Maintenance</td><td class="column-2">System and Information</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-16 from cache -->
<h2><b>Getting Started with CMMC Compliance</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CMMC 2.0 which is the latest version by the DoD is set to establish in an effort to mitigate cyberattacks that threaten U.S. military, technology, and commercial aspects. It is a standard that is designed to equip organizations and effectively deal with cybersecurity threats better. So, organizations looking to achieve CMMC 2.0 Compliance must kick-start their journey by achieving NIST 800-171. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is simply because the CMMC 2.0 Advanced Level 2 mirrors the NIST 800-171 standard and aligns with the standard’s 110 security controls. So, clearly, compliance with NIST SP 800-171 will ensure effective implementation and achievement of certain levels of CMMC 2.0 compliance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations handling CUI and looking to attain the DoD contracts must get started on their compliance path even if the final CMMC 2.0 requirements are yet to be officially established and work their way through the federal rulemaking and enforcement of federal cybersecurity regulations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, since NIST 800-171 continues as the standard, organizations must seek to comply with and prepare to meet the NIST 800-171 control requirements without any delay as preparation for it will take up to over a year. For assistance and guidance on NIST 800-171 or CMMC2.0, you can get in touch with our compliance experts at VISTA InfoSec. They can guide you through the process and help your organization in the compliance journey. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4545"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 0px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <span class="kksr-muted">Rating</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-cybersecurity-maturity-model-certification-cmmc-2-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article 28 – General Data Protection Regulation Act</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/article-28-gdpr-act-explained/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/article-28-gdpr-act-explained/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[EU GDPR]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4503</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[&#160; The General Data Protection Regulation Act (GDPR) requires Data &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/article-28-gdpr-act-explained/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<audio class="wp-audio-shortcode" id="audio-4503-2" preload="none" style="width: 100%;" controls="controls"><source type="audio/mpeg" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Article-28-General-Data-Protection-Act.mp3?_=2" /><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Article-28-General-Data-Protection-Act.mp3">https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Article-28-General-Data-Protection-Act.mp3</a></audio>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The General Data Protection Regulation Act (GDPR) requires Data Controllers to establish a written agreement with the Data Processor stating the terms and conditions for the data processing activity. So, before getting into a contract with the Data Processor, a Data Processing Agreement must be signed between both parties regarding the conduct of processing personal data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The terms, conditions, and requirements of the Data Processing Agreement are specified in the </span><b>GDPR Article 28</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><b>Article 28 of GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> outlines the requirements and provides guidelines for Data Processors highlighting their responsibilities towards ensuring the privacy and security of personal data. Elaborating the requirement by Article 28</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">we have explained what is expected of the Data Processor to ensure <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/gdpr-compliance-consulting-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GDPR Compliance</a>.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is Article 28 of GDPR? </b></h2>
<p><b>GDPR Article 28 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">outlines requirements for Data Processor in terms of processing personal data. It further requires Data Processors to follow the documented instructions from the Data Controllers for processing the data. Under special circumstances as per the law or legal requirement, the Data Processor must notify the Data Controller of the legal requirement, before processing the data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This requirement also applies to the transfer of personal data to a third country or international organization. Under any circumstance, the Data Processor must ensure they are authorized to process the data while meeting the security and privacy requirements of GDPR. The Data Processor must take all measures required as per </span><b>Article 32</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ensuring the Security of Processing Personal Data. That said, given below are the requirements that Data Processors are expected to meet, as specified in </span><b>Article 28 of GDPR. </b></p>
<h3><b>Selection of Data Processor</b></h3>
<p><b>Article 28 Paragraph 1 of GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> clearly states the criteria for the selection of a Data Processor. The <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/what-is-a-data-controller-in-gdpr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data Controller</a> must only engage with Data Processors who have sufficiently implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures that meet the requirement of GDPR. This is especially while they ensure the protection of the rights of the data subject. Data Controllers must work with only those Data Processors who can guarantee the implementation of sufficient security measures that meets the requirements of GDPR. </span></p>
<h3><b>Engaging with Sub Data Processors</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Data Processor is required to engage with Sub Data Processors only based on the approval from the Data Controller. </span><b>GDPR Article 28 paragraph 2</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> states that the Data Processor shall not engage with another processor without the prior specific or general written authorization of the controller. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Further, incase by the general written authorization, the Data Processor engages with Sub Processor, then the Data Processor needs to inform the controller of the intended changes relating to the involvement of the other processors, thereby allowing the Data controller an opportunity to object to such changes if they are deemed unfit. </span></p>
<h3><b>Governance of Processing Activity</b></h3>
<p><b>GDPR Article 28</b> <b>paragraph 3</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> requires the Data Controller to establish and sign a contract with the Data Processor stating the duration of the processing, the nature, and purpose of the processing, the type of <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-gdpr-personal-data-and-data-subject/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">personal data</a> to be processed and categories of data subjects, and the obligations and rights of the controller. The contract further includes-</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The requirement of conducting the data processing activity should be based on the documented instruction from the Data Controller.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Data Processor should ensure access to the personal data to only those personnel committed to confidentiality or abide by the statutory obligation of confidentiality of data. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Processors are expected to implement technical and organizational measures as outlined in </span><b>Article 32 of GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Processors will not engage with other Sub Data Processors without the prior consent of the Data Controller. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In case the Data Processor hires a Sub-processor, the Sub Processor must flow through the obligations and ensure that the Data Processor’s obligations are enforced. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Data Processors are required to or rather expected to fulfill the Data Controller’s obligation to respond to the requests exercised by the data subject under the data subject’s rights in Chapter III. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Processors are expected to assist Data Controllers in ensuring compliance with the obligations according to Articles 32 to 36 taking into account the nature of processing and the information available to the Data Processor.  This includes assistance in ensuring </span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><b>Article 32 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Security of Processing </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><b>Article 33 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Notification of a Personal Data Breach to Supervisory Authority.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><b>Article 34 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Communication of a Personal Data Breach to the Data Subject </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><b>Article 35 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – Data Protection Impact Assessment </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><b>Article 36 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – Prior Consultation with Supervisory Authority </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the advice of the Data Controller delete or return the personal data </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Provide the Data Controller with any information demonstrating the Data Processor’s compliance with GDPR and further allow contributing to audits, including inspections, conducted by the controller or another auditor mandated by the Data Controller. </span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>Contractual Obligation on Processor</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If and when the Data Processor engages with a Sub Processor, they need to ensure that the Sub Processor is bound by the same terms and conditions in the contract between the Data Processor and Data Controller. The Data Process is liable to ensure that the Sub Processor performs its activities in compliance with the requirements of GDPR and meets all the obligations. </span></p>
<h3><b>Approved Code of Conduct</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Data Processor is expected to comply with the approved code of conduct as outlined in </span><b>Article 40 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or an approved certification as outlined in </span><b>Article 42 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to demonstrate they offer sufficient guarantees to securely process personal data.</span></p>
<h3><b>Standard Contractual Clauses</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As per the standard contractual clause the contract between the Data Controller and the Data Processor can be in whole or in parts as referred to in </span><b>paragraphs 7 and 8 of Article</b> <b>28 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and as a part of the certification provided to the controller or processor according to </span><b>Articles 42 GDPR </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and</span><b> Article 43 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><b>Commission Adopting Standard Contractual Clauses</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/key-requirements-of-gdpr-regulation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The GDPR Regulations</a> authorizes the commission to adopt standard contractual clauses allowing Data Controllers to use with Data Processors as referred to in paragraph </span><b>3 and 4 of Article 28 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and in accordance with </span><b>Article 93 GDPR</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which is Committee Procedures, paragraph 2.  </span></p>
<h3><b>Supervisory Authority Adopting Standard Contractual Clauses</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The supervisor authorities are authorized to adopt standard contractual clauses based on the consistency mechanism referred to in </span><b>GDPR Article 63</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>paragraphs 3 and 4 of Article 28 GDPR. </b></p>
<h3><b>Written Contracts</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The General Data Protection Regulation requires the contract, agreement, or any other legal act referred to in paragraphs 3 and 4 of GDPR Article 28 between the Data Processor and the Data Contractor shall be in writing, including in electronic form.</span></p>
<h3><b>Data Processor Considered as Data Controller</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In case where the Data Processor determines the purpose of Data Processing, the Data Processor shall be considered as a Data Controller with regards to that processing activity without prejudice to </span><b>Article 82, Article 83 &amp; Article 84 </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">of GDPR.</span></p>
<p><b>(Source – </b><a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2016/679/oj#d1e3150-1-1"><b>EUR-Lex</b></a><b>)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more details on GDPR Regulation or any queries, you can contact us or drop us a mail at </span><a href="mailto:info@vistainfosec.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">info@vistainfosec.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You can even read our other articles, webinars, and expert videos explaining the GDPR Regulation in detail and ways to achieve compliance. For guidance and consultation relating to the GDPR Compliance you can avail our </span><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/"><b>FREE ONE SESSION OF CONSULTATION WITH OUR EXPERTS</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">!</span></a></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4503"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/article-28-gdpr-act-explained/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Requirements of PCI DSS</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 10:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PCI DSS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4476</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The Payment Card Industry Security Standard Council (PCI SSC) for &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Payment Card Industry Security Standard Council (PCI SSC) for the benefit of customers, cardholders, and other stakeholders of the industry established a stringent payment card security standard known as PCI DSS. Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard is a framework designed and developed to protect sensitive card data in the environment. The payment security standard is a comprehensive framework that outlines 12 requirements that organizations are expected to meet to ensure compliance. Explaining the 12 <strong>PCI Compliance requirements</strong> in detail we have elaborated what is expected from an organization when implementing each requirement.</p>
<h2><strong>What are the 12 requirements of PCI DSS?</strong></h2>
<p>The 12 requirements outlined by the PCI Council for <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/pci-dss-audit-certification-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>PCI DSS Compliance</strong></a> comprises technical and operational security measures that need to be implemented within the card environment. That said, it is important to note and understand that the primary focus of these <strong>PCI DSS 12 requirements</strong> is protecting sensitive card data. For organizations to implement these requirements it is essential that they first understand each of these requirements and know the purpose of implementing these security measures. So, read the explanation below to get a better perspective and understanding of the payment security standard.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 1</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Install and Maintain a Firewall Configuration to Protect Cardholder Data</u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Compliance Requirements 1</strong> is all about protecting systems and networks against external threats by installing firewalls. The requirement outlined is to ensure that service providers and merchants maintain a secure network with updated and well configure firewalls and routers in place. Firewalls are applications that constantly monitor online traffic and restrict incoming and outgoing traffic based on the rules set and configured by the organization.</p>
<p>The rules and criteria’s configured in the firewall systems accordingly restrict access to the critical network comprising the card data in the environment.  Firewalls are primarily installed to protect the network comprising of sensitive card data or connect to systems comprising sensitive card data. So, organizations must accordingly define and establish standard rules and criteria for firewalls and routers to allow or deny access to the network. These rules need to be aligned with the PCI DSS requirements to ensure the protection of card data. Further, these rules should be reviewed every 6 months to stay updated with the changing requirements of the industry.</p>
<p><strong>Also Read:</strong> <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-firewall-requirements-infographic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS Firewall Requirement Infographic</a></p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 2</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Do Not Use Vendor Supplied Defaults for Systems and Passwords and Other Security Parameters</u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Compliance Requirements 2 </strong>is all about ensuring the organization’s systems, network, applications devices, and all access points are well secured using strong security parameters and passwords.  Systems, devices, and applications often come with factory default settings including usernames and passwords. These default settings and insecure configuration can be a huge threat to the card data environment for they can be easily hacked as these passwords are simple to guess, and more than often even published online.</p>
<p><strong>PCI DSS requirement</strong> prohibits the use of default passwords and other security parameters. Further, as per Requirement 2 of PCI DSS organizations are also required to maintain an inventory of all the system configurations, passwords, and hardening procedures that ensure implementation of the security requirement. System configuration procedures and processes should be well defined, documented, and followed each time a new system is introduced in the environment.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 3</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Protect Stored Cardholder Data</u></strong></h4>
<p>PCI DSS Requirement 3 is the most critical and essential requirement of the PCI Compliance standard. The requirement focuses on securing sensitive card data like the <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-can-pan-data-be-rendered-unreadable-as-required-under-pci-dss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PAN</a> number (Primary Account Number) and SAD (Sensitive Authentication Data) against authorized access. The PCI Compliance requirement 3 also outlines rules concerning the display of PAN numbers which should be only the first six and last four digits of the entire PAN number.</p>
<p>As per the requirement, organizations need to identify, classify and locate the data stored in the environment and thereafter adopt techniques of encryption, tokenization, and truncation to secure the stored cardholder data. The<strong> PCI DSS encryption</strong> <strong>requirement</strong> also states the need for organizations to maintain the encryption key management process. Overall the requirement focuses on securing the stored card data in the environment.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 4</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Encrypt Transmission of Cardholder Data across Open &amp; Public Network</u></strong></h4>
<p>In elaboration and extension to the <strong>PCI Compliance Requirement 3</strong>, the <strong>PCI DSS Requirement 4 </strong>states the need to secure card data in transition over an open or public network. The PCI DSS requirement 4 outlines the need to encrypt data transmitted across public networks. This can prevent incidents of breach, unauthorized access to sensitive data transferred over the open network. It also prevents the possibility of data getting compromised when the data is secured as per the <strong>PCI DSS encryption requirement</strong>. The technique of cryptography for the secure transmission of data goes a long way in protecting card data.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 5</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Use and Regularly Update Antivirus Software or Programs</u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI Compliance Requirement 5</strong> focuses on securing the card data environment against malware. Organizations are expected to install antivirus software on all systems including laptops, desktops, tablets, and mobile devices that are used to access sensitive card data. Anti-virus applications and software are designed to protect systems from viruses, Trojan horses malware. So, <strong>PCI DSS Requirement 5</strong> needs the systems, and devices in the Card data environment to be protected with the latest antivirus software. Further, the installed anti-virus programs should be regularly updated to ensure there is constant monitoring and detection of malware. Systems should also be well configured for updates and alerts to report suspicious or abnormal activity including unauthorized access attempts.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 6</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Develop and Maintain Secure Systems and Applications</u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 6</strong> focuses on protecting systems and applications by identifying vulnerabilities. For this organizations are expected to define and implement policies, procedures, and processes that facilitate the identification of vulnerabilities and classify the severity of risk posed to the card data environment.</p>
<p>Organizations must also ensure the deployment of critical patches in all systems in the card data environment, including operating systems, firewalls, routers, applications, and POS terminals to name a few.</p>
<p>The PCI requirement deals with the deployment of secure applications and systems and appropriate management of security patches, system and application configurations to prevent misuse or compromise of cardholder data. It also includes addressing common coding vulnerabilities in the software development process. The PCI DSS Requirement 6 also mandates the need to document all systems and application controls including defined roles responsibilities, policies, procedures, and testing processes relating to securing systems and applications.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4487 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06.png" alt="Free Consulting" width="1070" height="543" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 7</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Restrict Access to Cardholder Data by Business Need to Know</u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 7</strong> expects organizations to implement access control measures to ensure that the access to data is restricted to only authorized individuals, based on business requirements. The requirement focuses on establishing role-based access controls to facilitate access to card data on a need-to-know basis. For this organizations need to define roles and responsibilities and develop policies and procedures to implement appropriate access control measures.</p>
<p>Further, organizations must also ensure that the security policies and operational procedures for restricted access to cardholder data are documented. The document should comprise the list of users, their roles, and responsibilities for access to the card data environment. The restricted access to cardholder data will prevent threats of comprise, theft, and data breach in the organization.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 8</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Identify and Authenticate Access to System Components</u></strong></h4>
<p>As per the <strong>PCI DSS Requirement 8</strong> organizations are expected to assign unique IDs for every authorized individual to access the card data environment. This way organizations can monitor activities around the use of card data and bring in transparency and accountability in the data processing. Requirement 8 includes</p>
<p>Identification and authentication for all users to access system components including third-party vendors. The requirement further states the need to develop, implement and document policies and procedures that ensure appropriate access management including policies to revoke access granted to users terminated or transferred off their roles and responsibilities. It also requires establishing security measures for system components and remote access to card data which includes using techniques of cryptography, 2-factor authentications, and strong password securities.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 9</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Restrict Physical Access to Cardholder Data</u></strong></h4>
<p>The <strong>PCI DSS 9 requirement</strong> focuses on protecting physical access to systems comprising of cardholder data within the cardholder data environment. This would mean appointing onsite security personnel, maintaining access logs, CCTV devices for constant monitoring of entry and exit doors to the sensitive data center. The physical access records should be documented, maintained, and retained for a period of 90 days.</p>
<p>Organizations are expected to have in place policies, procedures processes are in place that ensures security measures are implemented. Organizations are also expected to maintain a separate policy and process distinguishing staff and visitors’ onsite accessing card data for easy tracking and monitoring process. Implementing strong security measures is essential to prevent unauthorized access that may further result in theft, compromise, or destruction of critical systems and cardholder data.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 10</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Track and Monitor Access to Network Resources and Cardholder Data </u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 10</strong> focuses on securing the network connecting to the cardholder data environment. For this organizations are expected to maintain a detailed audit trail associated with accessing system components with individual users. The requirement covers securing, tracking, and monitoring all user activities to network resources and the cardholder data. This is to identify anomalies, suspicious activities, and vulnerabilities in networks connecting to card data.</p>
<p>There must also be systems, processes, and procedures in place to monitor logs and alert suspicious activity. Organizations are also expected to maintain access logs and review them periodically for constant monitoring and future plan of action. PCI Compliance requires that the audit trail records meet certain standards in terms of the information contained including logging, audit functions, and data all of which must also be maintained for a period of not less than a year.</p>
<p>Tracking monitoring of network and system access significantly prevents data breaches and minimizes the exposure of risk to data. Without the audit trails and logging functionality determining the vulnerabilities and potential cause of the breach is impossible.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 11</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Regularly Test Security Systems and Processes </u></strong></h4>
<p><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 11</strong> requires organizations to regularly test, review and update their security systems and processes in place.  The testing of the implementation of all the security controls is to validate the effectiveness and identify any shortcomings in the systems and processes before it is identified by an attacker. So, conducting internal and external network vulnerability scans, performing quarterly Approved Scanning Vendor by PCI SSC, Application and Network Penetrations tests, Vulnerability scans at least yearly or after any significant change is crucial and essential as per the PCI Compliance requirement.</p>
<p>A segmented network that isolates the CDE from other networks must also be scanned and tested by performing Penetration Tests to verify that segmentation is effective. Organizations are also expected to implement Intrusion Detection &amp; Intrusion Prevention systems to monitor network traffic and identify suspicious traffic that could compromise security.</p>
<p>File monitoring is another important aspect of the PCI DSS requirement wherein the files should be reviewed every week to detect any changes that may have gone unnoticed. The test conducted is designed to validate all security controls and other technical aspects of an environment including the servers, networks, applications, processes, etc. This is to simply identify issues and addressed them in a timely manner before the vulnerabilities are exploited by malicious hackers.</p>
<h3><strong>PCI DSS Requirement 12</strong></h3>
<h4><strong><u>Maintain a Policy that Addresses Information Security for All Personnel</u></strong></h4>
<p>The<strong> Requirement 12 of PCI DSS </strong>is largely dedicated to establishing a strong Information Security Policy for all employees and other relevant parties. The PCI Requirement states the need for policies to be developed and made available to all employees, vendors, and contractors. Thereafter they should document an acknowledgment of reading the policy and being aware of their roles and responsibilities.</p>
<p>Organizations are expected to ensure that all the employees and vendors dealing with the cardholder data and having access to the cardholder data environment must be aware of the security policies, processes, and procedures of the organization. This is to ensure that the roles and responsibilities defined are performed in alignment with the requirements of PCI DSS.</p>
<p>The Information Security policy works like a roadmap for implementing security measures and directing employees, vendors, and other stakeholders to secure sensitive data and assets. The PCI requirement also states the need for the policy to be reviewed annually and update the same based on the evolving threat landscape.</p>
<p>Updating of policy is essential to reflect the changes in the environment and new security measures implemented to address the threats. The organization must develop and maintain policies including the Information Security Policy, Usage Policies, and Procedures, documents defining Information Security responsibilities, and other relevant supporting documents. In addition to this, organizations are also expected to conduct Annual Risk Assessments, Security Awareness Program, and Incident Response Plan and document the same for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c-8DnDq3e1E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">audit purposes</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thought</strong></h2>
<p>PCI DSS compliance is a daunting task for organizations to meet, especially when the requirements are so detailed and elaborate.  Even companies having the best of resources and genuine intent falter in the process and find it challenging to constantly maintain the standard.</p>
<p>Despite how difficult it is companies should strive to achieve PCI DSS Compliance by meeting all the 12 requirements outlined by the council. This is to prevent breaches and suffering significant consequences. Understanding each of the requirements and also referring to the compliance checklist shared by us in our blogs, organizations can surely achieve and continue to maintain compliance.</p>
<p>You can also watch  the expert video on PCI DSS Requirements</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="12 PCI DSS Requirements" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LfxLVxajRik?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4476"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-compliance-in-dubai/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-compliance-in-dubai/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 08:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PCI DSS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4422</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai for businesses dealing with payment &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-compliance-in-dubai/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for businesses dealing with payment card data is given great importance and priority. PCI DSS Compliance is a global payment card data security standard established in the online <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/industry/payment-card-industry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">payment industry</a>. It is a standard created and adopted by major card brands (Visa, Mastercard, Discover, American Express, and JCB) to promote secure card transactions in the industry. So, businesses that deal with these credit card brands need to ensure compliance with PCI DSS. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The payment security standard outlines requirements that mirror the industry&#8217;s best security practices. So, any organization or business processing, storing and transmits cardholder data are required to comply with PCI DSS. It is an internationally accepted standard applicable to businesses across the globe. So, businesses that are a part of the payment card industry are expected to ensure </span><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/pci-dss-audit-certification-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS Compliance i</a>n Dubai<span style="font-weight: 400;"> as well.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is PCI DSS Compliance? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) is one of the most stringent and comprehensive Information Security Standard designed for organizations that deal with online payment cards. Comprising of 12 requirements and multiple sub-requirements PCI compliance works as a guide for organizations in matters concerning with security of card data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Merchants and Service Providers are expected to protect the cardholder data of customers by implementing the highest level of security measures for protecting the systems, networks, and infrastructure comprising the card data. So, technically all Merchants and Service providers are contractually obliged to comply with <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>PCI DSS requirements</strong></a>. This is to reduce and minimize the risk of payment data breaches and theft of cardholder data.</span></p>
<h2><b>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like in any other country</span><b>, </b>PCI DSS Compliance <span style="font-weight: 400;">is an essential standard for online retail businesses and related service providers dealing with card data. Businesses are required to demonstrate </span>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai<span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reflect their commitment and implementation of high-level information security. The certificate demonstrates that the service offered by these organizations to all the Dubai-based customers is safe and of the highest level of security. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obtaining the certificate implies that businesses are adhering to the industry&#8217;s best security practices and standards governing all security aspects of online payment. This would include technology, operations, human resources, policies, procedures, etc., ensuring the highest level of card data protection. Any businesses in Dubai that wish to accept and store consumer credit card data are required to have their systems, operations, and IT infrastructure compliant with PCI DSS.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4306 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06.png" alt="free consulting" width="1070" height="543" /></a></p>
<h2><b>How does PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai Benefit Business?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Achieving PCI DSS standard although not mandatory but is seen as an industry best practice that organizations must adhere to. Not just from the compliance and security perspective but </span>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai<span style="font-weight: 400;"> for business comes with multiple benefits. Let us learn the benefits of achieving PCI DSS compliance for businesses in Dubai and other countries around the globe. </span></p>
<h2><b>Benefits of PCI DSS Compliance</b></h2>
<h3><strong>1.</strong><b>Security is Prime Focus</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In PCI DSS Compliance security of payment card data is the prime focus. So, </span>PCI  compliance in Dubai<span style="font-weight: 400;"> for business means establishing strong payment security measures in the cardholder data environment and the overall IT Infrastructure. Organizations are required to build multiple layers of security including firewalls, antivirus software, techniques of encryption, and software</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">that helps detect and monitor threats in the payment card systems and network. Further, they need to have in places policies, procedures, and processes that support their strategy for overall IT and online payment security.</span></p>
<h3><b>2.Builds Credibility</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCI DSS Compliance is an international payment security standard in the payment card industry. So, meeting the security standard requirement will help in building a strong business reputation and brand.  PCI DSS Compliance is not just about secure payment but also building strong credibility in the industry. The certification reflects secure operations and handling of card data. So, this builds credibility in the market and automatically a sense of trust among customers. Trust is an important factor in the success of any retail or online business and PCI DSS Compliance will help cement the trust of customers in your business. </span></p>
<h3><strong>3</strong>.<b>Prevents Data Breach</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since PCI DSS is an industry best payment security standard and practice, the chances of a data breach are low. The PCI Requirements outlines a comprehensive list of operational and technical security measures that ensure the highest level of security is met for processing or storing sensitive customer data. So, this way businesses turn out to be less vulnerable targets to cybercriminals. Hacking businesses with strong encryptions, firewall installations, etc. makes it harder for hackers to hack into systems and create a breach. So, achieving and maintaining PCI DSS Compliance is a wonderful way of preventing data breaches. </span></p>
<h3><strong>4.</strong><b>Global Payment Security Standards</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCI DSS is a globally accepted payment security standard and framework. So, be it any business in Dubai that plans to process, store or transmit card data will need to meet the PCI DSS Compliance requirements. This allows organizations to scale their business globally among other international players who are compliant with this international security standard and data protection program. Compliance with this standard gives a competitive edge to businesses on a global platform. </span></p>
<h3><b>5.Baseline for Other Security Program</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCI DSS compliance simply means you have taken the necessary steps to protect sensitive card data. Compliance with this security standard means having achieved some of the basic parameters of security standards across different regulatory requirements including GDPR, <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/hipaa-compliance-audit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HIPAA</a>, CCPA, and other international data security regulations. It gives a good kick-start to these compliance programs and facilitates an easy journey of Data Security and Privacy. Achieving PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai will mean organizations will be better equipped to comply with other federal and state-mandated data security regulations.</span></p>
<h3><b>Final Thought </b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCI DSS Compliance is an international standard and best practice that should be adopted by organizations across the globe. It is not a payment security standard for a specific region but for businesses around the globe dealing with payment card data. So, be it an organization or business from any nation, ensuring compliance with payment security standard is a good practice to ensure high-level security of sensitive card data. Besides ensuring </span>PCI DSS Compliance in Dubai<span style="font-weight: 400;"> for businesses will also mean prevention of data breach, financial consequences, reputational loss, and potential lawsuits in case of data breach or theft. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4422"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-compliance-in-dubai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Cyber Security Awareness Among Employees?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-to-build-cyber-security-awareness-among-employees/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-to-build-cyber-security-awareness-among-employees/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 12:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4473</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[According to a PwC poll, the epidemic has increased the &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-to-build-cyber-security-awareness-among-employees/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a PwC poll, the epidemic has increased the number of employees working from home to almost 70%. Remote working, however, has its own set of risks. Companies are vulnerable to a host of network attacks because of employee-owned devices, insecure connections, and inappropriate device usage. That is where cybersecurity awareness training for employees comes into the picture and plays a key role in preventing cyber attacks. Now there are several training centers available across India like </span><a href="https://hkrtrainings.com/cyber-security-training-hyderabad" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Training in Hyderabad</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> where you can get trained in the Cybersecurity domain and upgrade professional knowledge with the necessary skill sets. But knowing what Cyber Security Awareness means and what kind of training is required for employees is essential. So, in the article today we have shared how organizations can build cyber security awareness among employees. </span></p>
<h2><b>How to Build Cyber Security Awareness among Employees?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employees are seen as the weak connection in an organization when it comes to building and strengthening the cyber security measures in an organization. While an organization can implement advanced and highly sophisticated cyber security measures in its IT infrastructure, the security strength of the organization comes down to how well the employees are trained to deal with and prevent evolving cyber threats and attacks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employees are often the weak link to an organization&#8217;s critical infrastructure through whom the attackers obtain access to sensitive data, systems, and networks. This could be through phishing, ransomware and malware, and other social engineering tactics. So, to prevent such threats and risk exposure, cyber security awareness training among employees is crucial. Employees must strengthen the first line of defense within the organizations to protect against external threats. So, here are seven strategies to teach your remote workers about security best practices.</span></p>
<h3><b>1. Understand What Cybersecurity Means</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first step in introducing <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cybersecurity</a> education to employees is to communicate a clear message about what is going on in your firm in terms of cybersecurity. A message of this kind must be comprehensible, relatable, and diverse.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Comprehensible:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Avoid using technical jargon, as it may cause employees to become confused and your message is clouded. When feasible, utilize simple language that is comprehensible to non-technical people.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Relatable</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">: When discussing external dangers, focus on personal computer security and home network infiltration rather than the central network. Employees will be able to relate to the threat if it is presented in terms of their laptop or phone. This gives individuals a personal investment in the security strategy: no one needs to be the cause of a data breach that affects the entire organization.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Diversified: </b>It is conceivable that a single email summarizing everything won&#8217;t suffice. Consider the number of emails each employee receives daily. You could ensure that all employees read the message instead of rejecting it as just another announcement by diversifying your communication plan.</li>
</ul>
<h3><b>2. Recommend Using Your Devices with Extreme Caution</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a Forrester report, lost or missing devices are responsible for 15% of enterprise breaches. Training your staff about cybersecurity includes making them aware that their device serves as a doorway to your organization&#8217;s network, whether it&#8217;s a personal or corporate device. This emphasizes the importance of properly caring for and using their technology, especially when they are at home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Execute the following to help encourage excellent device ownership:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Demonstrate the distinction between personal and business use.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make having a work account that is subject to monitoring, prohibited installations, and web filtering a must.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beware of old-fashioned theft and loss.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensure that security patches and operating system updates are applied.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By automating push notifications and tracking the device&#8217;s state and the location at all times, a device monitoring and management solution like our Multi-OS Device Remote Management can help limit risk. However, this must only be used as a backup, and the employee must be responsible for end-user security best practices.</span></p>
<h3><b>3. Teach Your Employees How To Recognize Suspicious Behavior</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enhance your employee’s ability to notice suspicious activity and raise their cybersecurity knowledge by teaching them to look out for the subsequent signs:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">New apps or applications arrive unexpectedly on their smartphones.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange pop-ups appear at start-up, while normal functioning, or right before closure.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The device starts to slow down.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tabs or new extensions or in a browser.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Control of the keyboard or mouse is lost.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encourage your staff to promptly report any suspicious symptoms. Even when it turns out to be a false alert, the employee may benefit from it since it corrects problems in their gadget that are causing them to be less productive.</span></p>
<h3><b>4. Reinforcing the Confidentiality</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People who work from home are more likely to be complacent, which extends to cybersecurity. Even when they work in their PJs, teach them the value of authentication and passwords. Security does not have to be compromised just because they are relaxed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To protect your company&#8217;s data from cyber-threats, undertake the following training sessions with your employees:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Change your passwords regularly and in a unique way.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use real-world examples from previous data breaches to teach staff about the risks of using universal passwords. They may also want to check to see if any of their account credentials have been pawned.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discuss why authentication with several factors, VPNs, and other secure log-on processes are vital, even though they are time-saving.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Give concrete examples of stolen data events caused by an errant flash drive or a hacked personal Dropbox account to combat unsecured data storage of company data.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>5. Study Individual Cybersecurity Breach Cases</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike in an office with a managed network, the security of your employee’s personal computers can differ tremendously. Some people would connect using their home Wi-Fi, while others will use public Wi-Fi at a coffee shop.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some people may have outdated devices that are not supported by security patches, thus it may be required to address those issues by:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encourage staff to use the devices given by the company. Verify the device brand and model year if it&#8217;s BYOD to determine if there are any outstanding exploits.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conduct a security audit of your home networks. A few older routers, for instance, may use the weaker WEP protocol instead of WPA-2, but some might use the default password!</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pay special attention to nomad employees and create a security policy for them, as roaming data and public Wi-Fi hotspots pose unique risks.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>6. Utilize Cybersecurity Courses Available Online</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If it comes to cybersecurity awareness training for employees, there are a plethora of free internet materials available.</span></p>
<p><strong>For management:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small enterprise owners and executives will find instructional tools on the FTC website. There are also cybersecurity quizzes to put what you&#8217;ve learned to the test.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Department of Homeland Security&#8217;s cyberdefense learning toolkit is geared toward small business owners.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 20-step organizational control program from the Center for Internet Security teaches good cyber defense habits, detects suspicious behavior, and creates a skills gap analysis.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Federal Virtual Training Environment offers a thorough 6-hour course separated into 30 modules for managers.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>For employees:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quizzes, short courses, webinars, and certification are among the free and low-cost online training options available from the National Institute of Technology and Standards.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The National Cybersecurity Alliance&#8217;s webinar series begins in November 2019 and ends in November 2020, with one video released every other month.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ESET provides a free one-hour training course on remote employee best practices. The commercial edition adds a dashboard to monitor employee progress, as well as a phishing simulator, certification, and Linkedin badges.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The IS-0906 workplace security awareness course from FEMA is only one hour long and covers risks, prevention strategies, and responsive actions for remote workers.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>7. Make the Conversation on Cybersecurity Awareness an Ongoing</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate employees spend up to a quarter of their working day on email-related activities on average. A one-shot email message regarding cybersecurity is therefore a poor choice, as they might not have been able to grasp the importance or assimilate the material in one session.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following are some guidelines to follow while making a cybersecurity notification to your employees:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use various methods to educate people about cybersecurity, like regular announcements and newsletter updates.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Follow the KISS rule for every update: Keep It Simple and Short. This allows them to absorb the lesson and retain it during their busy day.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep up with the latest trends. Make sure your members are aware of any new crypto-malware or exploits that might cause phones to crash with a single message.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each time, use eye-catching strategies to get them to pay attention to the message. Use beautiful infographics rather than dry stats or do&#8217;s and don&#8217;ts. Try a video presentation for longer topics.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can also take cybersecurity tests to determine how well the concepts have stuck with you. HP, for instance, sends out phishing test emails as part of its email security training and applauds employees who report them to IT.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Conclusion:</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The cybersecurity awareness training for employees enables them to comprehend how they contribute to the protection of your firm. They are the first line of defense against external threats, instead of being just another cog in the organization&#8217;s wheel. Encourage vigilance and strong cybersecurity knowledge, and they&#8217;ll be able to take it with them far beyond the office, even when things have returned to normal.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4473"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-to-build-cyber-security-awareness-among-employees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Security 101 – Free Security Suites and their reliability</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/internet-security-101-free-security-suites-and-their-reliability/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/internet-security-101-free-security-suites-and-their-reliability/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 07:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4454</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[With our mundane lives becoming more and more integrated with &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/internet-security-101-free-security-suites-and-their-reliability/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With our mundane lives becoming more and more integrated with technology daily, it is important to impart awareness of the subject matter, as well. Technology and mainly the internet has changed the landscape of even our imagination, to say the least, and while it is still embarked on curving the bits and nooks of the world, some tweaks need to be paid attention to, also. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybercriminals and hackers are not just individuals in today’s climate but full fledge companies that are trying to get into your system to exploit you in whatever capacity they can and that is scary. But, what if I tell you we have a potion to scare these ghosts away? Cybersecurity scientists have come up with security suites that can protect your system integrity ensuring that you are secure at all times.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The one thing that needs to be taken out on the table before going forward is the huge part played by your internet service provider in your online privacy and security. You need to understand that signing up with a mediocre ISP might look innocent at the time but can get you in deep waters if your internet usage information falls in the wrong hands. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, you should always go with a reliable and consistent internet provider and if you are looking to get through to one, we recommend you to check out</span> <a href="https://www.localcabledeals.com/rcn/internet"><span style="font-weight: 400;">RCN internet plans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that offer supreme internet security along with seamless connectivity and unlimited data allowance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this article, we would discuss internet privacy and security, aspects of internet security suites, and some free internet security options.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What do we know about Internet Security?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet security is a type of computer security involving several security measures taken to ensure network safety, browser protection, application security, and operating system security. Most of the cybercrimes are initiated by the internet and thus, internet security offers rules and regulations against such threats.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is a Security Suite?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When different security software are bundled together, a distinct suite of software is created which is referred to as a Security Suite. Antivirus programs are the basis of any security suite and in addition to it, these security suites offer a range of security products like:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Anti-phishing </i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">blocks Trojan sites that are trying to invade your privacy</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Anti-spyware</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> protects your important data and information from leaking on the web</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Anti-ransomware</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> protects cybercriminals from ceasing your device against monetary gains</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Dark web monitoring</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> enables you to monitor your identity info on the dark web</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Firewall</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> blocks unsolicited and suspicious network traffic</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Online Backup </i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">offers the opportunity to save, backup, and recover your computer files </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Password Manager</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> helps you save and create unique passwords for your accounts and devices</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Parental control</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> restricts your child to access any inappropriate content</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Virtual Private Network (VPN)</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> allows you to anonymously surf websites </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong><i>Webcam Protection</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> protects your webcam from being accessed by a third party</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Can I use a free Internet Security Suite?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In all honesty, you might not be able to find a <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/top-6-internet-safety-rules-what-not-to-do-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">good internet security</a> suite for free because a security suite ranges some great security programs that would be hard to find for free as a bundle but you might just be able to get fortunate enough to find some good security programs or software separately.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Basic Protection</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Free internet security programs can offer great services when it comes to core protection and we would cover some free-of-cost, great antivirus applications in this article.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An application from a reputable manufacturer will be able to keep you safe from any cyber-attacks and might even feel enough. Believe it or not, Windows Defender, in-built in Windows 10, is true to its name and can defend your PC from most threats.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bells and Whistles</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having all that said, it is imminent to mention that the basic level of protection might be enough for some but certainly cannot be applicable for all. The premium security products have been designed to offer keen security from all aspects. For instance, free security software like an antivirus might just be doing the best for your system but its upgraded premium version might have an added feature of antispyware or parental control per se. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, free applications commonly come along with some pop-up advertisements ruining the consistency of your work.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technical Support</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another important aspect of free security product is that the technical support granted to you would be minimal. However, upgraded premium products will get you a 24/7 customer care unit at your disposal.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Best Free Internet Security Software Programs for Windows</span></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Bitdefender Antivirus Free Edition</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This free edition of Bitdefender Antivirus ranks high when it comes to antivirus software with utmost consistency. It brings you the basic essence of the paid premium Bitdefender suite which roughly means that you get top-notch protection against malware, phishing, ransomware, viruses, and other scams. It also takes instant action to secure your whole system. It is an award-winning anti-malware and anti-virus protection software and works really well with resource-intensive programs like media editors or games.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Kaspersky Security Cloud Free</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kaspersky Security Cloud Free is the free internet security suite from the giant online security company, Kaspersky. It brings the best core protection experience from its paid counterpart but certainly without all the bells and whistles. In addition to an anti-virus and anti-malware system, Kaspersky Security Cloud Free now flaunts an integrated VPN feature as well as a secure password function.  It is designed to remove any virus or malware automatically and runs well in the background. It also scans your emails and other messaging apps for further protection.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Avira Free Antivirus</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avira Free Antivirus is hands down one of the best internet security suites currently available for free. This antivirus provides regular cleanups and offers real-time and manual protection against all odds. It can detect and block unnecessary and unwanted applications. You can take benefit from its adblocker and website detection feature by installing its browser extension. With rainbow comes rain as well and thus it has a downside too – way too many popups asking you to upgrade to its premium version.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Last Words</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can, of course, purchase security software in the form of a package or an individual program. However, we recommend that you only do so after doing some research to ensure that you get the best product for your needs. Internet security is a serious matter and your personal information should not be put at risk by using something other than what has been proven to work. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4454"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/internet-security-101-free-security-suites-and-their-reliability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Careers Within Preventative Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/careers-within-preventative-cybersecurity/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/careers-within-preventative-cybersecurity/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 07:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4445</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Businesses have become the custodians of massive amounts of data &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/careers-within-preventative-cybersecurity/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Businesses have become the custodians of massive amounts of data over the past several decades. Some of it is unstructured and ostensibly useless, but much of it contains valuable, sometimes very personal information. More data, more problems. As information proliferated so has the phenomenon of data breaches. Information leaks cost businesses millions of dollars, months of their time, and a good deal of trust from the consuming public. It is a bad situation but also one that breeds opportunity. Data security jobs serve as a lucrative way to flex your tech skills, earn a good living, and keep people’s personal information safe. In this article, we take a look at a few </span><a href="https://studyonline.ecu.edu.au/blog/top-10-cyber-security-jobs-and-salaries"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data protection careers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h2>Cyber Security Analyst</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber Analysts come in and take a close look at a business&#8217;s digital operations and data management strategies. While they don’t necessarily design security programs, they do craft strategies with existing tools that are specifically crafted to suit the needs of the business that they are representing.  The actual tasks they perform can vary considerably depending on their client. They may monitor security threats, conduct regular system checks, and install firewalls and other resources designed to keep information safe. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though much of the job is IT-focused, cyber security analysts may also benefit from good communication skills. Because parts of their job may involve explaining complicated programs, threats, and responses to people who don’t have a tech background, it helps to be able to take complex ideas, and present them clearly to laypeople. While there are several ways to enter the field, the majority of cyber analysts have at least a bachelor&#8217;s degree in cyber security.</span></p>
<h2>Cyber Security Architects</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber security architects take the responsibilities of cyber analysts to the next level. They too keep an eye out on the horizon for potential breach threats. However, they take a significantly more active role in developing responses to nip the threats in the bud. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After </span><a href="https://online.maryville.edu/blog/cyber-crime-investigation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">evaluating</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> an organization&#8217;s threats, the cyber security architect develops bespoke IT systems for maintaining the business network. Once systems are operational, the cyber security architect maintains and builds upon them to make sure the network continues to benefit from maximum protection.  Most cyber security architects will have a bachelor&#8217;s degree in computer science. Many will also have a graduate degree in something like Certified Information Systems Security. </span></p>
<h2>Security Administrators</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security administrators see more to the day-to-day maintenance and operations of a business’s IT infrastructure, particularly as it relates to meeting their cyber security needs. Like all of the jobs on this list, threat analysis may factor into the responsibilities of the security administrator.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On a day-to-day level, however, tasks may include updates, repairs, and security performance evaluations. IT infrastructure can take as much effort to maintain as it does to create in the first place. Security administrators are there to keep everything running smoothly in the long run.  While a range of different backgrounds may equip a person for this job, education in cyber security or computer science will typically be required. </span></p>
<h2>Cybersecurity Consultant</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity Consultants are experienced and specialized professionals hired by organizations to access their expertise in cyber security compliance and regulatory needs of the industry. They are hired by organizations for their advisory services. They assist businesses in developing and implementing strong security measures and policies that facilitate various regulatory and compliance requirements.  They help organizations in developing efficient strategies to protect their systems, network, and infrastructure in alignment with the industry regulatory requirement. </span></p>
<h2>Incident Response Analyst</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An Incident Response Analyst is an individual appointed in an organization who is responsible for monitoring, detecting, and reporting any threats directed against the organization&#8217;s systems and infrastructure. While some Incident Response Analysts work independently as consultants, others work as a part of an organization&#8217;s Cyber Security Incident Response Team.  The Incident Response Analyst assists the affected business with strategies and responses to address the occurred incidents. They are required to follow and implement certain procedures based on an organization&#8217;s pre-approved Cyber Security Incident Response Plan to address the issues accordingly. </span></p>
<h2>Ethical Hacker</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ethical hacker, the darker hero of the preventative cybersecurity industry. Ethical hackers have the skills to penetrate system networks and retrieve data, yet they chose to use their powers for the good.  Certified ethical hackers essentially approach a business&#8217;s network with the perspective of a hacker. They test for points of vulnerability and see what it would take to access sensitive information. They attempt to get around firewalls and other security measures to determine how effective they are. When weak spots are identified, the ethical hacker fortifies them. It is more like hiring a burglar to test the security measures and make sure no one can break into your house. </span></p>
<h2>Penetration Tester</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Penetration testers operate similarly to an ethical hacker. They run tests on systems to detect points of vulnerability and make fortifications where it is deemed necessary. The work can be very niche with people specializing in specific operating systems. As with all of these jobs, however, the purpose of the work is straightforward. Find risk and eliminate it.  Penetration testers are hired to identify security gaps in systems and strengthen the cybersecurity measures in an organization.</span></p>
<h2>Chief Information Security Officer</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Chief Information Security Officer is hired to ensure that a business’s security features are running at peak performance. They make enterprise-level decisions that shape the entire trajectory of how a business’s digital assets are protected. In other words, they are the ones calling the shots. A penetration tester or an ethical hacker might identify threats, but it is the Chief Information Security Officer that approves and ensures the implementation of strategies. It is good to work if you can get it, but these jobs are hard to come by. Most people occupying these positions have significant experience both in business and in IT. </span></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In today’s modern digital world cyber security is the need of the hour for every business. Although the IT industry is flooded with opportunities yet cyber security is a niche that is facing a short supply of security professionals. This is seen especially when there is a growing demand and importance of cyber security professionals in the industry.  From specialized consultants, all the way up to C-suite executives, there is a persistent and constant need for such professionals by businesses across different industries.  So, cybersecurity professionals looking for a lucrative career in this niche now is the right time to gain a strong foothold in the world of preventative cyber security. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4445"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/careers-within-preventative-cybersecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCPA Compliance Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/ccpa-compliance-checklist/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/ccpa-compliance-checklist/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CCPA]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4430</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[California Consumer Privacy Act is a data privacy regulation established &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/ccpa-compliance-checklist/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">California Consumer Privacy Act is a data privacy regulation established in the US</span><b>. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Achieving and maintaining compliance with the regulation can be</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">overwhelming for organizations. But with the right understanding of the CCPA Compliance regulation and adhering to the compliance requirements, achieving compliance can be easy. So, explaining the regulation in detail we have shared an informative checklist that organizations can refer to as steps to achieve <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/ccpa-compliance-audit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CCPA compliance</a>. So, before getting into the details of the checklist, let us first learn about the regulation for a better understanding of the requirements.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is CCPA Compliance?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA) which came into effect on January 1, 2020, is a regulation designed to protect the privacy rights of citizens of California. It is the first comprehensive law in the US that is established to protect the personal information of California residents. CCPA regulations promote security, transparency, and privacy of consumer’s data. It is seen as a regulation that mirrors <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/infographic-implication-of-gdpr-compliance-on-eu-citizen-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EU GDPR</a> in terms of the intent of its establishment and certain measures to secure data. CCPA regulation applies beyond California and applies to any for-profit business that falls in the scope of compliance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CCPA applies to organizations, or businesses that are “for-profit”, serving and processing data of residents of California. Businesses that earn more than $25,000,000 gross annual income and buy, sell, process personal information of at least 50,000 California consumers, households, or devices annually fall in the scope of CCPA Compliance. Further, a business that makes 50% or more of the annual gross revenues from selling the personal information of the California consumers also falls in the scope of <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/ccpa-compliance-guide-for-businesses-in-california/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CCPA Compliance</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that we know a bit about the regulation let us understand how businesses can comply with CCPA and meet all the requirements of the regulation. </span></p>
<h2><b>CCPA Compliance Checklist</b></h2>
<h3>A. Create a Personal Information Inventory</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding what is defined as personal information under CCPA and creating an inventory for the same is a crucial part of the compliance process. Organizations need to map out the flow of all the data personally identifiable information (PII) stored and processed in the organization to secure the data. This would include identifying systems, devices, and network that comprises sensitive personal information. So, basically, any information that identifies relates to, describes, and is capable of being associated with a particular individual or consumer needs to be protected under the CCPA regulation. For this, identifying data, classifying them, and creating an inventory is an essential first step of the compliance process. </span></p>
<h3>B. Create Policy, Procedures &amp; Processes</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations need to have in place privacy policies, procedures, and processes to support the security and privacy measures for the compliance program. They should be drafted and documented in plain language so that consumers, employees, and other stakeholders can easily understand the content. Further, these documents should be reviewed periodically and updated from time to time.</span></p>
<h3>C. Operational &amp; Technical Security Measures</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The prime focus of CCPA Compliance is to ensure the security and privacy of consumer data. So, implementing necessary measures to uphold the rights of consumers and protect their data is essential. For this, business needs to have a necessary security policy in place, implement encryption techniques and other security measures where applicable to ensure privacy and security of personal data. Identify the data stored, in systems, devices, and networks to accordingly implement security measures for consumer’s personal data. All of these security measures and appropriate steps are required for achieving and maintaining CCPA compliance. </span></p>
<h3>D. Uphold Consumer Rights</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CCPA broadly outlines a list of consumer rights that organizations must uphold. On request, the organization must adhere to it and allow consumers to exercise their rights. CCPA allows the consumer</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">rights over their personal information which includes Right to access, Right to portability, Right to deletion, Right to notice, Right to opt-out, Right to non-discrimination to name a few. Organizations should establish a policy and process to uphold these rights of consumers. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4306 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06.png" alt="free consulting" width="1070" height="543" /></a></p>
<h3>E. Consent for Minor</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protecting the information of minors is very important. There should be parental or guardian consent that should be provided on behalf of the minor. The consent received should be documented for future reference. There should also be an explicit grant for parents and guardians to access their children’s information when needed.</span></p>
<h3>F. Ensure Transparency in Data Processing</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Transparency is the key to CCPA Compliance. Organizations must ensure transparency in their data collection and processing operations. Customers should be informed or notified about the collection and use of their data clearly. They should also be given an “opt-out” option in case they wish to not allow processing and collection of their data. The “opt-out” option should be visible and easy to execute for all customers.  Pop-up window addressing the collection of personal information, and “Don’t Sell My Personal Information” should be clearly visible on the website. This demonstrates the organization&#8217;s efforts of upholding consumer’s privacy rights. </span></p>
<h3>G. User-friendly Information requests</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations should provide consumers information on ways to exercise their rights over their personal data. The request process should be easy, quick, and hassle-free for consumers. CCPA clearly outlines the need for organizations to provide an easy process for consumers to exercise their right over personal data.  Further, they should have a process in place to ensure quick response to requests from consumers who wish to access, delete or exercise any other right over their information. These processes need to be enforced with having necessary policies and procedures in place. All of this should further be documented and maintained for the compliance audit process and future reference. </span></p>
<h3>H. Respondto Requests in Time</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CCPA law mandates the need for an organization to establish an effective process to respond to the request promptly. This would mean responding to all requests including access, delete, and opt-out of the sale to name a few. Organizations should be prompt in their response once they receive the request. For this organization needs to plan and establish a systematic process to support the requirement on time.</span></p>
<h3>I. Compliance Training for Employees</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employees are an integral part of the organization and business processes. So, training employees and building awareness of the regulation and its requirements is essential. Employees need to be aware of the roles and responsibilities in line with the requirements of meeting CCPA compliance. For this, organizations should have regular training for employees to meet compliance requirements and handle customer’s data responsibly. Employees should also be given training on ways to handle customer inquiries pertaining to their rights to access their personal data. This is essential for CCPA requires organizations to respond to consumer&#8217;s requests promptly. </span></p>
<h3>J. Internal Assessment &amp; Review</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conduct an internal assessment and review process from time to time to ensure processes are in place and whether or not they are effective. This is important to ensure the organization has all measures in place and meets the CCPA requirements. It is during these internal assessments and reviews that organizations can identify gaps against the CCPA requirements and remediate the gaps in time.</span></p>
<h2><b>Consider CPRA Compliance Gaps</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">California Privacy Right Act is the latest version of the California Consumer Privacy Act that was passed on November 3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rd,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 2020. It is said to take effect on January 1, 2023, enhancing California residents’ existing privacy rights and providing protection to consumers concerning how their personal information is used. So, for organizations to stay ahead of the compliance game, should conduct a <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/key-additions-and-amendments-introduced-under-the-cpra-act/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CPRA</a> gap analysis to identify gaps and bridge them on time. Organizations should conduct an assessment and accordingly plan and prioritize their implementation to fill the gaps and meet the CPRA requirements. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4430"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/ccpa-compliance-checklist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vendor Third-Party Risk Management in PCI DSS</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vendor-third-party-risk-management-in-pci-dss/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vendor-third-party-risk-management-in-pci-dss/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 13:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PCI DSS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4403</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Given the operational efficiency and low overhead cost, collaboration with &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vendor-third-party-risk-management-in-pci-dss/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given the operational efficiency and low overhead cost, collaboration with a <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/vendor-third-party-risk-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vendor Third Party</a> for the processing of online payments is very common. However, like a double-edged sword, outsourcing business operations and services can be a huge risk for Merchants dealing with them. One of the major risks that merchants often deal with Vendor Third Party collaboration is the online payment card-related cybercrimes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensuring implementation of high-level security standards and compliance with PCI DSS from the vendor can be challenging.  Typically for large business and enterprises, incurring the heavy cost of <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/pci-dss-audit-certification-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS</a> comprehensive implementation and ongoing compliance is not a big deal, but for smaller business such as Independent Service Organizations or Third Party Service providers, mostly with a staff strength of 50-100 people, it gets very difficult and expensive to maintain such ongoing expenses. This is when Vendor Third-Party Risk Management plays a key role in minimizing risks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explaining what Vendor Third-Party Risk Management is all about in this blog, we have also shared details on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LfxLVxajRik" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS Requirement</a> 12 on Vendor Third-Party Risk Management. But let us first understand who is a vendor third party in the payment card industry. </span></p>
<h2><b>Who is a Vendor Third Party?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">n the payment card industry, a vendor third party is any service provider or vendor who stores, processes or transmits cardholder data (CHD) on behalf of the merchant. Since they have access to sensitive card data their operations have a direct security impact on the cardholder data environment (CDE). For those reasons, merchants need to evaluate their risk before proceeding with any vendor for business collaboration.  Merchants need to have in place a vendor third-party risk management to mitigate risk and ensure compliance. So, now that we know who is a vendor, let us further move on to understand about vendor third party risk management.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4306 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06.png" alt="free consulting" width="1070" height="543" /></a></p>
<h2><b>What is Vendor Third-Party Risk Management?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vendor Third-party Risk Management (VTPRM) is a risk management process that specifically focuses on identifying and mitigating risks concerning vendors that businesses collaborate with for outsourced services. It is a process of evaluating the vendors and service providers, to determine the risk exposure and the security measures that they have in place. It is an essential and integral process in various compliance and cyber security programs. Specifically, in <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-compliance-levels-for-merchants-service-providers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS, merchants</a> are expected to have in place vendor third-party risk management programs to track and monitor all their vendors and service providers dealing with sensitive card data. Further, as per PCI DSS requirements, vendors are also expected to ensure compliance with the payment security standard. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, it is also important to note that Vendor Third-party Risk Management is confused and interchangeably used with Third-party Risk Management programs. However, they are two different programs wherein Vendor Third-party Risk Management just focuses on vendors and service providers whereas Third-party Risk Management encompasses evaluating all types of third parties. The scope of the Vendor Third-party Risk Management program greatly depends on the organization, its industry, and the regulatory and compliance requirements. But in general Vendor Third-Party, Risk Management is seen as a best practice in <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cyber security</a> and compliance programs including PCI DSS.</span></p>
<h2><b>What does PCI DSS say about Vendor Third-Party Risk Management?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCI DSS Compliance applies to any organization that deals with card data, be it processing, storing, or transmitting card data. In that sense, PCI DSS applies to vendor third party and service providers offering outsourced services.  So, organizations that have outsourced their payment operations, system management, and data processing services are required to also ensure that vendors are compliant with PCI DSS requirements.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> PCI Council in its PCI DSS requirement 12.8 requires merchants to manage their third-party vendors. The requirement focuses on vendor management and also mandates organizations develop and execute policies and processes to manage vendors and service providers having access to cardholder data. The below-given table explains the PCI DSS 12.8 Requirement concerning vendor management briefly. These are requirements which are additionally applicable to Third Party vendors. So, these are not the only requirements but are required additionally.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<table id="tablepress-13" class="tablepress tablepress-id-13">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8</th><th class="column-2">Maintain and implement policies and procedures to manage service providers with which cardholder data is shared, or that could affect the security of cardholder data.<br />
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8.1 <br />
Maintain a list of service providers including a description of the service provided.<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Merchants are required to maintain a detailed list of service providers and vendors they deal with along with a detailed description of all the services provided. This makes it easier to monitor all service providers having access to the card data. It also helps determine the level of risk exposure to the card data outside the organization's environment. </td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8.2 Maintain a written agreement that includes an acknowledgment that service providers are responsible for the security of cardholder data the service providers possess or otherwise store, process, or transmit on behalf of the customer, or to the extent that they could impact the security of the customer’s cardholder data environment</td><td class="column-2">Merchants are expected to have in place contracts and agreements with the vendors they work with to ensure roles and responsibilities are well defined and reasonable security measures are implemented to protect the card data.  </td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8.3<br />
Ensure there is an established process for engaging service providers including proper due diligence prior to engagement.<br />
</td><td class="column-2">Merchants are expected to conduct a thorough risk assessment on all their vendors and service providers to evaluate the risk exposure before getting into a contract with them. </td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8.4 Maintain a program to monitor service providers’ PCI DSS compliance status at least annually.</td><td class="column-2">PCI DSS compliance applies to any organization dealing with card data. So this includes the vendors and service providers as well who have access to the card data of the merchant’s customers. So, it is the responsibility of merchants to ensure that their vendors are compliant with PCI DSS. For these reasons, merchants are required to monitor and evaluate their vendor’s compliance status annually. They need to maintain information and collect evidence from vendors on their status of compliance by asking Attestation of Compliance (AoC). </td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-6 even">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.8.5 Maintain information about which PCI DSS requirements are managed by each service provider, and which are managed by the entity.</td><td class="column-2">Merchants need to have a detailed document comprising not just the list of vendors and service providers they work with but also the specific requirements applicable to each of them based on their service offering. This means there should be roles and responsibilities clearly documented to ensure accountability and compliance with PCI DSS. <br />
<br />
</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-7 odd">
	<td class="column-1">PCI DSS Requirement 12.9 <br />
Service providers acknowledge in writing to customers that they are responsible for the security of cardholder data the service provider possesses or otherwise stores, processes, or transmits on behalf of the customer, or to the extent that they could impact the security of the customer’s cardholder data environment.<br />
<br />
</td><td class="column-2">An acknowledgment by the service providers to their customers on their acceptance to demonstrate commitment to ensuring the security of cardholder data also ensures accountability towards meeting PCI DSS Compliance requirements.<br />
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-13 from cache -->
<h2><b>Final Thought </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due diligence, Documentation of compliance evidence, and monitoring vendor third party forms the fundamental pillars of Vendor Third-Party Risk Management. Ultimately Vendor Third-Party Risk Management is all about conducting the required due diligence, engaging with vendors ensuring complete accountability with documents of contracts, and agreements, in place, and monitoring them from time to time. Ensuring vendors meet the PCI DSS requirements is one way of ensuring they have taken measures to safeguard customer card data.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4403"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vendor-third-party-risk-management-in-pci-dss/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Key Cybersecurity Threats to Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-key-cybersecurity-threats-to-cloud-computing/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-key-cybersecurity-threats-to-cloud-computing/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 09:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4398</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Cloud computing allows users to quickly spin up workloads without &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-key-cybersecurity-threats-to-cloud-computing/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud computing allows users to quickly spin up workloads without dealing with the burden of maintaining physical infrastructure, resulting in higher overhead costs. With an increasing number of businesses embracing the cloud in some form or another, it comes with its own set of security risks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Gartner, global research and consultancy firm, public cloud end-user spending might climb by as much as 18 percent by 2021. Cloud computing brings with it a slew of new security concerns and roadblocks. Data is kept at a third-party source and accessed using the internet through the cloud. So get your </span>free cloud computing course with a certificate<span style="font-weight: 400;"> now to get in the career demand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud security and risk are viewed as a shared responsibility by cloud service providers. In this model, the cloud service provider is in charge of its security while the customer secures the data they store there. Every cloud computing user is responsible for ensuring their data from security risks and limiting access to it, whether it is software-as-a-service (SaaS) like Microsoft Office 365 or infrastructure-as-a-service (IaaS) like Amazon Web Services (AWS).</span></p>
<p>Cloud data security<span style="font-weight: 400;"> is the heart of cloud computing security problems. The majority of difficulties in the cloud arise from the data clients save there, whether it is a lack of data visibility, an inability to manage data, or data theft. Read on to examine the top cloud security issues across SaaS, IaaS, and private cloud, ranked by the frequency with the enterprises worldwide encounter them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given its expanding popularity, what are the security dangers connected with cloud computing? So here is the list of top cyber risks that are listed below.</span></p>
<h2><b>1.Misconfiguration of the cloud</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As evidenced by recent data breaches at Verizon and Adobe Creative Cloud, incorrect cloud infrastructure configurations remain the main cause of cloud computing security breaches. The following are some of the most prevalent cloud infrastructure configuration issues:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The general public accesses the buckets.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access to resources is restricted in an insecure manner.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In public repositories, credentials have been exposed.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consistent monitoring for cloud misconfigurations becomes critical because most cloud breaches are caused by misconfiguration. That is what the Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM) software allows you to achieve. As a result, according to Reportlinker.com, the global CSPM market is expected to rise from USD4 million in 2020 to USD9 million by 2026. CSPM is now a required technology for cloud-based enterprises, according to the Gartner security summit in 2021.</span></p>
<h2><b>2. Service Denial</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud settings are particularly vulnerable to Denial of Service (DoS) and Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks because they require Internet connectivity to access them. Attackers can inundate a company&#8217;s cloud network with massive online traffic, leaving resources unavailable to consumers and employees.  A DoS attack will be more devastating the more significant the portion of infrastructure in the cloud. You can learn about it during a </span><a href="https://www.simplilearn.com/cloud-computing-bootcamp-certification-course" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cloud computing bootcamp.</a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To reduce the danger of DoS attacks, take the following steps:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For reducing the attack surface, limit access to network ports, protocols, and services.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To avoid single points of failure, use load balancers and content delivery networks (CDNs).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a baseline of usual traffic can help you notice anything out of the ordinary.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Install a web application firewall to keep attackers trying to exploit known flaws.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>3. Insider Threats:</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internal security breaches account for up to 43% of all security breaches. Insider attacks can be deliberate (as in the case of angry employees) or unintentional (as in the case of a rogue employee).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having proper training and awareness can prevent insider assaults. When designing your environment&#8217;s access controls, follow the concept of least privilege to limit employees might cause and build a suitable personnel off boarding strategy. Most crucially, cloud security is a people problem as it is a technical one. Taking care of your employees lowers the chances of renegade employees generating issues for your company.</span></p>
<h2><b>4. Infrastructure Visibility is Reduced</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because you&#8217;re using a third-party service for computing, you&#8217;re giving up some control to the cloud service provider (CSP). Because your organization does not own the physical infrastructure in this situation, getting a complete insight into your infrastructure and resource usage is more complex, especially if you lack the necessary technical competence. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The cloud is run on a shared responsibility model, which means you and the cloud service provider share the responsibilities. While the CSP manages the physical infrastructure, you are still responsible for ensuring the security of your data and application workloads in the cloud. This lack of visibility is a prevalent symptom in many complex cloud settings, rendering it vulnerable to data breaches and threats such as the next on this list, unauthorized cloud workload use. </span></p>
<h2><b>5.Unauthorized Workloads on the Cloud</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The majority of significant CSPs use a self-service paradigm. It allows users to provide and de-provision workloads according to their requirements quickly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand, this ease of usage leads to Shadow IT, or IT resources created and used without the IT staff knowledge. Shadow IT carries its own set of dangers, which include (but are not limited to)</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data loss and leakage are more likely.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Costs that were not expected.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Violations of the law</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensure to follow the concept of least privilege and only allow users to create workloads as part of their employment. Set up audit logging and alerting tools so you can keep track of all internal activity and quickly identify any unlawful ones.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion:</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">None of these dangers are novel, but the shifting landscape and move to the cloud necessitate a different approach than traditional on premise workloads. Being proactive not only boosts your organization&#8217;s reputation and allows you to focus on the tasks that add value to your business, but it also helps you avoid more extensive, more costly challenges. </span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4398"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-key-cybersecurity-threats-to-cloud-computing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Attack Vectors and How to Avoid Them?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cyber-attack-vectors-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cyber-attack-vectors-and-how-to-avoid-them/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4332</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[What Are Cyber Attacks? Cyber-attacks have been a critical issue &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cyber-attack-vectors-and-how-to-avoid-them/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Are Cyber Attacks?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber-attacks have been a critical issue for millions of internet users around the world. People are worried about cyber security on their laptops, computer, or cell phone with regards to hackers getting access to their confidential information. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While there are many secure and legitimate websites, there are many malicious codes used by hackers to gain access to your information for dangerous reasons. Read the article to discover common cyber attack vectors and ways to avoid them.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Are Common Cyber Attack Vectors?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A cyber attack is an attempt by a hacker to destroy or damage a computer system or network. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Essentially attack vector is a method that allows unauthorized parties to gain access to a protected network so they can launch a cyber attack.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybercriminals find vulnerabilities in the system and use attack vectors to exploit those vulnerabilities to their advantage. Once they gain access into the network, they can even gain access to highly sensitive information such as PII or personally identifiable information and other valuable information in the network.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.ibm.com/in-en/security/data-breach"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The cost of an average data breach is around $4.24 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Therefore, it is important to learn and understand what attack vectors cybercriminals could possibly use. Detecting vulnerabilities and addressing areas of exploit can help you prevent data breaches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">IP attribution and digital forensics can only help you so much. Your only safe bet is to work on prevention. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the common attack vectors are &#8211;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email attachments</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Viruses</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malware</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instant messages</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pop-ups</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Text messages</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web pages</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Social engineering</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With cyber threats on the rise, there is no telling what potential vulnerabilities listed on the dark web and  CVE cybercriminals could exploit to gain access to highly valuable information. Also, there is no one-size-fits-all solution to prevent all attack vectors. Today, antivirus software is no longer enough to ensure cyber safety. This is the reason many companies employ in-depth defense services to avoid such attacks and ensure cybersecurity.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How Do I Avoid Cyber Attack Vectors?</span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do Not Use Credentials That Are Weak Or Stolen</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Remember to always use a password containing a combination of uppercase, lowercase letters, numbers, and special characters as a way of keeping cyber attackers away from hacking into your computer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beware of sending your login credentials to another account. This gives hackers who are phishing easier access to personal information for further use. Remember your strong password by using a combination of names and numbers that are relatable to you. Hackers who are phishing are always looking for weak passwords they can use to enter an account.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do Not Use Compromised Credentials</span></h3>
<p><a href="https://datadome.co/resources/account-takeover/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account takeover fraud happens</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when a user&#8217;s information like his username and password have been compromised by an attacker. The hacker now has the user&#8217;s information and can use it however he wants. Often such attacks are not known to the user until he tries to log in and discover his username and password have been changed by the hacker. Now you have to figure out how to get into your own account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid this scenario by updating your password when it appears that it has suspicious activity. Experts recommend changing your password once every three months. Also use strong passwords that combine uppercase and lowercase letters, numbers, and special characters.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beware of A Malicious Insider</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A malicious insider may be an unhappy employee who may expose private company information to an unauthorized individual. Company CEOs, supervisors, employees, and others in the company need to be observant of disgruntled employees. Supervisors can take away certain computer levels to keep employees away from security information. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employees should have secure access to information according to their seniority in the company. Investigations should be done of the suspected disgruntled employee who is sending the unwarranted information. An employee should report this behavior to a supervisor immediately.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do Not Use Poor or Missing Encryption</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Old computer software will always have poor and lack encryptions. Update your computer software when needed to keep cyber security high on your computer. Updated computer software will be difficult for hackers to hack into your computer and place malware. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Updating your computer and using a VPN are two ways to keep hackers away from your important stored information.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Computer Software That Blocks Suspicious Software Or Ransomware</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ransomware is malicious software designed to block a computer system until money is paid for its&#8217; release. Use computer software that will alert you to these types of software so you can block the dangerous cyber attack.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be Observant For Phishing By Cyber Attackers</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be observant of hacker phishing for your information. Observe suspicious email attacks, website links, and other phishing opportunities that bring cyber attackers into your secure world. Experts say that </span><a href="https://expertinsights.com/insights/50-phishing-stats-you-should-know/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">96% of phishing activity from cyber attackers comes from sending emails</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. 61% of companies deal with phishing activity via their social media channels. 65% of phishing in large corporations deal with spear phishing, aimed at stealing the information of top executives. 3% of phishing activities occur through fake websites.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Strong Passwords</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strong passwords are a combination of capital letters, small letters, numbers, and special characters that cannot easily be identified by a cyber attacker. It should be a string of numbers and letters that you can remember. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It would also be best to have your passwords written down on a notepad for all of your accounts in case you have to refer back to them. Having a strong password ensures that cyber attackers trolling the internet cannot easily get into your accounts and get your personal information.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Always Update Your Computer Software</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Old software on your computer will continue to have bugs and holes in its cyber security that allows hackers to get your personal information. Updating your computer software ensures that you have the best cyber security to keep hackers away from attempting to destroy and compromise your software and information.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do Not Click On Weblinks</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every day you are asked by companies and other professional sources to click on a particular link to obtain information. However, if you do not pay attention to the link next to the legitimate company&#8217;s name, you may be opening yourself up to a world where cyber attackers can come into your life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do not click on </span><a href="https://www.lifewire.com/how-to-test-a-suspicious-link-without-clicking-it-2487171"><span style="font-weight: 400;">suspicious web links</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that can lead to malware dysfunction. Malware is a malicious code that destroys the secure information, integrity availability, and confidential nature of a computer information system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malware causes problems for the owner of the computer accounts, allowing cyber attackers to change passwords, usernames, and your personal information.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use A VPN</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a VPN on your computer helps protect against identity theft. A VPN sends your personal data through an encrypted safe tunnel that is far out of the reach of cyber attackers. A VPN makes sure that your confidential data is protected and off</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ers the best cyber security available.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bottom Line</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those were some practical and effective tips on avoiding common cyber-attack vectors. Remember to use a strong username and password that is not easily identifiable by a hacker. Pay close attention to suspicious emails that look like they come from a reputable company. Update your computer software to ensure the highest levels of cyber security. Use a VPN to keep your personal data and any threat of identity theft low. Watch for disgruntled employees who send unauthorized information and report this to a supervisor immediately.</span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4332"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cyber-attack-vectors-and-how-to-avoid-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Cybersecurity Vulnerabilities Within the Healthcare Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-cybersecurity-vulnerabilities-within-the-healthcare-industry/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-cybersecurity-vulnerabilities-within-the-healthcare-industry/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 10:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4287</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[For several reasons, the healthcare industry is susceptible to cyberattacks &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-cybersecurity-vulnerabilities-within-the-healthcare-industry/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For several reasons, the healthcare industry is susceptible to cyberattacks and threats. More than often due to the poorly established security measures of storing sensitive information (like the ones that healthcare entities often maintain) can be a tantalizing prize for <a href="https://online.maryville.edu/blog/types-of-hackers/">hackers of various kinds</a>. Because of this, entities both large and small within the healthcare industry must allocate resources to better protect their digital systems and increase their cybersecurity measures to prevent attacks and breaches. On that note we have today shared the top 5 cybersecurity vulnerabilities that the healthcare industry should be aware of and prevent falling prey to such events.</p>
<h2><strong>Top Cyber Vulnerabilities</strong></h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/industry/healthcare-industry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">healthcare industry</a> is greatly exposed to various cyber threats. Although there are regulations in place to address these issues and tackle such events of cyber-attacks yet healthcare institutions need to be aware of the evolving threat landscape and establish effective preventive measures. So, here are some of the most significant ways that entities within the healthcare industry can be particularly vulnerable to cyber-attacks that you should be aware of.</p>
<h2><strong>Outdated Software Systems</strong></h2>
<p>Within the healthcare industry, a good number of software management systems are outdated or have been used without being updated for a long period of time. This means that the average healthcare entity is probably using software that does not have adequate safety and security features that match cyber criminals’ capabilities. When external threats innovate and internal security measures don’t, it can spell disaster. So, healthcare institutes need to be ahead of the game and regularly review their system and update software.</p>
<h2><strong>Lack</strong><strong> of Cybersecurity Awareness</strong></h2>
<p>The healthcare industry represents thousands of individuals operating complicated software systems, collecting personal data, and working with large amounts of private information. The breadth of the industry and the sheer number of individuals who have access to restricted systems and sensitive information make breaches, mistakes, and password compromises relatively common. However, with proper training and awareness programs, the industry can prevent such incidents and compromises.</p>
<h2><strong>Data Manipulation and Misuse</strong></h2>
<p>This is a huge threat prevalent in the healthcare industry. Healthcare professionals collect large amounts of data to help make <a href="https://online.athens.edu/onlineathensedu/blog/data-driven-leadership/">evidence-based decisions</a> in their medical treatments. This makes accurate diagnoses and patient treatment possible. However, because so many professionals within the healthcare industry have access to large amounts of information, the possibility of data getting stolen and misuse of patient data is high. Threats are not always external &#8211; they can be internal as well. So, healthcare institutes must establish and enforce appropriate measures in terms of access controls, authorization, and other security measures to protect sensitive data and prevent data misuse and manipulations.</p>
<h2><strong>Patient Information Protection and Privacy Misdemeanors</strong></h2>
<p>The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) outlines strict regulations for the correct and safe handling of Patient Information. Healthcare entities must adhere to these guidelines. They risk negative repercussions, including compromising patients’ safety and trust, if that information is mishandled or allowed into the wrong hands. So, here adhering to the HIPAA requirements is essential.</p>
<h2><strong>Limited Budget for Cybersecurity Provision</strong></h2>
<p>Other industries like banking and the corporate sector are more likely to allocate adequate resources to cybersecurity. This includes current, up-to-date software systems and implementation costs as well as salary and contracting expenses for cybersecurity professionals to help mitigate the risks of breaches and attacks. Healthcare entities often lag in applying adequate resources for cybersecurity and data safety, and this makes it more lucrative for hackers to attack the healthcare entities than in comparison with other sectors that are in general likely harder to breach.</p>
<h2><strong>Closing Thought </strong></h2>
<p>Healthcare professionals and organizations need to prioritize cybersecurity. In an age when cybersecurity threats translate into huge losses and lawsuits each year across every industry, it is important that entities ensure that sensitive data are adequately protected and secured. If you are a decision-maker within the healthcare industry, use the list above to assess your cybersecurity status and make changes where necessary to protect your system from dangerous and costly cyber-attacks.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4287"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-cybersecurity-vulnerabilities-within-the-healthcare-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Trends Every Business Leader Needs To Be Aware Of In 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/</link>
      <comments>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 08:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4298</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Technology is advancing. It has altered how individuals interact and &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technology is advancing. It has altered how individuals interact and consume content for better and worse. It has impacted how businesses operate. Although the events of recent years have also </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">affected workplaces</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, technology has had the most significant impact on companies and their workforce.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the years, technology has benefited companies by providing them with an opportunity to enhance their production and increase productivity levels. It has enabled businesses to deliver more innovative services, helping to mark them as one of the best options in the industry. The downside to technology is that it has enabled a rise in cyber attackers, causing great harm to businesses across the globe. It has forced companies to stop operations and say goodbye to employees due to the loss of funds from the negative impact of data breaches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even in the new year 2022, the rise in cyberattacks is anticipated to continue with technology advancing and cyber attackers using new techniques. Since hackers are finding new ways to compromise businesses, it is crucial for companies to be on the top of their game when it comes to cybersecurity. These are some of the cybersecurity trends for the New Year that every business leader should be well aware of.</span></p>
<h2><b>Rise in Phishing Attacks</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The momentous shift in how businesses worldwide operate has now also altered the way cyber attackers work. It has forced them to find new alternative methods to carry out any of their attacks successfully. One of the most common cyber-attacks observed in the industry is the technique of phishing. Here the attacker targets a specific user to access their data by stealing their credentials. They also use it to compromise either their identity or the system.</span></p>
<h2><b>Increase in Ransomware</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most significant issues companies faced in the past year was ransomware. It was a growing problem for 2021. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Experts believe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it will likely continue throughout 2022, with incidents predicted to double. A ransomware attack typically works by encrypting critical files on a targeted computer. It then demands the affected user to make a payment for the files to be unlocked. In addition to this, these attacks are also responsible for displaying adult content at random. It can even block a person’s access to a specific app on the affected device. Being aware of preventing such attacks should be a top priority for companies, especially with the anticipated rise in cases.</span></p>
<h2><b>Cloud Security</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With most businesses choosing to continue working remotely, cloud security is and should be a top priority. Cloud solutions have become an essential tool for companies with a remote working workforce. It enables team members to access vital and sometimes sensitive information they need from wherever they work. Relying on cloud services comes with its own IT security challenges. Business leaders need to ensure that their cloud solutions are well protected to avoid being at the risk of possible attacks.</span></p>
<h2><b>Data privacy as a discipline</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the key information security trends is the rise of information privacy as a discipline in its claim. Many high-profile cyber-attacks have a light-emitting diode to the exposure of innumerable in-person identifiable info records (PII). This, in addition to the introduction of stricter information laws worldwide, like the EU&#8217;s GDPR, means that information privacy is more and more being prioritized.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Organizations that do not adhere to regulations and client expectations run the chance of fines, unhealthy content, and losing client trust. Information privacy affects most aspects of a company. As a result, organizations square measure putting additional stress on recruiting information privacy officers and making certain role-based access management, multi-factor authentication, cryptography in transit and at rest, network segmentation, and external assessments to spot areas of improvement.</span></p>
<h2><b>The Continued rise of AI</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sheer volume of cyber security threats is a lot for humans to handle alone. As a result, organizations have started turning more towards AI and machine learning to hone their security infrastructure.AI has been preponderant in building automatic security systems, language processes, face detection, and automatic threat detection. AI conjointly makes it potential to investigate a large number of risks at a far quicker pace.</span></p>
<h2><b>In Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As businesses look to invest and integrate new technologies into their daily operations, they must be aware of how to do it safely. It might be time-consuming to update the safety measures to prevent cyberattacks. However, keeping updated on cybersecurity trends and staying aware will help the business in the long run. Being consistent with regular reviews and constantly updating the safety measures will help minimize the risk of a data breach. Further, in doing so, the business will remain safe, and the sensitive information will be protected, while the company continues to operate regularly as they have minimized the risk. It will help them stay one step ahead of any cyber attackers.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4298"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-trends-every-business-leader-needs-to-be-aware-of-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>