<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>IdentityIQ</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.identityiq.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.identityiq.com</link>
    <description>Identity Theft Protection</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:27:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.identityiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
      <title>IdentityIQ</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>How to Dispose Outdated Electronics to Protect Your Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-to-dispose-outdated-electronics-to-protect-your-identity/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 22:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Identity Theft]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5420</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-to-dispose-outdated-electronics-to-protect-your-identity/">How to Dispose Outdated Electronics to Protect Your Identity</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Your iPhone is ancient, your laptop is malfunctioning, and your tablet is due for an upgrade. Of course, there comes a time for everyone to toss their old tech and level up to the latest version. But before trashing your old tech, make sure you don’t leave your personal information out there for the taking. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-to-dispose-outdated-electronics-to-protect-your-identity/">How to Dispose Outdated Electronics to Protect Your Identity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-to-dispose-outdated-electronics-to-protect-your-identity/">How to Dispose Outdated Electronics to Protect Your Identity</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Your iPhone is ancient, your laptop is malfunctioning, and your tablet is due for an upgrade. Of course, there comes a time for everyone to toss their old tech and level up to the latest version. But before trashing your old tech, make sure you don’t leave your personal information out there for the taking.</p>
<p>Recycling old tech correctly is essential considering the automatic logins and banking information that any mildly savvy cybercriminal could extract from your device. The improper disposal of smartphones and computers is one of the most common ways for a nefarious character to access sensitive information that can lead to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">identity theft</a>.</p>
<p>Verizon’s recent Data Breach Investigations Report detailed more than 1,000 identity theft cases in one year that resulted from unauthorized access to a mobile device. A recent data breach report by the <a href="https://www.idtheftcenter.org/">Identity Theft Resource Center</a> backs that up, highlighting device theft and the improper disposal of electronic devices as the cause of many identity theft cases in 2019.</p>
<p>At issue is the fact that many of us believe that just logging off and deleting files is enough to wipe clean whatever we have stored on our device. But the reality is that things like photos, videos or personal documents likely remain long after being simply deleted. The last thing anyone wants is their <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/5-password-best-practices-you-should-be-using/">passwords</a>, account numbers, private images and the like winding up in the wrong hands.</p>
<p>So, before you dispose of, donate or recycle that smartphone or MacBook, consider these tips so that you can help prevent any illicit data recovery.</p>
<ol>
<li>Consult your device’s user manual or check for online FAQs for factory reset directions. This can be done on laptops, tablets, smartphones or wearable tech.</li>
<li>Consider using a disk-cleaning software, which can delete your data and then wipe the information off your hard drive entirely, according to the Department of Homeland Security’s <a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-005">Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</a>.</li>
<li>Purchase an external drive or use a cloud-based service to back up your files. This can help keep sensitive data off local hard drives and do more accessible work of disposing of your old electronics without worrying about lost data.</li>
<li>Secure an <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">identity theft protection provider</a>, so you know you can be alerted about suspicious activity involving your personal data whether via a disposed electronic or another way.</li>
</ol>
<p>Note that your old device doesn’t necessarily need to be trashed but can be <a href="https://www.epa.gov/recycle/electronics-donation-and-recycling">donated or recycled</a>. Local governments are increasingly hosting e-cycling initiatives that keep electronics out of landfills and ensure that devices are purged of all user data. Search online for e-cycling centers near you before disposing of your electronics, including IoT devices and medical devices.</p>
<p>Finally, many device manufacturers accept old devices to be refurbished or recycled and can provide a credit to the consumer toward a new device. Some even take a device from any manufacturer for recycling. Check with the manufacturer to see if they offer a recycling program that might also help you secure a brand-new upgrade.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-to-dispose-outdated-electronics-to-protect-your-identity/">How to Dispose Outdated Electronics to Protect Your Identity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDIQ Continues Growth Trajectory with New Office in Tampa, Florida</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 15:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Newsroom]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5414</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/">IDIQ Continues Growth Trajectory with New Office in Tampa, Florida</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>—Location serves as third call center for fully U.S.-based workforce— Temecula, California, April 26, 2022 – IDIQ, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, announced today the opening of its new office in Tampa, Florida, to serve as a strategic hub for call center operations. The new space, located on Eisenhower Boulevard, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/">IDIQ Continues Growth Trajectory with New Office in Tampa, Florida</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/">IDIQ Continues Growth Trajectory with New Office in Tampa, Florida</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><em>—Location serves as third call center for fully U.S.-based workforce—</em></p>
<p><strong>Temecula, California, April 26, 2022</strong> – <a href="http://www.idiq.com">IDIQ</a>, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, announced today the opening of its new office in Tampa, Florida, to serve as a strategic hub for call center operations.</p>
<p>The new space, located on Eisenhower Boulevard, is the company’s third call center in the United States and houses a growing team of customer service agents and other management professionals. The more-than-17,000 square-foot call center can accommodate 100 employees. IDIQ is excited to expand its operations to Florida and hopes this gives local talent a premium option when looking for new job opportunities.</p>
<p>The call center features a completely renovated workspace as well as a game room, break room and executive offices.</p>
<p>The call center team supports members who are enrolled in the IDIQ credit report and identity theft monitoring services provided by its <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a>® and <a href="https://www.myscoreiq.com/">MyScoreIQ</a>® brands.</p>
<p>The addition of the new office space is a part of the company’s significant growth as well part of its roadmap for continued expansion. In the past two years, IDIQ has hired more than 125 employees to meet increased consumer demand for identity theft and credit report monitoring services. It has also grown its member base to more than a million users.</p>
<p>“We’re excited to add the Tampa office to our list of call centers throughout the nation,” said Jason Royal, senior vice president of operations at IDIQ. “It’s a beautiful building and call center with great people in a great state.”</p>
<p>The Tampa office joins the company’s two other offices and call centers in Temecula, California, and Mt. Prospect, Illinois. IDIQ also has hubs located in Texas and New York.</p>
<p>Scott Hermann, CEO and co-owner of IDIQ, said, “We have built an amazing team of member specialists to assist our members and provide them award-winning customer service. We are committed to keeping our workforce in the United States to quickly and efficiently address the needs of our members.”</p>
<p>IDIQ is one of the fastest-growing companies in America, earning <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-makes-the-inc-5000-list-of-fastest-growing-private-companies-in-america-for-second-consecutive-year/">two consecutive spots on the prestigious Inc. 5000 List</a> that has also featured Microsoft, Patagonia, Intuit and Under Armour as previous list honorees.</p>
<p>Recently, the company finalized <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-announces-acquisition-of-resident-link/">the acquisition of Resident-Link</a>, a service for the rental community that allows consumers access to help build and establish their credit.</p>
<p><strong>About IDIQ:</strong><br />
IDIQ® is recognized as one of the fastest-growing industry leaders in credit report and identity theft monitoring and data breach preparation. With its IdentityIQ® and MyScoreIQ® brands, the company delivers credit report information, education and protection that benefits consumers and businesses. The company features 100% U.S.-based customer service and support. For more information, visit <a href="https://idiq-my.sharepoint.com/personal/nbitting_idiq_com/Documents/Microsoft%20Teams%20Chat%20Files/www.IDIQ.com">www.IDIQ.com</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/">IDIQ Continues Growth Trajectory with New Office in Tampa, Florida</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Protect Yourself from Rental Scams</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-rental-scams/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5389</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-rental-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Rental Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Competition grows fiercer by the day in the nation’s hottest housing markets, and that translates to a competitive rental market as well. But this uptick in demand for apartments and rental homes has resulted in a tighter rental market, opening the door for scammers preying on the desperate. In fact, the Better Business Bureau warns renters [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-rental-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Rental Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-rental-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Rental Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Competition grows fiercer by the day in the nation’s hottest housing markets, and that translates to a competitive rental market as well. But this uptick in demand for apartments and rental homes has resulted in a tighter rental market, opening the door for scammers preying on the desperate.</p>
<p>In fact, the Better Business Bureau warns renters to beware of scammers posing as landlords in a bid to steal cash and personal information by posting fake properties for rent. A successful scam can con someone into giving out personal details like bank account information and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/6-tips-for-protecting-your-social-security-number/">Social Security numbers</a>, all in the hopes of obtaining a rental property before someone else nabs it. Unfortunately, if you don’t already have an <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">ID theft protection</a> service to help alert and protect you from fraud, the damage can take years to undo.</p>
<p>Here’s how <a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0079-rental-listing-scams">rental scam listings</a> works: Con artists steal a posted rental listing and rework the information to include their contact info. They’re likely to handle the deal over the phone, citing circumstances beyond their control that prevent an in-person meeting or quick property tour. With 3-D property tours now a standard feature, it’s easy to see how someone in a pinch might feel that an online photo tour can temporarily suffice. Or perhaps a drive-by of the property is suggested to ease concerns.</p>
<p>And then, when interest is piqued, and urgency is stressed, an emailed contract is pushed to ensure the property can’t be picked up by another renter. A deposit is requested, and perhaps even the first month’s rent, while keys are said to be on their way. But no key arrives, the contact has vanished, and the cash is gone.</p>
<p>The best way to help protect yourself from this type of fraud is to work with a reputable real estate agent, leasing agency or property manager. These days, finding and leasing an apartment online in a completely virtual transaction is too risky. Suppose you find yourself dealing directly with a landlord, research to confirm that they truly own the property. Whenever possible, deposits or fees should be paid with a check or credit card, never through electronic payment platforms like Venmo or Zelle – that way, you at least have an opportunity to dispute the charges.</p>
<p>But while you may take steps to help ensure that you won’t fall victim to rental scams, others might not catch on. So if you see a suspicious rental ad online, report it to your <a href="https://www.usa.gov/state-consumer">state consumer protection</a>, local law enforcement or <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/default.aspx">FBI Internet Crime Complaint Center</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-rental-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Rental Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Tech Support Scams and How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/common-tech-support-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 23:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5375</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/common-tech-support-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">Common Tech Support Scams and How to Avoid Them</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>These days, we live our lives online. Whether we’re ordering groceries or looking for new shoes, all we need to do is create an account, fill out some basic personal details and log in. But what happens when that account is compromised – or when we think that account is compromised? Maybe you get an [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/common-tech-support-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">Common Tech Support Scams and How to Avoid Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/common-tech-support-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">Common Tech Support Scams and How to Avoid Them</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>These days, we live our lives online. Whether we’re ordering groceries or looking for new shoes, all we need to do is create an account, fill out some basic personal details and log in.</p>
<p>But what happens when that <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/account-takeover-what-is-it-and-how-to-prevent-it/">account is compromised</a> – or when we think that account is compromised?</p>
<p>Maybe you get an email from technical support letting you know that your account has been breached and steps are needed to make it secure again. Just click on this link, the email might say, and we’ll take care of it.</p>
<p>But if this happens to you, think twice before you click.</p>
<p>The FBI recently posted an alert notifying consumers that <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/Y2022/PSA220316">tech support scams are on the rise</a>. Cyber scammers are nothing if not clever, and our increased reliance on technology following the COVID-19 pandemic left a massive opportunity for fraudsters to prey on unwitting consumers.</p>
<h2>Recognizing a Tech Support Scam</h2>
<p>While the scenario above is not uncommon, there are many other ways scammers use tech support fraud to con people out of personal information and their money. Here are some outlined by the FBI as particularly prevalent right now:</p>
<h3>Utility or cable/internet scam</h3>
<p>In this scenario, a scammer posing as someone from a utility company or internet provider sends a notification that your bill is past due and that these services can be shut off if this is not remedied.</p>
<h3>Travel industry scams</h3>
<p>Scammers pose as technical support reps for car rentals, hotels or airlines and present great deals, taking <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/booking-a-vacation-heres-how-to-spot-rental-listing-scams/">fake reservations for vacations</a> that are never actually booked.</p>
<h3>Ride-share driver scam</h3>
<p>Drivers for ride-share companies are being subject to scammers posing as their company’s customer support team, reaching out to correct an issue with the driver’s account or address a rider complaint. In the meantime, they are accessing the driver’s banking details.</p>
<h3>Crypto wallet scams</h3>
<p>People are receiving calls from <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/cryptocurrency-use-is-on-the-rise-and-so-are-crypto-scams/">crypto scammers</a> pretending to be tech support for cryptocurrency exchanges. In these schemes, the scammers claim to have flagged an issue with the victim’s crypto wallet and ask for information to secure their account.</p>
<h2>How to Help Avoid Tech Support Scams</h2>
<p>It’s important to remember that technical support reps never reach out to customers unsolicited. So, if someone is contacting you about your account and seeking details to fix a problem you didn’t know existed, don’t take the bait.</p>
<p>Installing a pop-up blocker on your computer helps reduce unwanted advertisements containing <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">malware</a>. Make sure you regularly update your computer with anti-virus software.</p>
<p>Cyber scammers can lure victims online by paying for their website to appear near the top in online search results, listing their contact information for those looking for tech support. So be wary of the sites you search for tech support information and pay attention as to whether or not they are marked as “paid ads” in a Google search. It’s always good practice to read reviews and investigate any company you plan to do business with.</p>
<h2>What to Do If You’re a Victim of a Tech Support Scam</h2>
<p>If you are the victim of a tech support scam that resulted in a transfer of funds, contact your bank or credit card provider immediately to try to stop the transaction.</p>
<p>If you granted a scammer access to your computer, update your security software and run a scan to ensure that remote access is no longer possible and the proper protection is in place.</p>
<p>If you’re concerned that personal details have been stolen that may result in <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">ID theft</a>, engage a reputable <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">identity theft protection and monitoring service</a> to check for breaches and put long-term protections in place.</p>
<p>Reporting your experience with technical support fraud can help stop others from falling victim to these schemes. You can report a scam to the <a href="https://reportfraud.ftc.gov/#/">Federal Trade Commission </a>and to the <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/">FBI’s Internet Crime Complaint Center </a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/common-tech-support-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">Common Tech Support Scams and How to Avoid Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDIQ Announces Appointment of Bryan Sullivan as Chief Operating and Financial Officer</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-announces-appointment-of-bryan-sullivan-as-chief-operating-and-financial-officer/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 15:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Newsroom]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5380</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-announces-appointment-of-bryan-sullivan-as-chief-operating-and-financial-officer/">IDIQ Announces Appointment of Bryan Sullivan as Chief Operating and Financial Officer</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>— Seasoned Business Leader Joins IDIQ to Scale Explosive Growth —   Temecula, California, April 5, 2022 – IDIQ, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, announces the appointment of Bryan Sullivan to the company’s top operating and financial role. Sullivan officially joined the company this past May, and brings more than [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-announces-appointment-of-bryan-sullivan-as-chief-operating-and-financial-officer/">IDIQ Announces Appointment of Bryan Sullivan as Chief Operating and Financial Officer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-announces-appointment-of-bryan-sullivan-as-chief-operating-and-financial-officer/">IDIQ Announces Appointment of Bryan Sullivan as Chief Operating and Financial Officer</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>—</em></strong> <strong><em>Seasoned Business Leader Joins IDIQ to Scale Explosive Growth —</em></strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Temecula, California, April 5, 2022</strong> – <a href="http://www.idiq.com">IDIQ</a>, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, announces the appointment of Bryan Sullivan to the company’s top operating and financial role. Sullivan officially joined the company this past May, and brings more than 20 years of successful advisory, investing and operating expertise with high growth platforms to IDIQ.</p>
<p>Sullivan is an industry leader with his most recent experience across such leading companies as Goldman Sachs, Pacific Investment Management Company (PIMCO) and loanDepot. He specializes in fintech, financial services, data services and real estate services. He also has a deep understanding of capital markets and acquisitions.</p>
<p>Before joining IDIQ, Sullivan’s most recent operating role was executive vice president and chief financial officer at loanDepot, where he successfully helped lead the company through several acquisitions, capital financings and significant growth into one the leading consumer finance platforms in the country.</p>
<p>Sullivan said, “It isn’t too often that you get an opportunity to help develop and grow a business with macro-sector growth, consumer demand and a product that provides real benefits to its members all while being profitable and with great margins. I was excited when Scott Hermann, CEO of IDIQ, and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/corsair-capital-acquires-majority-stake-in-idiq/">Corsair Capital</a> reached out to ask me to help continue to grow and further develop the company into the preeminent identity theft protection, credit monitoring and financial empowerment platform, especially during this explosive-growth period.”</p>
<p>Hermann said, “Sullivan’s track record as an advisor, investor and operator was exactly what we were looking to add to our executive management team, and, having had the opportunity to work with him over the last 11 months, it has been as advertised. His expertise has allowed us to complete two acquisitions, evaluate many others, develop better financial management and continue our explosive organic growth. He has also attracted new talent to the company and is developing new partnerships and relationships that will continue our growth trajectory.</p>
<p>The addition of Bryan and other recent executive hires to the IDIQ leadership team reinforces our commitment to a customer-first approach and building industry-leading identity theft, credit monitoring and financial empowerment product suite.”</p>
<p>Over the past year, IDIQ has hired industry veterans <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-names-john-bauer-president-and-chief-revenue-officer/">John Bauer</a> and  <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-names-patrick-glennon-chief-technology-officer/">Patrick Glennon</a> along with Sullivan to the executive ranks of IDIQ. This strong and experienced group of leaders, as well as others IDIQ will announce over the coming months, are set to help the company manage and execute on recent business growth and robust product roadmap.</p>
<p>That roadmap has significant organic growth but will also continue to include plans for acquisitions.  As previously reported, the company recently announced <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-announces-acquisition-of-resident-link/">the acquisition of Resident-Link</a>, a service for the rental community to allow consumers access to help build and establish their credit.</p>
<p>During the pandemic, the company has hired more than 125 employees to meet increased consumer demand for identity theft and credit report monitoring services.  It has grown its customers on the platform to over 750,000 with revenue growth for the full year ended 2021 of over 70%.</p>
<p>IDIQ is one of the fastest-growing companies in America, earning <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-makes-the-inc-5000-list-of-fastest-growing-private-companies-in-america-for-second-consecutive-year/">two consecutive spots on the prestigious Inc. 5000 List</a> that has also featured Microsoft, Patagonia, Intuit and Under Armour as previous list honorees.</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>About IDIQ:</strong><br />
IDIQ® is recognized as one of the fastest-growing industry leaders in credit report and identity theft monitoring and data breach preparation. With its <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a>® and <a href="https://www.myscoreiq.com/">MyScoreIQ</a>® brands, the company delivers credit report information, education, and protection that benefits consumers and businesses. The company features 100% U.S.-based customer service and support. For more information, visit www.IDIQ.com.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press_release/idiq-announces-appointment-of-bryan-sullivan-as-chief-operating-and-financial-officer/">IDIQ Announces Appointment of Bryan Sullivan as Chief Operating and Financial Officer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Social Media Account Cloning?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-social-media-account-cloning/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Acton]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5285</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-social-media-account-cloning/">What is Social Media Account Cloning?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>When a scammer has the right information, they can easily impersonate you on social media by cloning your account. It’s pretty simple to do when much of the information that scammers need is publicly available on the real person’s profile. Criminals can use cloned social accounts to scam your friends, commit identity theft and even [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-social-media-account-cloning/">What is Social Media Account Cloning?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-social-media-account-cloning/">What is Social Media Account Cloning?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>When a scammer has the right information, they can easily impersonate you on social media by cloning your account. It’s pretty simple to do when much of the information that scammers need is publicly available on the real person’s profile. Criminals can use cloned social accounts to scam your friends, commit <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">identity theft</a> and even get your existing accounts shut down. Here’s how social media account cloning works and how you can help prevent it from happening to you.</p>
<h2>What is Social Media Account Cloning?</h2>
<p>Cloned accounts use a real person’s name, picture and other information to duplicate that person’s social media profile. You don’t need to have your <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/account-takeover-what-is-it-and-how-to-prevent-it/">account taken over</a> for someone to create a fake account under your name. Unfortunately, most social media websites do little to ensure the new user is real and only require an email address to get started.</p>
<p>If your name and profile picture are publicly available, often that’s all a scammer needs to get started cloning your account. Once they do, they can attempt to connect to your friends, family and other contacts to start impersonating you.</p>
<h2>What Can Cloned Accounts Do?</h2>
<p>Once someone creates a cloned account, they can try to reach out to your existing online contacts and start running scams, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sending <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">malicious links</a> or <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/tips/ST04-010">attachments</a> to your friends and family.</li>
<li>Asking your friends and family for money.</li>
<li>Extracting personal data about yourself or your friends. They can use this information to make your social media account appear more legitimate or try to commit identity theft on you or your friends.</li>
<li>Compromising your reputation by posting inappropriate or illegal content.</li>
<li>Trying to have your legitimate account shut down by reporting you as the impostor.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tips for Fighting Account Clones</h2>
<p>Here are some ways to help <a href="https://www.investor.gov/protect-your-investments/fraud/how-avoid-fraud/protect-your-social-media-accounts">protect your social media accounts</a> from getting cloned.</p>
<ul>
<li>Search for your name on the social media websites you use. There may be plenty of people who share the same name, but you can start here to find impersonators.</li>
<li>Tweak your privacy settings to make your name, profile picture and other personal information private and visible only to your friends.</li>
<li>Hide your friends list. This is important to prevent scammers from seeing who you’re connected with, making it more difficult for them to find your friends and family.</li>
<li>Report any fraudulent accounts you find to the social media website.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cloned social media accounts are more than just an online prank. They can be used to run scams on you, your friends or your family. While locking down your <a href="https://staysafeonline.org/stay-safe-online/managing-your-privacy/manage-privacy-settings/">privacy settings</a> won’t completely protect you (a so-called friend who knows you on social media could always create a fake account), it can help protect you from anonymous scammers trolling the web for victims.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-social-media-account-cloning/">What is Social Media Account Cloning?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Identity Theft Protection is an Important Employee Benefit</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/why-identity-theft-protection-is-an-important-employee-benefit/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 14:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Identity Theft]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5266</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/why-identity-theft-protection-is-an-important-employee-benefit/">Why Identity Theft Protection is an Important Employee Benefit</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Employees are a company’s most valuable asset. According to Consumer Affairs, between 2019 and 2020, there was a 311% rise in identity theft victims. An employer can help keep their employees safe by providing identity theft protection. Identity theft protection as an employee benefit protects employees and protects the employer. Here’s why identity theft monitoring [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/why-identity-theft-protection-is-an-important-employee-benefit/">Why Identity Theft Protection is an Important Employee Benefit</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/why-identity-theft-protection-is-an-important-employee-benefit/">Why Identity Theft Protection is an Important Employee Benefit</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Employees are a company’s most valuable asset. According to Consumer Affairs, between 2019 and 2020, there was a 311% rise in identity theft victims. An employer can help keep their employees safe by providing identity theft protection. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">Identity theft protection</a> as an employee benefit protects employees and protects the employer. Here’s why identity theft monitoring is a valuable employee benefit.</p>
<h2>Employee Identity Theft Protection</h2>
<p>Employee identity theft protection includes <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/what-is-credit-report-monitoring-and-why-is-it-important/">credit report monitoring</a> and alerts employees to a range of activities:</p>
<ul>
<li>New applications for credit cards and cell phone plans</li>
<li>Possible fraud alerts</li>
<li>Change of address and public record alerts</li>
</ul>
<p>It also monitors the internet and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-dark-web-monitoring/">dark web</a> and provides <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/what-is-identity-theft-insurance/">identity theft insurance</a>.</p>
<h2>How Identity Theft Protection Benefits Employers</h2>
<p>Employees appreciate employers who want to protect them. Identity theft protection benefits employers. Disengaged employees cost companies more $500 billion a year, according to a report from Gallup.</p>
<p>Identity theft protection helps by preventing employees from becoming disengaged while dealing with the struggles of identity theft. They can focus on their work without worrying about <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">identity theft</a>.</p>
<p>It also helps protect a company’s reputation, which is vital for its future success.</p>
<p>If an employer makes a mistake that leads to an <a href="https://www.irs.gov/identity-theft-fraud-scams/employment-related-identity-theft">employee’s identity being stolen</a>, there can be repercussions that can include high litigation costs.</p>
<p>The government can also enforce fines and penalties if the company doesn’t provide enough employee protection. These fines and penalties can end up costing a company millions of dollars if this negligence leads to an identity theft incident.</p>
<h2>Benefits Employees Want</h2>
<p>By 2025, millennials will make up approximately 75% of the workforce. This generation expects more employee benefits. They are also more likely to leave a company than previous generations. Identity theft protection can be a benefit that helps attract the best talent for the company.</p>
<h2>How Can Employers Provide Identity Theft Protection?</h2>
<p>To bring identity theft protection to employees, and employer can <a href="https://partner.idiq.com/BecomeAnAffiliate/">partner with an identity theft monitoring company</a>. Employers can work with that company to create an identity theft protection benefit that best meets their employees’ needs.</p>
<p>Partnering with <a href="http://www.idiq.com">IDIQ</a> to provide industry-leading identity theft protection and credit monitoring is essential for today’s employers and their employees.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/why-identity-theft-protection-is-an-important-employee-benefit/">Why Identity Theft Protection is an Important Employee Benefit</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Brushing Scam?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-a-brushing-scam/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5238</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-a-brushing-scam/">What is a Brushing Scam?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Have you ever had a delivery guy knock on your door and wonder if there's yet another package you impulsively added to the cart and then forgot about? Well, you might be receiving a product you never ordered. Instead of it being the delivery website's fault, it's likely that you might be a part of [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-a-brushing-scam/">What is a Brushing Scam?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-a-brushing-scam/">What is a Brushing Scam?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Have you ever had a delivery guy knock on your door and wonder if there&#8217;s yet another package you impulsively added to the cart and then forgot about? Well, you might be receiving a product you never ordered. Instead of it being the delivery website&#8217;s fault, it&#8217;s likely that you might be a part of a brushing scam.</p>
<h3>What is a Brushing Scam?</h3>
<p><strong> </strong>A brushing scam is when someone delivers unmarked, mysterious packages to your doorstep without asking for a payment. The website from where you have allegedly received the product gets a review of the said product under your name — again, not initially provided by you. In a nutshell, it’s a form of <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">identity theft</a> in the e-commerce world. Like <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-protect-your-mail-from-identity-theft/">mail frauds</a> and ghost sellers, brushing scams are another activity that can potentially stir up quite a bit of trouble in the buyer and seller community of any website.</p>
<h3> How Do Brushing Scams Work?</h3>
<p>To keep their products on a specific seller website or community, increase their profit margin or avail other perks, a brand might need a certain number of sales and positive reviews. However, when these sellers aren’t receiving many sales or encouraging feedback, they might fake their sales and reviews. How does this happen?</p>
<ol>
<li>A company packs the product it wants to sell under the e-commerce store banner where it has placed its products, such as Amazon.</li>
<li>They enter your address and other credentials, which allow the website to register you as an authentic buyer.</li>
<li>If the store has a verification system through email or phone numbers, the counterfeiting company may also use fake addresses and numbers to cover up the scam.</li>
<li>Once the product reaches your hands, the e-commerce store marks the sale as a complete one.</li>
<li>Having a verified customer on a product permits the seller, pretending to be “you”, to post a product review.</li>
<li>The company then posts a fake positive review of the purchase.</li>
<li>With enough positive reviews, bulk sales and multiple restocking rounds, the company ends up with a more robust ranking in the e-commerce world.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Do Brushing Scams Occur Often?</h3>
<p><strong> </strong>It&#8217;s hard to tell for sure. Indeed, a wrongly delivered product isn&#8217;t always a result of a scam. Delivery service mess-ups, wrong delivery addresses and other mistakes from buyers and sellers in the e-commerce industry might also end up with you getting stuck with a product you never ordered.</p>
<p>Still, with the increase in both activity across the internet, there&#8217;s always a high chance of the delivery being a <a href="https://www.uspis.gov/news/scam-article/brushing-scam">brushing scam</a>.</p>
<p>Suppose you&#8217;re wondering whether you’ve fallen victim to a brushing scam or not. In that case, it&#8217;s safe to check out the product because the <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/">Federal Trade Commission</a> grants consumers the right to use a product with a completed delivery process even if the sender hasn&#8217;t charged a fee. So, if the product is cheap, lightweight, expired or has any other fishy characteristics, it&#8217;s most probably a scam. Lightweight products are the most common scam trades because they don&#8217;t cost that much in delivery.</p>
<h3>How Do I Avoid a Brushing Scam?</h3>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/scam-school-bad-practices-on-social-media-could-put-your-identity-at-risk/"> Avoid posting your personal information</a> everywhere, especially on the internet.</li>
<li>Contact the e-commerce store if you feel your address is used for counterfeit activities.</li>
<li>Try to change your <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/5-password-best-practices-you-should-be-using/">passwords</a> and other security information frequently to keep data breaches at bay.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong> </strong>A brushing scam may not seem like much of a threat. However, it also means your address and other information are in the hands of potential criminals and hackers, making it essential to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">protect your identity</a> and other personal data.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-a-brushing-scam/">What is a Brushing Scam?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Fake Donation Sites Amid the Russia-Ukraine War</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/avoid-fake-donation-sites-amid-the-russia-ukraine-war/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Newsroom]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5235</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/avoid-fake-donation-sites-amid-the-russia-ukraine-war/">Avoid Fake Donation Sites Amid the Russia-Ukraine War</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Times of tragedy often bring out acts of charity. But unfortunately, they also bring out scammers hell-bent on exploiting the situation. And the Russian-Ukraine War is no different. As Russia continues to invade Ukraine, more and more Ukrainians are getting displaced, and millions are fleeing the country. So, it makes sense for people to want [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/avoid-fake-donation-sites-amid-the-russia-ukraine-war/">Avoid Fake Donation Sites Amid the Russia-Ukraine War</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/avoid-fake-donation-sites-amid-the-russia-ukraine-war/">Avoid Fake Donation Sites Amid the Russia-Ukraine War</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Times of tragedy often bring out acts of charity. But unfortunately, they also bring out scammers hell-bent on exploiting the situation. And the Russian-Ukraine War is no different.</p>
<p>As Russia continues to invade Ukraine, more and more Ukrainians are getting displaced, and millions are fleeing the country. So, it makes sense for people to want to help as much and as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>This situation has also created an opportunity where scammers can take advantage of kind-hearted individuals. But before making any donations, whether it’s money or supplies, it’s wise to do your research to avoid falling victim to a <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/donating-to-charity-follow-these-best-practices-to-avoid-fraud/">charity scam</a>.</p>
<h3>Ukraine Wars Scams Hitting You Via Social Media, Email, and Phone</h3>
<p>Since the Ukraine-Russia war started, there’s been an increase in scammers tricking people into sending money. They pretend to be desperate Ukrainians in need of financial help. They execute these scams via <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/can-robocalls-steal-your-identity/">phone calls</a>, emails, text messages, social media, and online banner ads.</p>
<p>Although the caller ID and number might look legit, chances are the calls are coming from cybercriminals trying to benefit from the ongoing geopolitical turmoil.</p>
<p>Besides that, more fake donations websites are popping up, according to Newsweek. Below are some fake websites flagged by WeLiveSecurity.com:</p>
<ul>
<li>Help-for-Ukraine.eu</li>
<li>Tokenukraine.com</li>
<li>Supportukraine.today</li>
<li>Ukrainesolidarity.org</li>
</ul>
<p>These sites might appear legitimate because scammers tend to use names that sound similar to those you’ve heard before.</p>
<h3>Tips To Avoid Charity Scams Online</h3>
<ol>
<li>Avoid clicking on attachments and links to donation sites you have no information on. If you want to help the people in Ukraine, do some research about the site first.</li>
<li>When making your donation to a crowdfunding platform, it’s advisable to give the money to an individual you know. Also, take time to review the platform’s policies to learn how the money is distributed.</li>
<li>If donating money to a charity, visit Give.org, <a href="http://www.charitynavigator.org/">Charity Navigator</a>, or <a href="http://www.charitywatch.org/">CharityWatch</a>to check the legitimacy of the groups. Then, evaluate the charity’s trustworthiness by visiting <a href="http://www.give.org/">BBB Wise Giving Alliance</a>. Also, read the reviews and visit the site yourself to confirm if you’re working with the right organization.</li>
<li>Pay with credit cards that come with an extra layer of protection. Avoid using debit cards since they drain money from your checking account directly. And another thing: don&#8217;t make donations using wire transfers or <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/gift-card-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">gift cards</a>.</li>
<li>Only donate to charities with a presence in the country. While some charities have the best intentions, they might not have their feet in the ground. They have no established network in the regions, so they can’t offer relief right away. Therefore, it’s wise to check a charity’s history and see if it was already established in Ukraine.</li>
<li>Like any other organization, charities have overhead costs. So, if a donation website claims it donates 100% of the money to the cause, it might be a fake site. All relief organizations must deal with administrative and fundraising expenses, so giving 100% is most likely an exaggerated claim.</li>
<li>After making donations, monitor your account regularly for unauthorized charges or suspicious activity. It’s wise to set up notifications via your bank to track transactions made from your credit card. Or you can get <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">identity theft protection </a>for real-time <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/what-is-credit-report-monitoring-and-why-is-it-important/">credit report monitoring</a> and receive other alerts that may threaten your personal information.</li>
</ol>
<p>Although you want to help the Ukrainians affected by the ongoing conflict, be cautious. Make sure your charity is going to those you want to help.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/avoid-fake-donation-sites-amid-the-russia-ukraine-war/">Avoid Fake Donation Sites Amid the Russia-Ukraine War</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do I Get an IP PIN From the IRS?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-do-i-get-an-ip-pin-from-the-irs/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5233</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-do-i-get-an-ip-pin-from-the-irs/">How Do I Get an IP PIN From the IRS?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>As the tax season picks up, scammers are capitalizing on tax schemes to take your money, steal your identity and rob you of your peace of mind. While you can take several important steps to avoid being scammed, such as using an identity theft protection service, the IRS is also providing a new tool for those [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-do-i-get-an-ip-pin-from-the-irs/">How Do I Get an IP PIN From the IRS?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-do-i-get-an-ip-pin-from-the-irs/">How Do I Get an IP PIN From the IRS?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>As the tax season picks up, scammers are capitalizing on <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/">tax schemes</a> to take your money, steal your identity and rob you of your peace of mind. While you can take several important steps to avoid being scammed, such as using an <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">identity theft protection service</a>, the IRS is also providing a new tool for those filing digitally.</p>
<h3>What’s an Identity Theft Protection PIN (IP PIN)?</h3>
<p>An<a href="https://www.irs.gov/identity-theft-fraud-scams/get-an-identity-protection-pin"> IP PIN</a> is a six-digit number that prevents criminals from filing a fraudulent tax return using another taxpayer&#8217;s Social Security number. The IP PIN is known only to the taxpayer and the IRS and helps the IRS verify the taxpayer’s identity when they file their electronic or paper tax return.</p>
<p>IP PINs add an extra layer of security and are valuable for those who’ve been victims of tax-related identify fraud or who are concerned about becoming a victim. The number is only valid for one calendar year, so a new one is generated for your account each tax season</p>
<h3>How Do I Get an IP PIN?</h3>
<p>The IRS had previously made IP PINs automatically available to victims of tax-related identity theft. The IRS mails you a <a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/understanding-your-cp01a-notice">CP01A Notice</a> with your new IP PIN each year if that&#8217;s you.</p>
<p>Last year, the IRS made IP PINs available for all taxpayers to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-your-identity-during-tax-season-scams/">protect their identity during tax season</a>. Still, the only way to access a number was to file a paper application for an IP PIN or request an in-person authentication.</p>
<p>This year tax filers who are not identity theft victims can opt to get an IP PIN through the IRS website. To get a PIN, you have to verify your identity. This means you have to register for an online account with <a href="https://www.irs.gov/">IRS.gov</a>, a process that the IRS says takes about 15 minutes.</p>
<p>To register, you need to provide your email address, <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/6-tips-for-protecting-your-social-security-number/">Social Security number</a>, or Individual Tax Identification number, tax filing status, mailing address and one financial account number linked to your name.</p>
<p>That financial account number can be the last eight digits of your credit card, as long as it&#8217;s not an American Express, debit or corporate card; the account number listed on your student loan statement; the account number on your mortgage or home equity loan; account number of your <a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/home-equity-loans-and-home-equity-lines-credit">Home Equity Line of Credit</a>; or the account number of your auto loan.</p>
<p>You also need to provide a mobile phone number linked to your name so that the IRS can send you an activation code. If you can&#8217;t provide this, the IRS can send your activation code by mail.</p>
<h3>Do You Need an IP PIN?</h3>
<p>You might not necessarily need an IP PIN — most U.S. filers don’t typically need one, and the IRS infrequently mandates them. But that’s not to say they’re not worth considering.</p>
<p>IP PINs add an extra layer of security and are valuable for those who’ve been <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/8-warning-signs-you-might-be-a-victim-of-identity-theft/">victims of identity theft</a> or who are concerned about becoming a victim. They are designed to make it more difficult for thieves to file false tax returns in the names of other taxpayers. These PINs are unique six-digit numbers. When you file your return with an IP PIN, it provides the IRS with additional information to verify your identity.</p>
<p>Identity thieves, then, would need to know not just your SSN but your IP PIN, too, to file a return in your name.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-do-i-get-an-ip-pin-from-the-irs/">How Do I Get an IP PIN From the IRS?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>