<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>MIT Technology Review</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.technologyreview.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.technologyreview.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:28:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/20130408-ftweekendmag-mit-0030-final-w0-1.jpg?w=32?crop=0px,33px,1272px,716px&amp;w=32px</url>
      <title>MIT Technology Review</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">172986898</site>
    <item>
      <title>How digitization of supply chains can boost circular economies</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/05/02/1050759/how-digitization-of-supply-chains-can-boost-circular-economies/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Gerry Lavin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Clean energy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Climate change]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sponsored]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[sustainable energy]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1050759</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Research shows that businesses, governments, and consumers around the world are increasingly concerned about the environment. But despite our apparent concern, we seem to be doing very little about it. Per a recent report, material extraction and use has nearly quadrupled in the last 50 years, outpacing even population growth. The current economy is built&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Research shows that businesses, governments, and consumers around the world are <a href="https://fsc.org/en/newsfeed/2021-global-consumer-research-reveals-escalating-concerns-about-climate-change-and-threats" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increasingly</a> concerned about the environment. But despite our apparent concern, we seem to be doing very little about it. Per a recent report, material extraction and use has nearly quadrupled in the last <a href="https://www.circularity-gap.world/2022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">50 years</a>, outpacing even population growth. The current economy is built on a linear approach where organizations harvest Earth’s natural resources, then create and sell products to consumers who eventually use and throw away these products. It is estimated that over 100 billion tons of material are harvested and consumed every year, with more than 90% ending up in landfills without being recycled.</p>



<p>The circular economy aims to change all this by promoting a more sustainable approach where natural resources are extracted efficiently; production is carried out in a manner where there is minimum wastage; and at the end of the product’s life, materials are recovered, regenerated, repaired, and reused for as long as possible so that businesses no longer have to extract virgin natural resources to fuel demand. The circular economy has the potential to significantly reduce pressure on the environment, create a <a href="https://www.weforum.org/impact/helping-the-circular-economy-become-a-reality/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multi-trillion</a> dollar economy, stimulate innovation, and create <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90343657/the-circular-economy-could-create-an-enormous-jobs-boom" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">enormous</a> numbers of jobs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1200" height="833" src="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/132161331_l.png?w=1200" alt="" class="wp-image-1050756" srcset="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/132161331_l.png 1200w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/132161331_l.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/132161331_l.png?resize=768,533 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></figure>



<h3><strong>What’s stopping the circular economy from taking over?</strong></h3>



<p>Achieving a circular economy is easier said than done. Even the most well-intentioned companies can run into major obstacles while going down the circular economy path. According to <a href="https://www.cips.org/supply-management/news/2021/april/four-supply-chain-barriers-to-the-circular-economy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gartner</a>, there are four main challenges to the circular economy. First, returning ownership of end-of-life materials can be challenging. Organizations must do a deep dive in understanding how products are consumed and promote new supply chain models where expired products return to manufacturers. Second, raw materials must have enough residual value at end-of-life so they continue to be relevant to the business. Third, for businesses to make a compelling case to stakeholders, they must first possess an understanding of the quality, quantity, and intrinsic value of raw materials being returned. Fourth, the complexity of the product matters— the less complex the product being returned, the easier and cheaper the reprocessing, and vice versa.</p>



<h3><strong>How digitization of supply chains can boost circular economies</strong></h3>



<p>Digital innovation and the circular economy are kind of symbiotic in nature. In times of increasing internet proliferation, it’s hard to imagine any circular economy initiative that isn’t aided through technology. While there can be a number of ways in which digitization can positively impact the circular economy, here are the top three:</p>



<h4>1. <strong>Digitization can help organizations make better, more sustainable decisions</strong>.</h4>



<p>Digital technologies enable information to travel alongside the product. This enables businesses to capture, store, and analyze consumption patterns, which in turn helps organizations make better decisions. For example, research shows that <a href="https://www.circularity-gap.world/2022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">70%</a> of greenhouse gas emissions (GHG) are related to material handling and use. If businesses have insights into how full their aircraft, ship, or truck is, they can determine in real time how efficient their delivery will be. This translates to better efficiency, lower fuel costs, shorter delivery cycles, and reduced GHG. <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/in-2020-thyssenkrupp-elevators-max-predictive-maintenance-solution-further-established-itself-as-the-industrys-most-transformative-service-technology-301193766.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Thyssenkrupp</a>, one of the world’s leading elevator manufacturers, installed a cloud-based predictive maintenance system on 130,000 of its elevators worldwide. Its sensors collect health data of its components, systems, and performance. This helps Thyssenkrupp provide better service, extended elevator uptimes, and longer product lifespans.</p>



<p>2. <strong>Digitization can help unlock greater value across entire supply chains</strong>. Traditionally, most businesses are focused on connecting data and devices across their customer base. Digitization can be used to unlock a number of isolated parts, partners, and consumers from across the entire value chain. For instance, a raw material supplier can tap into the stocking system of a manufacturer (via APIs) to proactively validate if they are running out of certain raw materials. Once raw materials have reached end-of-life, manufacturers can leverage digital technologies to gauge whether the products have reached sufficient intrinsic value to be returned to them. This creates an opportunity for businesses to be more efficient, less resource intensive, and create less waste and emissions in the process. An increasing number of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.veltha.eu/blog/how-digital-platforms-are-enabling-circular-economy-innovation/" target="_blank">digital platforms</a> are promising to create tighter value-chain integrations and assist various manufacturers in transitioning to a circular economy model. On the consumer end, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/sustainable-retail-tech-circular-economy/" target="_blank">digital marketplaces</a> are helping to create more sustainability-conscious consumers.</p>



<p>3. <strong>Digital supply chains need to be reliable and secure</strong>. Supply chain digitization offers the promise of greater speed, efficiency, visibility, and control. However, the increased prevalence of APIs means that an organization’s attack surface increases. In the same way that a single container ship trapped in the Suez Canal can interrupt the world economy, an API that is unavailable or untrustworthy can disrupt important supply chain processes. As organizations digitize, they need to take the measures necessary to protect their digital assets.</p>



<h3><strong>How Citrix is engaging the circular economy</strong></h3>



<p>Citrix technologies empower individuals and businesses to work from anywhere and embrace adaptable work models. These technologies allow organizations to embrace a secure hybrid work model. This also means that organizations using Citrix can dramatically reduce commuting emissions while meeting employee needs for flexibility, given how <a href="https://www.c2es.org/content/reducing-your-carbon-footprint-at-work/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">27%</a> of U.S. emissions derive from transportation sources and office-related commuting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Workers using Citrix solutions can use low-energy devices and use those same devices for longer, reducing cost and emissions while keeping hazardous waste out of landfills. This supports two key principles of a circular economy with device reuse and waste reduction.</p>



<p>Citrix technologies also play a vital role in facilitating a seamless move to energy efficiency and lower carbon cloud computing. Citrix’s App Delivery and Security solution protects and scales APIs that are so vital to a streamlined and efficient digital supply chain. Protecting the digital backbone is an important step in moving to a more circular economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The shift to the circular economy will not be easy, but it will be rewarding. Customers are looking for businesses that provide great service, but also share their core values. Companies that leverage digitization to embrace circularity will be seen as visionary, and as such will be rewarded with deeper customer relationships and loyalty. As the old saying goes, what goes around, comes around.</p>



<p><em>This content was produced by Citrix. It was not written by MIT Technology Review’s editorial staff.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1050759</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Download: China’s delivery apps, and why Russia’s invasion has stalled</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/29/1051617/download-china-delivery-grocery-apps-shanghai-lockdown-russia-invasion/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 12:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Humans and technology]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Humans and Technology]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051617</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Shanghai’s lockdown is giving China’s online grocery apps a second chance During Shanghai’s ongoing month-long lockdown, online grocery apps have been a lifeline for residents unable to leave their homes. People are swarming&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>Shanghai’s lockdown is giving China’s online grocery apps a second chance</strong></h2>



<p>During Shanghai’s ongoing month-long lockdown, online grocery apps have been a lifeline for residents unable to leave their homes. People are swarming onto the services, including Dingdong, Alibaba’s Hema, and Meituan’s Maicai, at designated times to try to purchase as much as they can before the stocks run out in seconds.<br><br>The Shanghai lockdown is the latest stage of a two-year roller-coaster ride for the online grocery industry in China. Its rise and fall and rise again has mirrored the tightening and loosening of China’s covid-19 restrictions: while the apps are incredibly popular during restrictions, they’ve struggled whenever lockdowns are relaxed.<br><br>Now, as China continues with its zero-covid strategy, the harsh lockdown measures have given the industry another chance to shine after a year of disappointing business returns. Whether it continues to succeed when things are back to normal is another question.<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/29/1051604/shanghai-lockdown-online-grocery/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Zeyi Yang</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong>Quote of the day</strong><br>“We think the Chinese economy at this moment is in the worst shape in the past 30 years.”</p></blockquote>



<p>—Weijian Shan, the founder of one of Asia’s biggest private equity investors, criticizes the Chinese government’s policies in a video seen by <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6bf52409-fe31-4f57-ae24-f2bd9146a698">the Financial Times</a>.</p>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>The must-reads</strong></h2>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<p><strong>1 Why Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is falling apart</strong><br>It doesn’t appear to be learning from the mistakes it’s made, and it’s made a lot of them. (<a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/ukraine/2022-04-29/how-not-invade-nation">Foreign Affairs</a> $)<br><em>+ Meta’s attempts to curb misinformation about the war in Ukraine are harming local publishers.</em> (<a href="https://www.codastory.com/authoritarian-tech/ukraine-facebook-battle/">Coda Story</a>)<br>+ <em>The conflict in Ukraine could last for years, Nato says.</em> (<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/world-europe-61252785">BBC</a>)<br>+ <em>The UK is sending 8,000 soldiers to eastern Europe</em>. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/apr/28/uk-to-send-8000-soldiers-to-eastern-europe-on-expanded-exercises">The Guardian</a>) </p>



<p><strong>2 Social media refuses to admin whether it’s shadowbanning us<br></strong>And that means users trust platforms even less. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2022/04/social-media-shadowbans-tiktok-twitter/629702/">The Atlantic</a> $)<br>+ <em>Elon Musk’s links to China could come back to bite him at Twitter.</em> (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/29/technology/elon-musk-china-tesla.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>His plans to open up the company’s algorithms could also open a can of worms.</em> (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051472/the-problems-with-elon-musks-plan-to-open-source-the-twitter-algorithm/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">TR</a>)<em> </em><br>+ <em>It looks like Twitter has been overstating its audience figures for three whole years. </em>(<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/3184a769-4288-44e8-abea-300d27c1aa95">FT</a> $)<br>+ <em>But the platform does play host to the odd gem. </em>(<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2022/04/twitters-best-moments.html">Intelligencer</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>3 How one man escaped Shanghai’s brutal lockdown<br></strong>After three weeks of intense hunger and uncertainty. (<a href="https://www.codastory.com/authoritarian-tech/shanghai-zero-covid-lockdown-food-escape-restrictions/">Coda Story</a>)<strong><br></strong>+ <em>Weibo will post users’ IP locations to crack down on “bad behavior</em>.” (<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/04/28/tech/weibo-user-location-bad-behavior/index.html">CNN</a>)<br>+ <em>Tim Cook is worried China’s covid lockdowns could affect demand for Apple gear</em>. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-aapl-q2-earnings-report-2022-11651115203?mod=tech_lead_pos3">WSJ</a> $)<br><strong><br>4 Netflix wants to lure Asian subscribers away from local streaming rivals<br></strong>But they’re much cheaper. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/netflixs-battle-for-asian-subscribers-pits-it-against-rich-rivals-hundreds-of-local-upstarts-11651148887?mod=tech_lead_pos5">WSJ</a> $)<br>+ <em>Hollywood has had enough of those pesky VPNs. </em>(<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/hollywood-piracy-vpn-lawsuits/">Wired</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>5 It’s getting tougher to predict what the future holds for Big Tech </strong><strong><br></strong>The boom years of crazy growth are coming to an end. Now what? (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/28/technology/tech-uncertainty.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>Snap’s Evan Spiegel isn’t sold on the metaverse</em>. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/28/23046594/snap-evan-spiegel-metaverse-pixy-ar-interview">The Verge</a>)</p>



<p><strong>6</strong> <strong>Meet the Bitcoin fanatics who think crypto is a dirty word <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1fa99.png" alt="🪙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><br>Because crypto going mainstream means more clueless newbies. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/28/23042819/bitcoin-2022-miami-beach-conference-maxis">The Verge</a>)<br>+ <em>Banks are basically influencers now.</em> (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-28/central-banks-have-embraced-instagram-and-tiktok-could-be-next?sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+ <em>Scam loan apps are becoming a massive problem in India. </em>(<a href="https://restofworld.org/2022/digital-blackmail-scammy-loan-apps-india/?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=feeds">Rest of World</a>)</p>



<p><strong>7 Is Groups the last good thing on Facebook?</strong><strong><br></strong>Other platforms just aren’t as easy to form strong communities on. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/04/how-facebook-groups-create-community/629698/">The Atlantic</a> $)<br>+<em> Landlord influencers don’t care if you don’t like them</em>. (<a href="https://www.inputmag.com/culture/landlord-influencers-tiktok-youtube">Input</a>)</p>



<p><strong>8 Detecting depression can be tough. Video games could help</strong><br>But they’re not enough alone for a diagnosis. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/04/28/video-game-depression-thymia/">WP</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>9 We don’t know who’s behind the spike in spam calls <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4de.png" alt="📞" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br></strong>We do, however, know they’re probably going to keep coming. (<a href="https://slate.com/technology/2022/04/spam-calls-why-ajit-pai-fcc.html?via=rss">Slate</a>)<br><br><strong>10 Spanish workers are transforming old phones into furniture<br></strong>Which is a fun approach to tackling our growing e-waste problem. (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-28/electronic-recycling-turns-old-phones-tvs-into-furniture?srnd=premium&amp;sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></h2>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction in these weird times. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/RhiannonJudithW"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em><br><br>+ To celebrate Penélope Cruz’s 48th birthday, this <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2022/apr/28/penelope-cruz-20-best-films-ranked">look back through her 20 best movies</a> is a reminder of just how great an actress she is.<br>+ Desk-bound for lunch? Here are <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/collections/al-desko">some easy recipes</a>.<br>+ Turns out the Aristocats <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMLgRbfqn/">really enjoyed German industrial metal</a>.<br>+ Here’s why <a href="https://www.vox.com/23042703/selling-sunset-season-5-review-christine-quinn-chrishell-stause">Selling Sunset</a> is one of the most unhinged shows on television.<br>+ Brush up on the fascinating history of the famous names behind <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2022-04-19/getty-bradbury-marmont-lummis-the-people-behind-the-famous-l-a-buildings">LA’s most eye-catching buildings</a>.<br>+ I’m sorry, but Donald Trump calling tomatoes “<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/04/28/politics/donald-trump-dangerous-fruit-tomato/index.html">very dangerous</a>” is very, very funny.<br>+ If you’re feeling a bit burnt out ahead of the weekend, embracing some <a href="https://www.refinery29.com/en-gb/my-slow-life-searching-for-an-antidote-to-hustle-culture">slow living</a> could help.</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051617</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shanghai’s lockdown is giving China’s online grocery apps a second chance</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/29/1051604/shanghai-lockdown-online-grocery/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Zeyi Yang]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Humans and technology]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Coronavirus]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Humans and Technology]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051604</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Midnight, 6 a.m., 8 a.m., 8:30 a.m., 9 a.m.: these times are ingrained in Queeny Song’s mind. For over a week in April, the 24-year-old Shanghai resident had to get her phone out at these five points every day to refresh a different grocery delivery app in hopes of grabbing a hard-to-get delivery slot. During&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Midnight, 6 a.m., 8 a.m., 8:30 a.m., 9 a.m.: these times are ingrained in Queeny Song’s mind. For over a week in April, the 24-year-old Shanghai resident had to get her phone out at these five points every day to refresh a different grocery delivery app in hopes of grabbing a hard-to-get delivery slot.</p>



<p>During Shanghai’s ongoing month-long lockdown, these online grocery apps have been a lifeline for stranded residents. Song says that about 60 to 70% of her groceries have been purchased through online apps since the lockdown began. Without them, she would have run out of food.</p>



<p>The Shanghai lockdown is the latest stage of a two-year roller-coaster ride for the online grocery industry in China. Its rise and fall and rise again has mirrored the tightening and loosening of China’s covid-19 restrictions: apps like Dingdong, Alibaba’s Hema, and Meituan’s Maicai have struggled whenever lockdowns are relaxed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, as China continues with its zero-covid strategy, the <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/24/1051073/wechat-shanghai-lockdown-protest-video-the-voice-of-april/">harsh lockdown measures</a> have given the industry another chance to shine after a year of disappointing business returns. Whether it continues to succeed when things are back to normal is another question.</p>



<h3>The rise and fall of online grocers</h3>



<p>Around 2015, Chinese tech companies, including Alibaba, started experimenting with ideas to incorporate grocery shopping into the country’s thriving e-commerce landscape. It wasn’t until 2018 and 2019 that the industry really began to take off, with dozens of new startups competing for attention and investments. But growth was modest; startup failures were common.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was the first nationwide lockdown in China, in the first few months of 2020, that really supercharged the industry’s growth. As Chinese people first began to grapple with what it meant to be sheltering in place, they relied on these apps, most of which launched in 2018 and 2019, to have their supplies delivered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It soon grew into one of the hottest new tech industries in China, with venture capital funding pouring in and tech giants like DiDi and Meituan eager to take a slice. A <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/cn/our-insights/our-insights/what-can-we-expect-in-china-in-2021">February 2021 McKinsey report</a> predicted that “online grocery shopping will likely be one of the most contested and contentious consumer facing sectors in China in 2021.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And contested it was, as players in the market were not afraid to spend: according to an anonymous executive at the now-defunct Chengxin Youxuan, the e-grocer arm of DiDi, quoted in the <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Caixin/In-depth-The-shakeout-in-China-s-community-group-buying-market">Chinese business publication</a> Caixin, “The entire market was burning at least 10 billion yuan ($1.57 billion) every month.” In June 2021, startups Dingdong and MissFresh filed to go public in the United States on the same day, racing to be the first Chinese publicly traded online grocery company.</p>





<p>But things started to take a downturn last year. Despite the hype and money, these companies struggled to make a profit as lockdowns eased and people simply went back to shopping in person. What’s worse, they were caught in China’s new fight against antitrust behavior. The Chinese government was quick to <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3123894/community-group-buying-chinese-regulators-fine-businesses-tied-big-tech">impose fines</a> and <a href="https://supchina.com/2020/12/22/consumers-love-cheap-groceries-but-can-community-group-buying-withstand-government-scrutiny/">pen editorials</a> questioning the value of the industry.</p>



<p>As a result, the once-promising startups and big tech companies decided to cut back on their expansion plans, implement massive layoffs, or outright file for bankruptcy. DiDi and Ele.me, two successful tech companies that bet on online grocery as their new growth driver, decided to shut down those services. At least two more online grocery startups have closed their businesses in the last year. </p>



<p>The latest lockdowns are giving the industry a second chance. With other Chinese cities like Beijing and Hangzhou also facing imminent lockdowns, millions of people are once again downloading these apps and relying on them on a daily basis. In fact, Dingdong’s app rose to third place in the App Store’s free app chart in China in the beginning of April.</p>



<h3>The daily battle</h3>



<p>While the luckier Shanghai residents may receive one-off free grocery packages from their employers or local governments, most people, like Song, needed to figure out a way to buy their own groceries. Some residents <a href="https://restofworld.org/2022/shanghai-lockdown-wechat-group-buying/">formed neighborhood groups through messaging apps</a>, collecting everyone’s order and bulk-buying directly from nearby farms or food factories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Song soon realized that buying groceries with all her neighbors means she didn’t get to make her own choices. She lives in an older residential neighborhood where over three-fourths of the people are seniors or families with children. While her neighbors are placing family-size orders for things like five pounds of pork, such purchases would take her forever to consume.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The only other option for her, then, is the grocery apps. She frantically refreshes Dingdong, Hema, and Meituan Maicai every day to get a slot.</p>



<p>But with the lockdown interrupting the supply chain for many goods, including groceries, even placing an order on those apps requires luck and dedication. Like Black Friday shoppers waiting to bust the store doors open, Shanghai residents are swarming onto the apps at the designated time to try to buy as much as they can before the stocks run out in seconds. It can be stressful and frustrating. </p>



<p>Li, a consultant in Shanghai who’s only using her surname because she wishes to stay anonymous, also got up early every morning for a week to try her luck with half a dozen different apps. But during the lockdown, she didn’t secure one successful order, while her mother, living under the same roof, managed to get three. There was one time when Li put hundreds of RMB worth of groceries into the shopping cart—yet when she came to the payment stage, the only thing left in stock was a bag of candies. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong><em>To support MIT Technology Review&#8217;s journalism, please consider <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?utm_medium=onsite&amp;utm_source=story-cta&amp;utm_campaign=subscribe-BAU">becoming a subscriber</a></em></strong>.</p></blockquote>



<p>“Because of the explosive increase in Shanghai users’ demand, the purchase experience will certainly be different from how it was in ordinary times. The success rate for placing orders will be low,” the grocery app Dingdong said in an emailed response to MIT Technology Review. “In this situation, our product principle is to prioritize impartiality.” The company says that’s why it restocks at the same time every day and approves a random portion of the orders each time.</p>



<p>How the industry deals with these issues may determine what it looks like when life goes back to normal. Can it retain these new consumers once people are able to go to their nearby grocery stores again? It’s hard to say, but investors are no longer as optimistic as they were in 2020, and users are likely split.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Song says she will keep apps like Dingdong and JD on her phone, because she’s thankful that they have kept her and other people fed during a scary time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Li, the other Shanghai resident, thinks differently. “It is still my second choice. I’m only shopping on them because I can’t in any other way,” she says. “After the pandemic, I’m sure I won’t use them anymore.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051604</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern data management, the hidden brain of AI</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/28/1051009/modern-data-management-the-hidden-brain-of-ai/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Dina]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sponsored]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051009</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (AI) is the darling of businesses and governments because it not only promises to add tens of trillions to the gross domestic product (GDP), but it comes with all the excitement of action-packed movies or dopamine-drenched gaming. We are mesmerized by computer vision, natural language processing, and the uncanny predictions of recommendation engines.&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is the darling of businesses and governments because it not only promises to <a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/issues/data-and-analytics/publications/artificial-intelligence-study.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">add tens of trillions</a> to the gross domestic product (GDP), but it comes with all the excitement of action-packed movies or dopamine-drenched gaming. We are mesmerized by computer vision, natural language processing, and the uncanny predictions of recommendation engines. It protects us from fraud, lowers inventory costs, and teases us with programming we might enjoy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1800" height="1013" src="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hidden-brain.png" alt="stock image of lit-up neuron" class="wp-image-1051048" srcset="https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hidden-brain.png 1800w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hidden-brain.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hidden-brain.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/hidden-brain.png?resize=1536,864 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1800px) 100vw, 1800px" /></figure>



<p>The current state of the art, deep learning, comes from a brilliant concept to model algorithms <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/a-concise-history-of-neural-networks-2070655d3fec" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">based on how the human brain functions</a>. The way neurons wire together inspire the structure of mathematical calculations. And why not? We are making computers more human with eyes (video), ears (microphone), and fingers (temperature &amp; vibration sensors).</p>



<p>The name, AI, implies a replication of human intelligence in silicon form. Yet, it’s easy to lose sight of the hidden brain that brings AI to useful life. Let’s explore the neuroscience as a metaphor to understand this premise.</p>



<p>The typical adult brain <a href="https://www.verywellmind.com/how-big-is-the-brain-2794888" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">weighs about 3 lbs</a>. and consumes <a href="https://hypertextbook.com/facts/2001/JacquelineLing.shtml#:~:text=The%20brain%20consumes%20energy%20at,of%20the%20brain%2020%20W." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">20 WATTs</a> of power. It is a remarkably efficient machine. Nobel prize-winning psychologist, Daniel Kahneman alludes to this efficiency-seeking function when he describes <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking,_Fast_and_Slow" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">System 1 and System 2 thinking</a>. He proved that we have a subconscious, and thus low-powered, method of processing information. It operates more often than the higher-powered, executive function.</p>



<p>Neuro-anatomy experts believe that memories are encoded with emotions, but those emotions are not individually stored. They are essentially references built and stored in the limbic system. Basically, we remember an event and then there is a lookup table for how we felt about it. It is also a powerful influence on how we subconsciously make choices.</p>



<p>This limbic system, located in the middle brain, influences future decisions because <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/what-part-of-the-brain-controls-emotions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it uses emotional memory as a framework</a> for what might serve us or what might slay us. Without it, we make sub-optimal choices because we lose context for risk or reward.</p>



<p>Similarly, AI analysis without all the right data leads to a faulty future. Therefore, it is worthwhile to talk about how organizing and presenting “all the right data” is critical. Management of the messy, high-volume, unstructured data should be considered as important to AI as the limbic system is to the predictive function of the human brain.</p>



<p>Yet, there are other factors to automatic decision-making beyond the emotional memory system. Let us explore the brain metaphor further. Kevin Simler and Robin Hanson argue in their book, <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Elephant_in_the_Brain" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Elephant in the Brain: Hidden Motives in Everyday Life</a></em>, how unconscious we are about the nature of our own behaviors. They make the case that we are like our primate “cousins” in acting according to social motivations. Whether you consider this evolutionary biology or learned in the family of origin, matters less than understanding that there is something else hidden in our human brains. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This blind spot might also explain why technologists often oversee data management as phenomenon of culture. Typically, pundits only write about data management in two dimensions. The first is technology focused. It begins with byte sizes, throughput, and access patterns. This is a platform mindset that affords the procurement, storage, and availability of data. It has a strong bias to metadata (data about data) because this is the steering wheel with which to drive the car.</p>



<p>The second dimension commonly exploited is process. This systems-level view comprehends the entire pipeline, from acquisition at the source, to sorting and shuffling, to cataloging, to presenting, and finally to archiving. It is the farm-to-table point of view. Or rather, farm-to-Tupperware point of view. It concerns itself with the “how,” while technology takes a “what” perspective.</p>



<p>The third, and arguably invisible, dimension lies in culture, or the “who.” Culture can be described as a set a set of behaviors anchored by a shared belief system and bound by group norms. Culture pulls the puppet strings of process and technology. Yet, it is the most overlooked factor in data management.</p>



<p>Many institutions race to deploy technology and tool processes without first understanding how they want their culture to mature. They would be better served to model themselves in the way that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positive_psychology" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">positive psychologists</a> study the most successful people. Those researchers investigate the belief systems and behaviors that are common in the truly accomplished.</p>



<p>While it would be worthwhile to provide a few case studies to prove this point, for the sake of brevity, we will present a summary of findings of the most successful in data management.</p>



<p>It begins with a shift in belief systems around data. In this new paradigm, data is just not an artifact of what happened; it’s asset with tremendous economic implications. And unlike other items on the balance sheet, it can appreciate in value over time.</p>



<p>With that in mind, find below a checklist of new behaviors associated with a shift in mindset around data.</p>



<ul><li>Data is federated into a fabric, not centralized nor siloed.</li><li>Knowledge is organized by context and tagged by both publishers and subscribers.</li><li>Models are preserved for continuous learning and accountability.</li><li>Transparency (observability) mitigates legal and regulatory pressures.</li><li>A broader view of ethics expands beyond the initial concerns for privacy.</li><li>Machine learning automates data engineering tasks.</li><li>Knowledge workers become value-creation workers.</li><li>Top-down, data-driven decisions evolve into bottom-up shared insights.</li><li>Data is measured in economic terms and not accounting terms.</li></ul>



<p>So, if your organization aims at exploiting AI, do not overlook the importance of modern data management and the fundamentals that make it up. Begin by benchmarking the current state to the desired state. Build a cross-disciplinary approach to overcome the gaps. Lean heavily on technologists, process engineers, organizational developers, and economists in formulating a game plan.<br><br>If you have interest in going deeper into this modern data management philosophy, <a href="https://www.delltechnologies.com/asset/en-us/products/servers/industry-market/the-ugly-truth-about-data-management.pdf" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.delltechnologies.com/asset/en-us/products/servers/industry-market/the-ugly-truth-about-data-management.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">please check out this white paper</a> authored by Bill Schmarzo, the dean of big data, and an esteemed colleague at Dell Technologies. </p>



<p><em>This content was produced by Dell Technologies. It was not written by MIT Technology Review’s editorial staff.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051009</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Download: Police used social media to surveil Black people, and India’s worsening heat waves</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/28/1051543/download-police-social-media-black-people-india-heat-waves-climate-change/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech policy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech Policy]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051543</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Minneapolis police used fake social media profiles to surveil Black people The Minneapolis Police Department violated civil rights law through a pattern of racist policing practices, according to a damning report published today&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>Minneapolis police used fake social media profiles to surveil Black people</strong></h2>



<p>The Minneapolis Police Department violated civil rights law through a pattern of racist policing practices, according to a <a href="https://mn.gov/mdhr/assets/Investigation%20into%20the%20City%20of%20Minneapolis%20and%20the%20Minneapolis%20Police%20Department_tcm1061-526417.pdf">damning report</a> published today by the Minnesota Department of Human Rights. The report found that officers stop, search, arrest, and use force against people of color at a much higher rate than white people, and covertly surveilled Black people not suspected of any crimes via social media.<br><br>The findings are consistent with MIT Technology Review’s <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/supertopic/secret-police-surveillance-investigation-minnesota/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">investigation of Minnesota law enforcement agencies</a>, which has revealed <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/03/03/1046676/police-surveillance-minnesota-george-floyd/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">an extensive surveillance network</a> that targeted activists in the aftermath of the murder of George Floyd. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051517/minneapolis-police-racial-bias-fake-social-media-profiles-surveillance/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Tate Ryan-Mosley and Sam Richards</em></p>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-12 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="wp-container-11 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>Climate change is making India’s brutal heat waves worse</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Blistering temperatures:</strong> Heat waves are scorching India and Pakistan this week, breaking records as the region enters the hottest time of the year. Some states in India have already seen temperatures top 43 °C (110 °F).<br><br><strong>Peaking early: </strong>Extreme heat can be deadly, especially for a region where many lack access to cooling. And climate change is making heat waves more frequent and severe. Usually, peak temperatures in the region come in May and June, just before monsoon rains bring relief, but this year has been particularly hot, particularly early.</p>



<p><strong>Accelerated change:</strong> The effects of climate change on weather can sometimes be difficult to tease out. But for heat waves, researchers have “very high confidence” that climate change is making the problem worse. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/28/1051511/climate-change-india-heat-waves/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.</p>



<p><em>—Casey Crownhart</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-9 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>Quote of the day</strong></h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p>“I’m sure everyone will say hi to me. Everyone will be my friend.”</p></blockquote>



<p>—Artur, a 10-year-old from western Ukraine, is optimistic about settling into his new home in America, according to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/apr/28/ukrainian-refugees-tijuana-mexico-us-immigration">The Guardian</a>.</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-10 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>The must-reads</strong></h2>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 Elon Musk attacked Twitter’s top lawyer<br></strong>His tweets criticizing her triggered a wave of racist abuse. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/04/27/musk-twitter-attacks/">WP</a> $)<br>+ <em>Women and minorities are all too familiar with how it feels to be harassed on Twitter</em>. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/27/opinion/elon-musk-twitter-cesspool.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>Republican senators gained followers in the wake of the deal announcement.</em> (<a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2022/04/27/republican-senators-gained-almost-160000-twitter-followers-after-elon-musks-deal">Economist</a> $)<br>+ <em>No CEO is an island when it comes to running  a social media platform</em>. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/04/27/jack-dorsey-elon-musk-singular-solution/">WP</a> $)<br>+ <em>Twitter hid tweets promoting a documentary</em><strong> </strong><em>about</em><strong> </strong><em>QAnon.</em> (<a href="https://gizmodo.com/twitter-hbo-qanon-censor-q-into-the-storm-1848842476">Gizmodo</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 Russia is still being flooded with cyberattacks</strong><strong><br></strong>While hacks targeting Ukraine have decreased. (<a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/russia-hacked-attacks">Wired</a> $)<br>+ <em>Many of Russia’s cyberattacks appear to support its military strikes</em>. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/27/us/politics/russia-cyberattacks-ukraine.html">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>Ukrainians are fighting a colonial war. </em>(<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/essay/the-war-in-ukraine-is-a-colonial-war">New Yorker</a> $)<br>+ <em>Ukrainians are posing with destroyed Russian tanks for social media shots.</em> (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/27/ukraine-tanks-roadside-attraction/">WP</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>3 A second country has adopted Bitcoin as legal tender</strong><br>Though just 4% of people in the Central African Republic even have access to the web. (<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-61248809">BBC</a>) <br>+<em> Crypto millionaires are pouring money into Central America to build their own cities.</em> (<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/20/1049384/crypto-cities-central-america/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">TR</a>)</p>



<p><strong>4 Meta’s revenue growth is the slowest it’s been in a decade</strong><br>But it’s finally stopped losing users. (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/417c5c7b-6ba1-4414-ad1b-f939b82755d7">FT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>5 North Koreans are jailbreaking smartphones to access foreign media</strong><br>And it’s helping them to challenge the government’s regime. (<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/north-korean-phone-jailbreakers/">Wired</a> $)<br>+ <em>North Korean defectors have flown propaganda leaflets into the country</em>. (<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/nkorea-defectors-fly-leaflets-with-skoreas-yoon-photos-despite-ban-2022-04-28/">Reuters</a>)</p>



<p><strong>6 Google may remove search results that could be used to dox you</strong><strong><br></strong>That’ll involve taking down personal information such as your address or login credentials. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/27/23044951/google-search-results-personal-information-address-phone-number">The Verge</a>)<br>+ <em>A reminder that your social media timeline is not a democracy. </em>(<a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/women-rule/2022/04/22/how-to-deal-with-online-harassment-00027124">Politico</a>)</p>



<p><strong>7 Shanghai residents are crowdsourcing aid to survive lockdown</strong><br>As the city enters its fifth week of restrictions, people are forming networks to swap everything from recipes to pet care tips. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/shanghai-uses-crowdsourcing-to-survive-covid-19-lockdown-as-social-support-breaks-down-11651138991?mod=hp_lead_pos10">WSJ</a> $)<br>+ <em>Fury over lockdowns is testing China&#8217;s triumphant covid narrative</em>. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/27/world/asia/china-covid-propaganda.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">NYT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>8 Marine biologists have developed GPS for the ocean</strong><strong><br></strong>Hopefully it’ll make tracking sea creatures less challenging. (<a href="https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/gps-for-the-oceans/21808966">Economist</a> $)<br>+ <em>A gigantic ocean current appears to be slowing down. </em>(<a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-major-ocean-current-is-at-its-weakest-point-in-1-000-years/">Scientific American</a>)</p>



<p><strong>9 Lost your phone? Here’s how to get into your accounts<br></strong>To prevent anyone else getting their hands on your private info. (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/04/27/two-factor-authentication-2fa-lost-phone-what-to-do/">WP</a> $<br><br><strong>10 Zoom meetings may be making us less creative<br></strong>Because brainstorming with others is easier and more fruitful in person. (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2022/apr/27/workers-think-less-creatively-in-zoom-meetings-study-finds">The Guardian</a>)</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-13 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></h2>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction in these weird times. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/RhiannonJudithW"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em><br><br>+ This strikes me as <a href="https://twitter.com/jrrr1510/status/1517016472790441985?s=21&amp;t=HkpLiFbzB9TL0Njhk6JMgQ">parenting at its finest</a>.<br>+ The <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/in-pictures-61222913">winning picture</a> of this food photography contest makes me want a delicious kebab.<br>+ Time to brush up on more than 10,000 years of Indian art history, thanks to this <a href="https://mapacademy.io/">amazing open-source encyclopedia</a>.<br>+ Harry Styles’ Better Homes and Gardens cover shoot is <a href="https://www.bhg.com/better-homes-and-garden-magazine/harry-styles/">so much fun</a>.<br>+ A useful explanation of <a href="https://www.iflscience.com/technology/how-do-keys-open-locks/">how keys open locks</a>, if you’ve never really understood.<br>+ An essential investigation into <a href="https://www.vulture.com/2022/04/the-o-c-crypto-ranking-ben-mckenzie.html?utm_source=flipboard.com&amp;utm_medium=social_acct&amp;utm_campaign=feed-part">which characters from The OC would be Bitcoin moguls</a>.<br>+ Finally, a <a href="https://twitter.com/Beeshrine/status/1518623481679732738?s=20&amp;t=nNmf1iU6FrjBsmhplWd_Pw">joke about Twitter we can all enjoy</a>.</p>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051543</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change is making India’s brutal heat waves worse</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/28/1051511/climate-change-india-heat-waves/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Casey Crownhart]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Climate change]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051511</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Heat waves are scorching India and Pakistan this week, breaking records as the region enters the hottest time of the year. Some states in India have seen temperatures top 43 °C (110 °F), with northwest India likely to see even higher temperatures in the coming days, according to the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD). Extreme heat&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Heat waves are scorching India and Pakistan this week, breaking records as the region enters the hottest time of the year.</p>



<p>Some states in India have seen temperatures top 43 °C (110 °F), with northwest India likely to see even higher temperatures in the coming days, according to the Indian Meteorological Department (IMD).</p>



<p>Extreme heat can be deadly, especially for a region where many lack access to cooling. And climate change is making heat waves more frequent and severe, with periods of hot days stretching out longer in places like South Asia.</p>



<p>This heat wave is particularly concerning for its timing and its spread, says <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.climate.iitb.ac.in/en/employee-profile/prof-arpita-mondal" target="_blank">Arpita Mondal</a>, a climate researcher at the Indian Institute of Technology Bombay. Usually, peak temperatures in the region come in May and June, just before monsoon rains bring relief, she explains, but this year has been particularly hot, particularly early. March of this year was the hottest <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://internal.imd.gov.in/press_release/20220402_pr_1551.pdf" target="_blank">on record</a>, with an average temperature of 33.1 °C (nearly 92 °F).</p>



<p>The problem is also widespread across the country, affecting not only the typical hot spots in the northwest and southeast but also regions that aren’t used to seeing so much extreme heat, Mondal says. And the effects are even more stark because of a lack of rainfall so far this season.</p>



<p>“It’s part of a broader climate-change signal,” says <a href="https://amir.eng.uci.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amir AghaKouchak</a>, a climate researcher at the University of California, Irvine. India’s average annual temperature increased at a rate of 0.62 °C per 100 years between 1901 and 2020, according to data from the<a href="https://climateknowledgeportal.worldbank.org/country/india/climate-data-historical" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> World Bank</a>. And maximum temperatures have climbed even more quickly, at a rate of 0.99 °C every 100 years.</p>



<p>“People think a degree or two might not matter,” AghaKouchak says, but when average temperatures increase by even small amounts, it means extreme events are becoming more likely.</p>



<p>The effects of climate change on weather can sometimes be difficult to tease out. But for heat waves, researchers have “very high confidence” that climate change is making the problem worse, AghaKouchak says.</p>



<p>Heat can have <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/07/10/1028172/climate-change-human-body-extreme-heat-survival/" target="_blank">devastating impacts on human health</a>—356,000 deaths globally in 2019 were <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673621017001" target="_blank">linked to extreme heat</a>. The risk is greatest for elderly people and children, but anyone without adequate access to cooling can be affected, especially if heat continues for days at a time without letting up at night.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>





<p>Forecasting and early warning systems can help people <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2018/05/02/143103/how-to-prepare-cities-and-citizens-for-more-killer-heat-waves/" target="_blank">prepare for extreme heat</a>. And the IMD has started focusing on forecasting heat waves in recent years, Mondal says.</p>



<p>However, the realities of a developing country mean that many people will still come into harm’s way during heat waves in India. As of 2019, only about <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/05/india-heat-cooling-challenge-temperature-air-conditioning/">7%</a> of Indian households had an air conditioner. And staying inside when temperatures peak might not be an option for people who depend on income from daily work, Mondal says.</p>



<p>Some local governments are trying to adapt to extreme heat. Ahmedabad, a city in western India, experienced an especially devastating heat wave in May 2010: the official death count reached 800 people, and up to 1,300 deaths have been <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24633076/" target="_blank">attributed</a> to it indirectly. In 2013, the city launched a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.nrdc.org/sites/default/files/ahmedabad-heat-action-plan-2018.pdf" target="_blank">heat action plan</a>, which included early warning systems for residents, training for health-care professionals, and adjustments to help cool buildings naturally.</p>



<p>Since then, other local governments have followed suit and created plans of their own, but some hope to see more national action to help people adjust to heat, Mondal says.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong><em>To support MIT Technology Review&#8217;s journalism, please consider <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?utm_medium=onsite&amp;utm_source=story-cta&amp;utm_campaign=subscribe-BAU">becoming a subscriber</a></em></strong>.</p></blockquote>



<p>Cutting emissions will help prevent the worst future warming scenarios, but the current reality is already difficult to endure for many. And India’s deadly heat waves offer just one example of who will be most affected by a changing climate.</p>



<p>“Here are 1.4 billion people who will be affected by this heat wave, the majority of whom contributed very little to global warming,” Mondal says. “This phenomenon should put an end to the question of why people should care about climate change.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051511</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis police used fake social media profiles to surveil Black people</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051517/minneapolis-police-racial-bias-fake-social-media-profiles-surveillance/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tate Ryan-Mosley, Sam Richards]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 23:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech policy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[secret police]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051517</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The Minneapolis Police Department violated civil rights law through a pattern of racist policing practices, according to a damning report published today by the Minnesota Department of Human Rights. The report, which is the result of a two-year inquiry, found that officers stop, search, arrest, and use force against people of color at a much&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Minneapolis Police Department violated civil rights law through a pattern of racist policing practices, according to a <a href="https://mn.gov/mdhr/assets/Investigation%20into%20the%20City%20of%20Minneapolis%20and%20the%20Minneapolis%20Police%20Department_tcm1061-526417.pdf">damning report</a> published today by the Minnesota Department of Human Rights. The report, which is the result of a two-year inquiry, found that officers stop, search, arrest, and use force against people of color at a much higher rate than white people, and covertly surveilled Black individuals, organizations and politicians not suspected of any crimes via social media. The report also revealed a pattern of breakdowns in investigating and disciplining officers over complaints about use of force and other misconduct.</p>



<p>The findings are consistent with MIT Technology Review’s <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/supertopic/secret-police-surveillance-investigation-minnesota/">investigation of Minnesota law enforcement agencies</a>, which has revealed <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/03/03/1046676/police-surveillance-minnesota-george-floyd/">an extensive surveillance network</a> that targeted activists in the aftermath of the murder of George Floyd.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report establishes probable cause that the City of Minneapolis and the MPD violated the Minnesota Human Rights Act. The Human Rights Department will now work with Minneapolis public officials to develop a consent decree, which will require &#8220;specific changes to be made and timelines for those changes&#8221;, which will be enforceable by the state&#8217;s courts.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Severe disparities&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The Minneapolis Police Department (MPD) “engages in a pattern or practice of discriminatory, race-based policing,” begins the 72-page report. Investigators reviewed roughly “700 hours of body-worn camera footage and nearly 480,000 pages of City and MPD documents.” The state’s report relies on statistical analyses that weigh differing outcomes for white and non-white Minneapolitans in similar circumstances.&nbsp;</p>





<p>“Since 2010, of the 14 individuals that MPD officers have killed, 13 of those individuals were people of color or Indigenous individuals,” the report states. “People of color and Indigenous individuals comprise approximately 42% of the Minneapolis population but comprise 93% of all MPD officer-involved deaths between January 1, 2010, to February 2, 2022.”</p>



<p>A clear racial disparity can be seen in the widespread use of chemical and other “less-lethal” weapons as well. MPD officers deploy pepper spray against Black people at a higher rate than they do against white people. From the report: “Officers recorded using chemical irritants in 25.1% of use of force incidents involving Black individuals. In contrast, MPD officers recorded using chemical irritants in 18.2% of use of force incidents involving white individuals in similar circumstances.” Overall, according to the report, “between January 1, 2010, to December 31, 2020, 63% of all use of force incidents that MPD officers recorded were against Black individuals.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Traffic stops were unfortunately no different. “Although Black individuals comprise approximately 19% of the Minneapolis population, MPD’s data shows that from January 1, 2017, to May 24, 2020, 78%—or over 6,500—of all searches conducted by MPD officers were searches of Black individuals or their vehicles during officer-initiated traffic stops.” Black people in Minneapolis are at six times greater risk of being treated with force during traffic stops than their white neighbors, according to the report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minneapolis Police Department has not replied to our request for comment.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Illegal surveillance</h3>



<p>The report also describes the department’s use of secret social media accounts to monitor Black people: “MPD officers used covert, or fake, social media accounts to surveil and engage Black individuals, Black organizations, and elected officials unrelated to criminal activity, without a public safety objective.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Online, officers used covert accounts to follow, comment in, and message groups like the NAACP and the Urban League while posing as like-minded individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“In one case, an MPD officer used an MPD covert account to pose as a Black community member to send a message to a local branch of the NAACP criticizing the group. In another case, an MPD officer posed as a community member and RSVP’d to attend the birthday party of a prominent Black civil rights lawyer and activist,” the report says.</p>



<p>Similarly, <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/supertopic/secret-police-surveillance-investigation-minnesota/">MIT Technology Review’s reporting</a> shows that officers kept at least three watch lists of people present at and around protests related to race and policing. Nine state and local policing groups were part of a multi-agency response program called Operation Safety Net, which worked in concert with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the US Department of Homeland Security to acquire surveillance tools, compile data sets, and increase communication sharing during the racial justice protests in the state. The program <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/03/17/1047413/secret-police-surveillance-protesters-george-floyd-operation-safety-net/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/03/17/1047413/secret-police-surveillance-protesters-george-floyd-operation-safety-net/">continued long past its publicly announced demobilization</a>.</p>



<p>Though our investigation did not probe the extent of racial bias, it showed that local, state, and federal law enforcement agencies learned to work in concert to render anonymous protesting—a core tenet of free-speech protection under the First Amendment of the US Constitution—all but impossible.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong><em><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/supertopic/secret-police-surveillance-investigation-minnesota/">The Secret Police: An MIT Technology Review investigation</a></em></strong></h3>



<p><em>This story is part of a series that offers an unprecedented look at the way federal and local law enforcement employed advanced technology tools to create a total surveillance system in the streets of Minneapolis, and what it means for the future of policing.</em>&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/supertopic/secret-police-surveillance-investigation-minnesota/">You can find the full series here</a></em>.</p>



<h3>Lack of accountability</h3>



<p>Not only were these covert social media accounts used to track individuals not suspected of a crime, but the MPD officers behind the accounts sought to influence the democratic process: “MPD officers used MPD’s covert accounts to send private messages criticizing elected officials, while posing as community members.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Included in these sham conversations were a Minneapolis city council member and a state elected official. The report states, “Police officers using MPD’s covert social media to contact and criticize elected officials is an inappropriate use of official City resources. This inappropriate covert activity can also undermine the democratic process because false communications can distort elected officials’ perspectives and understanding of positions taken by community members.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, “MPD’s oversight of officers’ covert social media is insufficient and ineffective.” The MPD does not have a complete and accurate list of all the social media accounts used in a covert manner, according to the report: the department’s accounting of these activities “did not include at least two dozen additional covert accounts.” The MPD also lacks policies “to ensure that covert accounts are being used for legitimate investigative purposes.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>When members of the public sought remedy for perceived abuses and misconduct, they were met with a system in which “complaints are inadequately investigated and officers are not consistently held accountable for misconduct.” As an example, the report cites a troublingly long turnaround time for internal investigations: “Between January 2010 and May 2021, the average time that it took Office of Police Conduct Review and/or Internal Affairs to complete an investigation and for a Police Chief to issue a final disciplinary decision after a police misconduct complaint was filed was over 475 days, and the median time was over 420 days.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The US Department of Justice is currently investigating the City of Minneapolis and the MPD for possible violations of the Civil Rights Act.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong><em>To support MIT Technology Review&#8217;s journalism, please consider <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?utm_medium=onsite&amp;utm_source=story-cta&amp;utm_campaign=subscribe-BAU">becoming a subscriber</a></em></strong>.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051517</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Download: The Money Issue, and the problems with open sourcing Twitter’s algorithms</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051508/download-money-issue-crypto-dollar-problems-open-sourcing-twitters-algorithms-elon-musk/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rhiannon Williams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051508</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[This is today&#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.  Introducing: The Money Issue Money is weird now. Whether it’s a biometric-based universal cryptocurrency meant to underpin Web3, cities built by Bitcoin, digital currencies that are replacing cash, or the way iBuying is&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>This is today&#8217;s edition of <a href="https://forms.technologyreview.com/newsletters/briefing-the-download/?_ga=2.179569122.736533416.1649661040-405833893.1649413289">The Download</a></em>,<em> our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&#8217;s going on in the world of technology.</em></p>



<div class="wp-container-17 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong> Introducing: The Money Issue</strong></h2>



<p>Money is weird now.</p>



<p>Whether it’s a biometric-based universal cryptocurrency meant to underpin Web3, cities built by Bitcoin, digital currencies that are replacing cash, or the way iBuying is transforming the housing market, technology is fundamentally changing the ways we buy, spend, and save money. Even the way we gamble.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/magazines/the-money-issue/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">latest print issue of MIT Technology Review</a> delves deep into this weird new world of money. Here’s a selection of some of the new stories in the edition, guaranteed to get you thinking about what money means to you.</p>



<ul><li>Meet the MIT researcher <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1048930/digital-currency-neha-narula/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">helping senators to understand cryptocurrencies</a>.<br></li><li>The fascinating story of <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1049573/mazacoin-indigenous-digital-currency/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">MazaCoin</a>, an indigenous digital currency, inspired by the creator’s grandma.<br></li><li>Money is on the brink of <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/12/1049307/money-is-about-to-enter-a-new-era-of-competition/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">entering completely uncharted territory</a>, writes Eswar Prasad.<br></li><li>How the rapid adoption of mobile money also enabled <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/14/1049239/kenya-sports-betting-mobile-money/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">gambling addictions in Kenya</a>.<br></li><li>Lana Swartz examines what needs to change to <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/15/1049604/cash-digital-payments-money/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">make cash work for us in the internet era</a>.</li></ul>



<p>We hope you enjoy it, and that it reveals something new to you about the present that helps you better understand and prepare for the future.<br><br><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/magazines/the-money-issue/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full magazine</a>, and if you haven’t already, you can <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">subscribe</a> to MIT Technology Review for as little as $80 a year.&nbsp;</p>



<h2><strong>The problems with Elon Musk’s plan to open source the Twitter algorithm</strong></h2>



<p>Just hours after Twitter announced it was accepting Elon Musk’s buyout offer, the SpaceX CEO made his plans for the social network clear. In a press release, Musk outlined the sweeping changes he intended to make, including opening up its algorithms, which determine what users see in their feed.</p>



<p>Musk’s ambition to open-source Twitter’s algorithms is driven by his longstanding concern about potential political censorship on the platform, but it’s unlikely that doing so will have the effect he desires. Instead, it may bring a number of unexpected problems in its wake, experts warn. <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051472/the-problems-with-elon-musks-plan-to-open-source-the-twitter-algorithm/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">Read the full story</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>—Chris Stokel-Walker</p>



<div class="wp-container-14 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>Quote of the day</strong></h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p>“Control your soul&#8217;s desire for freedom. Do not open the window or sing.&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<p>—A surveillance drone warns angry Shanghai residents not to shout from their windows, as the city’s extensive lockdown continues, reports <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/04/26/opinions/china-zero-covid-omicron-censorship-mahoney/index.html">CNN</a>.</p>
</div></div>



<div class="wp-container-16 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="wp-container-15 wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<h2><strong>The must-reads</strong></h2>



<p><em>I’ve combed the internet to find you today’s most fun/important/scary/fascinating stories about technology.</em></p>



<p><strong>1 Nearly 60% of Americans have had covid at least once<br></strong>But that doesn’t mean it can’t be contracted again (and again.) (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-26/more-than-half-of-americans-show-signs-of-prior-covid-infection?sref=E9Urfma4">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+ <em>Vaccines for under-fives have been delayed by incomplete data</em>. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/04/26/world/mandates-cases-vaccine-covid-19">NYT</a> $)<br>+ <em>Millions of Beijing residents are being tested to try and prevent a local outbreak snowballing. </em>(<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/beijing-presses-with-mass-covid-testing-locked-down-shanghai-seethes-2022-04-27/">Reuters</a>)</p>



<p><strong>2 Congress is weighing up new privacy laws<br></strong>Unsurprisingly, Big Tech is attempting to control the narrative. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/online-privacy-protections-gain-traction-with-lawmakers-tech-industry-11650978000">WSJ</a> $)<br>+ <em>The European Union has warned Elon Musk that Twitter still has to follow its rules</em>. (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/22f66209-f5b2-4476-8cdb-de4befffebe5">FT</a> $)<br>+ <em>The progress Twitter has made on moderation could be squandered. </em>(<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/elon-musk-fear-twitters-moderation-progress-unravel-rcna25932">NBC</a>)</p>



<p><strong>3 Tech giants were duped into handing over data used to sexually extort minors</strong><br>By imitating police agencies and forging legal requests. (<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-26/tech-giants-duped-by-forged-requests-in-sexual-extortion-scheme">Bloomberg</a> $)<br>+<em> Inside police departments’ cozy relationships with surveillance tech firms.</em> (<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93b4b5/when-police-do-marketing-for-surveillance-tech-companiess">Motherboard</a>)<br>+ <em>Computer monitoring software is making workers’ lives a misery.</em> (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/apr/27/remote-work-software-home-surveillance-computer-monitoring-pandemic">The Guardian</a>)</p>



<p><strong>4 Even Facebook doesn’t know what it’s doing with your data</strong><br>And that lack of control makes it very difficult to change its data-sharing policies. (<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/akvmke/facebook-doesnt-know-what-it-does-with-your-data-or-where-it-goes">Motherboard</a>)</p>



<p><strong>5 Could changing how we perceive time make everything less awful? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f552.png" alt="🕒" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong><strong><br></strong>For a brighter political future, it could be worth a try. (<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/time-politics-democracy-elections/">Wired</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>6 Internet blackouts are now the weapon of choice for authoritarian regimes</strong><strong><br></strong>They’ve gone from last to first resort.&nbsp; (<a href="https://restofworld.org/2022/blackouts/">Rest of World</a>)<br>+ <em>But the public is getting quicker and smarter at circumventing censors. </em>(<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/24/1051073/wechat-shanghai-lockdown-protest-video-the-voice-of-april/?truid=*%7CLINKID%7C*&amp;utm_source=the_download&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=the_download.unpaid.engagement&amp;utm_term=*%7CSUBCLASS%7C*&amp;utm_content=*%7CDATE:m-d-Y%7C*">TR</a>)</p>



<p><strong>7 The shine is coming off Netflix</strong><br>It’s getting more expensive just as the steady stream of quality new content dries up. (<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/04/netflix-subscription-competition-password-sharing/629682/">The Atlantic</a> $)<strong><br></strong>+ <em>Could video games provide it with a crucial new source of revenue?</em> (<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2022/04/22/netflix-video-games/">WP</a> $)<br>+ <em>Can Netflix weather the cost of living crisis?</em> (<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/bf3ec21b-06e6-421a-9cd2-80912c0beb8a">FT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>8 These days, even toddlers are potential NFT customers</strong><br>So they can practice becoming “tomorrow’s digital citizens,” apparently. (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/26/arts/nft-zigazoo-qai-qai.html">NYT</a> $)</p>



<p><strong>9 Virtual reality might help ease chronic pain <br></strong>But affordability remains the obvious obstacle to wider adoption.<strong> </strong>(<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/26/magazine/virtual-reality-chronic-pain.html">NYT</a> $)<br><br><strong>10 How iPhone autocorrect actually works <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="📱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br></strong>Hint: turning it off altogether is a humbling exercise in how we’ve forgotten to spell. (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/autocorrect-explained-why-your-iphone-adds-annoying-typos-while-fixing-others-11651051891?mod=hp_lead_pos9">WSJ</a> $)</p>
</div></div>



<h2><strong>We can still have nice things</strong></h2>



<p><em>A place for comfort, fun and distraction in these weird times. (Got any ideas? </em><a href="mailto:rhiannon.williams@technologyreview.com"><em>Drop me a line</em></a><em> or </em><a href="https://twitter.com/RhiannonJudithW"><em>tweet &#8217;em at me</em></a><em>.)</em>+ I really enjoyed this reminder of how different cultures <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZgvO--dGLjY">enjoy their tea</a>.<br>+ Very cool: music from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2022/apr/26/pokemon-goes-to-the-proms-2022-season-to-feature-first-video-game-music-concert">video games including Pokémon</a> will feature at this year’s BBC Proms classical music season in London.<br>+ Finally—an official guide on how to submit your <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-submit-emoji-idea/">great idea for an emoji</a>.<br>+ If returning to the office holds little allure, these <a href="https://www.wallpaper.com/art/nicolas-haeni-office-rabbit-photography-series">sweet little bunnies</a> could change your mind.<br>+ This informative look inside the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/25/dining/haribo-gummy-bear.html">weird and wonderful world of gummy candy</a> is making me hungry.<br>+ This <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/04/archaeologists-found-a-1500-year-old-sandal-frozen-in-norwegian-ice/">ancient shoe</a> uncovered in Norway is surprisingly fashionable.<br>+ Maybe Moby was right and we really are all made of stars—the building blocks of DNA have been <a href="https://www.space.com/meteorites-brought-dna-blocks-to-early-earth">found inside meteorites</a>.</p>
</div></div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051508</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problems with Elon Musk’s plan to open-source the Twitter algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1051472/the-problems-with-elon-musks-plan-to-open-source-the-twitter-algorithm/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Stokel-Walker]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1051472</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Just hours after Twitter announced it was accepting Elon Musk’s buyout offer, the SpaceX CEO made his plans for the social network clear. In a press release, Musk outlined the sweeping changes he intended to make, including opening up the algorithms that determine what users see in their feed. Musk’s ambition to open-source Twitter’s algorithms&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Just hours after Twitter announced it was accepting Elon Musk’s buyout offer, the SpaceX CEO made his plans for the social network clear. In <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/elon-musk-to-acquire-twitter-301532245.html">a press release</a>, Musk outlined the sweeping changes he intended to make, including opening up the algorithms that determine what users see in their feed.</p>



<p>Musk’s ambition to open-source Twitter’s algorithms is driven by his long-standing concern about potential political censorship on the platform, but it’s unlikely that doing so will have the effect he desires. Instead, it may bring a number of unexpected problems, experts warn.</p>



<p>Musk might have a strong aversion to authority, but his desire for algorithmic transparency happens to chime with the wishes of politicians around the world. The idea has been a cornerstone of multiple governments’ attempts to fight back against Big Tech in recent years. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong><em>To support MIT Technology Review&#8217;s journalism, please consider <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/subscribe?utm_medium=onsite&amp;utm_source=story-cta&amp;utm_campaign=subscribe-BAU">becoming a subscriber</a></em></strong>.</p></blockquote>



<p>For example, Melanie Dawes, chief executive of Ofcom, which regulates social media in the UK, <a href="https://www.ofcom.org.uk/news-centre/2021/time-for-strong-external-oversight-of-social-media-companies">has said</a> that social media platforms will have to explain how their code works. And the European Union’s recently passed Digital Services Act, <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_22_2545">agreed on April 23</a>, will likewise compel platforms to offer more transparency. In the US, Democratic senators introduced <a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/news/press-releases/wyden-booker-and-clarke-introduce-algorithmic-accountability-act-of-2022-to-require-new-transparency-and-accountability-for-automated-decision-systems#:~:text=Y.%2C%20today%20introduced%20the%20Algorithmic,every%20aspect%20of%20Americans'%20lives.">proposals for an Algorithmic Accountability Act</a> in February 2022. Their goal is to bring new transparency and oversight of the algorithms that govern our timelines and news feeds, and much else besides. </p>



<p>Allowing Twitter’s algorithm to be visible to others, and adaptable by competitors, theoretically means someone could just copy Twitter’s source code and release a rebranded version. Large parts of the internet run on open-source software—<a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/chrisstokelwalker/the-internet-is-being-protected-by-two-guys-named-st">most famously OpenSSL</a>, a security toolkit used by large parts of the web, which in 2014 suffered a major security breach.</p>



<p>There are even examples of open-source social networks already. <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon, a microblogging platform that was set up after concerns about the dominant position of Twitter,</a> allows users to inspect its code, which is <a href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon">posted on the software repository GitHub</a>.</p>



<p>But seeing the code behind an algorithm doesn’t necessarily tell you how it works, and it certainly doesn’t give the average person much insight into the business structures and processes that go into its creation.</p>



<p>“It’s a bit like trying to understand ancient creatures with genetic material alone,” says Jonathan Gray, a senior lecturer in critical infrastructure studies at King’s College London. “It tells us more than nothing, but it would be a stretch to say we know about how they live.”</p>



<p>There’s also not one single algorithm that controls Twitter. “Some of them will determine what people see on their timelines in terms of trends, or content, or suggested follows,” says Catherine Flick, who researches computing and social responsibility at De Montfort University in the UK. The algorithms people will primarily be interested in are the ones controlling what content appears in users’ timelines, but even that won’t be hugely useful without the training data.</p>



<p>“Most of the time when people talk about algorithmic accountability these days, we recognize that the algorithms themselves aren’t necessarily what we want to see—what we really want is information about how they were developed,” says Jennifer Cobbe, a postdoctoral research associate at the University of Cambridge. That’s in large part because of concerns that AI algorithms can <a href="https://www.aclu.org/news/privacy-technology/how-artificial-intelligence-can-deepen-racial-and-economic-inequities">perpetuate the human biases</a> in data used to train them. Who develops algorithms, and <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/03/11/1020600/facebook-responsible-ai-misinformation/">what data they use</a>, can make a meaningful difference to the results they spit out.</p>



<p>For Cobbe, the risks outweigh the potential benefits. The computer code doesn’t give us any insight into how algorithms were trained or tested, what factors or considerations went into them, or what sorts of things were prioritized in the process, so open-sourcing it may not make a meaningful difference to transparency at Twitter. Meanwhile, it could introduce some significant security risks.</p>



<p>Companies often publish impact assessments that probe and test their data protection systems to highlight weaknesses and flaws. When they’re discovered, they get fixed, but data is often redacted to prevent security risks. Open-sourcing Twitter’s algorithms would make the entire code base of the website accessible to all, potentially allowing bad actors to pore over the software and find vulnerabilities to exploit.</p>



<p>“I don’t believe for a moment that Elon Musk is looking at open-sourcing all the infrastructure and security side of Twitter,” says Eerke Boiten, a professor of cybersecurity at De Montfort University.</p>





<p>Open-sourcing Twitter’s algorithms could create yet another problem: it could help bad actors get better at gaming the system, which could make one of Musk’s other stated goals, “defeating all spam bots,” even harder.</p>



<p>“That’s not necessarily because individuals would be able to understand the intricacies of how the code of the algorithm works. But they’d be able to discern roughly how Twitter recommends posts on users’ timelines,” says Boiten. While Twitter users aren’t exactly in the dark about how the platform operates now, open-sourcing its algorithms could provide bad actors with new ammunition, he says. </p>



<p>There are other, more troubling unintended consequences. One of the key worries is that inevitable squabbles that will ensue as people try, amateurishly, to parse the algorithm. That could lead to yet more poisonous and fruitless debates.  </p>



<p>“I worry that it’ll be made into a mountain where it’s really just a molehill,” says Flick. “There’s a lot of hype about the mysterious algorithm, but in reality it’s likely that bad behavior has social consequences that are reflected in the weightings of the tweets of those people.” </p>



<p>Open-sourcing the algorithm won’t fix any issues with bias, and taking action to fix biases that are raised will undoubtedly be viewed through a political, rather than technological, lens—at a time when we’re already massively politically polarized. </p>



<p>For example, a <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2025334119">recent paper</a> by Twitter researchers, highlighting how the algorithms more readily promote right-wing content than left-wing content, has already become a lightning rod. “It’s going to be a mess,” says Flick. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1051472</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning the nation’s capital into the next Kendall Square</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/27/1048572/turning-the-nations-capital-into-the-next-kendall-square/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ken Shulman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.technologyreview.com/?p=1048572</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Washington, DC, is dominated by the federal government and tourism, but Jeff Jamawat, MCP ’19, SM ’19, thinks that’s no longer enough. “We want people to also recognize DC as a tech hub,” says Jamawat, associate director of economic development and innovation at the Golden Triangle Business Improvement District. The nonprofit is launching an innovation&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Washington, DC, is dominated by the federal government and tourism, but Jeff Jamawat, MCP ’19, SM ’19, thinks that’s no longer enough. “We want people to also recognize DC as a tech hub,” says Jamawat, associate director of economic development and innovation at the Golden Triangle Business Improvement District. The nonprofit is launching an innovation district centered along Pennsylvania Avenue near the White House and George Washington University. “This would diversify the city’s workforce with tech talent and help DC remain competitive,” he says.</p>



<p>Born in Los Angeles, Jamawat grew up in Bangkok, Thailand. “Some kids liked sports or music. For me it has always been about the buildings,” he says. “The space between them, and how they touch the sky.”</p>



<p>Following college, Jamawat moved to DC for a fellowship with the US Environmental Protection Agency’s smart growth program. He then took a job with the Mayors’ Institute on City Design at the US Conference of Mayors. “It was a privilege to work with mayors from interior Alaska to coastal Florida, on projects ranging from relocating a train station to transforming a waterfront,” says Jamawat.</p>



<p>Four years into that job, Jamawat decided he needed skills that could only be found at MIT. “I recognized how the outcomes of many urban design projects were tied to real estate development,” he says. “But in most schools, the real estate program is taught at the business or public policy school. I wanted a program where real estate was part of the built environment and physical planning with the design DNA.” En route to dual master’s degrees in real estate development and city planning, he wrote a thesis exploring the hypothetical adaptive-reuse scenario for Amazon’s corporate headquarters in downtown Seattle.</p>



<p>Amazon continues to play a role in Jamawat’s current job; the company’s second US campus lies just across the river from DC, providing a friendly competition for the talent he’d like the innovation district to attract.</p>



<p>“We’re framing this project as a third leg of the DC economy,” he says. “All the elements to create another Kendall Square are here: talent pool, transit access, partnerships with the city, and a committed university partner. The physical infrastructure already exists; we just need to adapt them for tech-related uses. We’re only at the beginning of this process, and I’m a small piece in a much larger puzzle. This job has just about everything I was hoping to find after MIT.”&nbsp;</p>


]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1048572</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>