<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 09:13:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>Explained: What is Web3.0 and Why Does it Matter?</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/explained-what-is-web3-0-and-why-does-it-matter/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/explained-what-is-web3-0-and-why-does-it-matter/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 09:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Vijay Yadav]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Vijay Yadav</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Web3.0]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5197</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Web-3.0-2-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The Internet, as we all know it, is approaching a crossroads. The issues it&#8217;s currently facing are associated with the centralized model of computing (top-down, data-driven, and not necessarily human-centric), during which a finite number of private entities control the information. In this blog, we have explained how Web 3.0 &#8211; a much better technology, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/explained-what-is-web3-0-and-why-does-it-matter/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Explained: What is Web3.0 and Why Does it Matter?</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">3</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>The Internet, as we all know it, is approaching a crossroads. The issues it&#8217;s currently facing are associated with the centralized model of computing (top-down, data-driven, and not necessarily human-centric), during which a finite number of private entities control the information.</p>
<p>In this blog, we have explained how Web 3.0 &#8211; a much better technology, will replace the Internet in the future. Instead of using something like the Internet with its centralized architecture, the world will move towards a new technology based on decentralization, trust-less &amp; permission-less, and Ubiquitous connectivity.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Decentralization:</strong> Decentralization shifts control (authority and responsibility) from one leading group to several smaller ones.</li>
<li><strong>Trust-less:</strong> In a Trust-less network, participants can interact publicly or privately without a trusted third party.</li>
<li><strong>Permissionless:</strong> People and companies can exchange money and goods without any authorization from a governing body.</li>
<li><strong>Ubiquitous Connectivity:</strong> Unhackable secure connection from anywhere to anywhere.</li>
</ul>
<h3>The Evolution of the Web<img class="aligncenter wp-image-5198" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/The-Evolution-of-the-Web-894x1024.png" alt="Web3.0" width="500" height="573" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/The-Evolution-of-the-Web-894x1024.png 894w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/The-Evolution-of-the-Web-262x300.png 262w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/The-Evolution-of-the-Web-768x880.png 768w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/The-Evolution-of-the-Web.png 964w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Web 1.0 (roughly 1990-2005):</strong> Refers to the first version of the internet, and it comprised all text-based sites and the first browsers, web crawlers, and search engines that architect the net.</li>
<li><strong>Web 2.0 (roughly 2005-present day):</strong> The second version of the internet is Social Web or read-write web, which facilitates interaction between web users and sites and allows users to communicate with other users.</li>
<li><strong>Web 3.0 the &#8220;Semantic Web&#8221;(imminent):</strong> The third version is more of a vision than a structure of changes. In this version of the internet, users are creators, and information flows in more than one direction. With the power of artificial intelligence and machine learning, computers will be able to interpret and process complex information on the web.</li>
</ul>
<p>By leveraging the power of machine learning, Blockchains, and other decentralized technologies, Web 3.0 aims to achieve open and trust-less networks where personal data is protected and people retain control over their information. Web 3.0 will also allow users to have interoperability across all systems seamlessly and enhance efficiency in many industries.</p>
<h3>Technologies to be used for Web3.0</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Semantic Web:</strong> The goal of the Semantic Web is to make Internet data machine-readable so that is computers will be able to read and understand the content on the web.</li>
<li><strong>dApps:</strong> A decentralized application(dApps) is an application that can operate autonomously, typically through the use of smart contracts, that runs on decentralized computing and blockchain systems. Decentralized applications have been popularized by distributed ledger technologies (DLT), such as the Ethereum blockchain, on which DApps are built.</li>
<li><strong>Permissionless Blockchains:</strong> Permission-less blockchains, also known as trust-less or public blockchains, are open networks that anybody can join. There are no barriers to entry, and people are free to participate in the network’s consensus process. Since there aren’t any established authorities, the blockchain is trust-less – it allows strangers to transact with each other honestly and openly while benefiting from cryptographic accountability.</li>
<li><strong>Artificial Intelligence:</strong> Algorithms are more powerful than ever, enabling various technologies and services that can make our lives more efficient. For example, decentralized blockchain data structures now enable us to get instant access to a wealth of data that we could not rely on in the past because there was too much to keep track of. The potential applications of this technology extend far beyond targeted advertising into areas such as pharmaceutical development, climate modeling, and many more.</li>
<li><strong>AR &amp; VR (Metaverse):</strong> AR and VR are the cornerstones for metaverse projects. Augmented reality systems depend on virtual and real environments, real-time interaction, and pinpoint accurate 3D visualizations. On the other hand, Virtual reality is an entirely simulated experience in a virtual world. It is like a daydream and feels natural and makes the user feel like they are really in the skin of their chosen character instead of themselves. The combination of AR and VR also referred to as Extended Reality (XR) that we would experience in the metaverse.</li>
<li><strong>NFTs:</strong> Non-fungible tokens (NFTs) give users the ability to own virtual objects stored on the Ethereum network. Often NFTs will serve as collectibles for users and have a monetary value attached. This means that, like art, pictures, or digital music files, people are also buying digital copies because of their rarity.</li>
<li><strong>Interoperability:</strong> Interoperability is a characteristic of a product or system to work with other products or systems, enabling different agents, services, and applications to exchange information, data, and knowledge meaningful on the web.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>This matters because:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>We can send more information faster to more people, companies, and machines. You can also share information with more privacy and security.</li>
<li>We can have the power to own our data and digital footprint by harnessing provable digital scarcity techniques, tokenizing it, and adding a layer of valuable information about ourselves on top.</li>
<li>When investing in a new entrepreneurial project, one of the most common things a person will deal with is platform risk.</li>
<li>Societies can become more profitable by cutting out the middleman and generating revenue directly from their customer base.</li>
<li>An organization&#8217;s value essentially can be increased with the new peer-to-peer communication system and adjustable governance ties between participants engaged in the collaborative business environment.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/explained-what-is-web3-0-and-why-does-it-matter/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Explained: What is Web3.0 and Why Does it Matter?</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/explained-what-is-web3-0-and-why-does-it-matter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring4Shell: Zero-Day vulnerability CVE-2022-22965 in Spring Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/spring4shell-0-day-vulnerability-cve-2022-22965-in-spring-framework/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/spring4shell-0-day-vulnerability-cve-2022-22965-in-spring-framework/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 12:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shiv Mohan]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Shiv Mohan</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#RCE]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Spring4Shell]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#SpringShell]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[JAVA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Vulnerability]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ZeroDay]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5201</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Spring4shell-SQ-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>A Zero-day Remote Code Execution Vulnerability with critical severity has been identified as CVE-2022-22965 aka Spring4Shell or SpringShell in Spring Framework versions 5.3.0 to 5.3.17, 5.2.0 to 5.2.19 &#38; older. The Spring Framework is an open-source, popular, feature-rich application framework used for building modern &#38; enterprise Java web applications. Publicly available exploits in this widely [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/spring4shell-0-day-vulnerability-cve-2022-22965-in-spring-framework/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Spring4Shell: Zero-Day vulnerability CVE-2022-22965 in Spring Framework</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">2</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>A Zero-day Remote Code Execution Vulnerability with critical severity has been identified as CVE-2022-22965 aka Spring4Shell or SpringShell in Spring Framework versions 5.3.0 to 5.3.17, 5.2.0 to 5.2.19 &amp; older.</p>
<p>The Spring Framework is an open-source, popular, feature-rich application framework used for building modern &amp; enterprise Java web applications. Publicly available exploits in this widely used framework make it very dangerous.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Why is CVE-2022-22965 &#8220;Spring4Shell&#8221; vulnerability so dangerous? </strong></p>
<p>Invulnerable Spring Framework, SpringMVC, or Spring WebFlux applications running on JDK 9 or higher are prone to remote code execution via Data Binding. The vulnerability is due to the improper handling of the Java class properties, which leverages class injection. At the same time, the HTTP input binding and a specially crafted HTTP request could lead to a remote code execution attack and compromise the spring Java application without requiring authentication.</p>
<p>According to vendor advisory, &#8220;If the application is deployed as a Spring Boot executable jar, i.e., the default, it is not vulnerable to the exploit. However, the nature of the vulnerability is more general, and there may be other ways to exploit it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Affected Software and Versions</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>JDK 9 or higher</li>
<li>Apache Tomcat as the Servlet container</li>
<li>Packaged as a traditional WAR (in contrast to a Spring Boot executable jar)</li>
<li>Spring-webmvc or Spring-webflux dependency</li>
<li>Spring Framework versions 5.3.0 to 5.3.17, 5.2.0 to 5.2.19, and older versions</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Mitigation of &#8220;Spring4Shell&#8221;</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Immediately update to Spring Framework 5.3.18 and 5.2.20 or higher version.</li>
<li>Please refer to our <a href="https://spring.io/blog/2022/03/31/spring-framework-rce-early-announcement" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Vendor Advisory</a>.</li>
<li>Update the Network security solutions and endpoints with the latest definitions.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A <strong>CVE-2022-22963, a Remote code execution vulnerability</strong>, is also identified in Spring Cloud Function versions 3.1.6, 3.2.2, and older routing functionality. Hackers can exploit this by sending crafted SpEL routing expressions that could result in remote code execution. The affected versions should upgrade to 3.1.7 and 3.2.3.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Seqrite coverage for &#8220;Spring4Shell.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>We have released IPS rules to identify and block remote attacks exploiting Spring4Shell &amp; other vulnerabilities. We&#8217;ll continue monitoring the developments around this threat and update our detections. We advise our customers to patch their systems on time and keep the anti-virus software updated with the latest VDB updates.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/spring4shell-0-day-vulnerability-cve-2022-22965-in-spring-framework/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Spring4Shell: Zero-Day vulnerability CVE-2022-22965 in Spring Framework</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/spring4shell-0-day-vulnerability-cve-2022-22965-in-spring-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metaverse and the Cybersecurity: Evolving Security into the Latest Digital Universe</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/metaverse-and-the-cybersecurity-evolving-security-into-the-latest-digital-universe/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/metaverse-and-the-cybersecurity-evolving-security-into-the-latest-digital-universe/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 04:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[ganesh lakariya]]></dc:creator>
      <author>ganesh lakariya</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#AR]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#DataScience]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#DigitalMetaverse]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Metaverse]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Privacy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#VR]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5191</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Metaverse-3-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We are seeing the beginning of a space-age of digital exploration. Even though the Metaverse may be a buzz nowadays, it is an idea that is earning huge attention all over the globe. Supposing widespread adoption will change how humans powerfully interact with each other. However, this latest technology, in which individuals can connect online [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/metaverse-and-the-cybersecurity-evolving-security-into-the-latest-digital-universe/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Metaverse and the Cybersecurity: Evolving Security into the Latest Digital Universe</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">3</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>We are seeing the beginning of a space-age of digital exploration. Even though the Metaverse may be a buzz nowadays, it is an idea that is earning huge attention all over the globe. Supposing widespread adoption will change how humans powerfully interact with each other. However, this latest technology, in which individuals can connect online in enhanced ways, can open up doors for cybercriminals.</p>
<p>In this blog, we will discuss the security challenges in the Metaverse and how education and prevention can safeguard users from hackers and secure privacy and identity.</p>
<p><strong><b> </b></strong><strong><b>What is the Metaverse?</b></strong></p>
<p><img class="wp-image-5192 aligncenter" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Picture1-300x150.png" alt="" width="406" height="203" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Picture1-300x150.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Picture1-768x385.png 768w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Picture1.png 796w" sizes="(max-width: 406px) 100vw, 406px" /></p>
<p>A Metaverse is a network of 4 Dimension virtual globes focused on social media friends. In science fiction, it is often portrayed as a hypothetical iteration of the internet as a single, virtual world that is stimulated by the use of virtual and augmented reality headsets.</p>
<p>The term “Metaverse” was coined by science fiction author Neal Stephenson. Facebook gives Metaverse a more popular definition. Lately, Facebook changed the name of its internationally identified company to Meta.</p>
<p>The main reason behind this decision was to reflect their current focus on becoming a prime candidate in the Metaverse.</p>
<p>Facebook plays a big part in connecting people on the internet, but the idea of Metaverse moves a long way beyond Facebook friends and group calls. Metaverse allows enterprises to create “digital twins” to utilize data and develop algorithms to control decisions driven by executives in real life.</p>
<p>The Metaverse is a digital world that blends virtual and augmented reality. This online world will be identical to the real world or established on creativity, or some combination of both with the help of digital avatars. Avatars and VR headsets give more in-depth glances of users’ real lives better than anything seen on social media.</p>
<p>The personal qualities of the Metaverse and the data it produces will provide excellent opportunities for cybercriminals.</p>
<p><strong><b>Cybersecurity Challenges in Metaverse</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Some of the cybersecurity challenges in Metaverse will be similar to what we are already familiar with on the internet. The persistent rise of cyber-attacks over the past year and during pandemics has displayed just how worthwhile it can be for cybercriminals to hack into an enterprise or an individual’s online accounts.</li>
<li>However, along with the standard phishing, spear-phishing, malware, and ransomware attacks we are familiar with, the Metaverse will probably bring completely new cybercrimes because of its infrastructure. There is immense usage of NFTs and cryptocurrencies in the Metaverse; it can be tempting targets for cybercriminals.</li>
<li>For example, cybercriminals hunt NFT stores closely to replicate famous NFT marketplaces and create fake NFT stores. These websites can look almost similar to the originals and can fool even an experienced buyer of NFT, spending large amounts of money on fake artwork worth nothing. In the Metaverse, with multiple layers of virtual reality hiding the true identity of the cybercriminal, it is very difficult or impossible for victims to get their money back.</li>
<li>Cybercriminals are collaborating to form cyber firms. They are transferring information, data, and infrastructure to establish power. Cybercriminals use press releases on the dark web to announce their partnerships with other cybercriminals.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><b>Challenges of securing the </b></strong><strong><b>M</b></strong><strong><b>etaverse</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Dependency on hardware to experience Metaverse is another challenge. The Metaverse relies upon external devices like virtual reality headsets that can be effortlessly hacked by cybercriminals if left unprotected.</li>
<li>Data captured via these devices will be used in the future can be sold on the dark web. Personal data can be easily used as blackmailing threats or helpful to perform social engineering techniques; with the help of social engineering techniques, cybercriminals can achieve a significant spear-phishing attack targeting particular individuals or companies.</li>
<li>Also, intellectual property can be harder to protect when people and companies are not only living lives in the real world but also the Metaverse.</li>
<li>Future Cybercriminals may figure out how to make their existence unnoticeable. They could quickly get into victims&#8217; systems and invisibly enter meetings and keep track of essential business exchanges. Government and intelligence agencies may dedicate considerable resources to figure this out.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><b>How to stay secure from Cybercriminals in the </b></strong><strong><b>M</b></strong><strong><b>etaverse?</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Currently, there is no one explanation for how to make the Metaverse a secure place. In the Metaverse, a certain level of anonymity will probably still exist that will help cybercriminals get away with behaviors such as phishing, spear-phishing, cyberstalking, and online harassment.</li>
<li>Security awareness training remains the best way to train people and enterprises how to stay secure on the internet and the Metaverse in the future. People should understand the risks in this new internet world so that the right cybersecurity resources should be deployed to protect individuals and organizations.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/metaverse-and-the-cybersecurity-evolving-security-into-the-latest-digital-universe/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Metaverse and the Cybersecurity: Evolving Security into the Latest Digital Universe</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/metaverse-and-the-cybersecurity-evolving-security-into-the-latest-digital-universe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advisory on Russia-Ukraine Conflict-Related Cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/advisory-on-russia-ukraine-conflict-related-cyberattacks/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/advisory-on-russia-ukraine-conflict-related-cyberattacks/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 10:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Seqrite</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#War]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5184</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Russia-Ukraine-Conflict-–-Increasing-the-Risks-of-Global-Cyberattacks-1-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We all are aware of the ongoing conflict between Russia and Ukraine. As the physical war takes place on the ground, it also gives rise to cyberattacks against Russia and Ukraine. We are seeing an increase in malicious cyber activities as the conflict has evolved over the weeks. This write-up covered most of the malicious [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/advisory-on-russia-ukraine-conflict-related-cyberattacks/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Advisory on Russia-Ukraine Conflict-Related Cyberattacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">2</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>We all are aware of the ongoing conflict between Russia and Ukraine. As the physical war takes place on the ground, it also gives rise to cyberattacks against Russia and Ukraine. We are seeing an increase in malicious cyber activities as the conflict has evolved over the weeks. This write-up covered most of the malicious attacks in the news related to the Russia-Ukraine cyberwar.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hermetic Wiper: </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This was first observed on 23rd Feb &amp; is targeted against Ukraine. HermeticWiper is named based on the certificate it contains Hermetica Digital Ltd. It abuses the legitimate driver of EaseUS for wiping the process by loading it as a service. It also disables crash dumps with the help of registry entry and volume shadow copy through service. It overwrites MBR, MFT, and files at several locations with random bytes. The infected machine will fail to boot due to its MBR being overwritten.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>WhisperGate: </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This is a destructive malware that was first observed on 13th Jan 2022 is targeted to Ukraine. It corrupts the disk by over-writing MBR code with 16-bit assembly code and a ransom note. In this case, the ransom note is just a tactic as there is no way for recovery. If overwriting of MBR fails, there is a 2nd stage involved which has a file corrupter. This malware overwrites specific extensions files under specific directories with a fixed number of 0xCC bytes by adding random extensions to the filename.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Isaac Wiper:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Yet another malware that is targeted against Ukraine. Isaac Wiper was first spotted on 24th Feb 2022. It identifies physical drives and wipes the first 0x10000 bytes of each disk. This malware also can identify logical drives and wipe every file on such drives with random bytes.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>RURansom: </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Despite its name, RURansom is a wiper and not a ransomware variant because of its irreversible destruction of encrypted files. It spreads like a worm by copying itself to all removable disks and mapped network drives. After spreading, it begins encryption of all file extensions except for “.bak” files, which are deleted. The files are encrypted with a randomly generated key with a length equal to base64. The encryption algorithm used by RURansom is AES-CBC.</p>
<p>The encryption keys used by RURansom are unique for each encrypted file and are not stored anywhere. Hence making the encryption irreversible and marking the malware as a wiper rather than a ransomware variant. Some malware variants check the IP address to avoid execution outside Russia.</p>
<h4><strong>How does Seqrite protect its users?</strong></h4>
<p>Seqrite detects the above-listed malware with the following detection names:</p>
<ul>
<li>Whispergte.S26928601</li>
<li>Whispergte.S26928613</li>
<li>WhisperGateCiR</li>
<li>HrmetcWipr.S26876287</li>
<li>HermeticWiperCiR</li>
<li>Hermeticwiper</li>
<li>Win32CiR</li>
<li>RURansom</li>
<li>MSIL</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong> </strong><strong>Conclusion</strong></h4>
<p>With the Russia-Ukraine conflicts continuing, the malware authors are using new tools &amp; tricks to lure victims. The best defence against these evolving cyberattacks is to stay vigilant &amp; practice safe cyber hygiene.</p>
<p>Keep your Seqrite EPS products updated with the latest virus definitions. We at Seqrite are continuously monitoring all the developments and will update our detections on a timely basis. As of now, we already have protection against all the reported malware.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/advisory-on-russia-ukraine-conflict-related-cyberattacks/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Advisory on Russia-Ukraine Conflict-Related Cyberattacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/advisory-on-russia-ukraine-conflict-related-cyberattacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seqrite EPS Recognized as AV-Test ‘Top Product’ yet again!</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-recognized-as-av-test-top-product-yet-again/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-recognized-as-av-test-top-product-yet-again/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 13:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Seqrite</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Endpoint Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Endpoint Security Cloud]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Enterprise Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#EnterpriseSecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Endpoint]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[EPS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5148</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Seqrite_AV_Test_Certified_Blog_Sept_Oct21-230x168.png</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We Did It Again Seqrite EPS 7.6 has been recognized by the prestigious AV-Test Institute in Germany as a &#8216;Top Product&#8217; of endpoint and data protection solutions for the second time in a row. AV-Test Institute is an independent testing institute located in Magdeburg, Germany.  With Seqrite Endpoint Security, organizations can proactively protect endpoints while [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-recognized-as-av-test-top-product-yet-again/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite EPS Recognized as AV-Test ‘Top Product’ yet again!</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">5</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><h2><b>We Did It Again</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seqrite EPS 7.6 has been recognized by the prestigious AV-Test Institute in Germany as a &#8216;Top Product&#8217; of endpoint and data protection solutions for the second time in a row. AV-Test Institute is an independent testing institute located in Magdeburg, Germany. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">With Seqrite Endpoint Security, organizations can proactively protect endpoints while maintaining high productivity and output. Seqrite went through several tests before being recognized by </span><a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/antivirus/business-windows-client/windows-10/october-2021/seqrite-endpoint-security-18.00-212519/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">AV-Test</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as the best endpoint security provider. </span></p>
<h2><b>Our Path to Excellence</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Av-Test Institute conducted a series of tests before naming us the best endpoint security service provider. Several factors were evaluated, including &#8211; </span><b>Protection, Performance, and Usability.</b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Protection</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under this parameter, Seqrite has to demonstrate:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The effectiveness of our enterprise security services to handle the real-world malware problem and offer protection against 0-day malware attacks.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ability to detect the most prevalent malware discovered in the past four weeks</span></li>
</ol>
<p><b>How Does It Signify To Your Organization?</b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, Seqrite proved it is safe to identify any malware, Trojan horses, attacks and provide complete protection. AV-Test results confirm that the software successfully blocks all dangerous access attempts and covers every possible security function. So when you install Seqrite, you will never be at risk, as it will:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Block access to the URL </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Identify and block any identified exploit on the website</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Block malicious components from being downloaded</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Block the usage of malicious components </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Performance</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under this parameter, Seqrite EPS was tested to identify how it would affect your system&#8217;s performance and speed. Here, we scored a perfect six on a scale of 6.</span> <b>How Does This Affect Your Organization?</b></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Installation of Seqrite won&#8217;t affect the speed, performance, or other operations of your computer, making the process quick and safe at the same time.  </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your team&#8217;s day-to-day performance won&#8217;t affect as they need not worry about slowing down the actions like:</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Launching popular websites and standard software programs</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Downloading and launching frequently-used programs</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data storage and copying </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Usability</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This refers to how well Seqrite EPS will affect the system&#8217;s effectiveness in determining any threat or malware. Under this category, Seqrite EPS earned a perfect 6 out of 6.</span> <b>How Does It Impact Your Organization?</b></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our system gives you no false warnings and is proven to be consistently accurate. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">During a system scan, the software will not offer any false detection of legitimate software as malware. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No false blocking of any actions during the installation and use of legitimate software</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what are these challenges that you might face in terms of endpoint security? And how Seqrite will help resolve the issue. Read to the end and find out more:</span></p>
<h2><b>How Does Our Recognition Matter To You As A Company? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer is simple &#8211; by overcoming the most prominent Endpoint Security challenges, your company will likely face.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Seqrite is the answer to all the latest endpoint security problems, and we, as a dependable partner, help you secure your network&#8217;s endpoints. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Seqrite has also introduced </span><b>Seqrite HawkkEye, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">a holistic Centralized Security Management engine, to address real-world security problems and data-driven decision-making. With this, you can manage all your point products in one cloud-based console and streamline alerts! </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">It further powers other products, including HawkkHunt for extended detection and response, HawkkProtect for ZTUA, and HawkkScan for data privacy. </span></p>
<h2><b>Seqrite Endpoint Security Solutions Addresses The Following Challenges:</b></h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Malvertising</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Often called malware ads, these ads appear legitimate but are malicious. Fraudulent websites and social platforms may become involved before they are removed. Modern malware does not require the user to interact with it. Through pre-click capabilities, malicious software can be embedded into web pages and run automatically without the user&#8217;s interaction. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Our software is proven to identify all such malware attacks. </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Email Phishing Attacks and Attachments </b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hackers use malicious emails and programs to phish for information. Scammers trick users into providing personal information or downloading malware by sending emails from trusted entities. Using the information or malware, hackers gain access to the victim&#8217;s computer and subsequently access the organization&#8217;s network. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Seqrite security solutions block any suspicious email and deliver it by constantly checking it for questionable elements.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Data loss and data breaches</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even worse is a data breach. When data is lost irretrievably, it cannot be recovered. This means that priceless corporate data can end up on the dark web or in the hands of competitors. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">With the Seqrite endpoint security solution, users cannot upload or create databases without authorization or leave crucial data on the network without permission. Regardless of its size, you can better keep track of all your data. </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Remote workers </b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data loss is undoubtedly possible with remote workers due to a lack of oversight. Hackers can easily intercept traffic and impersonate users using public and private Wi-Fi connections. Such connections lack the level of security provided by corporate Wi-Fi networks. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Virtual private networks (VPNs) should be part of modern solutions either as a capability or as part of partnerships to help address these endpoint security challenges in 2021. </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Mobile Devices/BYOD </b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile devices cannot be processed by legacy endpoint security, especially not by bring-your-own-devices policies. Mobile security must be embraced as an essential component of next-generation endpoint security if we want to resolve critical challenges in endpoint security. For this, you should consider the number of devices that connect to your network daily and concurrently before deciding on a solution. See if the answer in question can accommodate future growth in mobile devices and scale it as well. </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Outdated patches</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protection of your organization&#8217;s network is vital when more and more employees connect their devices to company networks. Keeping up with evolving threats online requires constant patches, one of the ills of modern life. But many companies still neglect to hit the update button. But you don&#8217;t make these mistakes and partner with Seqrite for continuous patch updates and protect your systems against malware attacks.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>Script and macro attack</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Macros and script attacks are the names for malware written in the macro language. Hackers generally place these viruses in a word or excel document, usually disguised as viruses. These attachments appear simple, and few people would suspect anything was amiss. However, a script attack results from the infection of a site or application with a virus. Users who visit such a site or app send malicious commands without their knowledge.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">
<h3><b>DDoS</b></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Distributed Denial of Service attack involves flooding a website, server, or network with an overwhelming amount of incoming traffic. Compromise devices are continuously accessed by malware, resulting in the disruption of regular traffic. According to one research, in 2021, the number of DDoS attacks spiked year-over-year, with attacks coming in every minute. A majority of last year&#8217;s attacks targeted enterprise systems with customer-facing functions.</span></p>
<h2><b>How does Seqrite Protect You From These Challenges? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With changes in the workplace and evolving security threats, it is more challenging to ensure endpoint security than ever.</span> <b>With Seqrite</b></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your data is secured each day.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of your systems are protected from unforeseen attacks</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your business data pipelines have maximum protection against external malware attacks, ransomware, or a macro virus </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can stay stress-free even when more employees are working from home </span></li>
</ol>
<p><b>Why Seqrite EPS matters </b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">We provide such excellent service because we believe it only takes one threat to bring down the whole business. Your business works effectively in this high-stakes environment with us, and your essential data is organized and protected.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Accept nothing less than best; opt for Seqrite EPS with AV-Test recognition today.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-recognized-as-av-test-top-product-yet-again/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite EPS Recognized as AV-Test ‘Top Product’ yet again!</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-recognized-as-av-test-top-product-yet-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seqrite EPS accredited with “Advanced Approved Endpoint Protection” for protection against complex ransomware attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-accredited-with-advanced-approved-endpoint-protection-for-protection-against-complex-ransomware-attacks/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-accredited-with-advanced-approved-endpoint-protection-for-protection-against-complex-ransomware-attacks/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 12:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Seqrite</author>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#advanced]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#certificate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#threat]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5142</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Advanced-Approved-Endpoint-Protection_blog-image-230x168.png</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Enterprises are no longer safe from dangerous and expensive ransomware attacks in modern times. It can enter an organization through multiple vectors, such as email spam, phishing attacks, or malicious web downloads. For the highest level of protection, organizations are encouraged to deploy multiple layers of security on the endpoint, gateway, and mail servers. Ransomware [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-accredited-with-advanced-approved-endpoint-protection-for-protection-against-complex-ransomware-attacks/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite EPS accredited with &#8220;Advanced Approved Endpoint Protection&#8221; for protection against complex ransomware attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">2</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>Enterprises are no longer safe from dangerous and expensive ransomware attacks in modern times. It can enter an organization through multiple vectors, such as email spam, phishing attacks, or malicious web downloads. For the highest level of protection, organizations are encouraged to deploy multiple layers of security on the endpoint, gateway, and mail servers.</p>
<p>Ransomware attacks are growing more common and sophisticated. Advanced threat protection (ATP) solutions are designed to minimize these attacks&#8217; risks to an organization&#8217;s endpoints by preventing attacks before they occur.</p>
<p>We are proud to announce that Seqrite has received the &#8220;<a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/news/protection-solutions-vs-ransomware-in-the-advanced-threat-protection-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow" data-wpel-link="external">Advanced Approved Endpoint Protection</a>&#8221; 2021 Test Certification.</p>
<h3><strong>What is &#8220;Advanced Approved Endpoint Protection&#8221; </strong></h3>
<p>AV-Test, a leading international and independent service provider in IT security and anti-virus research, recently tested several security products for their protection capabilities against ransomware attacks.</p>
<p>The test cases in this test were guided by the MITRE framework and emulated attack patterns exhibited by various APT groups. The security products were evaluated based on how well they could protect target systems against ransomware delivered via these mechanisms.</p>
<p>All the test cases followed the fundamental MITRE matrix, i.e., started with ‘Initial Access’ or ‘Execution’ followed by ‘Defence Evasion’ then ‘Discovery’ and finally the ‘Collection’ phase. Some test cases tried to take remote control of the system, and thus the ‘Command and Control’ phase also came into the picture. All the stages recorded the behaviour of security products and scored their effectiveness on which phase the attack was detected.</p>
<p>Out of 10 test cases, Seqrite EPS completely detected eight instances at the 1st or 2nd stage itself. Seqrite EPS was seen and protected against the remaining 2 cases as well. However, some remnants of the attack were left on the system, and hence those detections were considered partial. As AV-Test also noted, though, those remnants were benign and not indicative of a successful infection.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h3>Seqrite EPS protects from Ransomware and APT attacks</h3>
<p>With an ever-evolving threat of ransomware, Seqrite’s EPS suite offers cutting-edge protection to your network, connected devices and data. The solution protects businesses from unknown advanced, sophisticated ransomware attacks and APT attacks from detection scan to asset management.</p>
<p>The 360-degree cloud Advanced Threat Protection and data security solution prevents, detects, and notifies for advanced threats – through email, mobile, social, and the desktop – and help you resolve them before they cause lasting harm.</p>
<p>Built with a Prevention-First mindset, Seqrite EPS helps protect organizations and the remote workforce from today&#8217;s complex threat landscape.</p>
<p>The Labs tested the detection capabilities of Seqrite&#8217;s advanced endpoint protection solution in terms of their performance against new, still unknown attack scenarios with ransomware, as hacker groups typically carry them out.</p>
<p>Multiple leading endpoint protection solutions were pitted against ten realistic APT attacks with ransomware. Seqrite received a protection score of <a href="https://www.av-test.org/en/news/protection-solutions-vs-ransomware-in-the-advanced-threat-protection-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow" data-wpel-link="external">31.5 pts </a>in the Test. The certification testifies that Seqrite EPS can deal with complex ransomware attacks. This enables organizations to recover encrypted data while ensuring business continuity and productivity.</p>
<p>See for yourself what Seqrite Endpoint can do for your organization through a free demo, or write to us at <a href="mailto:marketing@seqrite.com">marketing@seqrite.com</a> for additional details.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-accredited-with-advanced-approved-endpoint-protection-for-protection-against-complex-ransomware-attacks/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite EPS accredited with &#8220;Advanced Approved Endpoint Protection&#8221; for protection against complex ransomware attacks</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-eps-accredited-with-advanced-approved-endpoint-protection-for-protection-against-complex-ransomware-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2021-44228: New Apache Log4j ‘Log4Shell’ Zero-Day Being Exploited in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/cve-2021-44228-new-apache-log4j-log4shell-zero-day-being-exploited-in-the-wild/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/cve-2021-44228-new-apache-log4j-log4shell-zero-day-being-exploited-in-the-wild/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 09:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Seqrite</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Apache]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Apache]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Log4 Shell]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Log4J]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Vulnerability]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ZeroDay]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5135</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Log4-5-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>A critical zero-day vulnerability (CVE-2021-44228) recently discovered Apache Log4J, the popular java open source logging library used in countless worldwide applications. The maximum severity vulnerability has been identified as &#8216;Log4Shell&#8217;, which, if exploited, could permit a remote attacker to take control of vulnerable systems and execute arbitrary code remotely. According to some security researchers, the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/cve-2021-44228-new-apache-log4j-log4shell-zero-day-being-exploited-in-the-wild/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">CVE-2021-44228: New Apache Log4j ‘Log4Shell’ Zero-Day Being Exploited in the Wild</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">3</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>A critical zero-day vulnerability (CVE-2021-44228) recently discovered Apache Log4J, the popular java open source logging library used in countless worldwide applications.</p>
<p>The maximum severity vulnerability has been identified as &#8216;Log4Shell&#8217;, which, if exploited, could permit a remote attacker to take control of vulnerable systems and execute arbitrary code remotely.</p>
<p>According to some security researchers, the flaw is the most serious discovered in the past decade due to its ease of exploitation and the sheer number of affected enterprise applications and cloud services. It is the most high-profile security vulnerability on the internet right now and comes with a severity score of 10, the maximum severity rating possible.</p>
<p>After Log4Shell, security researchers identified a few more vulnerabilities in the same Log4j library. These new vulnerabilities are &#8211; CVE-2021-45046 &#8211; a Remote code execution, CVE-2021-45105 &#8211; a denial of services and CVE-2021-4104 &#8211; a remote code execution.</p>
<p>Apache addressed this vulnerability by releasing a patch and security advisory with mitigation details.</p>
<h3></h3>
<h3><b>What is Apache Log4J &#8220;Log4Shell&#8221; vulnerability?</b></h3>
<p>Log4j is an open-source Java-based logging utility in the Apache Logging Services. Logging untrusted or user-controlled data with a vulnerable version of Log4J may result in Remote Code Execution (RCE) against your application. This includes untrusted data provided in logged errors such as exception traces, authentication failures, and other unexpected vectors of user-controlled input.</p>
<p>Invulnerable Log4j, an unauthenticated, remote attacker, could exploit it by sending a specially crafted JNDI injection request to a target server and writing in a log file, leading to arbitrary code execution. This allowed attackers to inject malicious payloads from LDAP servers or other JNDI services such as DNS, RMI, NIS, NDS, CORBA, and IIOP when the message lookup mechanism is enabled.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Impacted Log4j versions</strong>: All versions from 2.0-beta9 to 2.14.1</li>
<li><strong>Severity</strong>: Critical</li>
</ul>
<h3></h3>
<h3><strong>Why is the &#8220;Log4Shell&#8221; vulnerability critical?</strong></h3>
<p>An unauthenticated, remote attacker can exploit this vulnerability in simple web requests that target identified vulnerable systems. Successful exploitation could lead to arbitrary code execution, and the attacker can take complete control of the system.</p>
<p>Apache Log4j is widely used in cloud and enterprise software services, so publicly available exploits code, easy exploitations &amp; detection evasions techniques make this vulnerability very dangerous.</p>
<p><strong>CVE-2021-45046</strong>, <strong>CVE-2021-45105</strong>, <strong>CVE-2021-4104</strong> <strong>in log4j: </strong></p>
<p><strong>CVE-2021-45046</strong> is Affecting versions from 2.0-beta9 to 2.15.0 excluding 2.12.2. Initially identified as &#8220;Low&#8221; severity, it is later moved to &#8220;Critical&#8221; remote code execution vulnerability. Logging configuration with non-default Pattern Layout with Context Lookup &amp; control over Thread Context Map (MCD) pattern, the attacker can craft malicious input using JNDI Lookup pattern, which could lead to DOS or an information leak and remote code execution.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Impacted Log4j versions</strong>: All versions 0-beta9 to 2.15.0 excluding 2.12.2</li>
<li><strong>Severity</strong>: Critical</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>CVE-2021-45105</strong> is affecting Log4j versions from 2.0-beta9 to 2.16.0 wherein non-default configuration. The attacker can send crafted requests with recursive lookup, which control Thread Context Map data to cause a denial-of-service vulnerability<strong>.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Impacted Log4j versions</strong>: All versions from 2.0-beta9 to 2.16.0</li>
<li><strong>Severity</strong>: High</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>CVE-2021-4104</strong> is affecting Log4j version 1.2 when Log4j is configured to use JMSAppender to perform JNDI requests which can cause remote code execution.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Impacted Log4j versions</strong>: version 1.2</li>
<li><strong>Severity</strong>: High</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Mitigation of &#8220;Log4Shell&#8221; </strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Immediately update to the latest Apache Log4j version from <a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/download.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow" data-wpel-link="external">here.</a></li>
<li>Please refer to <a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow" data-wpel-link="external">Vendor Advisory.</a></li>
<li>Update the Network security solutions and endpoints with the latest definitions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Seqrite Coverage for &#8220;Log4Shell&#8221; </strong></h3>
<p>We have released IPS rules to identify and block remote attacks exploiting vulnerable Log4j installations. We&#8217;ll continue monitoring the developments around this threat and improve our detections if needed. We advise all our customers to patch their systems properly and keep the anti-virus software updated with the latest VDB updates.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/cve-2021-44228-new-apache-log4j-log4shell-zero-day-being-exploited-in-the-wild/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">CVE-2021-44228: New Apache Log4j ‘Log4Shell’ Zero-Day Being Exploited in the Wild</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/cve-2021-44228-new-apache-log4j-log4shell-zero-day-being-exploited-in-the-wild/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 cybersecurity threats that every Startup or Business should have to be ready to fight in current times</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/top-6-cybersecurity-threats-that-every-startup-or-business-should-have-to-be-ready-to-fight-in-current-times/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/top-6-cybersecurity-threats-that-every-startup-or-business-should-have-to-be-ready-to-fight-in-current-times/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 13:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sanjay Katkar]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Sanjay Katkar</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Enterprise Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Cloudjacking]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#DataBreach]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#EnterpriseSecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#InsiderThreats]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#SmallBusiness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SMBs]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5130</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Top-6-cybersecurity-threats-to-address-in-2021-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve been following the news recently, you&#8217;ll undoubtedly have read about cybersecurity incidents impacting corporations of all sizes in all industries around the world. While it doesn&#8217;t often make the news, even small- and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) have been hammered by email phishing attacks or ransomware, which has been getting worse for some time. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/top-6-cybersecurity-threats-that-every-startup-or-business-should-have-to-be-ready-to-fight-in-current-times/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Top 6 cybersecurity threats that every Startup or Business should have to be ready to fight in current times</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">4</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>If you&#8217;ve been following the news recently, you&#8217;ll undoubtedly have read about cybersecurity incidents impacting corporations of all sizes in all industries around the world. While it doesn&#8217;t often make the news, even small- and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) have been hammered by email phishing attacks or ransomware, which has been getting worse for some time.</p>
<p>As per a recent report, almost 25% of the organization become victims who chose to pay the ransom. Hackers seem to be encouraged by their success and are growing more ambitious with time. The most recent example was the REVIL ransomware attack on Kaseya Software, holding more than 1,000 companies&#8217; ransom &#8211; affecting over 1 million customers.</p>
<p>It seems like no one is safe; even hospitals and schools are regularly targeted. Seqrite&#8217;s Q3 2021 Threat Report detected almost 4.6 Million cyberattacks in the professional service industry, followed by the manufacturing, government, and education sectors.</p>
<p>The increased reliance on the internet in the digitization era comes with increased vulnerability and zero-day threats. Small businesses often have less stringent technological defenses, less awareness of threats, and less time and resources for cybersecurity. This makes them an easier target for hackers than more prominent organizations.</p>
<p>For these reasons, small to medium businesses need to be aware of some top prevalent cybersecurity threats and how to combat them.</p>
<p><strong>Top 6 Security threats facing businesses – </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Phishing Attacks – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Phishing is a hacking scheme that tricks users into downloading harmful messages. This scheme appears like a regular email using legitimate-looking links, attachments, business names, and logos. The email persuades users to take action, whether it’s clicking a link or downloading an attachment. A phishing email may also have a clickbait subject line that catches your eye.</p>
<p>Cybercriminals also targets companies with Spear Phishing emails which sends emails to other specific members of a business to steal information. Phishing attack tops the list of enterprise cyber-attack and one wrong from an employee can expose a business to massive risk.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent phishing attacks – </strong></p>
<p>Part of what makes phishing attacks so damaging is that they’re very difficult to combat. They use social engineering to target humans within a business, rather than targeting technological weaknesses.</p>
<p>However, having a strong email security gateway in place can prevent phishing emails from reaching your employees inboxes. You can also provide security awareness training to your workforce allowing you to protect your employees by testing and training them to spot phishing attacks and report them.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Malware Attacks – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Malware, also known as malicious software, hacks devices by either slowing them down significantly or stopping them from working entirely. It destroys computer systems through agents such as Trojan malware, spyware, viruses, ransomware, adware, and worms.’</p>
<p>Malware authors target systems through infected links, malicious files or material from an unknown source, pop-up ads, or downloading an email attachment from an unknown sender. Once malware is released into the system, hackers can gain access to your company’s passwords, credit card numbers, banking data, personnel files, and more.</p>
<p>These attacks are particularly damaging for small businesses because they can cripple devices. Small businesses are more likely to employ people who use their own devices for work, as it helps to save time and cost. This, however, increases their likelihood of suffering from a malware attack, as personal devices are much more likely to be at risk from malicious downloads.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent malware – </strong></p>
<p>Business can prevent malware attacks by having strong technological defences in place. Endpoint Protection solutions protect devices from malware downloads and give admins a central control panel to manage devices and ensure all users’ security is up to date. Web Security is also important, stopping users from visiting malicious webpages and downloading malicious software.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ransomware Attacks – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Ransomware is a specific form of malware that encrypts a user’s computer systems. Once a ransomware attack has been implemented, users can no longer access their systems or files. In order for users to re-access their systems, they’re required to pay a ransom fee to the cybercriminals. The ransom costs can range tremendously from hundreds of dollars to thousands of dollars or more.</p>
<p>Ransomware is often spread through a malicious download in a phishing email. An attack can be targeted to either individual employees or entire organizations.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent ransomware – </strong></p>
<p>To prevent these attacks, businesses need to have strong Endpoint Protection in place across all business devices. These will help to stop ransomware attacks from being able to effectively encrypt data. Endpoint protection solution like Seqrite allows organizations to very quickly detect and mitigate against ransomware attacks.</p>
<p>Businesses should also consider having an effective cloud back-up or data back-up or recovery solution to quickly recover data in the event of ransomware attack without having to pay any ransoms, or lose productivity.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Data Breaches – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>A data breach occurs when sensitive data like credit card numbers, names, email addresses, user or passwords is stolen from a system without authorization from the system owner. Breaches may be implemented through a network attack when cybercriminals identify a weakness in a company’s online security system and use the weakness to invade the system. Social attacks are also prevalent, where hackers fool employees into granting access to an organization’s network.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent data breach – </strong></p>
<p>Small business have access to multiple accounts that hold more data. Hence, enterprises need to ensure that they have a strong culture of security awareness within their organization, proper security and vulnerability patch management is also important. They should have proper identity and access management implemented, have full disk encryption enabled to prevent tomorrow’s threat today.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Insider Threats – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Small businesses are also often the target of insider threats from the company staff and stakeholders. These threats could be an outcome of malicious intent or pure negligence.  Within small businesses, insider threats are growing, putting employees and customers at risk as more employees access multiple accounts. This can cause financial damage to the company.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent Insider Threats – </strong></p>
<p>To block insider threats, companies should help employees spot early on when an attacker has compromised or is attempting to compromise company data. Use comprehensive cloud-based tools like Seqrite HawkkProtect to detect unauthorized logins. The solution can help SMBs use two-factor authentication and detect the installation of new apps on locked-down computers, users with newly granted authorization access, and new devices on local networks.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cloud Jacking – </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Cloud jacking happens when an unauthorized party steals your organization’s cloud account. Once a hacker gets into your company cloud, they may try to reconfigure the code to manipulate sensitive data, eavesdrop on employees and company communications, and expand their reach to take control of the entire cloud. They can cause irreparable damage that can be financially devastating to the business.</p>
<p>Cloud jacking can be done in various ways, including phishing schemes, stealing passwords or social engineering attacks, stealing sensitive data, or even moving company funds into fraudulent accounts.</p>
<p><strong>How to prevent cloud jacking – </strong></p>
<p>Cloud jacking is a growing cybersecurity threat. Companies must limit access to sensitive information to only a handful of people, encourage the use of VPNs – encrypted connection, enable two-factor authentication, and use robust endpoint security tools like Seqrite HawkkEye or HawkkScan to maximize cybersecurity.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/top-6-cybersecurity-threats-that-every-startup-or-business-should-have-to-be-ready-to-fight-in-current-times/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Top 6 cybersecurity threats that every Startup or Business should have to be ready to fight in current times</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/top-6-cybersecurity-threats-that-every-startup-or-business-should-have-to-be-ready-to-fight-in-current-times/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anydesk Software Exploited to Spread Babuk Ransomware</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/4170-2/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/4170-2/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 11:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Preksha Saxena]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Preksha Saxena</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Babuk]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#BabukLocker #DarkWeb]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=4170</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Anydesk-SQ-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>We generally see that ransomware attacks are deployed through exploits, unsolicited malicious emails (malspam), or malicious Microsoft Office documents. Attackers trick the unsuspecting users into enabling macros, etc. Apart from these usual attack techniques, we came across a new way of using Anydesk software fake websites to spread Babuk ransomware. Anydesk is a remote-control tool [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/4170-2/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Anydesk Software Exploited to Spread Babuk Ransomware</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">8</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>We generally see that ransomware attacks are deployed through exploits, unsolicited malicious emails (malspam), or malicious Microsoft Office documents. Attackers trick the unsuspecting users into enabling macros, etc. Apart from these usual attack techniques, we came across a new way of using Anydesk software fake websites to spread Babuk ransomware. Anydesk is a remote-control tool that allows users to access remote computers and other devices running the host applications.<br />
Babuk Ransomware is recently very active. Its tactics for encryption are not much different from other ransomware families. Over time, ransomware releases new variants and improves its attack mechanisms to target new victims.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5102" style="width: 891px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-5102 size-full" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture1.png" alt="" width="891" height="204" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture1.png 891w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture1-300x69.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture1-768x176.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 891px) 100vw, 891px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Fig 1. Initial Vector of infection</figcaption></figure>
<p>When the user tries to download the Anydesk software from an unknown suspicious link, a fake website appears, which allows you to download Anydesk software. This fake website looks like the original Anydesk website. When the user clicks for downloading Anydesk software, ransomware is also downloaded as it is bundled with Anydesk software in the form of a self-extracting archive (in this case, it is in no setup files). It does so for evasion purposes.<br />
For eg:<br />
If Anydesk is searched in Microsoft or Bing, we get the following result. The first website is not related to the official Anydesk application, and After clicking on the setelog website, ads.htm redirects to a malicious website that downloads ransomware.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5105" style="width: 664px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-5105 size-full" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture2.png" alt="" width="664" height="523" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture2.png 664w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture2-300x236.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 664px) 100vw, 664px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Searching Anydesk Application</figcaption></figure>
<p>Similarly, we have found one more suspicious link for Anydesk application which is mentioned below.<br />
URL:<br />
<em><strong>https[:]//Anydesk1[.]websiteseguro[.]com/downloads/windows/?_ga=2.165501695.1936674747.1628634255-780551265.1627305233</strong></em><br />
Downloaded File Name: Setup_Anydesk.exe</p>
<figure id="attachment_5106" style="width: 506px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-5106" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture3.png" alt="" width="506" height="400" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture3.png 506w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture3-300x237.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Fig. After Clicking on downloaded file installation window appears</figcaption></figure>
<p>We analyzed the downloaded archive and discovered that it has a clean Anydesk setup along with a Babuk downloader, a RAT file, and a REG file.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5107" style="width: 434px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-5107" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture4.png" alt="" width="434" height="261" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture4.png 434w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture4-300x180.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 434px) 100vw, 434px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Fig. Files present inside Archive</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Understanding the Infection Process</strong><br />
When a user clicks on the downloaded archive, which pretends to be an Anydesk software application, other files in the bundle get dropped silently. The above image shows an Allakore Rat client named bthudtaskt.exe, a Babuk downloader called mdnsFULLHD.exe, and one registry file named Anydesk.reg is dropped in the Startup folder without user interaction. Clean Anydesk application is dropped at the desktop, and it gets installed. All the dropped files in the startup folder are executed through PowerShell and perform their activity in the background.<br />
<strong>Anydesk.Reg:</strong></p>
<p>Anydesk.reg file disables user account control by setting the value of EnableLUA by 0. It also disables windows defender by setting the value of DisableAntiSpyware by 1. Malware also disables real-time protection by setting values by 1.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5110" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture5.png" alt="" width="788" height="245" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture5.png 788w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture5-300x93.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture5-768x239.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 788px) 100vw, 788px" /></p>
<p><strong>Allakore RAT Client:</strong><br />
AllaKore Rat is an open-source simple Remote Access Tool written in Delphi and has a very high resemblance with code found on GitHub.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5108" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture6.png" alt="" width="696" height="372" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture6.png 696w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture6-300x160.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /></p>
<p>Babuk Downloader launches the Allakore Rat and it makes TCP requests as shown below.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5109" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture7.png" alt="" width="387" height="193" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture7.png 387w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture7-300x150.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 387px) 100vw, 387px" /></p>
<p><strong>Babuk Downloader:</strong><br />
The ‘mdnsFULLHD.exe’ file is PE32 executable for MS Windows, and it is Delphi compiled. It is immense (~ 12MB) as it has most of the code to impair the defences. It launches the Allakore Rat ùsing PowerShell cmdlet Set-MpPreference, and it makes TCP requests as shown above image.<br />
It adds the below paths in exclusion for the Windows Defender modules through the PowerShell cmdlet Set-MpPreference to hide all the malware components from Windows Defender.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5111" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture8.png" alt="" width="792" height="422" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture8.png 792w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture8-300x160.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture8-768x409.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px" /></p>
<p>For eg:<br />
cmd.exe /c PowerShell -Command Add-MpPreference -ExclusionPath &#8220;C:\Users\XXX\Contacts&#8221;<br />
cmd.exe /c PowerShell -Command Add-MpPreference -ExclusionPath &#8220;C:\Users\XXX\Links&#8221; etc<br />
Above are excluded by executing cmd.exe. The malware also excludes the below drives.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5112" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture9.png" alt="" width="703" height="130" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture9.png 703w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture9-300x55.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 703px) 100vw, 703px" /></p>
<p>It has a list of AVs as shown below and it checks if any of the antivirus product is installed in the system.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5113" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture10.png" alt="" width="224" height="269" /></p>
<p>If any of the antivirus processes are running on the system, the below prompt appears, asking the user to intervene and uninstall the product. If the user clicks on the Next button, then the control panel opens for uninstalling the software, and in the background, the malware checks whether it is uninstalled or not.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5114" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture11.png" alt="" width="433" height="344" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture11.png 433w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture11-300x238.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 433px) 100vw, 433px" /></p>
<p>The malware disables Task manager, and it undermines all the modules of Windows Defender.<br />
Further digging into the file revealed that malware sent an HTTP request to download the bat file and .exe file. The domain used are:<br />
<em>“hxxp://suporte01928492.redirectme.net/Update7/Update.bat.rar”</em><br />
<em> “hxxp://suporte01928492.redirectme.net/Update7/Update.exe.rar”</em><br />
These downloaded files are saved in:<br />
&#8220;C:\Users\AppData\Roaming\Microsoft\Windows\Start Menu\Programs\Startup&#8221; folder. Malware creates these files and names according to the user name and then executes both the files silently using PowerShell.<br />
Files created:.exe and .bat<br />
E.g., if the username is ABC, the file name is ABC.exe and ABC.bat in the folder mentioned above.</p>
<p><strong>Update.bat</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>It contains the following setting, which is executed through PowerShell, which help in evasion of the malware:</li>
<li>Hide per-user toggle notifications</li>
<li>Hide notification of windows defender in the systray icon</li>
<li>Disable dialogue prompt.</li>
<li>Cascade elevation.</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5116" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture14.png" alt="" width="1065" height="449" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture14.png 1065w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture14-300x126.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture14-768x324.png 768w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture14-1024x432.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1065px) 100vw, 1065px" /></p>
<p><strong>Update.exe: BABUK PAYLOAD</strong><br />
Downloaded Update.exe file is a Babuk ransomware payload. It is UPX packed file, and the size is small, around 25 KB. Malware is compiled in C/C++.<br />
After execution, it launches the vssadmin.exe process to delete all Shadow Copy using the command “vssadmin.exe delete shadows /all /quiet.” It also creates “mutex” with the name “DoYouWantToHaveSexWithChuongDong” in the system.<br />
Malware closes all the processes that are listed, which prevents file encryption. It also empties the Recycle Bin by calling the function SHEmptyRecycleBinA(), and it enumerates system folders and drives and creates ransom notes in each folder.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5117" style="width: 1021px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-5117" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture12.png" alt="" width="1021" height="443" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture12.png 1021w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture12-300x130.png 300w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture12-768x333.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1021px) 100vw, 1021px" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Fig . Ransom Note</figcaption></figure>
<p>It encrypts all files by the extension &#8220;.doydo&#8221;.extension may vary according to the payload variant downloaded.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5118" src="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture13.png" alt="" width="596" height="384" srcset="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture13.png 596w, https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Picture13-300x193.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 596px) 100vw, 596px" /></p>
<p>Malware appends the string “Choung dong looks like a hot dog!!” at end of the encrypted content of all the encrypted files.</p>
<p>After a successful attack, if the victim does not pay the ransom as demanded, the malware author either publishes the encrypted data or sells it on underground forums.</p>
<h3><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h3>
<p>This use case is not limited to a specific threat actor. However, we believe that this type of infection is affecting a wide range of Anydesk users. Using tools like Anydesk or other administrative agencies, the malware authors can easily take administrative privileges of the victim&#8217;s computer and perform the malicious activity in the system.<br />
In the end, we emphasize the customer to be very careful while clicking on links that are used for software download or any link received by email, messages, or WhatsApp. Always check whether the website is official and secure or not.<br />
Here are a few additional guidelines which will help to minimize the attack surface &amp; possible damage to IT infrastructure.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid downloading software from untrusted P2P or torrent sites. In most cases, they harbour malicious software. In this case, use <strong>https://Anydesk.com/en/downloads</strong> to download Anydesk software.</li>
<li>Always keep your security software (antivirus, firewall, etc.) up to date to protect your computer from new variants of Malware.</li>
<li>Do not download cracked/pirated software, as they risk backdoor entry for Malware into your computer.</li>
<li>Audit ‘Local /Domain Users’ and remove/disable unwanted users.</li>
<li>Don’t assign Administrator privileges to users.</li>
<li>Wherever possible, enable multi-Factor authentication to ensure all logins are legitimate.</li>
<li>Don’t stay logged in as an administrator unless it is strictly necessary.</li>
<li>Avoid browsing, opening documents, or other regular work activities while logged in as an administrator.</li>
<li>While signature-based protections alone are insufficient to detect and prevent sophisticated ransomware attacks designed to evade traditional protections, they are an essential component of a comprehensive security posture.</li>
<li>Respond carefully &amp; sensibly to the alerts raised by Behavioral-based detection systems and Anti- Ransomware Protection systems. We prefer to block/Deny unknown applications detected by these systems.</li>
<li>Audit RDP access &amp; disable it if not required. Else, set appropriate rules to allow access from only specific &amp; intended Hosts.</li>
<li>In almost all cases, attackers use PowerShell scripts to exploit the vulnerability, so disable the PowerShell in the Network. If you require PowerShell for internal use, then try to block the PowerShell.exe connecting to public access.</li>
<li>Always use a combination of online and offline backup of all your files.</li>
</ul>
<h3></h3>
<h3><strong><b>How Quick Heal Protect its Users:</b></strong></h3>
<p>Quick Heal products are equipped with multi-layered detection technologies like IDS/IPS, EDR, DNA Scan, Email Scan, NGAV, Web Protection, and Patented Anti Ransomware detection. This multi-layered security approach helps us protect our customers against Babuk Ransomware and other known, unknown threats efficiently.</p>
<p><strong><b>Indicators of compromise</b></strong></p>
<p><strong><b>Anydesk Innosetup files:</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>a64beabdb0c9ae6b5dca97b64bbd0358</li>
<li>d7751f57dca53de35be58c45e623ba54</li>
<li>b70fb92fadc90efca375850ed503af4d</li>
<li>225fcb613c1796a3f27a2b71aba77dc4</li>
<li>23c9916a932d3c3b03d9ebee5c2bd6eb</li>
<li>d443a25c6a4f9c553724da404676dee4</li>
<li>a0b78a347b3e8b1b17a3db6dda4079e3</li>
<li>d0af75fc8c88a51b044dad9bfa2cbd17</li>
<li>33dd883776eda150f4bdfebe97f00790</li>
<li>ea34fea96cbbc22091aab8c6a4225326</li>
<li>5763a24e3927c6053bb216b09d281c13</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><b>Domains:</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>myftp.biz</li>
<li>sytes.net</li>
<li>redirectme.net</li>
<li>sytes.net</li>
<li>serveirc.com</li>
<li>websiteseguro.com/downloads/windows/?_ga=2.165501695.1936674747.1628634255-780551265.1627305233</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><b>Babuk Downloader:</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>4935463e3f1f0e498f5928d579405725</li>
<li>4e376b65f35727c956782874d2777549</li>
<li>64c97cda282fdf8f5906f98d8b5e83d0</li>
<li>85deb376e4c3559ce010c8e9a4a6595c</li>
<li>a5d17bf427f8630e207564b3888af127</li>
<li>ad4461b7b14faa0dc2b77dbd95ab4330</li>
<li>aeef6cefcf78c8990a09eee89d831c7f</li>
<li>db4572ff504436ffb079ef5858176deb</li>
<li>Ead98682c4b5da91fa6380f1858cf8c4</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><b>Allakore Rat Client:</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1486cbb9b4ff1c5aceb67949eefa8cda</li>
<li>1bcbc44772aba8c5dd27b964e555a490</li>
<li>207ffd69134a589bbb5e24949664234a</li>
<li>2719bd7ab3de7b683041cd7c30f1041d</li>
<li>2f860f69a4090e9f6bf0833dc322ff77</li>
<li>304275544920ab64fc3d17e2c1a30fd7</li>
<li>3e45570f7b33f0f4c24bcc7b24b31d85</li>
<li>44c696374426167febbc290b8cd1b300</li>
<li>45d7c902614f094a846dea70b31bb846</li>
<li>4fc57386bfc22265a507adb818ef163e</li>
<li>65f7a1e438a33ec75adbc599d2362706</li>
<li>83020fda9cd8bc429a4141284ba41b21</li>
<li>c4a047327be1a3a481083cecbcc1c54d</li>
<li>d387a74efbb033c1d327a5e1c4a9e6ce</li>
<li>e5313dd64ce118e49e1dfd461af26835</li>
<li>F555a28a88f91ec639e5d86bc4c1c3c9</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><b>Babuk Payload:</b></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>0099963e7285aeafc09e4214a45a6a210253d514cbd0d4b0c3997647a0afe879</li>
<li>028facff67136de55fe200177a190da625c8e1713b4e7d95bf5fc5412a5afffc</li>
<li>0294114d5f411b6c47eb255d4ed6865df99d1c5252f4f585aabf44e6cbacaa59</li>
<li>02e9883501635da9b501e715bb827a0b9d0c265991f1263f073eb6c5d9b335c3</li>
<li>03110baa5aad9d01610293f2b8cd21b44cc7efa0a465e677d6b3f92510a4b1d7</li>
<li>0b93a024b5d6874d7bb69abd7f0e2d54a67c602584575a9b6d1212baae81442f</li>
<li>12c561ac827c3f79afff026b0b1d3ddec7c4b591946e2b794a4d00c423b1c8f8</li>
<li>15656e1825383c4749fadcc46f9825df6262ca2f1f98d895d64c840febe3d9d3</li>
<li>18e282e6806903ff00a78b91f6d0ad1bc3aae4b4846d6a5705c036a88138605f</li>
<li>1ab45a508da655ef755ad4394f869c664f664b3ac111875704a583e9485f2238</li>
<li>1d40f42fa328a9a6192d4fa8c6e5ce6f813ea9132774784521713b202d772994</li>
<li>1deb1efad2c469198aabbb618285e2229052273cf654ee5925c2540ded224402</li>
<li>1e24560100d010c27cc19c59f9fe1531e4286ecb21fe53763165f30c5f58dc90</li>
<li>63b6a51be736d253e26011f19bd16006d7093839b345363ef238eafcfe5e7e85</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/4170-2/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Anydesk Software Exploited to Spread Babuk Ransomware</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/4170-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud Supports Windows 10 21H2 Version</title>
      <link>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-endpoint-security-cloud-supports-windows-10-21h2-version/</link>
      <comments>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-endpoint-security-cloud-supports-windows-10-21h2-version/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 08:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Seqrite]]></dc:creator>
      <author>Seqrite</author>
      <category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Windows Update]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#21H2]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[#Win10]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Windows10]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.seqrite.com/blog/?p=5097</guid>
      <img>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Seqrite-EPS-Cloud-230x168.jpg</img>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has recently developed a new feature update for Windows 10 PCs, Windows 10, version 21H2 (Windows 10 21H2). This article highlights some of the new features of Windows 10 21H2 and how Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud is compatible with Windows 10 21H2. Few Highlights of Windows 10 21H2 Adding WPA3 H2E standards support for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-endpoint-security-cloud-supports-windows-10-21h2-version/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud Supports Windows 10 21H2 Version</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label">Estimated reading time: </span><span class="rt-time">2</span><span class="rt-label"> minutes</span></span><p>Microsoft has recently developed a new feature update for Windows 10 PCs, Windows 10, version 21H2 (Windows 10 21H2). This article highlights some of the new features of Windows 10 21H2 and how Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud is compatible with Windows 10 21H2.</p>
<h3><strong>Few Highlights of Windows 10 21H2</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Adding WPA3 H2E standards support for enhanced Wi-Fi security.</li>
<li>Windows Hello for Business introduces a new cloud trust deployment method to support simplified password-less deployments and achieve a deploy-to-run state within a few minutes.</li>
<li>GPU compute support in the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) and Azure IoT Edge for Linux on Windows (EFLOW) deployments for machine learning and other compute-intensive workflows.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Supported Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud Version Details </strong></h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>For Existing Users</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Users having Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud version 10.4 or later versions must take the latest Seqrite Updates first and then update Windows 10 21H2</p>
<p><strong>Recommendation </strong>– After receiving the latest Seqrite Update, restart your PC. Then update to Windows10 21H2.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>For New Users </strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud current version available for downloads is compatible with Windows10 21H2.</p>
<h3><strong>How to apply the latest Seqrite Update?</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The update will be applied automatically if Automatic Update is enabled in Server policy settings.
<ul>
<li>You can also apply the update manually by any one of the following methods:</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>On the client dashboard, click the update now.</li>
<li>In the Help menu, select About and click update now.</li>
<li>Right-click the Seqrite icon in the system tray and click update now.</li>
<li>Go to Start &gt; All Programs &gt; Quick Update &gt; Select the model you prefer for updating Seqrite and click.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>How to ensure if the Seqrite update has been successfully installed and is compatible with Windows 10 21H2 update?</strong></h3>
<p>If your Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud Client’s Virus Database Date is the latest, it means it is compatible with Windows10 21H2</p>
<p><em><br />
If you have any queries about Windows10 21H2 and your Seqrite product, please call us on 1800-121-7377 or drop us a message in the comments section below. </em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-endpoint-security-cloud-supports-windows-10-21h2-version/" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Seqrite Endpoint Security Cloud Supports Windows 10 21H2 Version</a> appeared first on <a rel="follow" href="https://www.seqrite.com/blog" data-wpel-link="internal" target="_self">Blogs on Information Technology, Network &amp; Cybersecurity | Seqrite</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.seqrite.com/blog/seqrite-endpoint-security-cloud-supports-windows-10-21h2-version/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
      <commentcount>0</commentcount>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>