<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker Combat</title>
    <atom:link href="https://hackercombat.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://hackercombat.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 13:21:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://hackercombat.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/HC_FAVICON_48_48.png</url>
      <title>Hacker Combat</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Remove Ransomware</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/guide-to-remove-ransomware/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/guide-to-remove-ransomware/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 13:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Leaks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27868</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Ransomware is malicious software that encrypts your files and demands a fee in exchange for access. This type of malware is now the most profitable form of cybercrime since victims...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/guide-to-remove-ransomware/">Guide to Remove Ransomware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ransomware is malicious software that encrypts your files and demands a fee in exchange for access. This type of malware is now the most profitable form of cybercrime since victims feel compelled to pay, even if there are no guarantees that their <a href="https://hackercombat.com/what-is-ransomware-know-all-about-it/">data will be recovered</a>.</p>



<p>Whether the victim is a one-person firm or a major multinational corporation, a ransomware assault can be crippling. It is therefore quite impossible to overestimate the value of prevention. However, if you are already facing this kind of an attack below are 5 pointers to assist you in removing the ransomware.</p>



<ol class="has-medium-font-size"><li><strong>Remove the infected device from the network.</strong></li></ol>



<p>Ransomware detection rate as well as the speed are important in fighting attacks before they spread across other networks and encrypt vital data.</p>



<p>When there is a suspicion that a computer has been infected, the first thing to do is separate it from other devices. Remove it from any form of shared system regardless of it being wired or wireless. Some <a href="https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/">ransomware can actually attach themselves</a> to other computers, which you should avoid. </p>



<p>Be mindful that there could be other infected computers, indicating that the malware may have infiltrated your company or household via many machines or that it may be inactive patiently waiting to manifest itself on other systems later on. Suspect all linked and networked devices and take precautions to guarantee that none of them pose any threat.</p>



<ol start="2" class="has-medium-font-size"><li><strong>Determine the specific type of Infection</strong></li></ol>



<p>Identifying the specific type of malware causing trouble is very important as it will enable you comprehend how it spreads, the actual files encrypted and the available removal options present. It will also provide you with the required information needed in reporting the incident to the relevant authorities who are in a better position of preventing such attacks on another system.</p>



<ol start="3" class="has-medium-font-size"><li><strong>Create a backup</strong>.</li></ol>



<p>In order to prevent any loss that may arise, you ought to back up your crucial files and documents. You can accomplish this by storing critical information on external media such as DVD/CDs, free cloud storage services, USB sticks or external drives.</p>



<ol start="4" class="has-medium-font-size"><li><strong>Get rid of the ransomware</strong>.</li></ol>



<p>The ransomware must be eradicated before the system is recovered. During the initial hack, ransomware software infects a computer system, encrypting files or restricting access to the machine. The limitation can only be unlocked or decrypted with a password or decryption key.</p>



<p><strong>Here are 4 ways to get rid of ransomware:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Check to see if the threat has been removed. After infecting a system, the malware may remove itself, or it may stay on the computer thus infecting other devices.</li><li>Only use legitimate antimalware software’s. The malicious software may be quarantined and removed using the majority of anti-ransomware programs.&nbsp;</li><li>Seek assistance from the relevant professionals. To aid with ransomware eradication, work with a skilled technician, either within the company or through an independent tech assistant who is certified in dealing with such issues.</li><li>Eradicate the threat manually by checking the installed software on the device and uninstalling the corrupted file if possible. However, only specialized security specialists should attempt this.</li></ul>



<p>IT&nbsp;specialists should&nbsp;undertake&nbsp;a&nbsp;thorough&nbsp;scan&nbsp;of&nbsp;the infected&nbsp;device as&nbsp;part&nbsp;of&nbsp;the forensic&nbsp;efforts&nbsp;to guarantee&nbsp;that no&nbsp;ransomware&nbsp;leftovers are still present.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before&nbsp;returning&nbsp;afflicted&nbsp;devices&nbsp;to&nbsp;service,&nbsp;it&nbsp;is important to&nbsp;quarantine&nbsp;them&nbsp;to&nbsp;ensure that&nbsp;they&nbsp;are&nbsp;fully&nbsp;cleansed.</p>



<ol start="5" class="has-medium-font-size"><li><strong>Restore the system&#8217;s functionality</strong></li></ol>



<p>After eliminating the threat, you can now restore your previously backed up files but be very careful while doing so. It is important to update all your passwords together with the device access codes to maximize security.</p>



<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>Ransomware attack will become a thing of the past if you secure all your devices and backing up your data frequently.&nbsp; Another point to keep in mind is the importance of always being cautious to avoid falling into the trap of suspicious applications especially from untrustworthy sources. Install a strong anti-virus application to ensure that your device is safe.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/guide-to-remove-ransomware/">Guide to Remove Ransomware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/guide-to-remove-ransomware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Ransomware Protection Tips to Help You Secure Data in 2022</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/7-ransomware-protection-tips-to-help-you-secure-data/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/7-ransomware-protection-tips-to-help-you-secure-data/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Leaks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27856</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>There were 2690 reports of ransomware attacks in 2021, which was a 97.1% increase on 2020 levels. Ransomware is malicious software that infects a personal or organizational computer and then...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/7-ransomware-protection-tips-to-help-you-secure-data/">7 Ransomware Protection Tips to Help You Secure Data in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There were 2690 reports of ransomware attacks in 2021, which was a 97.1% increase on 2020 levels. Ransomware is malicious software that infects a personal or organizational computer and then holds information for ransom until the affected party pays some money.</p>



<p>Ransomware cost businesses and individuals $18 billion in 2020, with the average sum paid totaling $220,298 in the first quarter of 2021. Finance and banking institutions are most vulnerable to ransomware attacks. They are followed closely by utility companies and retail organizations. Educational institutions and small businesses are next on the list.</p>



<p>A ransomware attack has several effects on the affected parties. In addition to financial losses, the parties experienced reduced productivity, data loss and breaches, and other disruptive changes. Fortunately, there are several steps that organizations and individuals can take to prevent ransomware attacks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Below are Seven ransomware protection tips to help you secure data in 2022;</p>



<p><strong>#1 Do not open suspicious attachments</strong></p>



<p>That nice-sounding email promising you holiday/bonus/free cash if you open an attachment is a scam. Opening it could open a gateway to attacks that steal and compromise your data. It may then take years and large amounts of finances to get your data back. Even if the attachment is from a trusted source, ensure that you run it through anti-phishing software before opening it.</p>



<p><strong>#2 Backup your data</strong></p>



<p>A ransomware attack could lock you out of your computer for days or even months as you work to resolve the issue. You could find yourself unable to access important information, passwords, and others. Regularly backing up your data will ensure that you can gain access to your data when you need it.</p>



<p>The best ways to back up your data are through the cloud or on an external hard drive where attackers cannot access it. This will help you access your data if it is attacked and avoid paying a ransom to get it back.</p>



<p>#<strong>3 Enable multi-factor authentication</strong></p>



<p>If you have ever had to sign in to your email and then insert a code sent to your phone to verify your identity, you are already familiar with multi-factor authentication.</p>



<p>Multifactor authentication is a verification method that requires a user to go through two or more steps to access sensitive information. An example of this is entering your email password, inputting the code sent to your phone, and finally using fingerprint verification.</p>



<p><strong>#4 Switch off wireless connections when they are not in use</strong></p>



<p>Cybercriminals have become so sophisticated that they can access your information through your WIFI, Bluetooth, and hotspots. In addition to securing these by using a strong password, ensure that you switch them off when they are not in use.</p>



<p><strong>#5 Make use of windows firewall</strong></p>



<p>Windows firewall protects your computer from malicious attacks by controlling who has access to your network. It also blocks traffic from incoming and outgoing connections. Ensure that your windows firewall is working by configuring it regularly.</p>



<p>Windows firewall prevents backdoor access, remote login hijacking, email abuse, source routing and other threats to your computer. By monitoring the traffic to, and from your computer, firewalls keep out threats and enhance your network’s protection.</p>



<p><strong>#6 Use strong spam filters</strong></p>



<p>There are tools available to help you stop phishing emails from reaching users in your network. Use technologies like DomainKeys Identified Email and Sender Protection Framework (SPF) to prevent cybercriminals from gaining access to your email and networks.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>#7 Use strong and unique passwords</strong></p>



<p>Practice password best practice by keeping your passwords unique and hard to guess. In addition, avoid using variations of one password as this can leave you open to attack if one of them is compromised.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>Ransomware attacks will continue to grow as cybercriminals become more sophisticated and daring. One ransomware attack can compromise sensitive information and force you to pay unscrupulous parties to get it back. Taking steps to protect your data will help you reduce ransomware attacks and keep cybercriminals out for good.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/7-ransomware-protection-tips-to-help-you-secure-data/">7 Ransomware Protection Tips to Help You Secure Data in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/7-ransomware-protection-tips-to-help-you-secure-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Ransomware Protection</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 04:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Leaks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[best ransomware protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware attack protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27818</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Ransomware attacks targeting governments, businesses, hospitals, and private individuals are rising. It has become a vast online issue that affects individuals and businesses alike. You are neither safe on your...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/">Best Ransomware Protection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ransomware attacks targeting governments, businesses, hospitals, and private individuals are rising. It has become a vast online issue that affects individuals and businesses alike. You are neither safe on your private nor public network, as ransomware can encrypt your files and hold them hostage. As a result, you have to pay ransom to unlock them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With so many businesses affected, there needs to be some way to combat this attack. We will look at the features of some of the best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ransomware" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ransomware</a> protection that you can run on your systems.</p>



<h2><strong>How Does Ransomware Work?</strong></h2>



<p>When you open an infected file that seemingly appears safe, ransomware executes its process by encrypting data. Once encrypted, you cannot access the data without a decryption key, which the cybercriminal capitalizes on by demanding payment for its exchange.</p>



<h2><strong>Features of the Best Ransomware Protection Solutions</strong></h2>



<p><strong>The most effective ransomware protection solutions will have the following features:</strong></p>



<ul><li>A centralized management console for enterprise-wide administration</li><li>Real-time detection of zero-day ransomware threats</li><li>Integrated email and web threat protection to block malicious email attachments and downloads from malicious websites</li><li>Automatic updates, patches, and remediation for connected endpoints to identify missing patches and update them as soon as new ones become available</li><li>Granular user controls apply restrictions on what users can do on the network.</li><li>Automatic application whitelist that allows only approved applications to run on endpoints.</li></ul>



<h2><strong>How to Protect Yourself from Ransomware</strong>?</h2>



<p>You can defeat ransomware through specific preventive measures, including software and encryption. A sure way to protect yourself from ransomware is to prevent it from happening in the first place. That’s where the best ransomware protection comes in as both a preventive measure and an early alert system to help you swiftly deal with an attack before it spreads throughout your entire organization.</p>



<p>Let’s look at some of the best ransomware protection measures;</p>



<h3><strong>Regular Data Backup</strong></h3>



<p>Backing up your data ensures you do not get hit by an attack, or if it happens, you won’t lose any critical data. The best ransomware protection combines solid, layered security defenses with data backups that an attacker can’t encrypt.</p>



<h3><strong>Regular Software Updates</strong></h3>



<p>You should ensure all your software is up-to-date by enabling automatic updates for Windows and your apps whenever possible. Regular updates patch any security vulnerabilities as quickly as possible so hackers won’t exploit them.</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Ransomware Protection Program</strong></h3>



<p>Several free anti-malware products that detect and block ransomware attacks are available. Some of the best options offer both free and paid versions. A good ransomware protection program should install as a layer on top of your existing antivirus software for maximum protection.</p>



<h3><strong>Use of Comodo Antivirus software</strong></h3>



<p>Comodo Antivirus takes the upper hand to ransomware attacks by scanning your systems and preventing malware in its tracks before the malware enters your system.</p>



<p>You can get free protection tools on the market. For example, Comodo offers free ransomware protection through its Forensic Analysis Scanning Tool.</p>



<h3><strong>Being Wary of Phishing Emails</strong></h3>



<p>Be on the lookout for phishing emails that appear to come from legitimate companies or individuals. Soliciting for a click on a link or opening an attachment is a common way that cybercriminals try to spread ransomware onto your devices. Be wary of opening attachments and clicking on links unless you are sure they are legitimate.</p>



<h3><strong>Use Strong Passwords</strong></h3>



<p>Set up strong passwords for all your accounts, including bank, credit cards, and email. Don’t leave any passwords blank, and don’t use the same password for everything. Use a long, alphanumeric password with a combination of numbers, letters and special characters.</p>



<h3><strong>Choosing Best Ransomware Protection Solution</strong></h3>



<p>It helps to have a proactive approach to protecting your business from ransomware. Here are some factors to consider when choosing a ransomware protection program:</p>



<h3><strong>Familiarity</strong></h3>



<p>You want a solution that you are sure works because it applies in real-world situations. Look for an established vendor with a proven track record of success.</p>



<h3><strong>Simplicity</strong></h3>



<p>You may waste time on complex solutions that take significant effort to implement and maintain. You want something easy to install and use, doesn’t require much configuration, and doesn’t need frequent updates or maintenance.</p>



<h3><strong>Compatibility</strong></h3>



<p>The solution must work with your existing hardware and any additional hardware you plan to add in the future. It should also work with your existing antivirus software if you use one.</p>



<h3><strong>Cost</strong></h3>



<p>Go for the solution that best fits your budget and needs.</p>



<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>



<p>The ransomware malware encrypts or locks your files and holds them, hostage until you pay the cybercriminal. It can affect computers, servers, smartphones, and tablets, thus causing severe disruption to your business operations and exposing your company to financial loss and legal liability. Even with the best ransomware protection, ransomware strains constantly evolve, and attacks still happen.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/">Best Ransomware Protection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/best-ransomware-protection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA Cautions of Attacks on UPS Devices</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-cautions-of-attacks-on-ups-devices/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-cautions-of-attacks-on-ups-devices/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 12:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Leaks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27816</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The Energy Department and the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) published guidelines this week on preventing attacks on UPS units. Threat actors are targeting UPS units that are...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/cisa-cautions-of-attacks-on-ups-devices/">CISA Cautions of Attacks on UPS Devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Energy Department and the US Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) published guidelines this week on preventing attacks on UPS units.</p>



<p>Threat actors are targeting UPS units that are linked to the net, typically using the original login authorizations, and the two government agencies advise disabling the access to the net by the information system of these units immediately.</p>



<p>UPS devices are connected to networks to monitor power, routine maintenance, or convenience. They are designed to supply immediate power when regular sources of power are disrupted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A feature adopted by a large number of manufacturers in the recent past is the addition of the internet and related features to their units. It has simplified administrative functions and enabled remote checks. As administrators celebrate these added values, the devices have become <a href="https://hackercombat.com/ransomware-trojans-ddos-malware-and-crypto-miners-delivered-in-log4shell-attacks/">vulnerable to malicious attacks</a>.   </p>



<p>UPS units were mostly offline until recently, humming away under desks or in equipment and server rooms, waiting for the chance to fulfill their duty in the event of a power outage. Many manufacturers, however, have incorporated internet connectivity and other capabilities into their UPS equipment in recent years to enable remote monitoring and management. These features are convenient for administrators, but they may also make the devices appealing targets for attackers looking for easy access to corporate networks.</p>



<p>The question then is, how does this happen? Hackers obtain access &#8220;usually through passwords and usernames that have never been changed,&#8221; the same applies to numerous Internet of Things (IoT) devices like smart-lighting structures and routers. Leaving the original credentials in IoT appliances and devices is not a new risk. It&#8217;s also a challenge that serves as a reminder to administrators of the value of hardening network controls.</p>



<p>UPS units are a crucial backup of power supply because of the costs of the interlude when staff devices and vital business applications can&#8217;t link to the internet. In the medical world, life may hinge on a UPS in the event of a power outage because most medical devices are powered.</p>



<p>UPSs may safeguard tiny loads, like a few servers, huge loads, similar to a whole building, or gigantic loads, equal to a data processing center, as reported by CISA.</p>



<p>The subject of who is required to handle UPS systems, which are only required amid a power loss, is one problem in an organization. An establishment may have different internal divisions responsible for the devices, including although not restricted to the IT departments, industrial maintenance, operations in the building, or contract monitoring service suppliers usually third parties, as stated by CISA.</p>



<p>CISA makes no mention of recent assaults, nor does it assign these dangers to specific culprits. But, in this scenario, the emphasis is on remedial steps or actions.</p>



<p>As a preventative measure against potential attacks that target UPS systems, businesses should take inventory of all units on their premises and ensure their disconnection from cyberspace.</p>



<p>If there isn&#8217;t any other alternative for accessing a UPS unit&#8217;s management except through the net, CISA recommends the following controls:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://hackercombat.com/comparing-two-of-the-best-vpns-nord-vs-express/">Incorporate a VPN</a>.</li><li>Adopt authentication using many factors</li><li>Change the default passwords and usernames on your UPS devices</li><li>Use compelling, long, passphrases or passwords that cannot be guessed. This is in conformance with guidelines from the National Institute of Standards and Technology (check out XKCD 936, CISA notes for a humorous description of password strength )</li><li>Make use of lockout features or embrace login timeout</li><li>All UPS units and related systems should observe the password criteria of having a solid length.</li></ul>



<p>The dangers that UPS devices face are far beyond theoretical. Armis, a security firm, recently revealed three severe flaws in several of APC&#8217;s (a sister company of Schneider Electric) Internet-connected UPS models. The devices&#8217; TLS implementation has been infected with two bugs, allowing a potential attacker to circumvent the authentication method.</p>



<p>A gap in the security of the equipment might allow the hackers to change the programming of the units and gain a long-term presence on the overall system.</p>



<p>CISA requests that organizations report any incidents or unusual activities with UPS devices.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/cisa-cautions-of-attacks-on-ups-devices/">CISA Cautions of Attacks on UPS Devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-cautions-of-attacks-on-ups-devices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacktivists Leak Email Data from Russian Pipeline Giant Transneft</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/hacktivists-leak-email-data-from-russian-pipeline-giant-transneft/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/hacktivists-leak-email-data-from-russian-pipeline-giant-transneft/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 13:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Leaks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27802</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Amid Russia&#8217;s war with Ukraine, Russian state-backed businesses continue to face attacks and data leaks from hackers. A website famous for hosting leaks released a link to around 79 gigabytes...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/hacktivists-leak-email-data-from-russian-pipeline-giant-transneft/">Hacktivists Leak Email Data from Russian Pipeline Giant Transneft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amid Russia&#8217;s war with Ukraine, Russian state-backed businesses continue to face attacks and data leaks from hackers.</p>



<p>A website famous for hosting leaks released a link to around 79 gigabytes of allegedly stolen emails from Transneft, a government-controlled Russian oil pipeline company.</p>



<p>Transneft, which has its headquarters in Moscow, is the largest pipeline company globally. The company transports oil and petroleum products between Russia and CIS countries and operates pipelines covering more than 70,000 kilometers. Under the sanctions against Russia, it cannot receive investments from the U.S. market.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://hackercombat.com/all-about-preventing-ddos-attack-on-enterprise-networks/">hacktivists</a> leaked information extracted from Transneft&#8217;s OMEGA Company, the department that deals with several disciplines of research and development.</p>



<p>Omega Company manufactures sophisticated acoustic and temperature monitoring systems for oil pipelines with its focus on leak detection.</p>



<p>The leaderless hacktivist group Anonymous claimed responsibility for the attack. Distributed Denial of Secrets (DDoSecrets), a website that hosts information leaks and compared to a modern-day WikiLeaks, posted the data. Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine is what prompted the group to hack Transneft.</p>



<p>It is essential to point out that DDoSecrets received the leaked data from Anonymous hacktivists and that the organization itself is not behind the hack.</p>



<p>The leaked data contains multiple email messages sourced from the accounts of several Transneft employees, along with attachments that include image files that have server racks and other equipment configuration, information on product shipment, invoices, among others.</p>



<p>In some of the messages, you can find the accounts of current activities and information related to the effects of sanctions that have been announced against Russia by the United States and European Union since February 25, shortly after the Russian invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Apart from sanctions, the emails revealed that the pipeline company was also worried about hackers. The leak contained a document dated March 14 with details of the security measures taken by the company in response to hacktivism targeting Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to changing passwords randomly, enabling multifactor authentication, imposing a moratorium on foreign software updates, and running a full anti-virus scan are the measures to be taken.</p>



<p>The emails also show passwords for <a href="https://hackercombat.com/is-zoom-safe-to-use/">Zoom meetings</a> that the company has organized. Some of the emails date back to 2018, but others may go back further, given the size of the leak.</p>



<p>Following recently targeted hacks against Russian companies, the website warned that ulterior motives, malware, altered or implanted data, and fake personas are highly likely in the email attachments. &#8220;As a result, we encourage readers, researchers, and journalists to take additional care with the data,&#8221; reads a note on the Distributed Denial of Secrets website.</p>



<p>In an unusual move, <a href="https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/">Distributed Denial of Secrets</a> in a note that accompanied the email upload revealed that the source dedicated the leaks to Hillary Clinton, who had publicly encouraged Anonymous to launch cyber attacks against Russian entities in an interview with MSNBC’s Morning Joe in February.</p>



<p>&#8220;I think that people who love freedom, people who understand that our way of life depends upon supporting those who believe in freedom as well, could be engaged in cyber support for those in the streets and Russia,&#8221; Clinton said.</p>



<p>&nbsp;The government of Ukraine also added its voice urging hackers to target Russia, even assembling its army of hackers to fight the invaders through cyber-action.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;In the aftermath of Russia&#8217;s invasion, Anonymous declared its full support for the Ukrainian people. Shortly after, they owned up to being behind cyberattacks against state news agencies RIA Novosti and Tass.</p>



<p>This is the latest in a growing number of hacktivist campaigns targeting Russia because of its continued aggression towards Ukraine. They claim to have hacked government agencies, private companies, and intelligence services.</p>



<p>However, not all hackers are stealing data and breaching systems. Known as squad303, one hacking group created an online tool so anyone could send emails, texts, and WhatsApp messages to Russians so they could learn about the war.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/hacktivists-leak-email-data-from-russian-pipeline-giant-transneft/">Hacktivists Leak Email Data from Russian Pipeline Giant Transneft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/hacktivists-leak-email-data-from-russian-pipeline-giant-transneft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Severe Vulnerability Patched in CRI-O Container Engine for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/severe-vulnerability-patched-in-cri-o-container-engine-for-kubernetes/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/severe-vulnerability-patched-in-cri-o-container-engine-for-kubernetes/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 13:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27776</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>A report by CrowdStrike reveals that an extreme weakness affecting the CRI-O container engine for Kubernetes could be utilized to break free from the container and gain root entry to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/severe-vulnerability-patched-in-cri-o-container-engine-for-kubernetes/">Severe Vulnerability Patched in CRI-O Container Engine for Kubernetes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A report by CrowdStrike reveals that an extreme weakness affecting the CRI-O container engine for Kubernetes could be utilized to break free from the container and gain root entry to the host. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CrowdStrike’s threat research team uncovered that lack of proper authentication for kernel parameters passed to the pinns utility caused the exposure to the bug tracked as </span><a href="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2022-0811"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CVE-2022-0811</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and dubbed creatively as cr8escape. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The high severity flaw in Argo CD is information leak risk</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and this loophole has been known to the development team since 2019 when an anti-path-traversal mechanism was added to the Argo CD, although the vulnerability exists from a control error. Argo CD is an open-source tool for Kubernetes used to monitor running applications and compare their live state. The path for this vulnerability was included in the </span><a href="https://github.com/argoproj/argo-cd/releases"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Argo CD releases v2.3.0</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, v2.2.4, and v2.1.9. Argo CD users are advised to update a patched version of the platform immediately. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This security vacuum was set in motion in CRI-O version 1.19 when sysctl support was attached to the container engine.  The </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cr8escape</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> bug which received a severity score of 7.7 out of 10 can be utilized by a rogue user to infiltrate a cluster as an administrator and install a virus and other malware. The security flaw allows an attacker to exfiltrate data and gain lateral movement across pods. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exploitation requires rights to deploy a pod on a Kubernetes cluster using the CRI-O runtime.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CVE-022-0811 is a path traversal bug that allows an attacker to load a Kubernetes Helm Chart YAML file and gain access to another application’s data. Helm charts are YAML files containing different fields that embed resources and configurations required for application deployment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The CRI-O explains that an attacker must have permissions to create or update applications and also knows or needs to guess “the full path to a file containing valid YAML” before they can exploit the vulnerability. Creating a malicious Helm chart to consume that YAML as values files can help the attacker gain access to data they would otherwise have no access to. The impact of this security breach becomes critical if confidential and sensitive data exists in the environment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As reported by CrowdStrike in its published proof-of-concept code focusing on the flaw, the consequences of this vulnerability in comparison to the broad and default use of CRI-O by many platforms is quite widespread. To prevent probable attacks, CrowdStrike recommends immediate updates of CRI-O by all users. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After the disclosure of the vulnerability by CrowdStrike, CRI-O’s developers resolved the flaw with the release of CRI-O versions 1.22.3, 1.21.6, 1.20.7, and 1.19.6, all of which contain protection and are a fix to a critical security vulnerability. CrowdStrike warns that other software platforms that use or depend on CRI-O including OpenShift and Oracle Container Engine for Kubernetes may also be vulnerable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A point to note is that “Kubernetes is not necessary to invoke CVE-2022-8011. An attacker on a machine with CRI-O installed can use it to set kernel parameters all by itself.”</span></p>
<h2><b>CrowdStrike remedy tips at both the Kubernetes and CRI-O levels include;</b></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the Kubernetes level, the security vendor said its ideal to “use policies to block pods that contain sysctl settings with ‘+’ or ‘=’ in their value.”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a “less ideal” measure, the security vendor recommended using “the PodSecurityPolicy forbiddenSysctls field to block all sysctls (it’s necessary to block all sysctls as the malicious setting is smuggled in a value).”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then obviously at the CRI-O level: upgrade to a patched version of the container runtime software. CrowdStrike also suggested users “set pinns_path in crio.conf to point to a pinns wrapper that strips the ‘-s’ option before invoking the real pinns. This will prevent pods from updating any kernel parameters, including sensitive ones.” </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although not recommended, a downgrade to CRI-O version 1.18 or earlier version could also prevent exploitation.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/severe-vulnerability-patched-in-cri-o-container-engine-for-kubernetes/">Severe Vulnerability Patched in CRI-O Container Engine for Kubernetes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/severe-vulnerability-patched-in-cri-o-container-engine-for-kubernetes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta Releases Open-Source Browser Extension for Checking Code Authenticity</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/meta-releases-open-source-browser-extension-for-checking-code-authenticity/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/meta-releases-open-source-browser-extension-for-checking-code-authenticity/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 12:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27771</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Meta, which is Facebook&#8217;s parent company, has announced the release of new technology that it aims to implement in its everyday workings. The technology, known as Code Verify, is an...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/meta-releases-open-source-browser-extension-for-checking-code-authenticity/">Meta Releases Open-Source Browser Extension for Checking Code Authenticity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta, which is Facebook&#8217;s parent company, has announced the release of new technology that it aims to implement in its everyday workings. The technology, known as Code Verify, is an open-source browser extension. The goal of the technology is to verify whether the codes that individuals input into the browser are authentic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Authenticity is the backbone of Code Verify, with most users relying on its accuracy and efficiency. The technology detects inauthentic codes people input to the browsers and notify the user about the issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta owns Facebook and, by extension, WhatsApp. When these applications have an issue with verifiable codes in the browser, Code Verify helps in that aspect.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The central aspect that drives </span>Code Verify <span style="font-weight: 400;">is the sub resource integrity. The element of sub resource integrity deals with ensuring browsers can identify the origin of a specific code.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding the code&#8217;s origin helps the application determine whether the code is verifiable. Verifiable codes allow the user to feel safe and secure to the extent that they accept the experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://engineering.fb.com/2022/03/10/security/code-verify/">Code Verify</a> relies on sub resource integrity to overcome specific issues with the integrity of a fetched file. The application depends on Cloudflare as a trusted third party.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Code Verify is an extension that the technology giant ensured they introduced to deal with various aspects of the user experience. The extension allows WhatsApp web users to find out if someone has tampered with the application.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The way the extension works on WhatsApp web is it compares its codes to those of a cryptographic source of truth. The hash source is </span>entrusted to Cloudflare<span style="font-weight: 400;">, and where the results show inconsistency between the two codes, it notifies the user.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to the third-party rights that Cloudflare offers, the checks are performed up to date and in real-time. Where the user updates WhatsApp web, Cloudflare updates the hash source of truth to enable comparison.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The extension is available for various browsers, but not all of them. The browsers it is available in are Chrome and Microsoft Edge, though they will also be available on Firefox.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Users are urged not to worry as their information is safe when used by the extension, and no data breach can occur. Meta encourages the users to trust the technology since it does not log any data or share information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta highlights that the company will not know when a user installs the extension. The Code Verify extension does not send WhatsApp users and Cloudflare information or messages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The extension runs precisely after it is installed, displaying a green icon when the validation of the code happens. When there is an issue with the extension, an orange icon appears, while a red icon appears whenever there is a security issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Code Verify has expanded the online places users can look for it from when they want to verify their applications. It is </span><a href="https://github.com/facebookincubator/meta-code-verify/">available on GitHub</a>, making it readily available to most technology users.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensuring that Code Verify is available to different users means the users and public can add their opinions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta believes the Code Verify is an innovative method the company can get behind and decide whether to implement. The extension relies on various technology that determines a chart into new territory. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The use of third-party verification on the large scale that Code Verify does is a new invention the company is trying to chart. Meta hopes more companies can take advantage of the extension and develop such technology to ensure the safety of the users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Code Verify is innovative like no other in the market at the moment. The complex extension allows users to receive a notification about whether the code they input is verifiable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meta has introduced the technology to account for WhatsApp web and ensure the application users get protection. Code Verify&#8217;s protection for the user is an essential step for building trust between the company and its customers.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/meta-releases-open-source-browser-extension-for-checking-code-authenticity/">Meta Releases Open-Source Browser Extension for Checking Code Authenticity</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/meta-releases-open-source-browser-extension-for-checking-code-authenticity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Trick by DDoS Attackers to Knock over Websites</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27758</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Attackers are finding new ways to access the websites and the browsers of different clients, affecting the user experience. The theoretical threat has become a real possibility, with attackers gaining...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/">New Trick by DDoS Attackers to Knock over Websites</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attackers are finding new ways to access the websites and the browsers of different clients, affecting the user experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The theoretical threat has become a real possibility, with attackers gaining an advantage through increased traffic to different websites.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://hackercombat.com/ransomware-trojans-ddos-malware-and-crypto-miners-delivered-in-log4shell-attacks/">Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attackers</a> are increasing, with most of them being innovative with their attacks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The attackers are using a new strategy that involves targeting vulnerable middleboxes like firewalls to increase the reach of their attacks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attackers have in the past implemented the use of amplified attacks to infect servers with a short burst of traffic as high as 3.47 Tbps. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft thwarted large-scale attacks which occurred due to an online gaming competition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the attacks are not over, with a leading content distribution firm, Akamai, reporting a wave of attacks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The firm says the attacks happened through the TCP Middlebox Reflection. The TCP reflection is a transmission control protocol among the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">founders for secured internet communication</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between machines in the same network.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Akamai put the speed of the attacks at 11 Gbps at 1.5 million packets per second (Mpps).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A research paper provided study results highlighting how amplification worked so well for the attackers. The paper showed how attackers relied on the technique to target middleboxes such as firewall.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The paper by researchers at the University of Maryland and the University of Colorado Boulder suggests the attackers could magnify how they denied their attacks by abusing middleboxes via TCP.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attacks by DDoS send small packets to the program&#8217;s server, which then replies with a larger packet size. The attackers then send the packet size to their targeted victims.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The small packets&#8217; attacks usually happen over the User Datagram Protocol (UDP). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Networks middleboxes that do not adhere to the TCP standard are the main target of TCP attacks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The research showed that hundreds of IP addresses amplified the attacks 100 times. The amplification of these attacks occurred through the utilization of middleboxes like firewall and content filtering devices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The information from the research takes us back to the beginning, where theoretical attacks have become a real possibility.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One blog post</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> talks about how alien the idea of middlebox DDoS amplification is to them. The post highlights the specific issue of amplification and its risk to the internet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like firewall, other middleboxes such as Cisco, Fortinet, PaloAlto Networks, and SonicWall form the major parts of a corporate framework. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When they enforce policies that aid filtering content, other middleboxes do not validate TCP stream states properly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Akamai suggests that users alter the boxes to respond to out-of-state TCP packets. The intended target&#8217;s responses aim to take over the client browsers to ensure they cannot access the blocked content.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The broken TCP implementation can reflect TCP traffic to the DDoS victims through abuse by the attackers, which includes data streams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through the source IP address spoofing, the attackers can abuse the middleboxes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The attackers utilize this method to ensure that traffic can be diverted from the middleboxes and carry out their attack.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The connections in TCP utilize the synchronization (SYN) control flag for easier exchange of messages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The exchange happens over a three-way handshake which the attacker intends to utilize as an attack strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In some middleboxes, the attackers tend to abuse the TCP implementation. The abuse enables the attackers to respond unexpectedly to SYN packet messages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Akamai observations also included amplification in certain instances.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some amplification instances involved single SYN packets with a 33-byte payload that produced a 2156-byte response. The production of the response amplified the size of the payload by 6.533%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amplification is a new trick that attackers have stumbled upon in their quest to access information from users. The trick has a lasting effect on some users, aided by the speed at which it generates traffic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, software developers and computer users have to be on high alert to safeguard their information from malware.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/">New Trick by DDoS Attackers to Knock over Websites</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/new-trick-by-ddos-attackers-to-knock-over-websites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA Warns of Imminent Exploits on Zabbix Monitoring Tool’s Recent Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-warns-of-imminent-exploits-on-zabbix-monitoring-tools-recent-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-warns-of-imminent-exploits-on-zabbix-monitoring-tools-recent-vulnerabilities/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 13:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27755</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This week, CISA updated Known Exploited Vulnerabilities Catalog by adding two flaws emanating from Zabbix monitoring solution. The two vulnerabilities, CVE-2022-23134 and CVE-2022-23131 could allow attackers to bypass security authentication...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/cisa-warns-of-imminent-exploits-on-zabbix-monitoring-tools-recent-vulnerabilities/">CISA Warns of Imminent Exploits on Zabbix Monitoring Tool’s Recent Vulnerabilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week, CISA updated Known Exploited Vulnerabilities Catalog by adding two flaws emanating from Zabbix monitoring solution. The two vulnerabilities, CVE-2022-23134 and CVE-2022-23131 could allow attackers to bypass security authentication and attack Zabbix.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The open-source enterprise solution tool, Zabbix, which collects and centralizes network data, and traffic, is susceptible to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">two vulnerabilities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that attackers can capitalize on by gaining administrator rights and executing arbitrary commands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The flaws are attributable to how Zabbix stores its client-side session data, leading to network compromise. The vulnerabilities were identified by researchers working for SonarSource, the code quality, and security solutions provider. The flaws affect all Web Frontend versions of Zabbix prior to versions 5.0.18, 4.0.36, and 5.4.8. Consequently, Zabbix Frontend 6.0.0beta2, 4.0.37, 5.0.19, and 5.4.9 addressed the two vulnerabilities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SonarSource asserts that once the attacker gets hold of the administrator rights, they could attack Zabbix Server linked to the monitoring tool. Additionally, the attacker can execute commands by leveraging past vulnerabilities because the Zabbix server component cannot disallow their execution.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SonarSource says that if the attackers are explicitly allowed in the configuration, they can access any attached Zabbix Server, including Zabbix agents, and execute arbitrary commands. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The attacker can exploit the security holes in situations where Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) Single-Sign-On (SSO) authentication is enabled. Despite a user validation mechanism when accessing client-side stored data, the CVE-2022-23131 flaw exists because the validation is never requested when using SAML authentication on the session entry that contains user attributes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CVE-2022-23134 compromised setup.php, accessible only to authorized privileged users. This unsafe use did not call for validation, thus allowing the attacker to rerun the final stage of the process, which creates the configuration file for Zabbix Frontend. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SonarSource further explains that the attackers can override the existing files, even though Zabbix instance is in progress, by taking over the control of a database control using a privileged administrator account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although no evidence exists yet on the attacks that exploit these vulnerabilities, public proof-of-concept (PoC) believes exploits exist. Subsequently, SonarSource reiterated that indeed Zabbix is a “high-profile target for threat actors” and further revealed that an unnamed exploit acquisition company has expressed interest in Zabbix.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the vulnerability doesn&#8217;t affect Zabbix Agent, a similar process can be used to attack the Server, which uses a database similar to Zabbix Frontend. SonarSource believes attackers could access the database (a user which can read and write to it) in order to compromise it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since Zabbix Server uses the same database, they could move laterally and gain access to the network after compromising the database. Updates for two unpatched security vulnerabilities in the open-source software management tool Zabbix were released last December. In December, Zabbix developers patched two open-source Web Frontend software vulnerabilities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, the firm published full details about the two, warning that they’re already exploited and rife out there. In addition, they urged government organizations and others to upgrade to its fixed version immediately.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) </span><a href="https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/current-activity/2022/02/22/cisa-adds-two-known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog"><span style="font-weight: 400;">warn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the security vulnerabilities in the open-source software management tool Zabbix. The two vulnerabilities, which could allow attackers to take control of a vulnerable system, were listed among the Known Exploited Vulnerabilities catalog published by CISA last month. Agencies use this catalog as a reference to check if their systems are at risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A BOD publication (22-01) of November alongside the </span><a href="https://www.cisa.gov/known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Known Exploited Vulnerabilities Catalog</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> , requires federal agencies to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">patch</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the two recently discovered vulnerabilities in Zabbix within two weeks; otherwise, their IT systems may be at risk. An attacker could take advantage of this vulnerability to gain unauthorized access to the database and use that access to steal data or access other parts of a company’s network. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/cisa-warns-of-imminent-exploits-on-zabbix-monitoring-tools-recent-vulnerabilities/">CISA Warns of Imminent Exploits on Zabbix Monitoring Tool’s Recent Vulnerabilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/cisa-warns-of-imminent-exploits-on-zabbix-monitoring-tools-recent-vulnerabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attacks against Customers of Top Brands Bank of America and Wells Fargo by Trickbot</title>
      <link>https://hackercombat.com/attacks-against-customers-of-top-brands-bank-of-america-and-wells-fargo-by-trickbot/</link>
      <comments>https://hackercombat.com/attacks-against-customers-of-top-brands-bank-of-america-and-wells-fargo-by-trickbot/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Hamilton‏]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Latest Security News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://hackercombat.com/?p=27739</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity professionals have to deal with the increasing threat of Trickbot malware. The malware uses phishing attacks and web injections to target 60 large tech companies&#8217; customers by accessing their...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/attacks-against-customers-of-top-brands-bank-of-america-and-wells-fargo-by-trickbot/">Attacks against Customers of Top Brands Bank of America and Wells Fargo by Trickbot</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity professionals have to deal with the increasing threat of Trickbot malware.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The malware uses phishing attacks and web injections to target 60 large tech companies&#8217; customers by accessing their personal information and login credentials.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Together with other simple malware such as Dridex, Agent Tesla, DanaBot, and Zeus, Trickbot started as a non-threatening bank trojan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The carrying out of a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> major police operation</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the 2016 elimination of the Dyre botnet led to the malware&#8217;s way more attention. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The international operation led by Europol and the FBI played the role of getting rid of the infrastructure supporting the Emotet Bonnet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The malware </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is prevalent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> among criminals because it can tailor its attacks. Trickbot also can perform many different attacks due to its modular nature.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A recent </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Check Point Research study</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> shows that many hackers use Trickbot to target organizations. The study indicated how the malware had become an issue for 60 large corporations, most based in the United States.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The malware&#8217;s operators do not intend to attack the company directly. Instead, they use Trickbot to leverage the reputations and names of the brands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among the brands that Trickbot is targeting, according to the study, are Wells Fargo, <a href="https://hackercombat.com/after-hacking-data-theft-european-central-bank-closes-its-website/">Bank of America</a>, Amazon, PayPal, and American Express. Others include RobinHood, Blockchain.com, and the Navy Federal Credit Union.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firms that the study concluded the Trickbot malware attack belonged to the cryptocurrency, financial firms, and technology industry.</span></p>
<h2><b>Modules that Trickbot Uses to Steal Victim’s Information</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though the Trickbot can use up to 20 modules, the study discovered three that it paid attention to over the rest. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The three modules caused some of the most straightforward issues to the PCs and affected how the users operated their systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These three modules are:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">InjectDII using web injection features.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TabDLL uses a five-step process.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pwgrabc that steals personal credentials.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The study provided the technical details on these three modules to prevent analysis and reverse engineering.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>injectDII</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first module, injectDII, has web injection features that affect a browser session for a user. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The injection includes putting JavaScript code into browsers for banking data and stealing account credentials.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The thieves do this by redirecting the users to a counterfeit page they believe one of the large corporations owns.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To prevent detection, the format for injection uses an obfuscated payload.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>TabDLL</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second module, TabDLL, has five different steps of stealing a victim&#8217;s information.:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Opening up the LSASS application for the storage of the stolen data.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Injecting the code into explorer.exe.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forcing users to enter their details then locking them out of the session.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using MIMIKATZ, the module steals the victim&#8217;s credentials from LSASS.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The module then transports the credentials to the attacker&#8217;s command-and-control center.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The module also implores </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">EternalRomance</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for exploiting and spreading the malware across SMBv1 networks.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>pwgrabc</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pwgrabc is another module that affects how the malware spreads.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The module steals victims&#8217; credentials from the specific applications that store them, such as Chrome, Firefox, and Internet Explorer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Login credentials are the most common information this module stole, ensuring the bot can spread without restrictions.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The dangers of the Trickbot are apparent, and researchers have stated they will continue to monitor how it affects users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Researchers opine that although the Trickbot&#8217;s effect is still under investigation, the creation process will not waste.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They argue that users can instill the skill and technology in the future if users can put the bot to better use.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An IBM research study shows that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">new variants</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the Trickbot malware affect computers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The variants contain specific features that block the researchers as they aim to use reverse engineering to analyze the malware.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trickbot is most likely to enter into a loop in the code beautification process. Beautification of the code involves cleaning it up for easier readability and analysis.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com/attacks-against-customers-of-top-brands-bank-of-america-and-wells-fargo-by-trickbot/">Attacks against Customers of Top Brands Bank of America and Wells Fargo by Trickbot</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://hackercombat.com">Hacker Combat</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://hackercombat.com/attacks-against-customers-of-top-brands-bank-of-america-and-wells-fargo-by-trickbot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>