<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
    <description>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</description>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rawstory.com/feeds/world.rss" rel="self">
    </atom:link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 02:25:55 -0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNDk4MDQwMC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTcwODk2ODc0NH0.CAuDKCrYnLogkIrRCoHwZj7vOQ_5oq7DyFBijbdG0dE/image.jpg?width=210</url>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
      <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>How the CIA is working with anti-Putin Russians to secretly gather information</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/anti-putin-russians/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-fbi-takes-over-internet-router-linked-to-russian-hackers-report.jpg?id=26788733&width=1200&coordinates=94%2C0%2C95%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>The CIA is working under Vladimir Putin's nose with Russians trying to circumvent his attacks on Ukraine, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/02/world/ukraine-russia-war-news#the-cia-offers-russians-a-safe-way-to-share-secrets-through-the-dark-web" target="_blank">according to a report in The New York Times</a> </p><p>The New York Times reported Monday that the US's international intelligence agency is using the dark web upload details in a way to bypass any of the Russian monitors. They're also using social media platforms like YouTube to explain to Russians how they can use private networks and a Virtual Private Network (VPN) to encrypt information.  </p><p>"The instructions, written in Russian, are meant to be relatively simple to follow," said the report. "Russians are told to use a VPN to contact the CIA They can also download the Tor browser, which allows users to access the dark web and submit information anonymously, without either the agency knowing where it came from or Russian security services knowing someone was contacting the Americans."<br/></p><p>CIA spokesperson Susan Miller explained that they're working to ensure that any Russian who wants to help the "unjust war" can do so "safely." The report also indicated they're using other means to push out information, but didn't disclose them. </p><p><u><em><strong>RELATED: </strong></em></u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/" target="_self"><u><em><strong>David Petraeus: Top Russian military official getting 'desperate' as Putin leans on him to make progress </strong></em></u></a></p><p>Tor browsers protect the identity of those using it using encryptions bouncing through various different way-points around the world making it difficult to trace. </p><p>For the past months, anti-Putin Russians have protested in whatever ways they could. Putin responded by passing new laws that effectively outlaw using the words "war" or "invasion" to describe the attacks on Ukraine. Thousands of Russians have been arrested for what they're calling "fake news" that opposes the Russian military. </p><p>“The Kremlin is wiping out all options for dissent to ensure that brave anti-war protesters do not return to the streets,” said Hugh Williamson, Europe and Central Asia director <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2022/03/07/russia-criminalizes-independent-war-reporting-anti-war-protests" target="_blank">at Human Rights Watch</a>. “When President Putin goes after such a fundamental right – the cornerstone of democracy – with such totalitarian tactics, he is dispensing with any pretense that his government has any respect for rule of law, human rights, or democracy.”</p><p>Russian Channel One producer <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-tv-protester/" target="_blank">Marina Ovsyannikova staged her own protest</a> in March, uploading a video to her Twitter account before she appeared on air with a poster saying that the government was lying to people about the war. <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/r-2656960142/" target="_blank">She now faces 15 years in prison.<br/></a></p><p><strong><em><u>RELATED: </u></em></strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/" target="_self"><strong><em><u>Pentagon 'cannot confirm' reports that Russia's top general was injured during Ukraine visit</u></em></strong> </a></p><p>After Ovsyannikova was arrested, Channel One colleague <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-russian-war-2656971912/" target="_blank">Zhanna Agalakova also quit her job</a> as the Europe correspondent for the Russian state television outlet. Two other journalists at Channel One's rival station NTV left as well. One of those was 30-year veteran reporter Vadim Glusker and Lilia Gildeyeva who has worked for the channel since 2006.</p><p>On Twitter, people post comments like "Russians, you can stop this war." But as <a href="https://mayavolf.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Maya Volf</a>, a producer for Russian YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/ivarlamov/videos" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ilya Varlamov</a> <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/how-russian-youtubers-are-trying-to-get-around-censorship/" target="_blank">explained</a>, they can't. "Even just getting information and sharing it with others is really dangerous for us and our families. For example, my husband is in Turkey right now because I am afraid for him."</p><p>Meanwhile, the hacker group Anonymous has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/r-2656999569/" target="_blank">worked on several fronts to stop</a> Putin propaganda from being distributed to Russians. They also say that they've hacked at least 700 gigs of data from <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-hacked-anonymous-data/" target="_blank">the Russian Ministry of Culture.</a> </p><p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/02/world/ukraine-russia-war-news#the-cia-offers-russians-a-safe-way-to-share-secrets-through-the-dark-web" target="_blank">Read the full report at the New York Times. </a></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/anti-putin-russians/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sarah K. Burris</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-fbi-takes-over-internet-router-linked-to-russian-hackers-report.jpg?id=26788733&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia reroutes internet traffic in occupied Ukraine to its infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-reroutes-internet-traffic-in-occupied-ukraine-to-its-infrastructure/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/white-and-blue-ceramic-round-plate.jpg?id=29751381&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C208%2C0%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>KYIV (Reuters) - Russia has rerouted internet traffic in the occupied Ukrainian region of Kherson through Russian communications infrastructure, the internet service disruption monitor NetBlocks said on Monday. The move appeared aimed at tightening Moscow's grip on a region where it claims it has taken full control. Russia-appointed authorities in parts of Kherson have said the region would start using the Russian rouble on May 1. London-based NetBlocks said it had tracked a near-total internet blackout across Kherson region on Saturday that affected various Ukrainian providers. Connection was...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-reroutes-internet-traffic-in-occupied-ukraine-to-its-infrastructure/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/white-and-blue-ceramic-round-plate.jpg?id=29751381&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia steps up Ukraine assault as US warns of annexation</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-steps-up-ukraine-as-us-warns-of-annexation/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751280&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="851ba71eb1411ba919b67b0b3832fafa" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="72568" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751282&width=980"/><figcaption>A woman who fled the besieged city of Mariupol arrives at a registration area for internally displaced people in Zaporizhzhia, Ukraine, on May 2, 2022</figcaption></figure></div><p>Zaporizhzhia (Ukraine) (AFP) - Russia on Monday launched a fresh assault on the critical Ukrainian port of Odessa as the United States warned that Moscow was preparing formally to annex embattled regions in the east.</p>
<p>The new heavy fighting came as the European Union said it was bracing for a complete end to Russian gas supplies, with the bloc preparing another package of sanctions sure to anger President Vladimir Putin.</p>
<p>After failing to take the capital Kyiv, Moscow has shifted its two-month-old invasion to largely Russian-speaking areas and has stepped up pressure on Odessa, a celebrated cultural hub that is a crucial port on the Black Sea.</p>
<p>Odessa's city council said that a Russian strike hit a residential building housing five people. A 15-year-old boy was killed and a girl was hospitalised, the council said on Telegram.</p>
<p>"A 14-year-old boy was killed. A 17-year-old girl was wounded, she has a shrapnel wound," Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky said in a video address, giving a different age for the boy.</p>
<p>"For what? What did these children... threaten the Russian state with? And that's how they fight. That's all," he said.</p>
<p>Fighting was particularly intense in eastern Ukraine around Izyum, Lyman and Rubizhne as the Russians prepared an attack on Severodonetsk, the farthest city still under Kyiv's control, Ukraine's general staff said.</p>
<p>In Lyman, relentless shelling has reduced hamlets around the city to rubble, according to AFP reporters.</p>
<p>"Half of the city is destroyed," said one resident, lifting luggage onto the roof of his beat-up Soviet-designed Lada car.</p>
<p>"I don't have a house anymore," he said.</p>
<p>The governor of the eastern region of Lugansk expected more intense battles ahead of May 9, the day Russia annually celebrates the 1945 surrender of Nazi Germany to allied forces, including the then-Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov, however, told Italian television that Moscow's forces "will not artificially adjust their actions to any date, including Victory Day".</p>
<h1>'Sham referenda'</h1>
<p>Whatever Russia's military decisions, the United States warned that Moscow was preparing imminently to annex both Lugansk and neighbouring Donetsk.</p>
<p>Pro-Russian separatists in the two regions declared independence in 2014, but Moscow has so far stopped short of formally incorporating them as it did that year with the Crimean peninsula, which it seized through special forces in unmarked uniforms.</p>
<p>"Russia plans to engineer referenda upon joining sometime in mid-May," said Michael Carpenter, the US ambassador to the Organisation for Security and Co-operation in Europe.</p>
<p>He said that Russia was considering a similar plan in a third region, Kherson, where Moscow has recently solidified control and imposed use of its ruble currency.</p>
<p>"We think the reports are highly credible," Carpenter told reporters in Washington.</p>
<p>As with Crimea, he vowed that the international community would not support Russian-dictated changes to Ukraine's borders.</p>
<p>"Such sham referenda -- fabricated votes -- will not be considered legitimate, nor will any attempts to annex additional Ukrainian territory," Carpenter said.</p>
<p>"But we have to act with a sense of urgency."</p>
<h1>Evacuating battered Mariupol</h1>
<p>The invasion has killed thousands and displaced more than 13 million people in a war the scale of which has not been seen in Europe for generations.</p>
<p>Among the most battered cities is Mariupol, where an untold number have died and survivors have little access to food, water and medicine as Russia battles to connect the southern and eastern strips of land under its control.</p>
<p>Kyiv said more than 100 civilians were evacuated over the weekend from the sprawling Azovstal steel plant, the last holdout of Ukrainian forces in Mariupol, where soldiers and civilians have been sheltering in a maze of underground tunnels.</p>
<p>Sviatoslav Palamar, deputy commander of Ukraine's Azov unit, said that another 20 people were transferred out on Monday evening, but only after a five-hour delay as "the enemy's artillery caused new rubble and destruction."</p>
<p>Ukraine and Russia have been coordinating civilian evacuations with the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>
<p>US State Department spokesman Ned Price called on Russia to allow humanitarian supplies to enter Mariupol and other besieged cities.</p>
<p>Doing so would "demonstrate that there may be a genuine humanitarian intent behind this evacuation and not just another craven attempt on the part of the Kremlin to charge the narrative," Price said.</p>
<p>Ukrainian forces have recaptured some territory in recent days, including the village of Ruska Lozova, which evacuees said had been occupied for two months.</p>
<p>"It was two months of terrible fear. Nothing else, a terrible and relentless fear," Natalia, a 28-year-old evacuee from Ruska Lozova, told AFP after reaching Kharkiv.</p>
<p>But Kyiv has admitted that Russian forces have captured a string of villages in the east and has asked Western powers to deliver more heavy weapons to bolster its defences there.</p>
<p>Ukraine's defence ministry said Monday that its drones had sunk two Russian patrol boats near the Black Sea's Snake Island, which became a symbol of Ukrainian resistance after soldiers there rebuffed Russian demands to surrender.</p>
<p>"The Bayraktars are working," said Valeriy Zaluzhnyi, the commander in chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, referring to Turkish-made military drones.</p>
<h1>Bracing for new sanctions</h1>
<p>Western powers have levelled unprecedented sanctions against Russia over the war while delivering money and weapons to Ukraine, including a $33-billion (31 billion-euro) arms and support package announced by US President Joe Biden last week.</p>
<p>The European Commission will on Tuesday propose a new package of sanctions, including an embargo on Russian oil, officials said.</p>
<p>After talks on Monday, the European Union warned member states to prepare for a possible complete breakdown in gas supplies from Russia, insisting it would not cede to Moscow's demand that imports be paid for in rubles.</p>
<p>Germany, Europe's largest economy, before the war became heavily dependent on Russian gas, but European views quickly hardened after Putin attacked Ukraine.</p>
<p>EU and French officials said the 27-member bloc was united with Poland and Bulgaria, whose gas supplies were cut last week after they refused to pay in rubles.</p>
<p>Meanwhile British Prime Minister Boris Johnson will announce Tuesday another £300 million ($376 million, 358 million euros) in military aid for Ukraine, his office said.</p>
<p>In a new blow to Russian prestige, European football's governing body, UEFA, announced that Russian clubs had been banned from participating in the Champions League and all other European competitions next season.</p>
<p>Western nations have been trying to show support by reopening embassies in Kyiv that were closed due to the invasion, with Denmark the latest to make the move Monday.</p>
<p>Kristina Kvien, the US charge d'affaires, announced in the western city of Lviv that Washington hopes to have diplomats back in Kyiv by the end of May.</p>
<p>burs-st/caw</p>
</div>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-steps-up-ukraine-as-us-warns-of-annexation/</guid>
      <category>Ukraine</category>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Conflict</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>AFP</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751280&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Petraeus: Top Russian military official getting 'desperate' as Putin leans on him to make progress</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C45%2C0%2C45&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>On Monday, former Gen. David Petraeus told CNN's Jake Tapper that a key Russian military official is feeling the heat for the ongoing failure of the invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>"We're told that the chief of staff for the Russian military recently visited Ukraine, including the Donbas region," said Tapper. "The U.S. says it isn't sure why he traveled to the Russian front lines. What do you make of that?"</p><p>"Well, he's probably trying to figure out what is going on, why can't we make progress?" said Petraeus, who previously headed the CIA. "He's down there trying to work with the commander. You know, they now have one commander in charge, General Dvornikov, the Butcher of Syria, known for the bombing of Aleppo in 2016. They really haven't made the progress that they hoped to achieve. And so he's probably down there trying to figure out why is it that we can't achieve combined armed effects. Why is it we can't integrate air and ground operations, why aren't we doing better? And of course, he did narrowly avoid, apparently, the demolition of the command post at which he was located during his visit. With a loss of another Russian general, reportedly."</p><p>"So again, he is probably getting desperate," said Petraeus. "I'm sure that President Putin is putting enormous pressure on him and on Defense Minister Shoigu, to achieve something, again, that he can announce, Putin can announce, on 9 May in Moscow."</p><p><u><em><strong>RELATED: </strong></em></u><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/" target="_self"><u><em><strong>Russia just demonstrated their ‘total depravity’ – according to this former US ambassador </strong></em></u></a></p><p>Petraeus has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/consequences-for-putin-s-war-on-ukraine-are-going-to-start-to-come-home-to-roost-in-moscow-gen-david-petraeus/" target="_blank">previously predicted</a> that Putin will face severe political consequences for the Ukraine invasion as the worldwide embargo against Russia causes economic collapse. The war, which experts once feared would result in Russia rapidly seizing the capital city of Kyiv, has stalled out with Russia struggling to hold territory in the east.</p><p>It's been claimed that numerous Russian generals have also been killed in combat, which Petraeus has <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-war-why-are-so-many-russian-generals-being-killed/" target="_blank">explained</a> is due to a breakdown in the Russian military's command structure.</p><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/" target="_blank">Watch below or at this link</a>: </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="1a9227ba18a54d18491faf9c7921b3c9" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xetwATi_-IU?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">David Petraeus says Russian military chief of staff is "desperate"</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xetwATi_-IU" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p><strong><br/></strong></p><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p>
<p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/petraeus-ukraine/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter estimates spam, fake accounts comprise less than 5% of users</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/twitter-estimates-spam-fake-accounts-comprise-less-than-5-of-users-filing/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751286&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Sheila Dang (Reuters) -Twitter Inc estimated in a filing on Monday that false or spam accounts represented fewer than 5% of its monetizable daily active users during the first quarter. The social media company had 229 million users who were served advertising in the first quarter. The disclosure came days after Tesla Inc Chief Executive Elon Musk, who has inked a deal to buy Twitter for $44 billion, tweeted that one of his priorities would be to remove "spam bots" from the platform. Twitter said in the filing it faced several risks until the deal with Musk is closed, such as whether adverti...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/twitter-estimates-spam-fake-accounts-comprise-less-than-5-of-users-filing/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29751286&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there solid evidence that Hitler had 'Jewish blood'? Here is what historians say</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/is-there-solid-evidence-that-hitler-had-jewish-blood-here-s-what-historians-say/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/hitler.jpg?id=26573801&width=1200&coordinates=95%2C0%2C96%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>The suggestion by Russia's foreign minister that Adolf Hitler had Jewish blood is just the latest version of a conspiracy theory exploiting a gap in the dictator's ancestry.</p><p>Sergei Lavrov's remarks at the weekend, which have sparked a diplomatic row with Israel, reheats rumours over the identity of Hitler's paternal grandfather dating as far back as the 1920s.</p><p>Hitler's father, Alois, was an illegitimate child whose own father was unknown, Austrian historian Roman Sandgruber told AFP.</p><p>Sandgruber, who last year published the first biography of Alois Hitler, explained that the rumours first began circulating in the 1920s, as Adolf Hitler began his rise to power.</p><p>The theory was encouraged by Hitler's political rivals as the Nazi leader took control of Germany in 1933.</p><p>Then after World War II, the memoirs of Nazi war criminal Hans Frank, who governed occupied Poland during the war, revived the story.</p><p>In his memoirs, published after his 1946 execution for war crimes, Frank said he had secretly researched Hitler's ancestry at the request of the Nazi leader himself.</p><p>"This must have been towards the end of the 1930s," wrote Frank, in an extract published by Germany's Der Spiegel magazine at the time.</p><p>Hitler, he said, had told him he was being blackmailed by a nephew over the matter.</p><p>Hitler's paternal grandmother Maria Anna Schicklgruber gave birth to Alois in 1837.</p><p>Frank claimed to have discovered that, at the time, she was employed as a cook for a Jewish family by the name of Frankenberger, in the Austrian city of Graz.</p><p>Her employer had paid her maintenance until Alois reached the age of 14, wrote Frank, claiming that an exchange of letters between her and the family proved this.</p><p>Frank said Hitler had told him that actually his grandmother and her future husband had let the Jewish man think he was the father in order to get the money out of him.</p><p>But historians remain sceptical.</p><p>There is no solid evidence to support Frank's claims, says Sandgruber. One problem is that, at the time in question, Jews did not have the right to live in Graz, he adds.</p><p>So who was Hitler's grandfather? "This is a question without an answer," historian Ofer Aderet wrote in Israel's Haaretz newspaper Monday.</p><p>Some Nazis still aired this theory "as an attempt to provide an explanation for their defeat in World War II", he argued.</p><p>"Other reports claimed that Hitler's persecution of the Jews resulted from feelings of shame about his partial Jewish ancestry," he added.</p><p>"The bottom line, though, is that there is no historical proof for any of this."</p><p>Israel's Foreign Minister Yair Lapid on Monday condemned Lavrov's remarks as "an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error.</p><p>"Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust," Lapid added. This kind of claim was the worst kind of anti-Semitism, he said.</p><p>Prime Minister Naftali Bennett denounced Lavrov's comments as "lies", and the foreign ministry has summoned Russia's ambassador for an explanation.</p><p>Russia has repeatedly justified what it calls its "special military operation" in Ukraine as a mission to "demilitarise" and "denazify" the country.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 21:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/is-there-solid-evidence-that-hitler-had-jewish-blood-here-s-what-historians-say/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/hitler.jpg?id=26573801&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon 'cannot confirm' reports that Russia's top general was injured during Ukraine visit</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/sergei-shoigu-and-valery-gerasimov.jpg?id=29750836&width=1200&coordinates=126%2C0%2C0%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>Russia's top general, Valery Gerasimov, visited the Donbas front in the Ukraine war last week, a Pentagon official said Monday, but reports that he was injured in a Ukrainian attack could not be confirmed.</p><p>"What we can confirm is that we know that for several days last week he was in the Donbas," a senior US defense official told journalists.</p><p>"We don't believe that he's still there -- that he has left and he's back in Russia," the official said.</p><p>"We cannot confirm reports that he was injured."</p><p>According to reports citing Ukraine officials, on Saturday Ukraine forces shelled a command center in Izium, where Gerasimov, chief of general staff of the Russian armed forces, visited to meet with top field commanders.</p><p>But he had apparently left the site before the shelling took place.</p><p>Gerasimov was believed to be touring the front to better understand field conditions and rally his troops as Russian forces, after failing to capture Kyiv in the north, attempt to take control of the Donetsk and Luhansk regions of the east.</p><p>In a daily briefing on the war, the Pentagon official said Monday that Russian forces were making minimal progress in a tough fight against Ukraine troops in the region and called their efforts "anemic."</p><p>"We continue to see minimal at best progress by the Russians in the Donbas. They've had some minor gains east of Izium and Popasna in the Luhansk Oblast."</p><p>The officials described the Russians as winning control of villages, then ceding them back to Ukraine fighters, and characterized Russian forces as demoralized and suffering from poor leadership and organization.</p><p>The Russian effort on the ground is "very tepid, very uneven... and in some cases, quite frankly, the best word to describe it would be anemic," the official said.</p><p>The official did not provide any similar assessment of Ukraine forces.</p><p>Arms deliveries from the United States and Western allies to Ukraine, including heavy artillery, radar systems, and attack drones, continue at a high pace, the official said.</p><p>Over the last 24 hours, two dozen flights carrying US arms landed near Ukraine, and another 11 were planned over the coming 24 hours, officials said.</p><p><strong>NOW WATCH:<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank"> 'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 20:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-official/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/sergei-shoigu-and-valery-gerasimov.jpg?id=29750836&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia just demonstrated their ‘total depravity’ – according to this former US ambassador</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/testimony-by-top-diplomat-bill-taylor-on-trump-and-ukraine-elicits-disturbed-responses-from-members-of-congress.jpg?id=24839692&width=1200&coordinates=11%2C0%2C12%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>Responding to recent <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/02/world/europe/israel-russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov.html" target="_blank">comments</a> from Russian foreign minister Sergei V. Lavrov, former U.S. ambassador William Taylor said the remarks "just demonstrate the total depravity, really, evil nature of the Russian government top to bottom." <br/></p><p>"It demonstrates that there is no justification, there <em>was</em> no justification, there's no rationale for this invasion," Taylor said during an MSNBC segment. "Ukraine posed no threat to the Russians -- they [the Russians] had to manufacture some reason ... the moral clarity of this war is there for all to see." </p><p>Moscow has previously claimed that it wants to "de-militarize" and "de-Nazify" Ukraine.</p><p>Lavrov, speaking to Italian outlet Mediaset's Rete 4 channel in an interview released Sunday, claimed that Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy "puts forward an argument of what kind of Nazism can they have if he himself is Jewish."</p><p>Lavrov, according to a transcript posted on the Russian foreign ministry website, then added: "I could be wrong, but Hitler also had Jewish blood."</p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/south-carolina-republican-arrested/" target="_self">South Carolina GOP county chairman arrested for alleged child abuse</a></em></strong></p><p>The comment also prompted fierce criticism from Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid.</p><p>"Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust," Lapid said in a statement. "The lowest level of racism against Jews is to accuse Jews themselves of antisemitism."</p><p>Israel's foreign ministry "has summoned the Russian Ambassador to Israel for a clarification meeting", the statement added.</p><p>Prime Minister Naftali Bennett then denounced Lavrov's "lies" that he said effectively "accuse the Jews themselves of the most awful crimes in history," perpetrated against them.</p><p><em><span></span><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/" target="_blank">Watch the video below or watch here</a>. </em></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d9f69e87c455bc8cf8f7eb1a4147e0d0" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TtukiZG9ac?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">05 02 2022 12 10 21</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6TtukiZG9ac" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p><em>With additional reporting via AFP</em><br/></p><p><strong><br/></strong></p><p><strong>NOW WATCH:<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank"> 'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</a></strong></p>
<p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d26026580ac0681adc0885f5bbe275e" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5J7DU9o6Gk?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">'Extremely dangerous' murder suspect and Alabama jail officer suspected of fleeing together</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U5J7DU9o6Gk" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 18:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-depravity-jewish-hitler/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sky Palma</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/testimony-by-top-diplomat-bill-taylor-on-trump-and-ukraine-elicits-disturbed-responses-from-members-of-congress.jpg?id=24839692&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QAnon leader who claims to be 'Queen of Canada' says Biden has asked her to mediate Russian peace talks</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/romana-didulo-2657250121/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/romana-didulo.png?id=29749365&width=1200&coordinates=43%2C0%2C83%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>QAnon influencer Romana Didulo claims President Joe Biden has asked her to mediate talks between the U.S. and Russia over the war in Ukraine.</p><p>Didulo, who also claims to be "queen of Canada," says she asked Biden to provide her with her own aircraft to fly to Moscow, or possibly St. Petersburg, for the talks, according to BBC correspondent Shayan Sardarizadeh.</p><p>"I address you today as your commander in chief and Queen," Didulo says in a video posted online. "to the Russian and American people, I address you as the mediator between the United States and Russia pertaining to the Ukraine crises. I have been requested by the commander in chief of the United States armed forces to act as the mediator between Russia and the United States."</p><p>Didulo claimed that aircraft would bear the flag of the "Kingdom of Canada" and be known as "Queen Romana," or "QR1," and she said she asked for military escort for her journey with 13-15 staffers.</p><p>In reality, Biden has not asked Didulo to be a mediator and she will not be getting her own special aircraft to fly to Eastern Europe.</p><p><em>Watch the video below</em>.<br/></p><p><br/></p><blockquote class="rm-embed twitter-tweet" data-partner="rebelmouse" data-twitter-tweet-id="1521158285210046465">
<div style="margin:1em 0">QAnon "queen of Canada" Romana Didulo says she's been asked by Joe Biden to "act as the mediator" between the US and Russia over the war in Ukraine. She's asked Biden to provide her with a "queen Romana one" aircraft for her journey to Moscow.pic.twitter.com/5eSdjDPA9b</div> — Shayan Sardarizadeh (@Shayan Sardarizadeh)
        <a href="https://twitter.com/Shayan86/statuses/1521158285210046465">1651507371</a>
</blockquote>
<script async="" charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script><p><strong>NOW WATCH: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X5Ewlf2zcig" target="_blank">Marjorie Taylor Greene says she opposes welfare because women 'need to be married'</a></strong></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="07d49712fb756df44e7bd0f5e918add5" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X5Ewlf2zcig?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Marjorie Taylor Greene says she opposes welfare because women 'need to be married'</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X5Ewlf2zcig" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>
]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/romana-didulo-2657250121/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Travis Gettys</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/romana-didulo.png?id=29749365&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/png">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swiss parliament gets climate lecture after father's hunger strike</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/swiss-parliament-gets-climate-lecture-after-father-s-hunger-strike/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29749217&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Emma Farge and Cecile Mantovani BERN (Reuters) -Climate scientists took turns to deliver speeches on the perils of global warming to the Swiss parliament on Monday in an event triggered by the hunger strike of a frustrated Swiss father on its doorstep last year. Guillermo Fernandez, a father of three, ended a 39-day hunger strike in December when the government submitted to his demand for the session. "It's really fantastic to be here knowing that today the facts are going to be laid out to parliament and the whole Swiss people," he told Reuters in Federal Square, the location of his strike...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/swiss-parliament-gets-climate-lecture-after-father-s-hunger-strike/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29749217&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel keen to set up cyber 'Iron Dome' to curb rise in attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-keen-to-set-up-cyber-iron-dome-to-curb-rise-in/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748621&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="64a387c4a9478e41538ada0469a94baf" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="66f10" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748624&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Steven Scheer</p>
<p>TEL AVIV (Reuters) - Israel's government on Monday ordered communications firms to step up their cyber security efforts in the wake of a rise in attempted hacking attacks.</p>
<p>New regulations are currently being implemented in which mandatory and unified standards will have to be met, the Communications Ministry and Israel's National Cyber Directorate said.</p>
<p>Under the new rules, firms must formulate plans to protect communications networks using a combination of monitoring and control mechanisms to make it possible to establish an up to date picture of cyber protection while ensuring privacy.</p>
<p>"We are trying to put the right standard on communications companies in order to protect Israel and create a kind of 'Iron Dome' from cyber security attacks. We are suffering from thousands of cyber attacks every year," Communications Minister Yoaz Hendel told a news conference.</p>
<p>Israel uses an Iron Dome air-defence system to intercept rockets fired by Palestinian militants, mostly from Gaza.</p>
<p>Hendel said that risks continued to mount, along with more digitisation.</p>
<p>"Communications networks are an attractive target for cyber attacks by hostile elements," Hendel said, citing potential damage or shutdown of services and leakage of information being stored.</p>
<p>According to cyber security firm Check Point, there was a 137% annual jump in average weekly attacks on Israeli companies, to nearly 1,500 per week, in the first three months of 2022.</p>
<p>Gaby Portnoy, Israel's new cyber security czar, said in the last month alone, Israel had seen a sharp rise in attacks trying to bring down websites. He accused Iranians of carrying out many of the attacks.</p>
<p>Last month, he noted, a denial of service attack aimed at bringing down government sites began through telecom providers but ultimately failed.</p>
<p>Portnoy said Israeli telecoms firms had very good cyber security but that the new regulations, which include a higher level of supervision, would be an improvement.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Steven Scheer; Editing by Jeffrey Heller and Bernadette Baum)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 15:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-keen-to-set-up-cyber-iron-dome-to-curb-rise-in/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748621&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Lowest level of racism': Israeli foreign minister buries Russia's Lavrov for comparing Zelenskyy to Hitler</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/sergei-lavrov/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748705&width=1200&coordinates=72%2C0%2C54%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>In response to remarks by Kremlin foreign minister Sergei Lavrov, who said that Adolf Hitler “had Jewish blood” and that the “most rabid antisemites tend to be Jews," Israel has summoned the Russian ambassador and demanded an apology, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/02/israel-summons-russia-envoy-sergei-lavrov-hitler-comments" target="_blank">The Guardian reports</a>. </p><p>Lavrov made comments while defending Russia's invasion of Ukraine, claiming that the Russian military is carrying out a campaign of "denazification." </p><p>“As to [Zelenskiy’s] argument of what kind of nazification can we have if I’m Jewish, if I remember correctly, and I may be wrong, Hitler also had Jewish blood,” Lavrov said during an interview with Italian television channel Mediaset. “It doesn’t mean anything at all.”</p><p>“We have for a long time listened to the wise Jewish people who say that the most rabid antisemites tend to be Jews,” Lavrov continued. “There is no family without a monster.”</p><p>In a statement, Israel's foreign minister Yair Lapid said Lavrov’s remarks "are both an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error."</p><p>“Jews did not murder themselves in the Holocaust. The lowest level of racism against Jews is to accuse Jews themselves of antisemitism," he said.</p><p><em>Read more at <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/may/02/israel-summons-russia-envoy-sergei-lavrov-hitler-comments" target="_blank">The Guardian</a>. </em></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/sergei-lavrov/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sky Palma</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748705&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian generals 'extremely frustrated' as they fail all of Putin's 'strategic objectives': CNN military analyst</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=1200&coordinates=0%2C45%2C0%2C45&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>On CNN Monday, Ret. Lt. Gen. Mark Hertling addressed the risk that Vladimir Putin escalates to using weapons of mass destruction in the invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>"I'm sure Mr. Putin and his generals are extremely frustrated, but truthfully, from the very beginning, as we said, they have not put the kind of forces and they have not had the kind of synchronization you need," said Hertling.</p><p>"There's a school of thought — Peggy Noonan wrote, 'The worse Putin's army does on the ground, the greater risk he takes an outlier move, such as using tactical nuclear weapons,'" said CNN anchor Jim Sciutto. "Again, I don't want to overstate that risk. I know it is one the Pentagon takes, at least seriously, and watches for any signs of. Putin can't lose, right? So, do you worry that as he gets more frustrated, that risk becomes greater?"</p><p>"I don't worry about it, Jim, but it is certainly a concern," said Hertling. "I think the intelligence indicators are focused on what might create those kinds of uses of extreme weapons, weapons of mask destruction. So, I firmly believe that the U.S. government and NATO is watching very closely for any indicators of the use of chemical or nuclear weapons and there will be a reaction to that, or preemption in some cases, if that happens."</p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/trump-supporter-kicked-off-plane/" target="_self">Slur-spewing couple kicked off flight — and complain it's because they're Trump supporters</a></em></strong></p><p>"You know, folks — the pundits since the very beginning have said, if we push too hard, Russia is going to use some kind of extreme measure," Hertling continued. "That is certainly a consideration. What we've seen so far is, Mr. Putin, since the very beginning, has failed in achieving every one of his strategic objectives. </p><p>"He continues to adjust his operational objectives. And even then, he continues to fail. So, you know, when you're talking about what is next for him, man, I hope that there's a potential that the Russian people will see what's happening and as more news gets back to the population, that they will take action and get this individual out of the leadership of Russia."</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/" target="_blank">Watch the video below or at this link.</a></strong></p><p><br/></p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="dee536be12c69d91d3a4250776252140" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vh1qfjMisdY?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Mark Hertling says Russian generals are "frustrated"</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vh1qfjMisdY&feature=youtu.be" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-generals-increasingly-frustrated-as-they-fail-all-of-putin-s-strategic-objectives-cnn-military-analyst/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global forecaster on 'another bad year for democracy': Is the world near a dire tipping point?</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/democracy-2657249124/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-gallows-set-up-by-the-capitol-rioters-screengrab.png?id=27789537&width=1200&coordinates=62%2C0%2C63%2C0&height=800"/><br/><br/><p>Global democracy is sick. In the United States, Donald Trump's supporters in the Republican Party <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/15/do-the-democrats-know-how-to-fight-jan-6-committee-signals-its-still-scared-of/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">continue to steamroll the Democrats and other pro-democracy forces</a>. To say that the latter have for the most part been hapless, uncoordinated and paralyzed by denial is not overstating the case. </p><p>Political scientists and other experts have warned that in the wake of the Trump presidency and the coup attempt of January 2021, the country is now an "anocracy," hovering in limbo between naked authoritarianism and a slowly failing democracy.</p><p>As I have repeatedly warned <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/28/latest-hate-rally-a-master-class-in-mind-control/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this is an existential struggle</a>: If the Republicans and the larger white right achieve their goals the United States will become a living nightmare for anyone who is not a rich white "Christian" heterosexual male, or otherwise deemed to be a "real American" and one of the MAGA-elect Trump cultists.</p><p>Writing at the Financial Times, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a2e499d0-10f0-4fa2-8243-e23eedc4f9f4" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">columnist Martin Wolf describes this moment</a> of peril and impending disaster:</p><blockquote>"An American 'Caesarism' has now become flesh." I wrote this in March 2016, even before Donald Trump had become the Republican nominee for the presidency. Today, the transformation of the democratic republic into an autocracy has advanced. By 2024, it might be irreversible. If this does indeed happen, it will change almost everything in the world….<br/>Thus, health permitting, Trump will be the next Republican candidate. He will be backed by a party that is now his tool. Most important, in the words of David Frum, erstwhile speechwriter for George W Bush, "what the United States did not have before 2020 was a large national movement willing to justify mob violence to claim political power. Now it does." It does so because its members believe their opponents are not "real" Americans. A liberal democracy cannot long endure if a major party believes defeat is illegitimate and must be rendered impossible.<br/></blockquote><p>Political scientist Thomas Homer-Dixon echoed these concerns in a <a href="https://homerdixon.com/states-of-emergency/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">widely read essay</a> last December in the Globe and Mail, warning that American democracy could collapse by 2015, "causing extreme domestic political instability, including widespread civil violence, and that by 2030, "if not sooner, the country could be governed by a right-wing dictatorship":</p><blockquote>We mustn't dismiss these possibilities just because they seem ludicrous or too horrible to imagine. In 2014, the suggestion that Donald Trump would become president would also have struck nearly everyone as absurd. But today we live in a world where the absurd regularly becomes real and the horrible commonplace.<br/>Leading American academics are now actively addressing the prospect of a fatal weakening of U.S. democracy…. Once Republicans control Congress, Democrats will lose control of the national political agenda, giving Mr. Trump a clear shot at recapturing the presidency in 2024. And once in office, he will have only two objectives: vindication and vengeance.<br/></blockquote><p>In the shadow of such darkness we must not surrender to despair. That is how the global right and the fascist movement wins. Instead, those who believe in true social democracy and the liberal democratic project must stare unflinchingly into the darkness, exile the hope-peddlers and naïve optimists who believe that compromise with such evil is possible, critically assess the reality of the crisis, and then organize and rally to victory.</p><p>Two months ago, Russian President Vladimir Putin, a hero and champion of the global right, unleashed a devastating war of aggression against Ukraine. The Ukrainians have resisted valiantly, and <a href="https://www.salon.com/2022/04/19/colin-clarke-truth-facts-ukraine/" target="_blank">Russia's military has been embarrassed</a>. What many experts foresaw as a quick campaign of conquest appears that it will now be a long slog of grinding death and destruction. The United States and its NATO allies have rallied to the aid of Ukraine; for the moment, at least, Western democracy seems (superficially) renewed through conflict with its former Cold War enemy.</p><p>French President Emmanuel Macron recently defeated Marine Le Pen and the far-right National Rally Party in that country's recent elections. However important that victory appears during this moment of democratic crisis, one should still be cautious for what it ultimately means about the power of the global right and its power in France and other Western European democracies. In her newsletter Lucid, historian Ruth Ben-Ghiat unpacks the larger significance of Le Pen's near-miss, which could have led to "the first female-led far-right government in Europe":</p><blockquote>In the conclusion to my 2020 book on the subject, I singled Le Pen out in suggesting that such a shift is inevitable. "That male model of authoritarian power... may give way in the future as female-led authoritarian states emerge. ... Yet a female-led rightist state would pose no threat to authoritarianism's appeal as a legitimating force of misogyny, kleptocracy, and, in many countries, White racial domination." ...<br/>For some voters, her "softer" feminine image likely goes a long way in making her seem acceptable. Her tasteful and understated clothing blunts the brute force of her racist proposals, such as her idea of eliminating birthright citizenship to more easily target French Muslims for discrimination. ... <br/>In fact, as the global right doubles down on its attention to families — claiming it is a priority to protect children and schools from pedophilic homosexuals, satanist Soros puppets, childless left-wing radicals, and more — being a mother, who can mobilize other mothers, will become an advantage in politics. …<br/>In the coming years, shifts in far-right tactics intended to normalize extremism and the aging of the current strongman cohort will likely produce a new wave of illiberal female leaders.<br/>While these authoritarians won't pose bare-chested, in the tradition of Benito Mussolini and Putin, they will be just as racist, corrupt, and violent as like-minded male leaders, and just as dedicated to using disinformation to create the alternate reality they need to stay in power.<br/></blockquote><p>A hopeful commitment to the basic idea that progress and societal improvement are attainable constitute the beating heart of the centuries-old Western democratic project. The fascist tide can be beaten back by leaning into those democratic and pluralistic values and dreams and then making them real for the mass public.</p><p>The global democracy crisis is real; the future remains unwritten and what happens next is very much in flux.</p><p>What do we know and where do we go from here? In an effort to answer these questions, I recently spoke with <a href="https://www.eiu.com/analysts/andrew-salomone-viteritti" target="_blank">Andrew Viteritti</a>, a senior member of the global forecasting team at the Economist Intelligence Unit, about its recent report, "Democracy Index 2021: the China Challenge."</p><p>In this conversation, Viteritti explains the unit's findings that how global democracy has fallen to its lowest levels since the Economist began tracking it in 2016. He also reports that in many "advanced" or "mature" democracies there is growing cynicism and distrust of government and its ability to solve problems such as price inflation or the COVID pandemic, and that those sentiments are being exploited by illiberal and other anti-democracy forces. Viteritti also discusses the challenge that China's "state capitalism" model represents for global democracy, and what Donald Trump's coup attempt of 2021 and related events tell us about extreme partisan political polarization and how it has imperiled the basic functions of government.</p><p>Toward the end of this conversation, Viteritti expresses optimism that despite all these challenges to democracy in the U.S. and around the world, democratic institutions have shown themselves to be much stronger than many expected, which should be a source of hope for the future. </p><p><em>This conversation has been edited for clarity and length.</em></p><p><strong>How are you feeling about democracy and the overall state of the world, as it faces so many political and other crises?</strong></p><p>The most recent edition of the Democracy Index shows that we've seen another bad year for democracy. The average global score has continued to decline. It is now at an all-time low by our measurements, 5.28 out of a scale of 10. That is a bigger decline than what we saw even in our previous studies, in the 2020 study, which is remarkable when you consider that was the year when the coronavirus pandemic hit. That had many implications for the state of democratic institutions, and also public perceptions towards government.</p><p>It is important to note that the decline that we saw in 2021 was only matched once before in our history of the study, which started in 2006. That was in 2010, in the shadow of the global financial crisis.</p><p>In our new study, many of what we call "full democracies" have also now fallen down to the "flawed democracy" category. We saw the number of authoritarian regimes increase as well. We also saw every region suffer a decline in its average score, except for Eastern Europe. The score there was unchanged. It is a very reasonable response to all this to feel very concerned and very discouraged.</p><p><strong>The public mood, both here in the United States and around the world, is that something is very wrong. How do we quantify that?</strong></p><p>One of the tools that we use for scoring individual countries is called the World Values Survey. It's authoritative, it's global in focus, it's up to date and it's standardized. We have results for the 165 countries and two territories that we cover in the Democracy Index. What we are seeing is that there is certainly a souring of public attitudes worldwide toward political institutions, the capacity of governments to respond to pressing concerns about the state of the economy and economic security, political concerns and also social concerns.</p><p>This is a trend that we've seen become acute in specific regions across the world as well as in specific countries, the United States included. These trends were at play before the coronavirus pandemic happened, but the pandemic accentuated and aggregated these trends, and even made these negative trends appear in countries where we had not seen evidence for such attitudes before. One example would be Canada, where there is a growing skepticism towards the ability of government to respond to these big societal and economic and political issues.</p><p><strong>Canada just endured mass protests and disruptions by a so-called Freedom Convoy of truckers supposedly protesting COVID restrictions and protocols. What do we know about such anxieties and anger?</strong></p><p>That reflects an increasing skepticism toward government and the capacity of governments to act effectively to solve collective problems. Canada is a very mature and strong democracy. But we still have seen a slippage in that country's ranking in our study in the functioning of government and measures of the health of political culture.</p><p>There has also been a hardening of attitudes. This has manifested itself in various countries. For example, in the United States there is intense polarization. Society has become incredibly divided, to the point where public consensus has virtually collapsed on even basic fundamental issues such as election results and public health practices around the pandemic. That was a trend that we discussed at length in our 2020 report for the Democracy Index and another trend that we explored in our most recent 2021 edition for the United States.</p><p>Polarization now has become the biggest threat to United States democracy, because not only has it generated an intense cleavage in United States society where we have these two camps that do not see eye to eye, but it has translated into the fact that it is now very hard for political institutions and democratic institutions to function. Looking at the data, there is little to suggest that polarization and that hardening of attitudes is going to ease up anytime soon. Reproductive rights are a big fault line right now. And of course, we're in a period where key elections are approaching, the midterms this year and the presidential election in 2024. Both Republicans and Democrats are going to frame these elections in existential terms. This does not bode well for the state of polarization in the United States, nor does it suggest that we're going to see things get better anytime soon.</p><p><strong>Whatever happened to the "end of history" and the ultimate triumph of liberal democracy?</strong></p><p>In this year's Democracy Index report we focus on what we describe as the "China challenge." We are in a moment where there is tension and conflict between two very distinct political systems. Is there a "China model" for democracy? What are its features? Is that sustainable? Can it be exported? Does China's leadership even want their system of government to be exported? Our quick answer to that is no.</p><p>We also look at the Western democratic model. Is there a democratic recession in the West, which many have been talking about, and which our studies certainly suggest is true over the years? We examine the causes and symptoms, and then ultimately what can be done to stop it. Ultimately, is the Western model of democracy — with its supposed superiority — sustainable?</p><p>There are some reasons to be optimistic when it comes to the state of democracy in the world, including the United States. One, we've seen very impressive voter participation in the United States. There was record voter turnout in the November 2020 elections. There was also record voter turnout in the runoff elections in Georgia that took place shortly afterward. And there are many reasons to believe we're going to see high voter participation and political engagement continue throughout this year, especially in the run-up to the midterms.</p><p>It is impossible to not think of the extraordinary events that happened at the beginning of 2021, which was our assessment period for the new study. Of course, we saw Donald Trump refuse to accept the results of an election that was held in a free and fair way. We saw Republican lawmakers also back that effort. We saw a sizable portion of the electorate refuse to accept those results.</p><p>It was pretty extraordinary to then see that Joe Biden's inauguration took place very smoothly. During Biden's first year in office, he didn't really face any major disruptions. To our eyes, that points to the strength and durability of United States political institutions. It is fair to assume that a smooth transition of power for Biden and a lack of disturbances over the first year in office for the new president would not have taken place in a country with weaker democratic institutions.</p><p>But at the same time, it is important not to take those institutions for granted. It remains to be seen whether these institutions can withstand similar types of stresses to those they saw at the beginning of 2021 and even during 2020, whether in terms of frequency or in terms of magnitude.</p><p><strong>What do we know about the health of global democracy and how it was impacted by the pandemic?</strong></p><p>There is a valid question as to whether, once we emerge from the pandemic, we will see any improvement in the democracy scores in our study. That may very well happen, especially since some of the indicators we use include public perceptions of things like whether governments are responding to crises effectively, and also questions about personal freedom.</p><p>There is also a risk that the trends that we've seen in policymaking by governments during the pandemic could in fact become "sticky" and thus could outlast the pandemic. There is an open-ended question as to whether governments will walk away from these restrictions quickly as the pandemic recedes. It's not a question that we have an answer to at the moment, because we're still in the middle of the pandemic.</p><p><strong>Where does your optimism come from? I am quite surprised by it.</strong></p><p>When we closed out 2020 and started 2021, it was a pretty dark moment for the United States for many reasons. And even just to see that bright spot in terms of the durability of the country's democratic institutions is very valid, valuable and positive, and certainly a reason to be optimistic.</p><p><strong>What about what experts call "democratic backsliding," or the many examples of how Republicans are seeking to undermine democracy with their new Jim Crow strategy and other attacks? There is great concern about an existential democracy crisis in America, and perhaps even violent insurrection or civil war.</strong></p><p><strong></strong>Polarization is one of the biggest issues in the country, and it hasn't gotten any better over the past year. We're not at the point of civil war, but we do have to keep an eye on this issue of polarization because there's nothing to suggest that it's going to go away immediately.</p><p><strong>Where do these global trends bring us? How close are we to democratic collapse?</strong></p><p>Our previous report was published at the beginning of 2020. In those two years, we see considerable slippage in terms of democracy at the global level. Certainly, that is alarming. One would assume that if we continue to see that happen next year, it could well be that the decline will continue to gain momentum and become harder to reverse.</p><p>What happens once the pandemic eases? There is reason to believe that will relieve some of the pressure that we've seen weighing down on the democracy scores of countries across the world. We will have to wait and see where the data takes us next year.</p><p><br/></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 14:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/democracy-2657249124/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Chauncey Devega, Salon</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-gallows-set-up-by-the-capitol-rioters-screengrab.png?id=27789537&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/png">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavrov's comparison of Zelensky to Hitler blasted by Israel, Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/lavrov-s-comparison-of-zelensky-to-hitler-blasted-by-israel-ukraine/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748573&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="760a73089d8aa2b3274578ab5fe0f617" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="850a3" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748576&width=980"/><figcaption>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov speaks during a press conference in Moscow. -/Russian Foreign Ministry/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Israeli and Ukrainian leaders have denounced Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov's comparison of Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky to Hitler as inaccurate and insulting.</p>
<p>Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba said his counterpart in Moscow "could not help hiding the deeply-rooted anti-Semitism of the Russian elites."</p>
<p>"His heinous remarks are offensive to [Zelensky], Ukraine, Israel, and the Jewish people. More broadly, they demonstrate that today’s Russia is full of hatred towards other nations," he wrote on Twitter.</p>
<p>Lavrov had defended Russian President Vladimir Putin's goal of the "de-Nazification" of Ukraine with war and said Zelensky's Jewish ancestry did not undermine Putin's position.</p>
<p>Lavrov said that Zelensky may indeed be a Jew, but "Adolf Hitler also had Jewish blood."</p>
<p>"That does not mean anything at all. The wise Jewish people say that the most keen anti-Semites are usually Jews," he told Italian TV channel Rete4 on Sunday evening, prompting outrage in Israel.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett said Monday that Lavrov's words were "untrue and their intentions are wrong."</p>
<p>"The goal of such lies is to accuse the Jews themselves of the most awful crimes in history, which were perpetrated against them," he said in a statement.</p>
<p>In a similar vein, Israeli Foreign Minister Yair Lapid said the remarks were "an unforgivable and outrageous statement as well as a terrible historical error."</p>
<p>Lapid continued: "My grandfather was not killed by Jews, but by Nazis." He told Lavrov to "open a history book."</p>
<p>Six million Jews were murdered by Nazi Germans and their collaborators during the Holocaust.</p>
<p>Ukraine, then part of the Soviet Union, was also occupied by Nazi Germany during World War II. Researchers estimate that at least 1.5 million Jews were murdered on what is today the territory of Ukraine, according to US Holocaust Memorial Museum.</p>
<p>The Israeli Ministry of Foreign Affairs summoned the Russian ambassador to Israel for clarifications on Lavrov's comments.</p>
<p>Dani Dayan, head of the Israeli Holocaust memorial Yad Vashem, called Lavrov's remarks as quoted as "absurd, delusional, dangerous and deserving of condemnation."</p>
<p>"Lavrov is propagating the inversion of the Holocaust - turning the victims into the criminals on the basis of promoting a completely unfounded claim that Hitler was of Jewish descent," he said in a statement.</p>
<p>"Equally serious is calling the Ukrainians in general, and President Zelensky in particular, Nazis. This, among other things, is a complete distortion of the history and an affront to the victims of Nazism."</p>
<p>German government spokesperson Steffen Hebestreit called Lavrov's statement "absurd."</p>
<p>"I think the Russian propaganda that is being made in this case by Foreign Minister Lavrov does not need to be commented on any further," he said in Berlin.</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="95c384e262241b47887f62fdeb22b02c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="6fe8a" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748579&width=980"/><figcaption>A photo released by the Ukraine Presidency on Sunday 1 May 2022 shows Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky arriving to receive Speaker of the United States House of Representatives Nancy Pelosi during her visit to Ukraine. -/Ukraine Presidency/dpa</figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/lavrov-s-comparison-of-zelensky-to-hitler-blasted-by-israel-ukraine/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Israel</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748573&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Commission accuses Apple of breaking bloc's competition rules</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-commission-accuses-apple-of-breaking-bloc-s-competition-rules/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748210&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="eaf03776947e1b7e591bb27771fd2bb7" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="24f0f" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748212&width=980"/><figcaption>The logo of the technology company Apple is seen at the Apple Store in downtown Munich. Apple is infringing EU competition rules with its Apple Pay system, the European Commission has found after months of preliminary investigation. Sven Hoppe/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>US tech giant Apple is infringing EU competition rules with its Apple Pay system, the European Commission has found after months of preliminary investigation.</p>
<p>The commission has "indications that Apple restricted third-party access to key technology" to the benefit of Apple products, European Competition Commissioner Margrethe Vestager said in a statement.</p>
<p>The European Union's top competition regulator contends that access restrictions for developers around mobile wallet technology on Apple's IOS operating system distorts market competition and suppresses innovation.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-commission-accuses-apple-of-breaking-bloc-s-competition-rules/</guid>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Eu</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748210&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's Bolshoi drops shows by two directors who spoke out against war</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-s-bolshoi-drops-shows-by-two-directors-who-spoke-out-against-war/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748214&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="87b8da802f1baa0a3845091cb1c696d2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b6280" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748220&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>LONDON (Reuters) - Russia's Bolshoi Theatre has upset opera and ballet fans by abruptly cancelling a series of shows this week by directors who have spoken out against the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>The theatre gave no reason for dropping Timofey Kuliabin's production of the opera "Don Pasquale" and Kirill Serebrennikov's ballet "Nureyev".</p>
<p>Kuliabin has used his Instagram account to express solidarity with Ukraine and ridicule Russia's description of its actions there. In one post, he showed a mocked-up version of the cover of Leo Tolstoy's "War and Peace", replacing the first word of the title with "Special Operation" - the term used by the Kremlin to describe the invasion.</p>
<p>Serebrennikov told France 24 in an interview last month that "it's quite obvious that Russia started the war", and that it was breaking his heart.</p>
<p>"It's war, it's killing people, it's the worst thing (that) ever might happen with civilisation, with mankind... It's a humanitarian catastrophe, it's rivers of blood," he said.</p>
<p>Both directors are currently outside Russia.</p>
<p>The replacement of the two shows with "The Barber of Seville" and "Spartacus", two longstanding staples of the Bolshoi's repertoire, drew hundreds of mostly critical online comments from ticketholders. Many demanded in vain to know the reason.</p>
<p>"What disrespect to the spectators and artists!" one woman, Valeria, wrote on the Bolshoi's Telegram channel.</p>
<p>There was particular outrage at the cancellation of Serebrennikov's "Nureyev", a controversial production that premiered at the Bolshoi in 2017. The story of dancer Rudolf Nureyev, who defected to the West in 1961, included a tender scene with his gay lover that tested the Kremlin's tolerance for what it calls "homosexual propaganda".</p>
<p>(Reporting by Mark Trevelyan; Editing by Peter Graff)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-s-bolshoi-drops-shows-by-two-directors-who-spoke-out-against-war/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748214&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tears and chocolate as New Zealand opens its borders to 60 more countries</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/tears-and-chocolate-as-new-zealand-opens-its-borders-to-60-more-countries/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747543&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="27da19d5011f38ac5502990c1e5bdbdd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9aeaa" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747545&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Lucy Craymer</p>
<p>WELLINGTON (Reuters) - New Zealand welcomed thousands of travellers from around the globe on Monday as the country opened its borders to visitors from around 60 nations including the United States, Britain and Singapore for the first time since COVID-19 hit in early 2020.</p>
<p>Maori cultural performers sang songs at the arrivals gate in Auckland and travellers were handed popular locally made chocolate bars as the first flights came in from Los Angeles and San Francisco.</p>
<p>Friends and family hugged and cried as people were reunited for what was for some the first time in more than two years.</p>
<p>Garth Halliday, who was waiting at the airport for his son, daughter-in-law and grandson to land from London, told local media it made him happy and emotional to see so many families reunited.</p>
<p>New Zealand had some of the toughest curbs in the world during the pandemic and only recently started to ease the increasingly unpopular measures, hoping to boost tourism and ease labour shortages now the Omicron variant is widespread domestically.</p>
<p>Borders were opened to New Zealanders and Australians in February and March. Now visitors from around 60 visa-waiver countries can enter as long as they are vaccinated and test negative for COVID. There are no requirements for isolation.</p>
<p>New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern told attendees at the U.S. Business Summit in Auckland that overseas visitors will really "bring back a piece that has been missing from New Zealand and New Zealanders."</p>
<p>On Monday, 43 international flights were scheduled to arrive or depart from Auckland International Airport carrying around 9,000 passengers.</p>
<p>Air New Zealand Chief Customer and Sales Officer Leanne Geraghty said demand had exceeded expectations with many of the services filling up.</p>
<p>"This is welcome news for the New Zealand tourism industry who has weathered a difficult storm," she said.</p>
<p>Tourists from a number of countries including India and China continue to be barred with restrictions for them not being lifted until October.</p>
<p>(The story is updated to correct day of the week in first paragraph)</p>
<p>(Reporting by Lucy Craymer; Editing by Lincoln Feast)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/tears-and-chocolate-as-new-zealand-opens-its-borders-to-60-more-countries/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747543&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muslims around the world begin celebrating Eid al-Fitr</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/muslims-around-the-world-begin-celebrating-eid-al-fitr/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747988&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="9d1043c751e899536f7898047035ce49" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="37446" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747991&width=980"/><figcaption>Muslim worshippers participate in Eid al-Fitr prayers, signifying the end of the holy month of Ramadan, at the Great Mosque of Mecca. -/Saudi Press Agency/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Many Muslims around the world are celebrating the Eid al-Fitr festival on Monday, the first to come after many countries lifted anti-coronavirus restrictions imposed two years ago.</p>
<p>Eid al-Fitr marks the end of the holy Islamic fasting month of Ramadan.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, home to Islam's holiest sites, declared that Monday is the start of the three-day Eid al-Fitr, one of the holiest occasions in the Islamic calendar.</p>
<p>Many other countries have done the same. A few others, such as Afghanistan, celebrated on Sunday.</p>
<p>The beginning and end of Islamic months are determined by the sighting of the new moon.</p>
<p>Over the past two years, Muslims celebrated amid curfews and social distancing measures imposed to combat the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>On Monday, thousands of worshippers were seen at the Grand Mosque in Saudi Arabia's holy city of Mecca to perform the early morning special Eid prayers. Similar scenes were seen in and around mosques in other countries such as Egypt, Morocco and Jordan.</p>
<p>Eid al-Fitr is also usually marked with social gatherings, new clothes, and cookies filled with dates or nuts.</p>
<p>The joy has been dampened by rising food and fuel prices, however.</p>
<p>Last month, the International Monetary Fund said the war in Ukraine is impacting the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region significantly, as higher food prices and potential supply shortages are challenging the affordability and availability of basic food staples like wheat.</p>
<p>The IMF expected inflation this year to remain high in the MENA region at 13.9%.</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3c1477ff2f6cae19413c260c72f7b7e2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="a4f05" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747996&width=980"/><figcaption>Muslim worshippers perform Eid al-Fitr prayers, which marks the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, at Al Masjid an Nabawi mosque. -/Saudi Press Agency/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3f63c8c6f2f2fc437ef6148ce7b19763" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3580b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747998&width=980"/><figcaption>Palestinian Muslims perform Eid al-Fitr prayers, which mark the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, at Gaza's Al-Saraya Square. Mohammed Talatene/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e99ba1e84d2c75868cfeec0dd0637eee" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ef8be" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748001&width=980"/><figcaption>Muslims perform prayers at the Green Lane Masjid to celebrate Eid al-Fitr which marks the end of the the holy month of Ramadan. Jacob King/PA Wire/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="67f23009b27846ccf9313e618abb6877" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="740b1" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29748003&width=980"/><figcaption>Muslim worshippers celebrate with balloons after they performed Eid al-Fitr prayers, which marks the end of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, outside Abou Bakr El Seddik Mosque. Lobna Tarek/dpa</figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/muslims-around-the-world-begin-celebrating-eid-al-fitr/</guid>
      <category>World</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747988&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia swerves to avoid default: what is next?</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-swerves-to-avoid-default-what-is-next/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747365&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Rodrigo Campos and Davide Barbuscia NEW YORK (Reuters) - Russia may have averted default as it announced it had made several overdue payments in dollars on its overseas bonds, shifting the market's focus to upcoming payments and whether it would stave off a historic default. Russia's $40 billion in international bonds and the chance of a default have become the focus of global financial markets since it was hit with sanctions from the United States and its allies after its invasion of Ukraine in late February. Dubbed a "special military operation" by Russia, the invasion has turned Russia i...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-swerves-to-avoid-default-what-is-next/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747365&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setback for Shanghai's COVID battle; Beijing focus on mass testing</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/setback-for-shanghai-s-battle-beijing-focus-on-mass-testing/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747350&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="88ef525196dd11b0c7d84232b980c109" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b5a46" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747356&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Brenda Goh and Sophie Yu</p>
<p>SHANGHAI/BEIJING (Reuters) - China's commercial capital of Shanghai was dealt a blow on Monday as authorities reported 58 new COVID-19 cases outside quarantine areas while Beijing pressed on with testing millions of its people on a May Day holiday few were celebrating.</p>
<p>Tough coronavirus measures in Shanghai have stirred rare public anger, with millions of the city's 25 million people confined indoors for more than a month, some sealed inside fenced off residential compounds, and many struggling to secure daily necessities.</p>
<p>Shanghai residents breathed a sigh of relief at the weekend on news that no cases had been confirmed outside quarantine areas for two days, but bad news came on Monday with the report of the 58 new infections.</p>
<p>Authorities did not comment on the new cases at a media briefing but members of the public weighed in online.</p>
<p>"They announced that they stamped out cases at the community level too early," one person commented on the Weibo social media platform.</p>
<p>But many people also took heart from data that showed an encouraging trend with 32 new deaths on Sunday, compared with 38 a day earlier, and 6,606 new asymptomatic cases, from 7,084 the previous day.</p>
<p>"There is hope for May," said another Weibo user.</p>
<p>The coronavirus first emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan in late 2019 and for the two years authorities managed to keep outbreaks largely under control with lockdowns and travel bans.</p>
<p>But the fast-spreading Omicron variant has tested China's "zero-COVID" policy this year, an important one for President Xi Jinping who is expected to secure a precendent-breaking third leadership term.</p>
<p>NEW FOCUS ON BEIJING</p>
<p>China's COVID policy looks increasingly bizarre to much of the outside world, where many governments have eased restrictions, or thrown them off altogether, in a bid to "live with COVID" even though infections are spreading.</p>
<p>China has given no hint of deviating from its policy despite a mounting toll on the world's second-largest economy, and the ripples of disruption travelling out through global supply chains.</p>
<p>In the capital, home to 22 million people, authorities tighten COVID restrictions over the five-day Labour Day holiday that runs through Wednesday, traditionally one the busiest tourist seasons.</p>
<p>Beijing, with dozens of daily infections in an outbreak now entering two weeks, has not locked down, instead relying, at least for now, on mass testing to locate and isolate infections.</p>
<p>Beijing's restaurants are closed for dining in and some apartment blocks are sealed shut. The streets are quiet and the residents who do venture out have to show negative coronavirus tests to enter most public venues.</p>
<p>Authorities are tracking down close contacts of confirmed cases, warning them to stay at home and contact authorities, and calling on everyone to abide by lockdown rules.</p>
<p>China reported 7,822 new COVID-19 cases on Sunday, down from 8,329 new cases a day earlier, the National Health Commission said on Monday.</p>
<p>All of China's 32 new deaths were in Shanghai, taking the country's overall death toll since the virus emerged to 5,092.</p>
<p>India, the only country with a comparable population to China's 1.4 billion people, has officially recorded more than half a million deaths, though some health experts believe its toll is even higher.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Brenda Goh, Sophie Yu and Tony Munroe; Writing by Anne Marie Roantree; Editing by Robert Birsel)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d83192b0214786aa284f3783885c5934" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="22b85" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747361&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/setback-for-shanghai-s-battle-beijing-focus-on-mass-testing/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747350&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence erupts in May Day protests in Paris, marchers criticize re-elected Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/violence-erupts-in-may-day-protests-in-paris-marchers-criticise-re-elected-macron/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746353&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="df55621ed640c04dc60d09204e820d13" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="20b19" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746358&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Dominique Vidalon and Noemie Olive</p>
<p>PARIS (Reuters) -Police fired tear gas to push back black-clad anarchists who ransacked business premises in the French capital Paris on Sunday during May Day protests against the policies of newly re-elected President Emmanuel Macron.</p>
<p>Thousands of people joined May Day marches across France in which they called for salary increases and for Macron to drop his plan to raise the retirement age.</p>
<p>Most were peaceful but violence broke out in Paris at the start of the march near La Republique Square and when it reached La Nation Square in eastern Paris.</p>
<p>"Black Bloc" anarchists ransacked a McDonald's restaurant on the Place Leon Blum and trashed several real estate agencies. Their windows were broken and garbage bins set on fire.</p>
<p>Police said activists had even attacked firemen, trying to put out fires. Police responded by firing tear gas.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said on Twitter that theses acts of violence in Paris were "not acceptable.</p>
<p>About 250 rallies were organised in Paris and other cities including Lille, Nantes, Toulouse and Marseille. In the capital, trade unionists were joined by political figures - mostly from the left - and climate activists.</p>
<p>The cost of living was the main theme in the presidential election campaign and looks set to be equally prominent ahead of June legislative elections that Macron's party and its allies must win if he is to be able to implement his pro-business policies, including increasing retirement age to 65 for 62</p>
<p>Joshua Antunes, a 19-year-old student said: "It is important to show Macron and the whole political world that we are prepared to defend our social rights,". He also criticised the president's "inactivity" on environment issues.</p>
<p>Marchers carried banners reading "Retirement Before Arthritis", "Retirement at 60, Freeze Prices" and "Macron, Get Out"</p>
<p>"The government has got to deal with the purchasing power problem by raising wages," Philippe Martinez, the head of the hardline CGT union, told Reuters before the rallies.</p>
<p>Macron won a new five-year presidential term after beating far-right challenger Marine Le Pen in last Sunday's runoff vote.</p>
<p>Far-left leader Jean-Luc Melenchon, who came third in the first round of the presidential vote, was attended the Paris march.</p>
<p>He wants to rally a union of the left, including the Greens, to dominate parliament and force Macron into an awkward "cohabitation" but so far this has not materialised.</p>
<p>"We will not make a single concession on pensions," Melenchon said before the march started.</p>
<p>He said he still hoped an agreement to build a new union of the left could be reached by this evening.</p>
<p>Unlike in previous years, Marine Le Pen did not lay a wreath in Paris at the statue of Joan or Arc, whom her party uses as a nationalist symbol. She was replaced by the Rassemblement National Interim President Jordan Bardella, who said Le Pen was preparing for the legislative elections.</p>
<p>Le Pen urged voters in a video message to elect as many deputies from her party as possible in June so that she could "protect your purchasing power," and prevent Macron from carrying a "harmful project for France and the French people"</p>
<p>The parliamentary elections will be held on June 12 and 19.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Dominique Vidalon, additional reporting by Yonathan Van der Voort, Noemie Olive, Sarah Meyssonier, Caroline Pailliez; Editing by Angus MacSwan)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="41eda867e82febb68c0766f5022b643f" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="67017" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746361&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="f748b13a3af132dd47cd8d40adb4fdb5" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3bc0b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746365&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ab4fbe23e88f41004b70ba269947ddb9" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b2bef" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746371&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a08ab6f4008444e2c4ced697689945ef" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="03a79" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746374&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="319dd25cc23d5cb153eb9d4bf36fb9f2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="48a73" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746380&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="0a2835ed8af772f370243c3d3e3b476c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="be1a0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746382&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/violence-erupts-in-may-day-protests-in-paris-marchers-criticise-re-elected-macron/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746353&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ricardo Alarcon, Cuban point man for U.S. relations, dies aged 84</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ricardo-alarcon-cuban-point-man-for-u-s-relations-dies-aged-84/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746103&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ba724b32bf9158773e488ac69e635aab" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="6400c" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746110&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Marc Frank and Nelson Acosta</p>
<p>HAVANA (Reuters) - Ricardo Alarcon, one of the most powerful men in Cuba under former President Fidel Castro and a key player in relations with the United States, died in Havana on Saturday evening, his family said.</p>
<p>The former diplomat was one of the architects of the first migratory dialogue between Washington and Havana in 1978, the year in which negotiations also began with a group of representatives of the Cuban community in the United States.</p>
<p>Alarcon played a key role in negotiating an immigration agreement with the United States that put an end to a massive exodus of Cubans by sea in 1994. He was also central in arranging the return of young castaway Elian Gonzalez from relatives in Miami to his father in Cuba in 2000.</p>
<p>The cigar-puffing and rum-sipping Alarcon, invariably clad in a white guayabera, at one point became the third most powerful man in the country's Communist Party elite after Fidel and Raul Castro.</p>
<p>He was foreign minister between 1992 and 1993 and then served as president of the National Assembly for 20 years until he was removed from the post and the ruling political leadership.</p>
<p>No reason was given for Alarcon's fall from grace, however his closest aid, Miguel Alvarez, had been arrested the previous year for being a U.S. spy and it is standard procedure in such cases to consider all contacts compromised.</p>
<p>Alarcon remained a loyal member of the Revolution despite his political downfall.</p>
<p>"To Ricardo Alarcon de Quesada, the Master of the diplomats of our generation, we will always have deep respect, admiration and infinite affection," Deputy Foreign Minister Josefina Videl, Cuba's lead negotiator with the administration of former U.S. President Barack Obama, tweeted on Sunday.</p>
<p>Alarcon was born on May 21, 1937. From a very young age he participated in the July 26 Movement, the revolutionary organization that overthrew U.S.-backed dictator Fulgencio Batista in 1959.</p>
<p>Alarcon then served as a leader of the University Student Federation and later the Union of Young Communists, the youth arm of the ruling Communist Party.</p>
<p>During his years as head of Parliament, Alarcon played an important role in the island's campaign for the release of five Cuban intelligence agents who had been sentenced to long prison terms in the United States for espionage.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Marc Frank; additional reporting by Nelson Acosta; Editing by Andrew Heavens)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b03fab6794a8251f0d76224fe740321c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="11d11" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746112&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b34528a0dd4a110a4f63d29691013250" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="d10b4" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746116&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/ricardo-alarcon-cuban-point-man-for-u-s-relations-dies-aged-84/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746103&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beijing concerned with rising North Korea tensions, envoy says in Seoul</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/beijing-concerned-with-rising-north-korea-tensions-envoy-says-in-seoul/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747320&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="955a28271b3c40ab97b77779307a8adb" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="54199" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747322&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Josh Smith</p>
<p>SEOUL (Reuters) - Beijing is concerned about the tense situation on the Korean peninsula, China's Korean affairs envoy said as he arrived for talks in Seoul this week, adding that both the symptoms and root cause of tensions needed to be addressed.</p>
<p>Amid stalled denuclearisation talks, North Korea has conducted a flurry of weapons tests this year, from hypersonic missiles to intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs).</p>
<p>North Korea had not conducted an ICBM or nuclear weapons test since 2017. Officials in Seoul and Washington say there are signs of preparations for a new nuclear test.</p>
<p>The "legitimate and reasonable concerns of all parties" need to be acknowledged for there to be a political settlement, Liu Xiaoming, Special Representative of the Chinese Government on Korean Peninsula Affairs, told reporters at Seoul's airport late on Sunday.</p>
<p>"We call on all parties to stay cool-headed and exercise restraint, and we disapprove (of) actions by any party that could escalate tension," he said in a summary of his remarks on Twitter.</p>
<p>In his first visit to South Korea since taking office in April 2021, Liu is due to meet his South Korean counterpart, nuclear envoy Noh Kyu-duk, on Tuesday. He may also meet representatives of South Korean President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol, who takes office on May 10, Yonhap news agency reported.</p>
<p>The United States has pushed for more United Nations sanctions on the North. But China and Russia have signalled opposition, arguing that sanctions should be eased to jumpstart talks and provide humanitarian relief to the impoverished North.</p>
<p>The issues on the peninsula can be resolved politically and China will continue to play a "positive role," Liu said.</p>
<p>However, the key to resolving the issues is in the hands of North Korea and the United States, he added.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Josh Smith; Editing by Edwina Gibbs)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 04:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/beijing-concerned-with-rising-north-korea-tensions-envoy-says-in-seoul/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747320&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilians evacuated from Mariupol, Pelosi meets Ukraine's Zelenskiy</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/civilians-evacuated-from-mariupol-pelosi-meets-ukraine-s-zelenskiy/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747188&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>KYIV, Ukraine (Reuters) - Around 100 civilians evacuated from the ruined Azovstal steelworks in Mariupol were due to arrive in a Ukrainian-held city on Monday, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said, after U.S. Speaker Nancy Pelosi made a surprise visit to Kyiv. The strategic port city on the Azov Sea has endured the most destructive siege of the war with Russia - now in its third month - with Pope Francis, in an implicit criticism of Moscow, telling thousands of people in St Peter's Square on Sunday it had been "barbarously bombarded". "For the first time, we had two days of a ceasefire...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 02:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/civilians-evacuated-from-mariupol-pelosi-meets-ukraine-s-zelenskiy/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29747188&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian oligarchs to be targeted in U.S. aid package for Ukraine, Schumer says</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-oligarchs-to-be-targeted-in-u-s-aid-package-for-ukraine-schumer-says/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746421&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4f05f53ad24a99186afde1fe7231df78" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c3649" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746428&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>(Reuters) -U.S. Senate Democratic leader Chuck Schumer said on Sunday he will add provisions to a $33 billion Ukraine aid package to allow the United States to seize Russian oligarchs' assets and send money from their sale directly to Ukraine.</p>
<p>"Ukraine needs all the help it can get and, at the same time, we need all the assets we can put together to give Ukraine the aid it needs," Schumer said at a media briefing in New York City.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden asked Congress to approve $33 billion in assistance for Kyiv on Thursday in what would mark a dramatic escalation of U.S. funding for Ukraine more than two months after it was invaded by Russia.</p>
<p>Schumer said the Biden administration had asked lawmakers to insert provisions into the aid bill to help it seize assets, liquidate them and send Ukraine the money. The U.S. House of Representatives signaled its support for giving the administration more power to target oligarchs profiting from their association with Russian President Vladimir Putin when it approved non-binding legislation on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The $33 billion in funding for Ukraine, which lawmakers have said they want to approve quickly, would be used to provide weapons, ammunition and other military assistance, as well as direct economic and humanitarian aid to Ukraine.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Katharine Jackson; Editing by Tim Ahmann and Daniel Wallis)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 16:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russian-oligarchs-to-be-targeted-in-u-s-aid-package-for-ukraine-schumer-says/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746421&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German far-right group attacks counter-demonstrators ahead of march</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/german-far-right-group-counter-demonstrators-ahead-of-march/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746120&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="05253815fc7d02eca26b10a89a9de73a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9ba80" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746125&width=980"/><figcaption>Policemen accompany members of an extreme right-wing group during a counter demonstration against rallies of the International Labour Day (May Day). Sebastian Willnow/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Right-wing extremists attacked counter-demonstrators on their way to disrupt a far-right march in the eastern German city of Zwickau on Sunday, according to police reports.</p>
<p>The far-right contingent reportedly threw stones at a train carrying left-wing activists as it arrived at Glauchau station, a police spokesperson said at noon (1000 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>The police arrested 41 right-wing extremists, a spokesperson said. One counter-demonstrator reportedly sustained mild injuries.</p>
<p>Earlier, there had been clashes at the railway station in nearby Chemnitz. There, 50 far-right demonstrators were removed from a train headed for Zwickau. The police did not provide any further information.</p>
<p>Some 500 participants were expected at the march in Zwickau organized by far-right splinter party Der Dritte Weg (The Third Way).</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="69f7be7a4935a75cad8a030e553a26c5" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="35d5a" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746127&width=980"/><figcaption>Policemen accompany members of an extreme right-wing group during a counter demonstration against rallies of the International Labour Day (May Day). Sebastian Willnow/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3a62496e767cb98b94cc50f71caeee70" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="aa7d7" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746131&width=980"/><figcaption>Policemen accompany members of an extreme right-wing group during a counter demonstration against rallies of the International Labour Day (May Day). Sebastian Willnow/dpa</figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 13:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/german-far-right-group-counter-demonstrators-ahead-of-march/</guid>
      <category>Extremism</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746120&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark summons Russian ambassador following airspace violation</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/denmark-summons-russian-ambassador-following-airspace-violation/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746028&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="0cc9de747ff200c737f19e7843b1e932" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="26de9" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746033&width=980"/><figcaption>Danish Foreign Minister Jeppe Kofod speaks to media upon arrival to attend the EU Extraordinary Foreign Affairs Council. Mario Salerno/EU Council /dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>The Danish Foreign Ministry said it had summoned the Russian ambassador for talks on Monday after a Russian aircraft violated Denmark's airspace.</p>
<p>"This is completely unacceptable and particularly worrying in the current situation," Foreign Minister Jeppe Kofod said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Both Denmark and Sweden allege that a Russian AN-30 propeller plane entered their airspace on Friday night, when the aircraft was flying east of the Danish Baltic Sea island of Bornholm, which lies off Sweden's south-eastern coast.</p>
<p>Since the Russian invasion of Ukraine more than two months ago, there has been intense debate in Sweden, as well as in neighbouring Finland, about joining NATO.</p>
<p>Russia has repeatedly warned the EU's two northernmost states against such a move. Denmark is already a member of the Western military alliance.</p>
<p>Concerns were raised in early March when four Russian fighter jets penetrated the airspace over Sweden.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 12:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/denmark-summons-russian-ambassador-following-airspace-violation/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Denmark</category>
      <category>Sweden</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29746028&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU leans towards Russian oil ban by year-end, diplomats say</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-leans-towards-russian-oil-ban-by-year-end-diplomats-say/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745857&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>BRUSSELS (Reuters) - The European Union is leaning towards a ban on imports of Russian oil by the end of the year, two EU diplomats said, after talks between the European Commission and EU member states this weekend. The European Union is preparing a sixth package of sanctions against Russia over the invasion just over two months ago of Ukraine that Moscow calls a special military operation. The package is expected to target Russian oil, Russian and Belarusian banks, as well as more individuals and companies. The Commission, which is coordinating the EU response, held talks dubbed "confessiona...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/eu-leans-towards-russian-oil-ban-by-year-end-diplomats-say/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745857&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkish police detain dozens in May Day demonstrations</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/turkish-police-detain-dozens-in-may-day-demonstrations/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745869&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="c1888434b1b882dcf9b1c46c2555ed2e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0b7a8" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745871&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>ISTANBUL (Reuters) - Turkish riot police detained dozens of protesters trying to reach Istanbul's main Taksim Square for May Day demonstrations against economic hardship caused by raging inflation.</p>
<p>The Istanbul governor's office had allowed May Day celebrations to be held in another district and deemed gatherings in all other locations as unauthorised and illegal.</p>
<p>A Reuters journalist saw riot police brawling with and handcuffing protesters, images of which were shown on television by domestic broadcasters.</p>
<p>Police also detained 30 people in central Besiktas and 22 others in Sisli districts, the Demiroren News Agency reported.</p>
<p>A statement from the Istanbul governor's office on Sunday said that 164 protesters had been detained across the city for "attempting to hold illegal demonstrations".</p>
<p>Marches led by workers and unions are held on May 1 every year as part of International Labour Day celebrations in many countries.</p>
<p>Turkey's annual inflation rate is expected to rise to 68% in April, driven higher by the Russia-Ukraine conflict and rising commodity prices, receding only slightly by the end of the year, a Reuters poll showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The soaring inflation and the economic hardship it causes were cited in May Day statements from several groups.</p>
<p>"Our main theme this year had to be cost of living," the head of the Confederation of Turkish Labor Unions (Turk-Is), Ergun Atalay, said as he placed a wreath in Taksim Square and demanded that minimum wages be adjusted monthly to reflect rising prices.</p>
<p>"Inflation is announced at the beginning of each month. The inflation rate should be added to wages every month," he said.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Murad Sezer; Writing by Ece Toksabay; Editing by David Goodman)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4e4ca4498d52473ef5c5629cc6ef96a0" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="a6b2b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745877&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="106bc8a0bf6966ab15fa28cc02f31df6" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="bf4b5" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745881&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="66a5f1dc64858bb6a4c69a0e1ed2961a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="1aef9" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745885&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="84e398235e3efca01f407b31ad59b323" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9e1f6" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745890&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e9fbc664a5dc4859e2fa2af5abd6a0e7" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="3a1eb" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745894&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="46a4cb8914c5e477c88be71b23513aaa" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="59cfe" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745896&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/turkish-police-detain-dozens-in-may-day-demonstrations/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29745869&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>