<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtru</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.virtru.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.virtru.com</link>
    <description>Privacy, Secured.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:34:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/virtru-favicon-50x50.png</url>
      <title>Virtru</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Your Zero Trust Identity Management by Tying Identity to Data</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-identity-management/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve started down the path of Zero Trust security, identity and access management (IAM) is likely a substantial part of your road map — and it should be. Identity...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-identity-management/">Maximize Your Zero Trust Identity Management by Tying Identity to Data</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve started down the path of Zero Trust security, identity and access management (IAM) is likely a substantial part of your road map — and it should be. Identity management providers, such as Okta, Ping, and AuthO are focused on ensuring that people and systems accessing your network are who they say they are — requiring users to authenticate themselves before gaining access to your essential applications and network assets.</p>
<p>We all know that Zero Trust journeys can be layered, complex, and expensive. As you’re thinking about stronger identity management on your Zero Trust roadmap, why not extend the value of that investment by applying identity to specific, granular data access decisions?</p>
<h2>First Things First: What Is Identity Management (IAM)?</h2>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/information-technology/glossary/identity-and-access-management-iam">Gartner</a>, Identity and Access Management (IAM) is “the discipline that enables the right individuals to access the right resources at the right times for the right reasons.” Identity management providers specialize in honing smart approaches to identity, putting safeguards in place that validate and authenticate that a user, system, or device is a known entity.</p>
<h2>Identity Informs Access: What is Access Control?</h2>
<p>Access control applies identity to the applications and parts of a network that the user should have access to. In the context of cybersecurity, it’s assigning access parameters to an individual user. This determines what applications, which areas of your network, and what types of data the individual should have the authority to access.</p>
<p>Identity management (authentication/AuthN) and access control (authorization/AuthZ) are often paired together: For example, once you’ve logged into your single-sign-on provider (which authenticates your identity), you’ll then be authorized to access the applications that are needed in order to do your job. One informs the other.</p>
<p>But, what about particularly sensitive data? What if organizations could get smarter about exactly who can access certain pieces of data?</p>
<h2>Getting Granular: What Is Attribute-Based Access Control (ABAC)?</h2>
<p>Attribute-based access control is a granular, nuanced way to ensure that sensitive data is only accessed by the individuals who have a need to know. Whereas role-based access control (RBAC) may be based on an individual’s role and responsibilities within a company, attribute-based access control (ABAC) allows you to further delineate access rights based on more granular details, like being a stakeholder on a certain project for a specified amount of time, or needing access to a certain subset of sensitive data rather than the entire dataset.</p>
<p>Role-based access controls can cause you to over-grant data access to your employees. But, by assigning granular tags to certain datasets or files, sensitive data can only be accessed by those with a true need to know.</p>
<h2>The Complete Zero Trust Picture: Tying Identity and Access Controls to Data Itself</h2>
<p>According to John Kindervag, the father of Zero Trust, “The first principle of Zero Trust security is to protect the data.” At the end of the day, it’s your data that you’re protecting, not the network, and not the apps. The data is where the true value lies — and that data is critical to your business, both from a day-to-day operations perspective and from a brand value and loyalty perspective.</p>
<p>To best protect that data, you can apply attribute-based access controls that grant access only to those with a true business need to know.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://www.okta.com/blog/2020/09/attribute-based-access-control-abac/">as Okta points out</a>, it can be challenging to implement ABAC if you’re starting from scratch.</p>
<p>So, it’s a good thing you don’t have to start from scratch: Virtru’s data protection provides Zero Trust Data Control to safeguard information shared in the applications you use every day: <a href="https://www.virtru.com/google-workspace-encryption/">Google Workspace</a>, <a href="https://www.virtru.com/outlook-encryption/">Microsoft Outlook</a>, <a href="https://www.virtru.com/data-encryption-enterprise-applications/">Salesforce</a>, and other critical apps. With Virtru, you can extend your identity management work past the network and application layers and to the data layer — arguably the most foundational layer of Zero Trust.</p>
<p>Our data protection capabilities are built on the open, IC-standard <a href="https://www.virtru.com/trusted-data-format/">Trusted Data Format</a>, which enables you to apply sophisticated, granular access controls to the data itself, giving you full visibility and control over exactly who can access it at any given time. You can revoke access to specific data if business needs change. You can prevent users from forwarding the information. You can set an expiration date for short-term projects. For federal agencies that already use tagging tools such as TITUS or Boldon James, you can <a href="https://www.virtru.com/press-release/virtru-announces-secure-file-collaboration-for-sensitive-and-classified-data/">pull from existing classification and tagging regimes</a>, appropriately tagging data under CAPCO Classification &amp; Control Markings, STANAG 4774 (NATO’s confidentiality metadata syntax), IC-EDH or other classification or categorization structures defined within standard tools.</p>
<p>In this way, your data becomes self-protecting and self-directing: These access controls and policies are cryptographically bound to the data itself, traveling with it everywhere it moves. Even after a file or other piece of data has been shared outside your network, those policies are still in place, and can be changed by admins or end users at any time.<br />
This extends your identity management to your most important asset, the data — while enabling that data to move in and out of your organization while still remaining fully under your control.</p>
<h2>Maximize Your Zero Trust Identity Investment with Virtru</h2>
<p>You’ve already invested in Identity and Access Management. Make the most of that investment by leveraging Virtru to apply those policies and access controls to the data itself, everywhere it moves. To learn more, <a href="https://www.virtru.com/contact-us/">contact Virtru’s team of data protection experts</a> to book a demo.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-identity-management/">Maximize Your Zero Trust Identity Management by Tying Identity to Data</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our military protects us. Are we doing enough to protect them?</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/military-data-privacy-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Federal]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Modern warfare takes shape in many ways. Even in the past year alone, global attacks have manifested in physical, on-the-ground conflict; cyberattacks on critical infrastructure; malware and ransomware attacks to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/military-data-privacy-security/">Our military protects us. Are we doing enough to protect them?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Modern warfare takes shape in many ways. Even in the past year alone, global attacks have manifested in physical, on-the-ground conflict; cyberattacks on critical infrastructure; malware and ransomware attacks to gain access to vital sensitive data; social media disinformation campaigns; and many other scenarios. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In wartime, national security is of the essence, not just to physically protect our nation and its allies, but also to protect the critical data that underpins day-to-day life.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the Ukraine conflict, we see attacks on several fronts, including phishing and malware attacks aimed at military and defense personnel. As Jessica Dawson and Brandon Pugh highlighted in a </span><a href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/opinion/2022/04/14/ukraine-conflict-heightens-us-militarys-data-privacy-vulnerabilities/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">powerful op-ed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, military service members are now being actively targeted for their data — and the impact can be catastrophic, especially when connected with other personal information. Dawson and Pugh write, “Linking biometric data and even publicly available information with service data creates a target of opportunity for malign actors looking to identify and target service members and their families.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Military service members give so much to protect our country and our global allies. But the question remains: Are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">we</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> doing enough to protect </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">them</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">? To protect their privacy and their own personal data? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stronger security is within reach, and it’s urgent that we act quickly to protect the data and privacy of our military service members. </span></p>
<h2>Privacy is a national security imperative.</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Dawson and Pugh rightly point out, the lack of federal privacy legislation means that personal data can be bought and sold without consequence — and when it comes to individuals who put their lives on the line to protect our country, safeguards should be in place to maintain their right to privacy and, as a result, fortify military data security. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. lags far behind other nations in data privacy regulation. Federal-level privacy protections are long overdue, particularly as we seek to fortify our nation’s digital security. </span></p>
<h2>Protect the data where it lives.</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data can be difficult to protect because it’s not just located in one place. It’s everywhere — and it’s always moving. Data evolves, and it’s shared between individuals and their families, friends, workplaces, professional networks, physicians, and any number of other entities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data should be protected in transit and at rest. A practical way to achieve this is to apply comprehensive security, such as encryption, to emails, files, and any other communications containing sensitive data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the aim of <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-cybersecurity-government/">Zero Trust security</a>, which has been a primary focus for federal agencies since </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/countdown-to-zero-trust-federal-roundtable-webinar-recap/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">last year’s Executive Order on the Nation’s Cybersecurity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Giving military personnel and veterans the tools to protect their own information on commonly used digital platforms can go a long way toward strengthening data privacy and security. </span></p>
<h2>Data privacy means respect.</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to strengthening national security, protecting our military service members’ private data is a way to respect their contributions, their commitment, and their personal safety. In an environment where cyber attacks are quickly becoming more sophisticated and more targeted, we have to take action now to ensure that personal and professional data does not become compromised, whether via <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/psychology-of-social-engineering-knowbe4/">social media</a>, <a href="https://www.virtru.com/email-encryption/">email</a>, or other digital channels. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Respect and security go hand in hand, and it’s urgent that we prioritize both. The cost of not doing so is far too high. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/military-data-privacy-security/">Our military protects us. Are we doing enough to protect them?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Conventional Wisdom for Zero Trust Security Falls Short</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-security-advice/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Howard]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Zero Trust security transformation. Why is everyone talking about it? Because we now live and work in a digital world without walls. And, without walls, cyber leaders must rethink their...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-security-advice/">Why Conventional Wisdom for Zero Trust Security Falls Short</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zero Trust security transformation. Why is everyone talking about it? Because we now live and work in a digital world without walls. And, without walls, cyber leaders must rethink their entire strategy for defending businesses against attacks and securing valuable data.</p>
<p>But what exactly are people saying about Zero Trust? And, more importantly, what aren’t they saying? What critical points might be missing from the current Zero Trust conversation?</p>
<p>Conventional cybersecurity wisdom has brought us this far, but in order to adapt to a rapidly escalating threat landscape, we have to think differently. We have to think beyond the status quo.</p>
<h2>Old Habits Die Hard</h2>
<p>The rapid adoption of public cloud infrastructure means that most companies have migrated some, or all, of their IT operations to the cloud. Furthermore, the global pandemic has fundamentally changed the nature of work itself, which now requires every IT department to support remote-first operations. Simply stated, the IT perimeter has vanished – and with it, the proverbial castle wall. Thus, companies everywhere are actively rethinking their approach to cyber security.</p>
<p>But, old habits die hard.</p>
<p>Despite living in a world without walls, most cyber professionals today still have perimeter-centric thoughts defining their priorities and guiding their actions. As a result, they tend to focus a majority of their time and energy on one thing: keeping bad guys off their networks and out of their systems. They do this by investing heavily to implement identity-based perimeters, complete with single sign-on and multi-factor authentication. They invest further to strengthen endpoint security. They dig even deeper into their pockets to implement best-in-class network security solutions and services like cloud access security brokers (CASB) in an attempt to bring SaaS apps inside of virtual perimeter. In other words, at this early stage of the Zero Trust security transformation journey, the prevailing cybersecurity mindset is still focused on defending the ever-expanding <a href="https://www.okta.com/identity-101/what-is-an-attack-surface/">digital attack surface</a> from external threats – rather than securing sensitive data objects which live on the <a href="https://docs.paloaltonetworks.com/best-practices/9-0/zero-trust-best-practices/zero-trust-best-practices/the-five-step-methodology/step-1-define-your-protect-surface#:~:text=Identify%20data%2C%20applications%2C%20assets%2C,to%20ensure%20normal%20business%20operation.">digital protect surface</a>.</p>
<h2>Conventional Wisdom Falls Short</h2>
<p>In the modern economy, organizations that are able to collect, analyze, and mine massive amounts of data have a huge advantage over their competitors and a clear path to rapid growth and value creation. However, these same companies that possess massive amounts of sensitive data must contend with huge overhead costs, including regulatory compliance, engineering operations, security risk management, and the enormous obligation that comes with being trusted to protect sensitive and private information about customers, employees, and business partners.</p>
<p>Furthermore, because data is the lifeblood of every business, organizations find themselves constantly sharing it with others, with or without proper controls. Similarly, companies must accommodate the fact that sensitive data, owned by others, is frequently being shared with them.</p>
<p>Today, conventional wisdom advocates that cyber leaders focus first and foremost on defending the digital attack surface from external threats. Such thinking isn’t wrong. It’s just a bit myopic, because it diminishes the critical importance of securing the data itself, which flows constantly in and out of your digital protect surface.</p>
<h2>Thinking Outside of the Zero Trust Box</h2>
<p>Against this backdrop, cyber security leaders would be well served to expand their Zero Trust thinking beyond conventional wisdom and simply defending their ever expansive attack surface. They should challenge themselves and their teams to examine innovative solutions designed to secure an organization&#8217;s protect surface where sensitive data actually lives and breathes, flowing in and out of businesses on a daily basis.</p>
<p>A convenient way for cyber security leaders to think beyond conventional wisdom is to ask themselves and their teams three critical questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>How should we govern sensitive data that we own and possess internally?</li>
<li>How should we govern sensitive data that we own, but no longer possess internally because we’ve shared it externally?</li>
<li>How should we govern sensitive data that has been shared with us, but is owned by others?</li>
</ol>
<h2>Zero Trust Data Access (ZTDA) for Inbound Workflows</h2>
<p>Conventional wisdom on Zero Trust Data Access (ZTDA) advises a five-pronged approach to governing risk:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, use micro-segmentation in datacenters and cloud environments to separate workloads.</li>
<li>Next, embrace the principle of least privilege to allow each user to access only the data they need.</li>
<li>Third, apply role-based access controls (RBACs) to make sure the right people have access to the right data.</li>
<li>Then, leverage Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) and single sign-on (SSO) to reduce the prevalence of passwords and insecure user behavior.</li>
<li>And finally, take advantage of multi factor authentication (MFA) to further strengthen authentication and authorization.</li>
</ul>
<p>Indeed, if your sole mission is to govern sensitive data that your organization owns and possesses internally – then it makes sense to follow conventional wisdom and invest all of your time and energy into governing which people and devices can access which data over a virtually secure network via inbound workflows.</p>
<h2>Zero Trust Data Control (ZTDC) for Dynamic Workflows</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, data isn’t static. It’s dynamic, constantly moving and evolving — born to be free in order to maximize its potential to shape strategies and inform important decisions. You can’t afford to lock it away. And you can’t afford to lose control of it either.</p>
<p>Thus, if your mission is to govern the entire protect surface and all forms of sensitive data, including data shared externally with third parties, then it is a good idea to think outside of the proverbial box. To do this, you will want to examine Zero Trust controls like Trusted Data Format (TDF) which is well-suited to facilitating secure collaboration, so you can guarantee access ONLY by intended identities, even when data has been shared externally.</p>
<h2>Think Different – Say Hello to the Trusted Data Format</h2>
<p>TDF is a super fast and affordable way for any organization to expand their zero trust security controls to encompass common information assets, like emails and files, which frequently contain sensitive and risky data.</p>
<p>TDF leverages military-grade data encryption to wrap data objects in a layer of security that remains with the data wherever it flows. We call this approach Zero Trust Data Control (ZTDC), because it gives you complete control over your data at all times – even after it has left your organization. You retain ownership and control for as long as the data exists, so you can always ensure access only by intended entities.</p>
<p>The graphic below shows how this works. The right hand side represents the conventional part of the zero trust wisdom as follows: identity and endpoint controls coupled with secure networks work in concert to determine which people and devices can access which apps and data with least privilege.</p>
<p>But the real power is on the left — and this is the essential part of the Zero Trust strategy that is often missing from conventional thinking. These are your collaboration and outbound workflows, and this is where TDF-based solutions give you a unique ability to minimize risk by securing granular pieces of data moving dynamically in and out of your business via emails, files, and SaaS applications. You can apply policy, attach identity, encrypt the data, authenticate and authorize the intended recipient, easily decrypt the data, and maintain control wherever the data flows and for as long as the data exists.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-28911 size-large" src="https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM-1024x527.png" alt="An infinity chart shows the Virtru Zero Trust Advantage" width="1024" height="527" srcset="https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM-1024x527.png 1024w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM-600x309.png 600w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM-768x395.png 768w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM-1536x790.png 1536w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Screen-Shot-2022-04-23-at-1.18.43-PM.png 1832w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>In this way, TDF compliments and extends your existing zero trust initiatives. It does so by creating a continuous, virtuous circle of policy control where you can enable your organization to collaborate with others and easily conduct business without ever losing control of sensitive information.</p>
<p>With TDF-based solutions, users can simply click a button to safely share sensitive data via email and files. Further, your organization can safely move customer data in and out of mission-critical software-as-a-service (SaaS) applications. Finally, TDF can easily help you govern data flowing to and from a vast array of IoT devices.</p>
<p>As cyber risk continues to grow exponentially, Zero Trust security transformations will only become a greater imperative. TDF-based solutions enable you to <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-cybersecurity-government/">maintain Zero Trust Data Control</a> over both your inbound and your outbound workflows – safeguarding the entirety of your protect surface and equipping you to share data with confidence.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-security-advice/">Why Conventional Wisdom for Zero Trust Security Falls Short</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Essential Components of a Strong SASE Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/sase-strategy-components-gartner-roadmap/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 10:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Workplace]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Email Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Encryption]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[File Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Global Trends]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog/sase-secure-access-service-edge-strategy__trashed/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Secure Access Service Edge (SASE) is becoming increasingly adopted in both commercial and federal organizations. In a complex technology ecosystem, a SASE strategy aims to streamline disparate systems into a...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/sase-strategy-components-gartner-roadmap/">3 Essential Components of a Strong SASE Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secure Access Service Edge (SASE) is becoming increasingly adopted in both commercial and federal organizations. In a complex technology ecosystem, a SASE strategy aims to streamline disparate systems into a common, unified framework.</p>
<h2>What is SASE?</h2>
<p>According to Gartner, SASE delivers “multiple converged network and security ‘as a service’ capabilities, such as software-defined wide-area network (SD-WAN), secure web gateway (SWG), cloud access security broker (CASB), firewall, and Zero Trust network access (ZTNA). SASE supports branch office, remote worker and on-premises general internet security use cases. SASE is primarily delivered as a service and enables dynamic Zero Trust access based on the identity of the device or entity, combined with real-time context and security and compliance policies.”</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-28177 size-large" src="https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Secure-Access-Service-Edge-Detail-Gartner-Virtru-1024x878.png" alt="Secure Access Service Edge, with detail on SASE strategy for security services edge" width="1024" height="878" srcset="https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Secure-Access-Service-Edge-Detail-Gartner-Virtru-1024x878.png 1024w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Secure-Access-Service-Edge-Detail-Gartner-Virtru-600x514.png 600w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Secure-Access-Service-Edge-Detail-Gartner-Virtru-768x658.png 768w, https://www.virtru.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Secure-Access-Service-Edge-Detail-Gartner-Virtru.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This graphic was published by Gartner, Inc. as part of a larger research document and should be evaluated in the context of the entire document. The Gartner document is available upon request from Virtru.</span></i></p>
<h2>What are the benefits of SASE?</h2>
<p>SASE aims to streamline a complex and disparate set of systems and network management tools with a more unified model, bringing Zero Trust cloud security and network functions — including identity — into a common framework.</p>
<p>Technology teams benefit from a tech stack optimized for interoperability: SASE aims to unify security efforts across multi-cloud environments, teleworking setups, and data-sharing networks. Enterprise leaders benefit from a more sustainable and unified approach that consolidates vendors and ensures new software and systems provide the necessary integrations and support.</p>
<h2>Components of a Strong SASE Strategy</h2>
<p>Whether SASE is in your current strategic plan or on your long-term roadmap, there are several components that are essential to a sustainable and effective SASE strategy:</p>
<h3>1. Move Beyond ZTNA to ZTDA — Zero Trust Data Access.</h3>
<p>According to the Gartner 2021 Strategic Roadmap for SASE Convergence, “The legacy perimeter must transform into a set of cloud-based, converged capabilities created when and where an enterprise needs them — that is, a dynamically created, policy-based secure access service edge.”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust/">Zero-Trust approach to security</a> assumes that your network has already been breached, and it requires every user or system to authenticate its identity. While the Gartner recommendation of implementing Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA) is a step in the right direction, a stronger approach is Zero Trust Data Access — implementing Zero Trust at the data level. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A data-centric approach is a more sustainable and flexible strategy because it protects the data itself, wherever it travels — both inside and outside your organization. When the data itself is safe, it can travel through cloud environments and even compromised locations while still remaining secure. Building policies that focus on the data itself will equip your organization to glean the greatest value from its SASE framework. History and our current security climate remind us that we must move our decisioning to the only true common denominator: the data. Only then can we convincingly say we have moved <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/beyond-the-perimeter-breach-preparedness-rapid-response/">beyond a perimeter-based approach</a>.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Risk to an organization changes, and usually increases, as data moves. That movement creates risk because there is no assurance that the protection and access intent is accurately applied and equally enforced where that data travels. A SASE implementation, built on a true ZTDA pillar, solves this problem because the data itself describes the burden of proof required to gain access ensuring the system it finds itself in isn&#8217;t the weakest link.</span></p>
<h3>2. Get organized, categorized, and contextualized.</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Context is everything. SASE is tightly integrated with identity management, ensuring that enforcement decisions can be immediately applied across the breadth of an organization’s tech stack. It’s vital that endpoints (whether human or machine) prove that they are who they say they are, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Legacy, role-based access control is simply not flexible enough to meet the needs of modern organizations. Data access needs change, and basing access on roles alone is likely to give individuals access to more data than they realistically need, often resulting in access that extends well beyond the intended period and purpose. By using attribute-based access control (ABAC), organizations can get far more granular and accurate in ensuring that the right people have the right access to the right data, at the right time. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For ABAC to be effective, your organization needs to complete an assessment of <a href="https://www.virtru.com/resource/cross-department-data-protection-checklist/">what kinds of sensitive information you manage and share</a>. This process can take time, especially for a large enterprise, so in the meantime, this shouldn’t prevent you from adopting ABAC protections from this point forward, for new data being created or shared. This will help you deploy essential data protection, such as <a href="https://www.virtru.com/file-encryption/">encryption</a>, to safeguard those most sensitive assets. </span></p>
<h3>3. Embrace (and prepare for) change.</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Change is inevitable. Partner and coalition relationships evolve. Information may need to be shared externally for a short time, and some groups may need more access than others. Ensure your <a href="https://www.virtru.com/resource/secure-file-collaboration-white-paper/">ABAC-tagged data</a> remains fully under your control at all times, whether it’s in motion or at rest, and whether it’s shared internally or externally. A strong SASE strategy, plus selecting vendors that deeply integrate those principles, including ZTDA, will give your teams flexibility and control without introducing hurdles or roadblocks.</span></p>
<h2>SASE and Zero Trust: Complementary Strategies</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You don’t need to choose between Zero Trust and SASE; you can (and should) have both. Zero Trust is a strategy that strengthens data protection, and SASE is the greater security framework that should be approached with a Zero Trust mindset. Zero Trust should guide your data security decisions, and a data-centric approach to Zero Trust is the most granular and effective way to ensure your data remains protected, regardless of what network it lives on, and even after it’s been shared with an external third party. </span></p>
<h2>Underpin Your SASE Strategy with Virtru’s Data Protection</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Virtru’s flexible data protection supports a key component of a SASE framework: A Security Services Edge informed by Sensitive Data Awareness. By assessing the scope of sensitive data your organization manages — and ensuring it’s properly secured — your organization can confidently manage its vital assets in an increasingly challenging threat landscape. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No matter where you are in your journey toward a SASE framework, Virtru can help you put tools and processes in place that will help you maximize the value of your investments by protecting your most important asset — your data — everywhere it travels. <a href="https://www.virtru.com/contact-us/">Contact Virtru today</a> to start the conversation. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://gartner.com/">Gartner</a>, 2021 Strategic Roadmap for SASE Convergence, Neil MacDonald, Nat Smith, Lawrence Orans, Joe Skorupa, 25th March 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">GARTNER is a registered trademark and service mark of Gartner, Inc. and/or its affiliates in the U.S. and internationally and is used herein with permission. All rights reserved</span></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/sase-strategy-components-gartner-roadmap/">3 Essential Components of a Strong SASE Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Government Agencies Need to Place Data at the Center of Their Zero Trust Cybersecurity Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-cybersecurity-government/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Howard]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Federal]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>In late January 2022, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) released a 28-page strategy memo for implementing Zero Trust cybersecurity in federal organizations. The memo itself was a follow-on...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-cybersecurity-government/">Why Government Agencies Need to Place Data at the Center of Their Zero Trust Cybersecurity Approach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In late January 2022, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) released a 28-page <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/M-22-09.pdf">strategy memo</a> for implementing Zero Trust cybersecurity in federal organizations. The memo itself was a follow-on to President Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/">Executive Order on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity</a>, released eight months earlier in May 2021 – which sent shockwaves throughout the government by imposing a 60-day deadline for federal agencies to have a plan for implementing a Zero Trust security architecture, as codified by the <a href="https://www.nist.gov/publications/zero-trust-architecture">National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)</a>.</p>
<p>Collectively, the May 2021 Executive Order, the January 2022 OMB memo, and a series of high profile cyberattacks against government organizations, have made Zero Trust security transformations a top priority for <a href="https://www.fedscoop.com/hhs-oig-zero-trust-model/">every agency</a>.</p>
<p>A critical component of national security and government work is the ability to easily share sensitive data and collaborate with third-party partners without sacrificing security, privacy, and compliance with regulations. In this modern world, Zero Trust security is much more than just controlling which identities and devices can access which data over a network &#8212; it&#8217;s about giving people the confidence and digital controls to share sensitive data freely without ever relinquishing ownership and sovereignty.</p>
<p>Thus, the OMB document itself is seminal for three reasons. First, it details specific steps agencies should take to implement Zero Trust. Second, it widens the lens through which organizations should view Zero Trust priorities. Third, it emphasizes the need for agencies to incorporate data-centric policy controls into their Zero Trust security transformation efforts.</p>
<p>Ask anyone who knows, including <a href="https://www.fedscoop.com/hhs-oig-zero-trust-model/">Gerald Caron, CIO at Health &amp; Human Services</a>, and there are very good reasons to embrace a data-centric approach to zero trust security transformations by taking these four steps:</p>
<h2>1. Apply policy control directly to data objects.</h2>
<p>Data isn’t always static. It often moves in and out of your organization at high velocity. That means you need to protect data wherever it resides.</p>
<p>Ask yourself: Are you currently protecting data throughout its lifecycle? Do you have a clear picture of how and where it’s being shared? Once it leaves your organization, do you have control over how it can be accessed? Can you guarantee that data shared externally is accessible only by the intended recipient? And if necessary, do you have a way to take the data back? If you can’t answer yes to these questions, then your data is at risk.</p>
<p>The good news is that you can continue to control your data wherever it resides, inside or outside of your organization.</p>
<h2>2. Focus less on “attack surface” and more on “protect surface.”</h2>
<p>The attack surface of every organization is constantly expanding. It expands as you shift from on-prem data centers to cloud native infrastructure. It expands further as you embrace remote and hybrid workplace strategies. It expands again, again, and again as employees use more and more mobile devices. And so on.</p>
<p>Clearly, organizations need to do the basics to protect their attack surfaces with policy controls aimed at identities, endpoints, and networks. That said, if you’re not careful, attempting to govern the ever expanding attack surface can consume all of your time and attention – and leave precious little time for you to focus on the super sensitive “protect surface”, where data itself resides.</p>
<h2>3. Leverage the advantages of the Trusted Data Format (TDF) standard.</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.virtru.com/trusted-data-format/">TDF is an open standard</a> for protecting sensitive data, regardless of where that data resides. TDF is also the standard of the <a href="https://www.dni.gov/index.php/who-we-are/organizations/ic-cio/ic-cio-related-menus/ic-cio-related-links/ic-technical-specifications/trusted-data-formathttps://www.dni.gov/index.php/who-we-are/organizations/ic-cio/ic-cio-related-menus/ic-cio-related-links/ic-technical-specifications/trusted-data-format">Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI)</a> and is widely used by the U.S. intelligence community (IC).</p>
<p>TDF applies military-grade encryption to wrap each data object in a layer of security and privacy that stays with the data. The technology gives you complete control of your data at all times. It’s what we call Zero Trust Data Control (ZTDC).</p>
<p>By leveraging data-centric policy control powered by TDF, organizations can:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Easily implement data centric policy controls without creating friction for frontline workers.</strong> Create simple and intuitive controls that anyone can use.</li>
<li><strong>Attach attribute-based access controls (ABAC) to data.</strong> Role-based access controls can result in over-granting of data access. Assigning granular tags to data means that only users who truly need access get access.</li>
<li><strong>Revoke access when circumstances change.</strong> People work on short-term projects, get reassigned, change jobs, and so on. You need the ability to instantly revoke data access at any time.</li>
<li><strong>Secure data across multi-cloud environments.</strong> Whether your teams are using AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud or any combination of the three, you need data protection that’s cloud-agnostic</li>
</ul>
<h2>4. Shift resources from expensive endeavors and “macro policies” aimed at wrapping the enterprise, to “micro policies” aimed at protecting the data itself.</h2>
<p>Protecting your data can give you confidence that even if your network is breached, your data remains safe. A data-centric Zero Trust framework safeguards data across email, files, SaaS applications and cloud:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Email</strong> – Virtru <a href="https://www.virtru.com/gmail-encryption/">data protection for Gmail</a> and <a href="https://www.virtru.com/outlook-encryption/">Microsoft 365 Outlook</a> gives users a simple toggle button to protect data they share. Configurable rules can automatically encrypt sensitive information before it leaves your organization.</li>
<li><strong>File sharing</strong> – <a href="https://www.virtru.com/google-workspace-encryption/">Virtru data security for Google Workspace</a> – including Google Drive, Meet, Docs, Sheets and Slides – puts protections in place for data shared across teams and outside your organization.</li>
<li><strong>SaaS applications</strong> – Virtru technology can secure data that flows through <a href="https://www.virtru.com/data-encryption-enterprise-applications/">Salesforce, Zendesk, Looker, Workday and more</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Cloud environments</strong> – Virtru technology provides cloud-agnostic protections. Virtru is also a Google-recommended partner for <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-google-workspace-client-side-encryption/">Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption (CSE)</a>. CSE gives Google customers direct control of the keys to encrypt their data so that no one – not even Google – can access the data without permission.</li>
</ul>
<p>Zero Trust is an important step forward for agencies. But it’s crucial that Zero Trust cybersecurity initiatives not be myopically focused on identities, endpoints, networks and applications. Applying policy controls directly to the data flowing through your email, files, SaaS applications and cloud infrastructure is a remarkably affordable and efficient way to advance your Zero Trust journey.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-cybersecurity-government/">Why Government Agencies Need to Place Data at the Center of Their Zero Trust Cybersecurity Approach</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtru Delivers Zero Trust Data Control for New Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-google-workspace-client-side-encryption/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Google Workspace]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zero Trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Virtru has been a longtime Google partner, equipping thousands of joint customers to extend Zero Trust Data Control across the Google portfolio. We&#8217;re excited to announce the general availability of...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-google-workspace-client-side-encryption/">Virtru Delivers Zero Trust Data Control for New Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Virtru has been a longtime Google partner, equipping thousands of joint customers to extend Zero Trust Data Control across the Google portfolio. We&#8217;re excited to announce the general availability of our support for Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption, <a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2022/03/stronger-data-security-and-privacy-with.html">which Google announced this week</a>.</p>
<h2>Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption: A Data Privacy Milestone</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 500;">This update equips organizations to make their data indecipherable to Google using encryption across Google Drive, Docs, Sheets, and Slides, including additional file types stored in Drive, such as Office files, PDFs, and more, without sacrificing Google’s market-leading collaboration capabilities. The beta program for Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption launched in <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/virtru-recommended-encryption-key-provider-google-workspace-client-side-encryption/">June 2021</a>, and this week, </span><span style="font-weight: 500;">Google announced its general availability </span><span style="font-weight: 500;">to Enterprise Plus and Education Plus customers. </span></p>
<h2>Selecting an Encryption Key Partner for Google Client-Side Encryption</h2>
<p>To take advantage of Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption, customers need to select a data protection partner for encryption key management. Virtru is the only Google-recommended key management partner that provides holistic security solutions across the <a href="https://www.virtru.com/google-workspace-encryption/">Google portfolio</a>, including support for Gmail, Workspace, and Google Meet, and GCP — as well as other SaaS applications such as Salesforce and Zendesk. To discover what sets Virtru apart from other key management providers, read our post: <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/choose-virtru-as-google-workspace-client-side-encryption-partner/">5 Reasons to Choose Virtru as Your Google Client-Side Encryption Partner</a>.</p>
<h2>How Google Client-Side Encryption Works</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 500;">By managing their encryption keys separately from the data, organizations can ensure that their information remains indecipherable to both Google and their key management partner, maintaining data sovereignty and full ownership at all times. This method of </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/encryption-key-management/"><span style="font-weight: 500;">encryption key management</span></a><span style="font-weight: 500;"> is foundational to an effective </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/resource/zero-trust-security-across-google/"><span style="font-weight: 500;">Zero Trust Data Control strategy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 500;">, and one that Virtru recommends for heightened security and confidentiality — especially for industries handling regulated information. </span></p>
<h2>Virtru&#8217;s Zero Trust Data Protection, Recommended by Google</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 500;">“Virtru is proud to be Google Workspace’s first recommended data protection partner and to have helped architect Google’s Client-Side Encryption capability with Google, in concert with our strategic enterprise partners. We are thrilled that Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption has become generally available for enterprises worldwide, and to include other partners in this open and extensible ecosystem,” said Virtru CEO John Ackerly. “In a cloud-first world, Zero Trust Data Control is fundamental to safeguarding organizations’ most valuable information — including intellectual property, financial data, and other highly sensitive content. With Virtru and Google, enterprises can leverage the cloud to collaborate in real-time with greater security, privacy and confidence than ever before.” </span></p>
<h2>Take the Next Step Toward Zero-Trust Security in Google Workspace</h2>
<p>Ready to get started with Virtru&#8217;s encryption solutions? <a href="https://www.virtru.com/contact-us/">Contact the Virtru team today</a> to start the conversation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-google-workspace-client-side-encryption/">Virtru Delivers Zero Trust Data Control for New Google Workspace Client-Side Encryption</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Achieve Agility, Collaboration, and Complete Control of Data in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/cloud-collaboration-control/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This article on securing data in the cloud was originally featured in Computer Weekly.  Historically, global organizations have had to make a tradeoff between the agility and collaboration benefits of...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/cloud-collaboration-control/">How to Achieve Agility, Collaboration, and Complete Control of Data in the Cloud</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This article on securing data in the cloud was originally featured in <a href="https://www.computerweekly.com/opinion/Achieving-agility-collaboration-and-data-control-in-the-cloud">Computer Weekly</a>. </em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, global organizations have had to make a tradeoff between the agility and collaboration benefits of the cloud and maintaining data sovereignty, security, and control. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this is no longer the case: You can have the best of both worlds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are simple ways that organizations can take complete control of the data they store and share in the cloud, ensuring that their sensitive data can only be accessed by the people and systems that have been granted the authority to do so. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this level of control, global organizations can maintain data sovereignty and residency, as well as implement a Zero Trust architecture, while using the cloud providers of their choice. </span></p>
<h2>How We Got Here: The Evolution of Global Data Privacy</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A company based in Europe may find itself in a situation where it’s required to hand over its customer data to the U.S. government. Why? Because: (a) the leading cloud providers are predominantly U.S.-based and subject to various laws requiring cooperation with U.S. local and federal government entities, and (b) there is currently no multilateral privacy framework.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The absence of a global privacy framework has caused governments to take different legal and policy approaches to data and with this, privacy has become a polarizing issue for global businesses. However, while the system of national and regional law continues to evolve, companies are demanding flexible and universally compliant cloud enablement solutions/tools right now: to enable their full participation in the global economy, maintain the benefits of the public cloud, and provide complete control over data access.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud providers have taken steps to strengthen data residency and sovereignty, such as </span><a href="https://www.computerweekly.com/feature/Cloud-storage-data-residency-How-to-achieve-compliance"><span style="font-weight: 400;">defining regions and zones</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for data storage and processing. But this approach is incomplete, and depending on the location of your organization, the capabilities can vary. For example, GPUs may not be available in some regions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a world where speed, efficiency, and collaboration are table stakes for innovation, global companies need a better option. You shouldn’t have to sacrifice productivity for security and control of your own information. </span></p>
<h2>Achieving Complete Control of Sensitive Data In the Cloud</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implemented correctly, end-to-end encryption of sensitive data can not only shield data from unauthorized access, but it can also give you complete control over that data as it travels and is shared.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The European Data Protection Board (EDPB) has </span><a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/sites/default/files/consultation/edpb_recommendations_202001_supplementarymeasurestransferstools_en.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">identified end-to-end encryption</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as an effective means of securing data while leveraging a third-country service provider, so long as that encryption and its algorithm are robust; that the encryption is applied for the entire time period that the data must remain confidential; the keys are reliably managed; and that the keys are controlled by the data owner. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">End-to-end-encrypted data is protected before it hits the cloud provider’s server, shielding sensitive data from anyone without authorized access — including the cloud provider themselves. When you control the encryption keys, only you can decide who to grant access to your sensitive data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The result is that your most important asset — your data — remains secure and fully under your control, while giving you the ability to leverage the cloud provider of your choice, even if they’re located in the U.S. If your data is protected by end-to-end encryption and shielded from the cloud provider, you don’t have to worry about whether foreign governments subpoena your information, because while the cloud provider may be forced to turn over the information they have, that information is incomplete: It does not include the true, meaningful contents of that data, because they don’t have the keys to what’s inside.  </span></p>
<h2>What to Look For In End-to-End Encryption Partners</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not all encryption providers are created equal. In a rapidly evolving global cloud landscape where cyber threats are continuing to escalate, you’ll want to consider the following: </span></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Data-centric protection</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that wraps each data object in its own layer of encryption</span></li>
<li><a href="https://www.virtru.com/resource/virtru-zero-trust-data-access-webinar/"><b>Zero Trust Data Access</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> controls that are granular and sophisticated enough to ensure the recipient is authorized to view the encrypted data  </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ability to </span><b><a href="https://www.virtru.com/encryption-key-management/">host and manage your own encryption keys</a>, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">so that neither your cloud provider nor your encryption partner can access the contents of your data</span></li>
<li><b>Persistent control across the full lifecycle of the data</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, even after that data has been shared externally. Ensure that your encryption partner can facilitate the revocation of data, should circumstances change. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2>Getting Started with Zero Trust Data Control</h2>
<p>Ready to take the next step toward Zero Trust Data Control? <a href="https://www.virtru.com/contact-us/">Contact Virtru today</a> to start the conversation, and get up and running quickly.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/cloud-collaboration-control/">How to Achieve Agility, Collaboration, and Complete Control of Data in the Cloud</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning Enterprise Security Inside Out</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-enterprise-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This article was originally featured on Intelligent CISO.  The insider threat is one of the most harmful threats to an organisation and business leaders are becoming heavily reliant on operating...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-enterprise-security/">Turning Enterprise Security Inside Out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This article was originally featured on <a href="https://www.intelligentciso.com/2022/03/15/turning-enterprise-security-inside-out/">Intelligent CISO</a>. </em></p>
<p><em>The insider threat is one of the most harmful threats to an organisation and business leaders are becoming heavily reliant on operating with a Zero Trust approach to security. Renaud Perrier, SVP International, Virtru, discusses the importance of a Zero Trust model for transforming the way you monitor, prevent and mitigate risks associated with insider threats.</em></p>
<h2>Maximising collaboration and data protection with Zero Trust</h2>
<p>According to Verizon’s recent <em>Data Breach Investigation</em> report, 85% of data breaches involve a human element — whether that be a phishing attack, human error, intentional misuse of privileges, or data misuse. While this might seem a pretty alarming statistic, it represents an opportunity for security leaders to fundamentally shift how they approach securing their data and their organisation.</p>
<p>As many organisations still continue to focus outward — on the perimeter — to prevent malicious cyberattacks, they may overlook internal security behaviours that could put their organisation at even greater risk. But we all know that perimeters get breached and people make mistakes; why not switch things up and manage security from the inside out?</p>
<h2>Mitigate the insider threat</h2>
<p>Most of the time, insider threats aren’t malicious or even intentional. It can be as simple as selecting Sarah from your stationery supplier rather than Sarah from finance and in the blink of an eye your sensitive customer data is out in the ether.</p>
<p>More unusual — but still an area of concern — is the disgruntled employee who chooses to exfiltrate company data. This presents a risk to organisations where data access is not carefully governed, granting employees with more access to sensitive data than they realistically need to do their jobs. Unfettered access to sensitive customer data is a significant risk that needs to be mitigated to reduce the likelihood of a malicious insider threat.</p>
<p>Regardless of the intent, data is the common denominator across these <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/how-to-detect-insider-threats-saas-software/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">insider threat scenarios</a> — and protecting the data itself has to be a key priority. But businesses still need to collaborate and share information. In a world where speed and innovation are essential, locking down the data can’t be the answer.</p>
<p>Instead, imagine this: rather than stopping the flow of data as a means of securing it, you can provide your workforce with a way to easily share and innovate across applications and ecosystems, knowing you have full control over where it goes and who can access it.</p>
<h2>Never trust, always verify</h2>
<p>Zero Trust is gaining momentum, with ResearchAndMarkets.com estimating it to be a £44 billion market by 2028. But there are a wide range of definitions of what Zero Trust actually means. Put simply, Zero-Trust security is <a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-encryption-key-management-google-microsoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a policy of maintaining Zero Trust</a> towards all users, providers and network traffic — even those inside the network.</p>
<p>Zero Trust operates under the guiding principle, ‘never trust, always verify’. All users, platform providers and network traffic are treated as potential threats, so additional measures are needed to mitigate risk.</p>
<p>So, what does strong Zero Trust security look like in action? This approach can transform the way you monitor, prevent and mitigate the risks associated with insider threats. When you stop treating the network as an automatically safe space and, instead, put processes in place to monitor and verify traffic, data access and the flow of data sharing, you gain more control over where the data goes and who is authorised to access it.</p>
<p>Because, at the end of the day, the perimeter is bound to be breached in some way. Insider threats are a powerful example of this: even a well-intentioned employee can, without malice, exfiltrate sensitive data and cause a breach. As cyberattacks like ransomware and phishing continue to escalate and become even more sophisticated, it’s essential to stop granting unearned trust to entities within the bounds of the corporate network.</p>
<h2>Focus on the data</h2>
<p>The Zero Trust policy control plane is layered and has several facets: identities and people; devices and endpoints; network transport; apps and services; and — most critically — the data itself.</p>
<p>Why focus on protecting the data itself? Because it is the lifeblood of modern businesses and the core pillar of how organisations operate today. John Kindervag, the father of modern Zero Trust, is known for saying ‘The first principle of cybersecurity is to protect data and prevent breaches’. Across all security efforts, data is the common denominator.</p>
<p>Zero Trust is certainly a multi-layered endeavour. You can’t have strong security without considering how you authenticate the people, devices and systems that access your data. But, should the other areas of Zero Trust protection fail, if you are protecting the data itself with a layer of encryption as a data-centric protection, it still remains secure.</p>
<p>Ultimately, Zero Trust will always come back to the data.</p>
<h2>Empower employees</h2>
<p>So, how can security leaders take steps to make sure their data is protected in support of a Zero Trust strategy?</p>
<p>It’s essential to put processes and tools in place that automate security and mitigate risk, but ultimately, security is a human problem: you also need to bring your employees along with you, equipping them to make the right decisions when it comes to data.</p>
<p>This starts with implementing user-friendly tools that enable employees to protect the data they’re sharing. For too long, security and encryption products have neglected ease of use, which is a critical error. If you want employees to prioritise data security, you have to make it simple and you have to ensure it doesn’t introduce hurdles into their daily workflow. Efficiency, speed and innovation are table stakes for businesses today, so security should support those business objectives, not detract from them.</p>
<p>Finally, leadership is key to cultivating engagement around security. To get individuals invested in protecting data, it’s important to help them understand why they should care and that their actions truly have power. Educating employees about breaches in the news, for example, and their impact on businesses and their own teams, can help them gain perspective on how a breach could impact their own lives. If you make it personal, you will start to see a shift in awareness and behaviour, ultimately mitigating the likelihood of those hard-to-detect, inadvertent insider threats.</p>
<p>Security has to be a collaborative and cross-functional process. By making security conversations compelling, informative and engaging, organisations can better prepare their people to handle the sensitive data they’re entrusted to protect. This kind of a company culture, underpinned by strong Zero Trust practices, can equip your business to confidently navigate an increasingly complex digital world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/zero-trust-enterprise-security/">Turning Enterprise Security Inside Out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Shield 2.0: Opening Trustworthy Data Flows Between the U.S. and the EU</title>
      <link>https://www.virtru.com/blog/privacy-shield-updates/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Editorial Team]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 14:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Global Trends]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virtru.com/blog//</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Today’s announcement of a ‘revamped Privacy Shield’ data transfer agreement between the EU and the U.S. has been long awaited. Whilst the finer details are yet to be announced, it...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/privacy-shield-updates/">Privacy Shield 2.0: Opening Trustworthy Data Flows Between the U.S. and the EU</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today’s </span><a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-us-strike-preliminary-deal-to-unlock-transatlantic-data-flows/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announcement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of a ‘revamped Privacy Shield’ data transfer agreement between the EU and the U.S. has been long awaited. Whilst the finer details are yet to be announced, it marks progress in addressing the uncertainty created by the </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/data-sovereignty-in-a-post-privacy-shield-world/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Schrems II ruling back in July 2020</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Schrems II was a major milestone for international data protection and privacy, but it put mounting legal pressure on organisations who operated, or wished to operate, in the global market, and it limited data sharing practices between the EU and the U.S.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As an interim measure in November 2020, the European Data Protection Board (EDPB &#8211; the body that oversees the national privacy regulators in each of the EU member states &#8211; </span><a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/sites/edpb/files/consultation/edpb_recommendations_202001_supplementarymeasurestransferstools_en.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">adopted guidance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that clarified </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/what-is-end-to-end-encryption/"><b><i>end-to-end encryption</i></b></a><b><i> as an effective measure to enable both cloud adoption and data sovereignty requirements</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when transferring personal data outside the EU. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless of the final outcome of the new privacy shield agreement, there are still likely to be concerns from individuals and organisations about how data that originates from the EU is handled and subject to U.S. surveillance practices. It is expected that the resolution will lean on technology, perhaps furthering the EDPB guidance on encryption, but organisations shouldn’t wait: Data is the lifeblood of an organisation and needs to be shared to foster collaboration, innovation and growth. By applying policy controls that follow data wherever it goes, across any geography, organisations can lawfully participate in the global economy, without ever sacrificing the control and ownership of their data.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Virtru helps thousands of global organisations safeguard their data and maintain full data sovereignty and control. To learn more about how you can apply our Zero Trust encryption to your organisation’s sensitive data, </span><a href="https://www.virtru.com/contact-us/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">contact our team</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> today. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com/blog/privacy-shield-updates/">Privacy Shield 2.0: Opening Trustworthy Data Flows Between the U.S. and the EU</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.virtru.com">Virtru</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>