<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>CyberTalk</title>
    <atom:link href="https://cybertalk.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://cybertalk.org</link>
    <description>Cyber Security News And Insights For Executives</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:51:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The 8 best tech newsletters you should subscribe to right now</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/05/the-8-best-tech-newsletters-you-should-subscribe-to-right-now/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[OPINION]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cybertalk.org/?p=18807</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: We’ve combed the internet and put together a variety of the best tech newsletters to keep technology and security leaders informed of the latest trends, developments, resources, and news, enabling leaders to stay up-to-date with all security industry developments. Keep ahead of the curve and get information delivered to you in the most [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/05/the-8-best-tech-newsletters-you-should-subscribe-to-right-now/">The 8 best tech newsletters you should subscribe to right now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:</p>
<p>We’ve combed the internet and put together a variety of the best tech newsletters to keep technology and security leaders informed of the latest trends, developments, resources, and news, enabling leaders to stay up-to-date with all security industry developments. Keep ahead of the curve and get information delivered to you in the most efficient way possible – via email. Read on to get started.</p>
<p>CyberTalk Newsletter – <a href="https://cybertalk.org/cyber-security-newsletter/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=8-best-tech-newsl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>This cyber security-focused weekly newsletter delivers expert-curated premium content, exclusive resources, and powerful business and security insights from top industry experts. Resources provided include eBooks, webinars, whitepapers and the latest research. Join thousands of your peers in receiving these exclusive cyber security updates.</p>
<p>Benedict’s Newsletter – <a href="https://www.ben-evans.com/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>VC Ben Evans, a partner at Andreessen Horowitz, publishes this weekly update to 150,000+ subscribers, which is well-known in the tech industry inner circle, and focuses on intriguing news, productivity and emerging trends. Choose from a free edition or a premium edition.</p>
<p>CIO Newsletters – <a href="https://www.cio.com/newsletters/signup" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>With CIO, you can customize your subscriptions and receive a wide variety of CIO and IT newsletters that provide the latest ideas, data, strategies, expert advice, and today’s trending stories. You can also get expert perspectives from some of the best IT leaders in the world.</p>
<p>Devops Weekly – <a href="https://www.devopsweekly.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>Developers and operators may enjoy an expert weekly dose of the latest DevOps news from Gareth Rushgrove, who provides a unique perspective on today’s headlines in this super-techie newsletter.</p>
<p>Digital Trends: Decrypted – <a href="https://newsletter.digitaltrends.com/p/6MG2-2XC/sign-up-for-digital-trends-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>A daily bulletin from senior writers of Digital Trends, focusing on in-depth stories, features, current tech trends and unbiased reviews of the latest technology products.</p>
<p>MIT Technology Review: The Download – <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>Get daily updates in this newsletter that highlights the latest in emerging technology, with a slant towards tech&#8217;s societal impacts, from the world-famous Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT).</p>
<p>TechCrunch Newsletters – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>Choose from a great selection of technology-focused newsletters that will keep you up-to-date on today’s most significant updates, the latest industry events, headlines and startups news.</p>
<p>TED Newsletters – <a href="https://www.ted.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up now</a></p>
<p>The leader in well-known inspirational talks produces a daily email to keep you up-to-date on the newest talks -including release dates- upcoming podcasts, interviews with industry visionaries and informative videos. Choose from TED Recommends or the TED Daily Email.</p>
<p>It is critical to keep ahead of the tech and cyber security curve. By subscribing to some of the best newsletters in the industry, you can save time, energy, and resources. You can also keep informed about the latest breaking news.</p>
<p>If you have any suggestions regarding additions to our top tech and cyber newsletters list, please email our Cyber Talk editors <a href="mailto:email:EditorInChief@CyberTalk.org?subject=Best%20Tech%20Newsletters%20-%20Suggested%20Addition" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/05/the-8-best-tech-newsletters-you-should-subscribe-to-right-now/">The 8 best tech newsletters you should subscribe to right now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNS targeted: Astonishing IoT attack affecting millions of devices and routers</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/04/dns-targeted-astonishing-iot-attack-affecting-millions-of-devices-and-routers/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[bferrite]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[code]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[DNS Vulnerability]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[IoT]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4Shell]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[open source code management]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Routers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Spring4Shell]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://cybertalk.org/?p=18800</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: Researchers have found that an unpatched Domain Name System (DNS) bug enables attackers to deploy “DNS poisoning” attacks against millions of IoT devices and routers. The bug is 10 years-old and does not have a ready fix. The bug exists within popular standard C libraries; uClibc and uClibc-ng, which help generate predictable, incremental [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/04/dns-targeted-astonishing-iot-attack-affecting-millions-of-devices-and-routers/">DNS targeted: Astonishing IoT attack affecting millions of devices and routers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:</p>
<p>Researchers have found that an unpatched <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/what-is-a-domain-name-system-dns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Domain Name System</a> (DNS) bug enables attackers to deploy “DNS poisoning” attacks against millions of IoT devices and routers. The bug is 10 years-old and does not have a ready fix.</p>
<p>The bug exists within popular standard C libraries; uClibc and uClibc-ng, which help generate predictable, incremental transaction identifiers (IDs) in DNS response and network communications.</p>
<p>The bug was reported to ICS-CERT roughly six months ago, and the fact that it remains unpatched serves as a reminder of the challenges associated with open source code security.</p>
<p>If successful in exploiting the vulnerability, hackers can potentially take control over systems.</p>
<h3><strong>Devices affected</strong></h3>
<p>The flaw affects products from as many as 200 major vendors, including Linksys, Netgear, Axis and Linux. Specific products impacted by the bug were not formally named in the research.</p>
<h3><strong>What is a DNS poisoning attack?</strong></h3>
<p>In a DNS poisoning attack, also known as DNS spoofing or DNS cache poisoning, an attacker tricks a client device into accepting a false response. When this occurs, it forces a program to perform network communications with an arbitrarily defined endpoint rather than the legitimate one.</p>
<h3><strong>Possible consequences</strong></h3>
<p>Successful DNS poisoning attacks allow for man-in-the middle attacks, and the re-routing of network communications to a server under attacker control. In such circumstances, attackers could then steal or manipulate user information or perform other attacks against devices in order to further compromise them.</p>
<p>Cyber security experts are currently working with the manager of a certain code library in order to create a fix for the vulnerability.</p>
<h3>DNS as target &#8211; <em>technical insights</em></h3>
<p>This DNS vulnerability has parallels to last year’s Log4Shell flaw, which sent shockwaves through the cyber security community. Although the DNS flaw affects a different set of targets, it retains a broad scope on account of the inherent importance of DNS to any device connecting over IP.</p>
<p>DNS reflects a hierarchical database that serves the integral purpose of translating a domain name into a relevant IP address. In distinguishing the responses of different DNS requests, every request includes transaction parameters, known as a “transaction ID”.</p>
<p>The transaction ID is a unique number associated with the request. It’s generated by the client and included in each request sent. The transaction ID needs inclusion within a DNS response in order to be accepted by the client as the valid one for request.</p>
<h3><strong>Mitigation</strong></h3>
<p>The bug exists on millions of IoT devices. Until a patch is released, experts recommend that network administrators increase their network visibility and security in both IT and Operational Technology environments.</p>
<p>Researchers are working with the owner of the code library and the broader community in order to develop a solution. Public disclosure of the bug is expected to yield greater collaboration around a creative technical management.</p>
<p>Organizations that use IoT and router devices are encouraged to keep an eye on new firmware releases from vendors and to apply updates as soon as they become available.</p>
<p>For the latest insights into security for code vulnerabilities, check out <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2022/04/28/4-log4j-fix-strategies-that-can-stop-log4j-threats-now/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org’s past coverage</a>. <em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news, best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/04/dns-targeted-astonishing-iot-attack-affecting-millions-of-devices-and-routers/">DNS targeted: Astonishing IoT attack affecting millions of devices and routers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can you give a new life to your old firewalls?</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/03/how-can-you-give-a-new-life-to-your-old-firewalls/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[OPINION]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Firewall]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[firewalls]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Lari Luoma]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Quantum Maestro]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18787</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Lari Luoma has over 20 years of experience working in the fields of security and networking. For the last 11 years, he has worked with Check Point Professional Services as a security consultant helping customers worldwide to implement the best in class cyber security. He is a subject matter expert in hyper-scalable security solutions. In [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/03/how-can-you-give-a-new-life-to-your-old-firewalls/">How can you give a new life to your old firewalls?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Lari Luoma has over 20 years of experience working in the fields of security and networking. For the last 11 years, he has worked with Check Point Professional Services as a security consultant helping customers worldwide to implement the best in class cyber security. He is a subject matter expert in hyper-scalable security solutions.</em></p>
<p>In this outstanding interview, Lari Luoma shares insights into how to give new life to older firewalls. Discover new mindsets, methodologies and helpful moves for your organization.</p>
<p><strong>Please provide context: </strong></p>
<p>Many organizations use physical firewall clusters with hardware that’s a few years-old, which might not be powerful enough to provide enough protection and performance in today’s traffic conditions and threat landscape. These kind of clusters are ineffective and often not powerful enough to provide sufficient protection in high traffic and low latency conditions.</p>
<p><strong>Why is this a problem?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Traditional active/backup-clustering technology does not fully utilize the capacity of the system, since only one member is active and the backup member takes over only if the primary one fails. This means that half of your security investment can sit unused for years. You also should test these kind of clusters regularly to ensure their failover capabilities.</p>
<p><strong>Why should CTOs, CIOs or CISOs prioritize this issue?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>With high-availability clusters you don’t get everything out of your security investment. In high traffic and low latency conditions it is crucial that you can utilize the full potential of your hardware platforms. With Check Point Quantum Maestro you can use your existing hardware to the fullest and get better security without having to worry about performance.</p>
<p><strong>How can organizations upgrade?</strong></p>
<p>Check Point Quantum Maestro is a revolutionary new security architecture that enables businesses of any size to enjoy the power of flexible cloud-level security platforms, and seamlessly expand their existing security gateways to hyper-scale capacity. Maestro is effectively a stack of up to 50+ security appliances that are orchestrated into several logical gateways called security groups on a single system for maximum efficiency.</p>
<p>There are two ways to migrate your existing gateways into Maestro.</p>
<ol>
<li>Migrate the existing cluster members keeping all configurations</li>
<li>Add gateways to an existing Maestro Security Group to boost its performance.<br />
You can mix and match different hardware models.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What else should defenders know about giving new life to old firewalls?</strong></p>
<p>Quantum Maestro introduces a new, simplified way to manage cyber security, saving time and money. Grouping hardware into logical gateways gives the operational supremacy where only one member gateway represents the entire security group. Other gateways clone configuration from the first one.</p>
<p><strong>Closing sentiments</strong></p>
<p>Outdated firewall software can facilitate exposure to threats that result in remote code execution, denial of service attacks, and other misfortunes. If you decide that giving new life to old firewalls isn’t the right route for your organization, consider replacing your firewalls altogether. A replacement firewall may be able to offer extra features and can potentially support more connections. With more connections, organizations can integrate more wireless access points into a single hardware, and can extend a wireless network further without additional hardware purchases.</p>
<p>For more exclusive firewall security insights, see <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2022/01/20/6-top-firewall-threats-and-vulnerabilities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org’s past coverage.</a> <em>Lastly, to receive cutting-edge cyber security news, insights, best practices and analyses in your inbox each week, sign up for the </em><a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/cyber-security-newsletter/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=articles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/03/how-can-you-give-a-new-life-to-your-old-firewalls/">How can you give a new life to your old firewalls?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REvil ransomware gang returns, targeting new high-value victims (like you)</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/02/revil-ransomware-gang-returns-targeting-new-high-value-victims-like-you/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 17:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REvil]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REvil back]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REvil ransomware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[REvil ransomware gang]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18766</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: REvil is back. The REvil ransomware gang is an ambitious Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) operation. It first came to light in 2019, as another ransomware gang, known as GandCrab, dissolved into a digital black hole. On occasion, the group is known by other names, including Sodin and Sodinokibi. What makes REvil unique REvil has a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/02/revil-ransomware-gang-returns-targeting-new-high-value-victims-like-you/">REvil ransomware gang returns, targeting new high-value victims (like you)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:</h2>
<p>REvil is back. The REvil ransomware gang is an ambitious Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) operation. It first came to light in 2019, as another ransomware gang, known as GandCrab, dissolved into a digital black hole. On occasion, the group is known by other names, including Sodin and Sodinokibi.</p>
<h3><strong>What makes REvil unique</strong></h3>
<p>REvil has a rap sheet that includes requesting exorbitant payments from corporate victims. Its affiliates are also known for pursuing high levels of financial gain. In ‘underground’ cyber crime forums, REvil’s software is often recommended by cyber criminals as the best choice for maximizing profits.</p>
<p>In an interview, the group’s product developers claimed to have earned more than <a href="https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/featured/revil-ransomware-what-you-need-to-know/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$100</a> million USD per year through their operations. The developers are thought to receive just a fraction, roughly 20-30%, of the total funds extorted from victims.</p>
<p>In the past, numerous high-profile o<span style="color: #000000;">rganizations have contended with REvil’s ransomware. The group is allegedly responsible for the <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/06/02/global-meat-processor-ransomware-attack-shut-down-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JBS cyber attack</a>, which affected the global food supply chain, the <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/07/06/kaseya-what-this-ransomware-attack-fallout-means/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kaseya VSA ransomware attack</a>, which affected hundreds of managed service providers, and the <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/06/09/colonial-pipeline-co-attack-what-really-happened/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Colonial Pipeline attack</a>, which disrupted the oil supply chain in the US.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Wait, but weren’t REvil members arrested?</strong></h3>
<h3></h3>
<p>In January, authorities in Russia announced the disruption of the REvil ransomware gang’s activities. Fourteen of the group’s members were arrested. General operations were halted. The event “marked a rare positive moment” in geopolitical relations, according to the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/01/14/russia-hacker-revil/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Washington Post.</a></p>
<p>The takedown occurred in Russia, at the request of the US government, which intended to curtail possibilities for repeats of past cyber security incidents.</p>
<p>At the time, the FSB seized millions of USD, Euros and Rubles, 20 luxury cars, computer equipment, and cryptocurrency wallets containing more than £<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-59998925#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20Russian%20state,440%2C000%20worth%20of%20crypto%2Dcurrency." target="_blank" rel="noopener">440,000</a> worth of Bitcoin from REvil members. A partial video of the sting made its way onto the internet.</p>
<p>However, amidst recent geopolitical tensions, REvil members may have been excused from past offenses. REvil has begun operating again.</p>
<h3><strong>REvil ransomware reemergence – <em>technical details</em></strong></h3>
<p>Last week, researchers obtained a sample of a seemingly new ransomware operation’s encryptor. They <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/revil-ransomware-returns-new-malware-sample-confirms-gang-is-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed ties</a> to the REvil group. Although a few ransomware operations do use REvil’s encryptor, all rely on patched executables as opposed to maintaining direct access to the gang’s source code. Multiple security researchers and malware analysts state that the discovered REvil sample reflects a compilation of source code and includes new changes to the original encryptor.</p>
<h3><strong>Closing thoughts</strong></h3>
<p>In general, if affected by ransomware, organizations can restore systems from backups. The danger in relation to REvil stems from the fact that the group may try to sell an organization’s data in cyber crime forums, tarnishing a brand’s image and client relationships. This represents another &#8216;layer&#8217; of the REvil extortion scheme.</p>
<p>In the event that your organization suffers a ransomware attack, pursue mitigation strategies and inform law enforcement agencies of the incident. Work with them to determine which ransomware group conducted the attack.</p>
<h3><strong>Further resources<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>For more information about the REvil ransomware gang, see our past articles:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/10/06/revil-ransomware-gang-scams-its-own-affiliates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">REvil ransomware gang scams its own affiliates</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/06/14/this-nuclear-weapons-subcontractor-just-hit-with-revil-ransomware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nuclear weapons subcontractor hit with REvil ransomware</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/09/29/global-ransomware-group-reappears-did-it-ever-leave/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Global ransomware group reappears; did it ever leave?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news,  best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/05/02/revil-ransomware-gang-returns-targeting-new-high-value-victims-like-you/">REvil ransomware gang returns, targeting new high-value victims (like you)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing cyber security concerns on employees’ personal devices</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/29/addressing-cyber-security-concerns-on-employees-personal-devices/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 17:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[OPINION]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile device cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile device management]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18760</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Devin Partida writes about cyber security and technology. She is also the Editor-in-Chief of ReHack.com.  Almost every American carries their smartphone wherever they go. Mobile devices have become an integral part of life for most people, meaning employers should expect that their employees will bring smartphones and other devices to work. While BYOD in the workplace [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/29/addressing-cyber-security-concerns-on-employees-personal-devices/">Addressing cyber security concerns on employees’ personal devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Devin Partida writes about cyber security and technology. She is also the Editor-in-Chief of <a href="https://rehack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ReHack.com</a>. </em></p>
<p>Almost every American carries their smartphone wherever they go. Mobile devices have become an integral part of life for most people, meaning employers should expect that their employees will bring smartphones and other devices to work.</p>
<p>While BYOD in the workplace is nothing new, these personal devices can make a business more vulnerable to cyber attacks. Without the right security policies, personal devices are a risk. Here’s more about cyber security risks around personal devices that should concern employers, especially as employees return to the workplace.</p>
<h3><strong>The potential risks of personal devices in the workplace</strong></h3>
<p>Mobile devices can be susceptible to attack in ways that laptops or desktop computers are not – especially when those mobile devices are personal devices that employees may not properly secure and IT does not have access to by default.</p>
<p>Employees may inadvertently compromise their personal devices with malware from spam, malicious links, or phishing campaigns (which <a href="https://www.f5.com/company/news/features/phishing-attacks-soar-220--during-covid-19-peak-as-cybercriminal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have become much more common</a> since the beginning of COVID-19).</p>
<p>Social engineering attacks and lost devices may also provide attackers with direct access to an employee’s personal device – and, as a result, any corporate information or business network access their device may have. A compromised personal device may easily lead to a more serious corporate data breach.</p>
<p>Hackers have plenty of reasons for targeting personal mobile devices, even if they don’t know a device has corporate data or network access. Tools like digital wallets, for example, <a href="https://www.hydrogenplatform.com/blog/what-is-a-digital-wallet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">make transactions much easier</a>, but may also hold onto financial information that a cyber criminal may attempt to steal.</p>
<p>Personal mobile devices may not be subject to the same security policies as corporate devices and IT teams may not even know they exist. These devices can create serious security risks that businesses will need to anticipate and manage. At the same time, preventing employees from bringing these devices to work may not be practical or could be seen as unusual.</p>
<h3><strong>How businesses can manage cybersecurity with personal devices</strong></h3>
<p>A combination of BYOD policy, training, and mobile device security tools will help businesses manage the security risks of personal devices while allowing employees to bring their devices to work.</p>
<p>Effective BYOD policies help IT teams identify and secure personal devices. They also teach employees how to safely use their personal devices at work and provide specific guidance that they can use to protect both their devices and the company&#8217;s network.</p>
<p>For example, a BYOD policy may require that employees not use their devices to store company information. This helps ensure that if a device is compromised, corporate information will remain confidential.</p>
<p>Businesses can use tools like <a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/cyber-hub/threat-prevention/what-is-mdm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mobile device management software</a> to ensure that employees use their personal devices in a way that protects their data, the company’s data, and the company network.</p>
<p>These management tools create barriers on employee devices that separate corporate information from personal information, helping to ensure that employees do not accidentally compromise corporate information on their devices.</p>
<p>If necessary, a business could also require that employees use only business-provided devices in the workplace and leave their personal devices at home or off while they work. This solution can be challenging to implement if the company isn’t willing to invest in new devices for workers, however, and able to navigate ongoing tech shortages.</p>
<p>The company must also be willing to accept a transitional period during which employees adapt to new workflows that don’t involve their personal devices. These employees may also need to transfer work files off of their personal devices if they were using these devices for storage.</p>
<h3><strong>Protecting employees’ personal devices in the workplace</strong></h3>
<p>Having personal devices in the workplace is already the norm for many businesses, but these devices can come with cyber security risks.</p>
<p>If compromised, a personal device may provide a hacker with access to important business information or network access. Because these devices are often unprotected and unmonitored by business IT teams, they may be more vulnerable to attack.</p>
<p>Businesses should take action to ensure employees’ personal devices don’t create additional cyber security risks. Otherwise, they may be exposing both the business and its employees to cyber crime.</p>
<p>For more from Editor-in-Chief of Rehack.com, Devin Partida, <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2022/01/21/how-to-improve-cyber-security-awareness-company-wide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">see CyberTalk.org&#8217;s past coverage</a>. <em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news, best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/29/addressing-cyber-security-concerns-on-employees-personal-devices/">Addressing cyber security concerns on employees’ personal devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Log4j strategies that can stop Log4j threats right now</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/28/4-log4j-fix-strategies-that-can-stop-log4j-threats-now/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j core]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j detection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j fix]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j management]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j vulnerability management]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4j wordpress]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Log4Shell]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[patching]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18738</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: The Log4j vulnerabilities represent a complicated and concerning set of issues for organizations and management around the globe. International cyber security watchdogs say that organizations should continue to remain cognizant of risks associated with Log4J attacks, and should stay on high-alert for potential Log4j-based threats. In the eyes of some experts, Log4j is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/28/4-log4j-fix-strategies-that-can-stop-log4j-threats-now/">4 Log4j strategies that can stop Log4j threats right now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:</h2>
<p>The Log4j vulnerabilities represent a complicated and concerning set of issues for organizations and management around the globe. International cyber security watchdogs say that organizations should continue to remain cognizant of risks associated with Log4J attacks, and should stay on high-alert for potential Log4j-based threats. In the eyes of some experts, Log4j is among the most dangerous flaws disclosed in recent years. ​</p>
<p>Upon its discovery, a Log4j fix was not apparent or available, and the cyber security workforce spent many hours attempting to identify and mitigate the vulnerability. Since then, a patch has been released. However, vulnerability isolation and patching hasn’t necessarily proceeded in the way that experts might have hoped…</p>
<h3><strong>Recent Log4j developments</strong></h3>
<p>In a recent scan, cyber security researchers discovered that more than 90,000 internet-exposed servers continue to contain vulnerable versions of the software. And this number may represent a mere fraction of the available attacker targets, as researchers only investigated publicly facing servers running on open source software. Once internal network servers and servers running proprietary applications are accounted for, the cumulative number of vulnerable targets could far surpass 90,000.</p>
<h3><strong>Limitations of patching</strong></h3>
<p>While the obvious Log4j fix does consist of patching, a Google open source scanning service recently revealed that just 7,140 Java packages have been patched since Log4j was disclosed. This number represents only 40% of affected packages, which total 17,840. In other words, many vulnerable Java packages containing the Log4j library remain unpatched.</p>
<p>Adding to the concern around continued possibilities for exploit, researchers note that 36% of Log4j versions downloaded from Maven Central remain vulnerable.</p>
<h3><strong>Other issues</strong></h3>
<p>One difficulty is that many organizations lack visibility into their software components, which explains the continued use of vulnerable versions of Log4j. Few organizations maintain detailed configuration management databases that would show precise Log4j usage locations.</p>
<h3><strong>Log4j fix information</strong></h3>
<p>The continued exploitation of Log4j indicates that organizations aren’t prioritizing vulnerability identification, patching and other protective measures. For some, there may not be a single Log4j fix. However, you’ll find both short and long-term means of improving protection for your organization below.</p>
<p><strong>1. Update Web Application Firewalls (WAFs) and other perimeter security tools. </strong>In so doing, organizations can immediately halt inbound and outbound Log4j attacks. However, experts note that hackers will likely attempt to overcome such barriers and that updating these tools likely represents a partial or temporary fix. Try out a breach and attack simulation tool to assess your WAF or NGFW protection against Log4j-related attacks.</p>
<p><strong>2. Monitor your network activity. </strong>Are you seeing any unexpected outbound connections? Consider disabling outbound communications from internet-facing devices that are not business critical. In the event that you have a vulnerable system to which someone can pass a malicious JNDI command, but the malware fetch is blocked, you will have some level of protection.</p>
<p><strong>3. Check device update status’.</strong> Search through every server, printer and other devices for inbound Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) connections. Contact device vendors to explore updates for Log4j. Java script is commonly in use on network appliances, printers, mobile phones and other types of devices. Experts suggest temporarily doing without use of these types of devices, if possible, until you can access Log4j information from the vendor.</p>
<p><strong>4. Update all servers to Log4j 2.15.0. </strong>The importance of updating servers cannot be overstated, as hackers are quick to <span style="color: #000000;">identify and exploit such <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://www.cpomagazine.com/cyber-security/what-does-log4j-mean-for-the-enterprise-strategies-to-protect-your-organization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vulnerabilities</a>.</span></p>
<p>Unpatched devices and systems using Log4j represent easy targets for threat actors. To further enhance protections, organizations may also wish to implement multi-factor authentication, zero-trust principles, network segmentation, and endpoint detection systems. Further, reach out to your security vendor for more customized security insights.</p>
<h3>Additional information</h3>
<h3></h3>
<p>In the event that a vulnerable Log4j asset is found, security teams should act on the basis that the system has seen compromise – searching for threats, malicious activity and ways to take action.</p>
<p>For more Log4j and Log4j solutions or Log4j fix information, see <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2022/03/16/where-are-we-with-log4j/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org’s past coverage</a>. <em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news,  best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>​</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/28/4-log4j-fix-strategies-that-can-stop-log4j-threats-now/">4 Log4j strategies that can stop Log4j threats right now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you install these dangerous Android apps? Delete them now, experts warn</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/27/did-you-install-these-dangerous-android-apps-delete-them-now-experts-warn/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 20:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Android app]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SharkBot]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sharkbot malware]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18724</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by George Mack, Content Marketing Manager, Check Point Software. Over 15,000 Android users installed applications used to spread Sharkbot malware, which is capable of stealing your credentials and banking information. According to Check Point Research, earlier this year, there were a total of six Android applications masquerading as anti-virus solutions. Google has removed these [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/27/did-you-install-these-dangerous-android-apps-delete-them-now-experts-warn/">Did you install these dangerous Android apps? Delete them now, experts warn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Contributed by George Mack, Content Marketing Manager, Check Point Software.</em></p>
<p>Over 15,000 Android users installed applications used to spread Sharkbot malware, which is capable of stealing your credentials and banking information.</p>
<p>According to Check Point Research, earlier this year, there were a total of six Android applications masquerading as anti-virus solutions. Google has removed these apps from the Play Store, but if you installed any of the apps below, you should delete them immediately.</p>
<h3><strong>Remove these malicious apps from your phone</strong></h3>
<p>Here is a list of the Sharkbot-related apps:</p>
<ul>
<li>Atom Clean-Booster, Antivirus</li>
<li>Antivirus, Super Cleaner</li>
<li>Alpha Antivirus, Cleaner</li>
<li>Powerful Cleaner, Antivirus</li>
<li>Center Security – Antivirus (listed twice with two different icons)</li>
</ul>
<p>After revealing the details to Google on March 3<sup>rd</sup>, the apps were removed from the Play Store by March 27<sup>th</sup>. But if you have any of these apps on your device, then you still need to remove them. Make sure you check your bank account statements for any odd activity and change the passwords to your bank accounts.</p>
<h3><strong>Ho<span style="color: #000000;">w <a style="color: #000000;" href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2022/03/08/sharkbot-banking-malware-hits-google-play-store-posing-as-antivirus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sharkbot malware</a> works</span></strong></h3>
<p>SharkBot’s goal is to initiate money transfers from compromised devices via Automatic Transfer Systems (ATS). According to researchers, this is an uncommon and advanced attack technique.</p>
<p>In traditional Android banking malware, a live person needs to authorize and transact the money transfer. SharkBot is more advanced; threat actors can auto-fill the fields in the mobile banking app and initiate the money transfer. The malware can also simulate button touches and clicks, allowing other malicious applications to be installed.</p>
<p>Sharkbot is also able to bypass multi-factor authentication mechanisms by using ATS. However, for SharkBot to abuse many of the features in Android, the victim needs to enable the <strong>Accessibility Permissions &amp; Services</strong>. The Android banking malware uses the permissions to intercept the accessibility events produced by the victim, such as touches, button presses, and other events. The accessibility events also detect when the banking application is open in order to steal user’s credentials.</p>
<p>Sharkbot has the ability to reply to notifications from WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger to distribute phishing links to the banking Trojan, thus spreading the malware to more users.</p>
<h3><strong>How to avoid downloading malicious apps</strong></h3>
<p>Threat actors are always looking for new ways to spread malware by any means possible. They accomplish this by making their apps look legitimate and by creating applications that are already in high demand, such as calculators and flashlights, to attract more downloads. If you’re looking for an application from the Play Store, make sure to do your due diligence.</p>
<p>Android users should:</p>
<ul>
<li>Only install applications from trusted and verified publishers</li>
<li>Check if there is an equivalent application from a trusted publisher if you find an application from a new publisher</li>
<li>Report any suspicious applications or activities to Google</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Mobile security protections</strong></h3>
<p>If you’re responsible for the security of your business or organization, then you need a mobile security solution.</p>
<p>Check Point’s <a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/harmony/mobile-security/mobile/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Harmony Mobile</a> prevents malware from infiltrating mobile devices by detecting and blocking the download of malicious apps in real-time. Harmony Mobile’s unique network security infrastructure – on-device network protection – allows you to stay ahead of emerging threats by extending Check Point’s industry-leading network security <a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/quantum/maestro-hyperscale-network-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">technologies</a> to mobile devices.</p>
<p><em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news,  best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/27/did-you-install-these-dangerous-android-apps-delete-them-now-experts-warn/">Did you install these dangerous Android apps? Delete them now, experts warn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing security with the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/advancing-security-with-the-mitre-attck-framework/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 20:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Deryck Mitchelson]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Deryck Mitchelson Field CISO EMEA Check Point Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MITRE ATT&CK]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18705</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Deryck Mitchelson, Field CISO EMEA, Check Point Software. The MITRE ATT&#38;CK framework represents a globally accessible knowledge base containing adversary tactics, techniques, and resources designed to aid cyber security defenders. The framework empowers defenders to identify gaps in visibility, defensive tools, and cyber security processes. It also serves as a “common language” for understanding the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/advancing-security-with-the-mitre-attck-framework/">Advancing security with the MITRE ATT&#038;CK framework</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Deryck Mitchelson, Field CISO EMEA, Check Point Software.</em></p>
<p>The MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework represents a globally accessible knowledge base containing adversary tactics, techniques, and resources designed to aid cyber security defenders. The framework empowers defenders to identify gaps in visibility, defensive tools, and cyber security processes.</p>
<p>It also serves as a “common language” for understanding the mechanics and impact of attacks. In turn, experts can then prepare stronger attack responses.</p>
<p>This article decodes the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework, highlights its utility and describes how to operationalize the information so that it seamlessly integrates into your existing cyber security processes and programming.</p>
<h3><strong>The MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>The MITRE Corporation is a federally funded non-profit group that receives security information from researchers, which is then catalogued in easy-to-read matrices.</p>
<p>The three core matrices that MITRE produces are:</p>
<p><strong>Enterprise: </strong>In this matrix, users can find information covering enterprise-level preparatory techniques for Windows, macOS, Linux, cloud, network and container environments.</p>
<p><strong>Mobile: </strong>In this matrix, users can see how adversaries may hack into Android or iOS devices. Individual matrices exist for each respective mobile device type.</p>
<p><strong>Industrial Control Systems:</strong> Attack for Industrial Control Systems (ICS) provides tactics and technique information pertaining to ICS infrastructure. A helpful list of resources is also available to offer contextual information around ICS attacks.</p>
<p>MITRE ATT&amp;CK information should not necessarily be applied directly. Some concepts or techniques may require customization in order to maximise benefits for specific organisations or projects.</p>
<h3><strong>MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework’s utility<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>The MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework allows for the aggregation and distribution of critical security information. Shared insights among the cyber security community can assist everyone in preparing for a more cyber secure future.</p>
<p>Through the active use of MITRE, security teams can prevent breaches and stop in-motion attacks. The framework can help your organisation better align security strategy with attacker behaviour, enabling you to champion meaningful and measurable security outcomes.</p>
<h3><strong>MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework: Blind spots<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>MITRE ATT&amp;CK&#8217;s resources primarily help defenders protect internal networks. Should your organisation need to monitor Infrastructure-as-a-Service or web applications, prioritise the adversarial techniques that need to be monitored, and conduct simulations accordingly. This will assist you in preventing the most common threats that may affect your sector or organisation.</p>
<h3><strong>Closing thoughts<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>The MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework represents an invaluable resource for security professionals. It is open and available to any person or organization at no charge<em>. </em>In operationalizing the framework, you can increase your levels of threat intelligence, visibility, vulnerability management, and mitigation effectiveness.</p>
<p>CheckPoint has integrated MITRE ATT&amp;CK’s taxonomy into its entire solution portfolio, and in so doing, we frame attacks in a common language that the cyber community understands.</p>
<p>Mappings to MITRE ATT&amp;CK techniques are included in forensic reports, malware capability descriptions, <a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/products/infinity-soc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Infinity SOC</a> and <a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/cyber-hub/threat-prevention/what-is-xdr-extended-detection-and-response/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Infinity XDR</a>, and more.</p>
<p>This provides an SOC analyst with a number of advantages. When analysing a particular attack, the use of MITRE ATT&amp;CK makes it easy to understand the root causes, attack flow, and the attacker’s intent in each stage. By understanding what the attacker is trying to achieve and how, an SOC team can easily understand the scope of an attack, any necessary remediation, and how to improve defences for the future.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-18706 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Picture_MITRE_ATTCK-300x181.png" alt="Picture_MITRE_ATT&amp;CK Framework" width="300" height="181" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s less a question of &#8216;if&#8217; your organization will experience a cyber security breach, as much as &#8216;when&#8217;. Incorporate MITRE ATT&amp;CK into your security framework to augment your security effectiveness and to achieve stronger results.</p>
<p><em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news, best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/advancing-security-with-the-mitre-attck-framework/">Advancing security with the MITRE ATT&#038;CK framework</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 cloud security breaches (and lessons)</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/top-5-cloud-security-breaches-and-lessons/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cloud security attack]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cloud security attacks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud security breach]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud security breaches]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18688</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: Organizations leverage cloud computing to reduce compute costs and to rapidly provision new computing resources for the purpose of supporting evolving business needs. Cloud-based technologies provide opportunities to go-to-market quickly, allowing enterprises to reach stakeholders and customers faster than ever before. Across the past 10 years, cloud computing has transformed from into a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/top-5-cloud-security-breaches-and-lessons/">Top 5 cloud security breaches (and lessons)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:</p>
<p>Organizations leverage cloud computing to reduce compute costs and to rapidly provision new computing resources for the purpose of supporting evolving business needs. Cloud-based technologies provide opportunities to go-to-market quickly, allowing enterprises to reach stakeholders and customers faster than ever before.</p>
<p>Across the past 10 years, cloud computing has transformed from into a cornerstone of the IT industry, boosting power of virtualization, storage, hosting and other networking services. Nonetheless, the cloud environment is vulnerable to cyber attacks. In 2021, <a href="https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/96412-40-of-organizations-have-suffered-a-cloud-based-data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noopener">forty percent</a> of organizations reported cloud security breaches.</p>
<p>Below are five cloud security breach examples and lessons that all organizations can benefit from.</p>
<h2><strong>5 cloud security breaches (and lessons)</strong></h2>
<p><strong>1. Accenture.</strong> In August of 2021, Accenture fell prey to a LockBit ransomware attack. The culprits claimed to have stolen 6TB worth of data, for which they requested a ransom of $50 million.</p>
<p>The largest exposed server appeared to contain credentials linked to Accenture customer accounts. One backup database contained nearly <a href="https://www.healthcareitnews.com/news/accenture-latest-breach-client-data-due-misconfigured-aws-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener">40,000</a> passwords – the majority of which were in plain text.</p>
<p>“This cloud leak shows that even the most advanced and secure enterprises can expose crucial data and risk serious consequences,” wrote security researcher <a href="https://www.healthcareitnews.com/news/accenture-latest-breach-client-data-due-misconfigured-aws-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chris Vickery</a>.</p>
<p><em>Lesson learned:</em> Ensure that IT departments and/or cyber security personnel check to ensure correct configuration of AWS cloud servers. Attacks on misconfigured servers can cause extreme reputational, client and financial damage.</p>
<p><strong>2. Kaseya.</strong> In July of 2021, IT solutions provider Kaseya identified an attack on their unified remote monitoring and network perimeter security tool. The attackers aimed to steal administrative control for Kaseya services; from managed service providers to downstream customers.</p>
<p>The attack itself disrupted the organization’s SaaS servers and affected on premise VSA solutions used by Kaseya customers across nearly a dozen countries. After Kaseya alerted customers about the attack, it then rolled out the Kaseya VSA detection tool, which enabled business users to analyze VSA services and to screen endpoints for indicators of vulnerability.</p>
<p><em>Lessons learned:</em> From this attack, organizations observed the importance of maintaining updated backups in easily retrievable, air-gapped repositories that remain segregated from organizational networks. Businesses are also reminded to manage patches, implement multi-factor authentication, and follow principles of zero trust.</p>
<p><strong>3. Cognyte.</strong> In May of 2021, the cyber analytics firm Cognyte left a database unsecured without authentication protocols. In turn, hackers managed to expose 5 billion records. Information such as names, email addresses, passwords, and vulnerability data points within their system were leaked. Information was even indexed by search engines.<strong></p>
<p></strong><em>Lessons learned:</em> The company managed to secure the data within four days, but the incident highlighted how persistent cyber attackers can effectively exploit the smallest of flaws. In this instance, the importance of cyber attack prevention cannot be overstated. Prevent as many attacks as possible through a combination of policies, tools, education and vigilance.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>4. Facebook.</strong> In April of 2021, Facebook reported a breach affecting hundreds of millions of user records, which were publicly exposed on Amazon’s cloud computing service. Although Facebook confirmed that it identified and resolved the issue immediately, the attack managed to impact founder Mark Zuckerberg.<strong></p>
<p></strong>In precipitating the incident, two third-party Facebook app development companies posted the records <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/millions-facebook-user-records-exposed-amazon-cloud-server/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in plain sight</a>. The database exposed contained private information that social engineers could use in targeted attacks or within hacking attempts.</p>
<p><em>Lessons learned: </em>In resolving this issue, Facebook reached out to Amazon, which took down the exposed servers. “…If you’re still opening AWS buckets [to the public], you’re not paying attention,” says business advisor <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-tn-facebook-user-data-amazon-web-services-privacy-20190403-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corey Quinn</a>.</p>
<p><strong>5. Raychat.</strong> In February of 2021, Raychat, an online chat application, survived a large-scale cyber attack. A cloud database configuration breach gave hackers free access to 267 million usernames, emails, passwords, metadata and encrypted chats. Shortly thereafter, a targeted bot attack erased the entirety of the company’s data.<strong></p>
<p></strong>According to reports, a MongoDB misconfiguration left the data openly available. The attack highlighted how NoSQL databases can function as easy targets for bot threat actors.<strong></p>
<p></strong>Organizations need to ensure that databases are secure. NoSQL databases in particular represent targets for malicious actors who wish to steal or wipe content, unless given a ransom payment. In Raychat’s case, a README ransom note appeared, demanding roughly $700 USD.</p>
<p><em>Lesson learned:</em> Database security requires a range of tools controls and measures that can protect the database itself, the actual data embedded within, its database management system and the assorted applications that access it. End-to-end compliance technologies and cybersecurity penetration tests can help.</p>
<h3><strong>In closing</strong></h3>
<p>Cloud computing increases operational efficiency and simplicity, provided that security measures are in place. Is your cloud secure enough?</p>
<p>Be sure to avoid AWS security breaches and other common stumbling points. For more cloud security breach insights, see <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/2021/10/20/key-cloud-security-statistics-that-will-reshape-your-cloud-perspectives/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org’s past coverage</a>. Also, be sure to check out our <a href="https://pages.checkpoint.com/buyers_guide_to_cloud_security_posture_management.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cloud Security Buyer’s Guide</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/26/top-5-cloud-security-breaches-and-lessons/">Top 5 cloud security breaches (and lessons)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing the cyber criminal supply chain</title>
      <link>https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/25/exposing-the-cyber-criminal-supply-chain/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shira Landau]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 21:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[OPINION]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TRENDING NOW]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://dm-cybertalk.us.checkpoint.com/?p=18681</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>By Pete Nicoletti, Check Point Field CISO, Americas Since the inception of the internet, we’ve referred to the bad guys as “hackers.”  But who are they exactly? How many people are involved? And most importantly, how can we reverse the increasing number of breaches conducted by cyber criminals? Recently, criminal organizations have evolved into large [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/25/exposing-the-cyber-criminal-supply-chain/">Exposing the cyber criminal supply chain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Pete Nicoletti, Check Point Field CISO, Americas</p>
<p>Since the inception of the internet, we’ve referred to the bad guys as “hackers.”  But who are they exactly? How many people are involved? And most importantly, how can we reverse the increasing number of breaches conducted by cyber criminals?</p>
<p>Recently, criminal organizations have evolved into large multi-national enterprises. They now have all of the characteristics of a regular business. As with any other organization, cyber criminals need to pay their hundreds of employees, write and modify software code, create exploits, manage the targeting, exploitation and extortion of companies, and then dole out their ill-gotten gains to the participants. They have standard operating procedures, ticketing systems, tech support, contracts, hiring bonuses, training programs, college recruiting days and other characteristics of a normal company. Furthermore, the cyber criminal supply chain consists of not just one organization, but also dozens of affiliate crime groups that work together to profit from malware, DDoSing, ransomware-as-a-service, botnets, and other threat types.</p>
<p>Cyber crime is an illicit multi-billion dollar industry. If you’re an IT security practitioner or a C-level executive, then it’s critical to understand who you’re up against and how you can disrupt their activities.</p>
<h3><strong>The rise in cyber criminal syndicates</strong></h3>
<p>Financial reward is still the main motive behind most cyber attacks, so it comes as no surprise that cyber attacks have increased at alarming rates. In 2021, organizations witnessed a 50% rise in cyber attacks compared to 2020, and this number is expected to increase throughout 2022.</p>
<p>Cyber criminal organizations are structured like any other business enterprise. Every year, they evolve, pivot, and expand with new business angles and revenue streams. These organizations have one goal in mind – to spread of malware, ransomware, encryption extortion and related disruptions to generate profits.</p>
<h3><strong>The cyber criminal supply chain</strong></h3>
<p>What does the cybercrime supply chain look like? There are multiple players working together. First, the creators of malware sell, license, and distribute their software to affiliates and distributors, who then sell the software to partners, clients, and individual threat actors who target their victims.</p>
<p>Then, there are hackers -also known as “brokers”- who sell access to hacked companies as well as to others who manage “insiders” willing to sell out their company for some silver. These criminals are charging anywhere from $500 to $7,000 for access to organizations’ networks, and these victims range from healthcare organizations to charities. When profits are at stake, morals don’t matter.</p>
<p>Brokers often advertise their breaches in the corners of the Dark Web. Thus, it’s recommended that organizations lurk there or hire consultants to find out about whether or not a broker is advertising a breach of their network. Then, the victim organization can take preventative actions to remove the backdoor. A Spain-based arm of Doctors Without Borders discovered that a broker was advertising access into one of their servers. Once discovered, they immediately took corrective measures and strengthened their security processes.</p>
<p>On the financial end, you have money managers who launder money and churn transactions to hide the ultimate money destinations, and those that process transactions and distribute payroll. Other individuals manage the sale of information on the Dark Web. They take advantage of money mules, who unwittingly lauder money and have no idea that what they’re doing is illegal. For example, a crime group will hire for an “Accounts Payable Manager,” portraying it as an easy job that anyone can do. However, what the job entails is processing invoices and sending them off to pay another account, which is actually laundering their money. And the legal consequences will fall on the person moving the money, even if they don’t know that what they’re doing is illegal.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at one of the most infamous examples of a cyber attack that has become the bread and butter of cyber criminal groups: ransomware, or more specifically, Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS). There’s a reason as to why ransomware has become incredibly popular; it’s because it works. The average ransom payment for US victims has increased to more than $6 million. With the amount of money at stake, it makes sense for threat actors to treat this professionally &#8211; like a business enterprise.</p>
<p>There are a growing number of organizations, such as REvil, DarkSide, and others who provide Ransomware-as-a-Service to threat actors. Affiliates and clients are responsible for using the tools to penetrate the organization, while the ransomware franchisers provide ransom collection, encryption tools, and other services. They also collect a percentage of the total ransom obtained. The affiliates then attempt to monetize stolen blueprints and intellectual property and will even start blackmailing customers of the hacked company.</p>
<p>This is referred to as “Triple Extorsion Ransomware” as it extracts money from the target company, their customers and their partners. Hackers commonly target critical infrastructure entities such as healthcare, transportation, and citizen services. These organizations often can’t afford the downtime, may not have the budget or security experts on staff, and are more likely to pay a ransom than other types of groups.</p>
<h3><strong>How to break the supply chain<br />
</strong></h3>
<p>The goal of disrupting any threat is to block it before it can cause damage. In the previous generation of cyber threats, we used the “Kill Chain” model of an attack. That model has evolved into the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework, as it is much more descriptive of the tactics, techniques and procedures that threat actors use. When attackers start to arrive at the front door, the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework is often put into immediate play.</p>
<p>But what are some approaches we’ve seen used before the hackers knock on your front door?  Until you are willing to travel to Russia, China or North Korea, we’ll have to depend on Law enforcement! The FBI, Interpol and other agencies can be a great partner that is at least partially focused on different methods to disrupt the hacker supply chain. In the past, we have seen government agencies shut down pirate sites set up for facilitating illegal sharing of movies and television shows. That was small time stuff.</p>
<p>Now, law enforcement is targeting sites that sell and trade credit cards, illegal drugs, weapons, and hacking tools. Law enforcement is focusing on shutting down service providers, data hosts, and command and control networks that allow criminals to use their infrastructures to carry out their nefarious operations.</p>
<p>It’s also critical to follow the money: police and detectives can focus on tracking cryptocurrency transactions through the block chain to see which groups and affiliates are connected. There is an entirely new FBI Division focused exclusively on criminals abusing cryptocurrency.  Compromising those sites and taking internal information and decryption keys, learning their tactics, freezing those assets and arresting the bad actors will have a significant impact.  Last week, six members of the LAPUS$ group were arrested, and their activities were disrupted. We have also seen how law enforcement can seed the Dark Web forums with misinformation or traps to lure criminals into giving up valuable information.</p>
<p>Once the attack is directed towards you, there are several ways an organization can disrupt the criminal supply chain. First, you must have your cloud, network, endpoint and email protection tools all working together to “prevent” issues rather than just “detect” them.  Detection is no longer good enough as the threat actors have sped up the time from initial compromise to data exfiltration and encryption to mere seconds. Your tools must work at “machine speed,” not at “human speed.”</p>
<p>If your tools only detect an issue, and you create a ticket while waiting for a human to research the problem, then you will experience a compromise soon! Your tools must also leverage artificial intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) algorithms designed to spot zero-days and their indicators. This capability enhances companies’ ability to execute countermeasures automatically as an attack hits.</p>
<p>Second, your tools must leverage threat feeds to harness the power of seeing threats as they are seen attacking others. This info sharing also needs to be bi-directional, as by sharing this threat intelligence, organizations around the world can be prepared at the hint of a new attack. Of course, there are many other ways that organizations can beef up their own security and make it more difficult for cyber criminals to get in, so they will move on to an easier target. Finally, businesses need to thoroughly examine all the links in their own supply chain, partners, franchisees and remote offices to improve their security posture. This includes requiring 3<sup>rd</sup> party suppliers to verify the security of their processes as well as not fully trusting them and using security gateways to inspect their traffic. All these tactics combined will effectively disrupt the cyber criminal business model.</p>
<p>Cyber crime has evolved into a huge industry in which threat actors have copied the business structures of legitimate organizations and are becoming more successful and damaging. With their own well-funded supply chain in place, it’s on us – organization and government leaders – to take the necessary actions to disrupt and ultimately put an end to their business model. This requires moving your tools to a “prevention” posture, identifying and dropping zero-day attacks before they are implemented, leveraging AI/ML to respond at lightning speed while working with and cheering on law enforcement as they are disrupting their hacking and financial networks.</p>
<p>Don’t think that it can’t happen to you! <em>Lastly, to receive more cutting-edge cyber security news,  best practices and analyses, please sign up for the <a href="https://www.cybertalk.org/weekly-digest/?utm_source=cybertalk&amp;utm_medium=cp-website&amp;utm_campaign=ct&amp;utm_content=top-10-newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CyberTalk.org newsletter. </a></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org/2022/04/25/exposing-the-cyber-criminal-supply-chain/">Exposing the cyber criminal supply chain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cybertalk.org">CyberTalk</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>