<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:event="https://www.brookings.edu/events/">
  <channel>
    <title>International Affairs</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/international-affairs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.brookings.edu</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:03:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Does the China-Solomon Islands security pact portend a more interventionist Beijing?</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/05/06/does-the-china-solomon-islands-security-pact-portend-a-more-interventionist-beijing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patricia M. Kim]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1604497</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The recent announcement of a new security agreement between China and the Solomon Islands has rattled leaders in Washington, Canberra, and other Indo-Pacific capitals who fear it opens the door to a Chinese military presence in the southern Pacific. Much of the attention has been on the deal’s potential to lead to a Chinese military&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Patricia M. Kim</p><p>The recent announcement of a new security agreement between China and the Solomon Islands has rattled leaders in Washington, Canberra, and other Indo-Pacific capitals who fear it opens the door to a Chinese military presence in the southern Pacific. Much of the attention has been on the deal’s potential to lead to a Chinese military base on the island nation, and the power-projection capabilities the People’s Liberation Army (PLA) would gain as a result. But the new pact raises another critical question that has received less attention: is China is reentering the business of militarily propping up friendly regimes?</p>

<p>While Beijing is no stranger to serving as an economic and diplomatic lifeline to close partners, it has largely eschewed providing direct security assistance to other states since the second half of the Cold War, for both pragmatic and principled reasons. Although it remains to be seen how precisely Beijing and Honiara will operationalize their new security pact, a looming question is whether this agreement will prove to be an exception or if it heralds the rise of a more activist China that is now willing to extend military support to other states in its concerted <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2021-11-15/chinas-search-allies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">search for allies</a>.</p>
<p>If the latter turns out to be the case, there may be sweeping geostrategic consequences, including heightened incentives for rogue actors and regimes to play off Washington and Beijing in pursuit of their parochial interests, the erosion of democratic governance and norms, and greater volatility in the global arena as a result.</p>
<h2><strong>Is China entering a new chapter of interventionism?</strong></h2>
<p>According to the <a href="https://twitter.com/annapowles/status/1506845794728837120" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leaked draft</a> of the security agreement between China and the Solomon Islands, Beijing has agreed to send armed police, military personnel, and other law enforcement forces to assist Honiara in “maintaining social order, protecting people’s lives and property, and providing humanitarian assistance.” The draft text also states that China, with the consent of Honiara, can use its forces to protect Chinese personnel and projects, and for its ships to stopover and carry out “logistical replenishment” in the Solomon Islands. While firmly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/solomon-islands-pm-says-wont-accept-militarisation-pacific-2022-04-29/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">denying</a> that the agreement allows for a Chinese naval base, Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare has <a href="https://www.solomonstarnews.com/a-stable-solomon-islands-a-stable-pacific/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">characterized</a> the new security pact with Beijing as necessary for countering the “hard internal threats” facing his country. Sogavare has made the case that the Solomon Islands’ existing <a href="https://www.dfat.gov.au/geo/solomon-islands/Pages/Bilateral-security-treaty" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bilateral security treat</a> with Australia, which was most recently activated last year following anti-government protests in the capital, has proven “inadequate.”</p>
<p>Beijing’s commitment to help Honiara “maintain social order” through a bilateral agreement is quite striking because while Chinese security personnel have been dispatched to foreign conflict zones in recent years, they have usually been sent under the auspices of a <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/chinas-pragmatic-approach-to-un-peacekeeping/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">United Nations peacekeeping operation</a> or as part of <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/01/15/extending-the-long-arm-of-the-law-chinas-international-law-enforcement-drive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multinational law enforcement efforts</a> focused on combating terrorism and criminal activities such as piracy and drug trafficking, rather than with the mandate of keeping a particular government in power. Chinese leaders often emphasize that their country is a “<a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/mfa_eng/wjb_663304/wjbz_663308/2461_663310/t1376908.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new type of major power</a>” that opposes militarily interventions. In fact, Chinese leaders and elites tend to believe that the United States’ misadventures as a global security provider have contributed to its decline, and insist China has no interest in taking on such a role.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Beijing has increased its peacekeeping and law enforcement activities abroad over the past two decades to both strengthen China’s image as a “responsible power,” and to advance its narrower interests in protecting Chinese citizens and investments abroad; extending its extraterritorial reach to monitor and extradite Chinese nationals in foreign settings; and securing its borders from extremist groups. Beijing’s new deal with Honiara is motivated by many of these same objectives. The desire to protect Chinese citizens and businesses was likely a large factor given that <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/deep-roots-solomon-islands-ongoing-political-crisis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent unrest</a> in the Solomon Islands targeted Chinese businesses and was driven in part by Sogavare’s decision to formally recognize China instead of Taiwan. The opportunity to extend the PLA’s reach into a strategically important theater was undoubtedly a decisive factor as well. But the fact that Beijing agreed to provide direct security assistance to help a foreign government defend against “internal threats” in exchange for advancing Chinese interests indicates a potentially alarming shift in China’s modus operandi, which until now has primarily involved the extension of loans, investments, and other economic incentives, rather than direct intervention in civil conflicts, to win friends and influence in the global arena.</p>
<p>In addition, the leaked draft agreement explicitly states China may send the <a href="https://inss.ndu.edu/Media/News/Article/1815868/chinas-other-army-the-peoples-armed-police-in-an-era-of-reform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">People’s Armed Police</a> (PAP) to engage in law enforcement activities. The PAP is the Chinese Communist Party’s paramilitary force with a primary mission to maintain internal stability inside China. The PAP’s duties include relatively benign assignments such as providing disaster relief and protecting government compounds, as well as more notorious ones such as suppressing “mass incidents” throughout the country and “maintaining order” in regions like Xinjiang and Tibet. Although there are instances of PAP forces being dispatched beyond China’s borders for joint <a href="https://www.uscc.gov/sites/default/files/2020-11/Shanghai_Cooperation_Organization-Testbed_for_Chinese_Power_Projection.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">counterterrorism initiatives</a> with neighboring states such as Tajikistan and Afghanistan, and in relatively small numbers as part of U.N. peacekeeping missions, its deployment abroad to keep a particular regime in power would be unprecedented.</p>
<h2><strong>How China’s growing security activism could change the geostrategic landscape, and implications for U.S. policy </strong></h2>
<p>To be certain, China is not the only player helping maintain internal stability in the Solomon Islands. Australia, New Zealand, and other Pacific states have sent police and troops to the island nation for peacekeeping purposes since the early 2000s. Canberra most recently faced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/solomon-islands-province-not-happy-australian-police-presence-political-aide-2021-11-29/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">criticism</a> from protestors for deploying forces to combat unrest at Sogavare’s request and giving a “moral boost” to the incumbent government. Nor would China be the first great power to use its military might to keep friendly foreign regimes in power. But Beijing’s deal with Sogavare has come <a href="https://www.aspistrategist.org.au/opposition-leader-says-solomon-islanders-dont-want-deal-with-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">under scrutiny</a> by opposition forces in the Solomon Islands and other regional stakeholders for its complete lack of transparency and <a href="https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/dutton-suggests-bribes-swayed-solomons-in-china-pact-20220421-p5aezz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">allegations of corruption</a>. The potential for the deployment of PAP forces to the region also raises concerns about the use and spread of Beijing’s repressive domestic security practices and technologies outside China’s borders.</p>
<p>Given the secretive nature of the China-Solomon Islands agreement and what is likely vague language that is open to interpretation if the final text is akin to the draft version, it will be critical to watch how Beijing and Honiara ultimately implement their security deal. For instance, Beijing may choose to narrowly protect Chinese citizens and businesses in the case of renewed unrest and otherwise remain above the fray, or it may elect to lean in heavily to provide decisive security support to keep its favored party in power. If Beijing chooses the latter model, and this serves as a precedent for deals with other partner states going forward, it could very well set into motion destabilizing dynamics unseen since the Cold War when two competing blocs sponsored rival regimes around the world. Such a development would be devasting for democratic governance and norms, global prosperity, and much needed international coordination to address pressing challenges like climate change and nuclear nonproliferation.</p>
<p>The United States has been <a href="https://islandtimes.org/time-is-up-u-s-you-are-too-late-solomon-islands-mp-kenilorea/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">criticized</a> for overlooking the Solomon Islands for decades and coming “too late” to the region, jeopardizing its longstanding interest in preserving a free and open Indo-Pacific and ensuring no rival power creates exclusionary zones or uses the Pacific to threaten the security of the United States or its allies and partners. While the past cannot be undone, the Biden administration has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/02/12/us/politics/blinken-fiji-pacific-islands.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">promised</a> to deepen engagement with Pacific island nations going forward and to assist these states with pressing 21st century challenges including addressing climate change, COVID-19 vaccines, and illegal fishing.</p>
<p>Delivering on these commitments while ensuring partner states are not treated simply as pawns in a geopolitical battle will be essential for preserving the United States’ influence and soft power in the region. In addition, long-term investments in capacity building to strengthen democratic norms, civil society, the free flow of information, and media literacy in the Pacific islands — as elsewhere — will be just as, if not more critical, so that leaders and citizens can effectively scrutinize and better manage China’s growing economic, diplomatic, and military presence in their region.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/ChinaSolomons_001.jpg?w=277" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Asia &amp; the Pacific" label="Asia &amp; the Pacific" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/asia-the-pacific/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s role in the Indo-Pacific: Opportunities and challenges under the Yoon administration</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/events/south-koreas-role-in-the-indo-pacific-opportunities-and-challenges-under-the-yoon-administration/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=event&amp;p=1604220</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[South Korean President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol and U.S. President Joseph Biden will hold their first summit meeting in Seoul on May 21. The incoming Yoon administration is expected to take a more active role in the Indo-Pacific region, working together with Washington and other like-minded U.S. allies and partners in the region. What are the prospects&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol and U.S. President Joseph Biden will hold their first summit meeting in Seoul on May 21. The incoming Yoon administration is expected to take a more active role in the Indo-Pacific region, working together with Washington and other like-minded U.S. allies and partners in the region. What are the prospects and challenges facing the Yoon administration as it seeks to strengthen bilateral and multilateral relationships in the Indo-Pacific? How do different regional players, including the Quad countries, perceive South Korea’s role as a potential Indo-Pacific partner? How will other regional actors such as ASEAN or China respond to South Korea’s more robust foreign policy in the Indo-Pacific?</p>
<p>On May 18, the <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/center/center-for-east-asia-policy-studies/">Center for East Asia Policy Studies</a> at Brookings will host a webinar featuring regional experts for a discussion of what South Korean foreign policy in the Indo-Pacific may look like under new leadership.</p>
<p>Viewers can submit questions via e-mail to <a href="mailto:events@brookings.edu">events@brookings.edu</a> or via Twitter at <strong>#ROKIndoPac</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Seoul001.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="South Korea" label="South Korea" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/south-korea/" />
      <event:locationSummary>Online Only</event:locationSummary>
      <event:type>upcoming</event:type>
      <event:startTime>1652878800</event:startTime>
      <event:endTime>1652883300</event:endTime>
      <event:timezone>America/New_York</event:timezone>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan’s economy during a time of global uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/events/taiwans-economy-during-a-time-of-global-uncertainty/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 19:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=event&amp;p=1604237</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A compounding set of global challenges has raised concerns for some observers about Taiwan’s security and its economic situation. These challenges include the continuing spread of COVID-19 and its associated disruptions to global supply chains, rising energy and food prices, inflationary pressures around the world, and the ripple effects of war in Ukraine and elsewhere.&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A compounding set of global challenges has raised concerns for some observers about Taiwan’s security and its economic situation. These challenges include the continuing spread of COVID-19 and its associated disruptions to global supply chains, rising energy and food prices, inflationary pressures around the world, and the ripple effects of war in Ukraine and elsewhere. How should members of the policy, commercial, investment, and technology communities evaluate risks relating to Taiwan? What analytic framework provides the clearest picture for understanding Taiwan’s economic value proposition?</p>
<p>On May 16, the Center for East Asia Policy Studies at the Brookings Institution and the US-Taiwan Business Council will co-host an event at the Brookings Institution featuring policy and business experts. The first panel, moderated by Brookings Senior Fellow Ryan Hass, will discuss Taiwan’s economic prospects in the shadow of cross-Strait tensions. The following panel, moderated by President of the US-Taiwan Business Council Rupert Hammond-Chambers, will discuss Taiwan’s globalized economy as companies move beyond cost and competitiveness when deciding where to deploy capital.</p>
<p>After the discussion, panelists will take questions from the audience. Online viewers can submit questions via e-mail to <a href="mailto:events@brookings.edu">events@brookings.edu</a> or via Twitter at <strong>#TaiwanEconomy</strong><strong>. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong>Brookings requires all staff and visitors to show proof that they are </strong><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/stay-up-to-date.html?s_cid=11747:fully%20vaccinated%20guidelines"><strong>fully vaccinated</strong></a><strong> against COVID-19 via vaccines approved by the FDA or WHO. After submitting your registration, please proceed to the provided link on the confirmation page to complete the registration process by verifying your vaccination information.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/2022-04-19T113906Z_1298643028_RC27QT9N5ZLZ_RTRMADP_3_HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS-TAIWAN.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Taiwan" label="Taiwan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/taiwan/" />
      <event:locationSummary>Washington, DC</event:locationSummary>
      <event:type>upcoming</event:type>
      <event:startTime>1652704200</event:startTime>
      <event:endTime>1652713200</event:endTime>
      <event:timezone>America/New_York</event:timezone>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on the future of the global order</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2022/05/04/perspectives-on-the-future-of-the-global-order/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin I. Bradford]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1603656</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[At this tense moment, it seems that the confrontational narratives driving the U.S.-China bilateral relationship now contain specifically conflicting perspectives on the future of the global order. China seems to highlight the degree to which the West is seen to have imposed its presumptively universal values on the global system in the post-war period, which&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Colin I. Bradford</p><p>At this tense moment, it seems that the confrontational narratives driving the U.S.-China bilateral relationship now contain specifically conflicting perspectives on the future of the global order.</p>

<p>China seems to highlight the degree to which the West is seen to have imposed its presumptively universal values on the global system in the post-war period, which has been favorable for the exercise of U.S. hegemony. At the same time, the United States interprets China’s commitment to forging a <em>multipolar order </em>based on different values and driven by different norms more favorable to non-Western countries as China becoming a leading global power in the process. These two perspectives on the future of the global order seem to drive greater divergence and create the atmospherics of a “new Cold War,” even though the U.S. and China each say they want to avoid it.</p>

<p>Today <em>the world as it is</em> is fragmented, torn by crosscurrents, contradictions, and multivalent forcefields, not singular visions. Internal political pressures generated by social divides drive domestic political dominance over addressing global existential imperatives. A close look reveals that <em>the world as it is</em> is one in which the values of the West will continue to have relevance in public discourses and civilizational dialogues. And, today’s world is also one in which voices and perspectives of other cultures will drive differentiation and excellence, not universalism and emulation.</p>
<p>Fierce independence, assertion of uniqueness, and willpower for autonomy characterize indigenous expression and spill over into the global public square creating greater diversity and cross-cutting tensions. These countervailing forcefields now ripple through global forums and international institutions, issues, and challenges, and define the new global order. The tensions between the West and the non-Western world are central, significant, and involve many countries.</p>
<p>The votes in the United Nations General Assembly on condemning the Russian invasion of Ukraine on March 2 and on suspending Russia from the U.N. Human Rights Council on April 7 reveal the scale of the thrust toward independent and countervailing position taking. Apart from the five states that voted against the March 2 resolution (Belarus, North Korea, Eritrea, Russia, and Syria), 19 other countries also voted <em>against</em> on April 7. Adding these 19 to the 58 countries that <em>abstained</em> on April 7 gives a total of 77 countries who demurred on the condemnation of Russia in these two votes, 40 percent of the total 193 members of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Of the 58 countries that abstained on April 7, at least 17 stand out as countries of consequence in their regions or in the world because of their population size, GDP, possession of nuclear weapons, or cultural impact. Those countries are India, Indonesia, Pakistan, and Bangladesh in Asia; Malaysia, Singapore, and Thailand in Southeast Asia; Brazil and Mexico in Latin America; Ghana, Kenya, Nigeria, South Africa, Tanzania, and Uganda in Africa; and Egypt and Jordan in the Middle East and North Africa. If China, Iran, Vietnam, and four of the Central Asian countries who voted against on April 7 are added, there are 24 countries with weight in the system who are capable of pushing back on divisive issues, six of whom are G-20 member countries. They make the emerging multivalent global order a reality. Forty percent of the world is following “another narrative,” as Christiane Amanpour put it in an interview with U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield on April 7.</p>
<p>The way to manage the global agenda in a multivalent world order is to <em>accept</em> complexities, contradictions, and contrariness as realities; <em>delink </em>issues from one another to prevent singular difference from overwhelming other functional relations; <em>decentralize </em>global negotiating forums from one another; <em>devise</em> diverse ways to work on issues that are distinctly different; <em>encourage</em> varying clusters of country officials to lead on different issues; <em>nurture</em> plurilateral leadership groups by rotating their composition from issue to issue; <em>embrace</em> variety; <em>avoid</em> blocs; <em>invite</em> innovation; <em>focus</em> on substance; and <em>dial back</em> on polemics.</p>
<p>This new era of complexity, contradiction, and multivalent forcefields invites new approaches which are characterized by greater openness to diversity, difference, and eclecticism and driven more by practical details, substantive understandings, knowledge-based policymaking, and a keen sense of global imperatives to address systemic challenges and existential threats. In a multivalent world, these approaches would be more effective and functional than using global forums to try to advance values, political preferences, and polemical differences.</p>
<p>German leadership of the G-7 this year needs to encourage the other six G-7 member countries to come into the Indonesian G-20 this year and the Indian G-20 next year with a different mindset more open to difference rather than pushing against it.</p>
<p>The country composition of the G-20 reveals that it consists of a set of 10 highly aligned Western countries composed of the G-7 plus Australia, South Korea, and the European Union and a set of six non-Western countries that make up the BRICSAM group composed of Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa, and Mexico. After fourteen years of G-20 summits during which time only two countries from the Global South served as chair—Mexico (2012) and Argentina (2018)—the G-20 over the next four years will be organized by the Global South. As it happens, after Indonesia and India host the G-20, Brazil will host in 2024, and South Africa in 2025. The visibility of the multivalent global order will be more manifest in the next four years than it has been in the last 14, as a result.</p>
<p>Religion is a significant driver in the evolution of culture. The G-20 has four countries with significant Muslim populations, whereas the G-7 has none. The four are Indonesia, India, Turkey, and Saudi Arabia. The 10 countries with the largest number of Muslims have a total number of adherents equal to 1.15 billion people, one-seventh of the world’s population. The G-20 has a G-20 Interfaith Forum, an engagement group which has been meeting for each annual G-20 Summit since its founding in 2014 in Australia. These next four years may be the moment to focus attention on religious faith as a healer of divides and a force for peace in the world.</p>
<p>Indonesia is in the hot seat this year. The central challenge for Indonesia is to mediate between the G-7-plus&#8211;3 group and other five BRICSAM countries (Brazil, India, China, South Africa, and Mexico), now that Russia is on the fringes of the G-20.</p>
<p>In this dramatic moment with the global order in flux, the key issue is whether the G-7 plus 3 can prioritize the G-20 as an important platform <em>both </em>for working through these crosscurrents <em>and </em>for addressing existential and systemic threats despite the turmoil and tension. For this to happen, G-7 plus 3 <em>and</em> the five BRICSAM countries need to commit to moving forward <em>together,</em> bridging the divides within the G-20 and, by extension, the tensions within the global community.</p>
<p>The G-7 plus 3 countries need to seize this moment as an opportunity to use the G-20 to work out functional working relationships with China. China, too, is crucial in creating new dynamics within the G-20 and could benefit from contributing to strengthening the G-20 as a means of strengthening global governance. All G-20 countries need to support the Global South as Indonesia, India, Brazil, and South Africa assume the G-20 presidency over the next four years. These shifts in behavior are extremely important. Otherwise, the G-20 could dissipate as a significant forum for global governance due to lack of effort, and the world could well divide into two global orders, between the West and non-Western countries.</p>
<p>Leaders and governments will need to use these behaviors and practices to project to the world an inclusive, eclectic, practical, respectful, and responsible strategic vision of convergence toward a new era in the global order that can tolerate not only diversity and difference but also complexity, contradiction, and even contrariness as central dynamics that must be managed to reestablish a single international community for all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/shutterstock_1377696476.jpg?w=320" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Post" label="Post" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/search/?post_type=post" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20220430 New York Times Madiha Afzal</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/media-mentions/20220430-new-york-times-madiha-afzal/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicki Sullivan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 13:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=media-mention&amp;p=1604044</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Nicki Sullivan</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <atom:category term="Pakistan" label="Pakistan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/pakistan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany has a special responsibility to stop Putin’s evil</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/04/26/germany-has-a-special-responsibility-to-stop-putins-evil/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Constanze Stelzenmüller]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 15:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1602470</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A merciless war is being waged in the middle of Europe — on Germany’s ruling Social Democratic Party (SPD). That, at least, is what a casual observer of German politics might conclude. Rolf Mützenich, the head of the SPD’s parliamentary faction, has denounced demands by his Green and Free Democratic coalition partners for heavy weapons&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Constanze Stelzenmüller</p><p>A merciless war is being waged in the middle of Europe — on Germany’s ruling Social Democratic Party (SPD). That, at least, is what a casual observer of German politics might conclude.</p>

<p>Rolf Mützenich, the head of the SPD’s parliamentary faction, <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/russland-ukraine-krieg-marie-agnes-strack-zimmermann-kritisiert-rolf-muetzenich-a-76eb4adb-9f54-4062-a844-0e17de11bff8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has denounced</a> demands by his Green and Free Democratic coalition partners for heavy weapons deliveries to Ukraine as “irresponsible.” His colleague Ralf Stegner toggles between angry tweets and accusatory <a href="https://www.facebook.com/login/?next=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F480641715335370%2Fposts%2F5119978991401596%2F" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook screeds</a> against critics of his party’s past policy towards Russia.</p>
<p>Sigmar Gabriel, a former foreign minister, has <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/sigmar-gabriel-wir-brauchen-zumindest-einen-kalten-frieden-gastbeitrag-a-411895f4-557e-42e7-9453-c62baa490d82" target="_blank" rel="noopener">inveighed</a> against “dangerous conspiracy theories” about German-Russian networks of influence. The maudlin self-pity is unedifying. Its stridency suggests that the criticism is hitting home.</p>
<p>Chancellor Olaf Scholz himself is becoming thin-skinned. He has <a href="https://www.rnd.de/politik/olaf-scholz-an-jungs-und-maedels-kanzler-interview-sorgt-fuer-unmut-VBSMMZEUMJEMZGBDNYCCNTNN24.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dismissed</a> three Bundestag members who had visited Ukraine and called for more military support, as “boys and girls.” In a recent interview, he suggested sending heavy weapons would make Germany and NATO <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/international/germany/interview-with-german-chancellor-olaf-scholz-there-cannot-be-a-nuclear-war-a-d9705006-23c9-4ecc-9268-ded40edf90f9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“parties to the war.”</a></p>
<p>The cold truth is that there is much to criticize. It is way past time for the SPD to expel its top Russian gas lobbyist, former Chancellor Gerhard Schröder. It is also essential that German courts should investigate the links between <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6560170c-95f5-478e-860f-eec683c049af" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Manuela Schwesig</a>, premier of the eastern state of Mecklenburg West-Pomerania, and the pipeline operator Nord Stream 2, fully owned by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/exclusive-nord-stream-2-owner-considers-insolvency-after-pipeline-halt-sanctions-2022-03-01/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gazprom</a>.</p>
<p>But Germany’s self-serving Russia policy and its self-inflicted energy dependence — part willfully naïve, part deeply corrupt — found eager supporters across the political party spectrum. They emboldened the Kremlin, and they enabled Vladimir Putin’s war.</p>

<p>It is, however, missing the point <a href="https://www.rnd.de/politik/deutsche-russland-politik-wadephul-fordert-auseinandersetzung-A5DAZNZ5Q5BBFLH46W7ZBZKMF4.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to call for</a> Frank-Walter Steinmeier, the president and another former foreign minister, or former chancellor Angela Merkel to be hauled in front of a parliamentary commission of inquiry. When they held power, they and other German politicians shrewdly assessed that they were doing exactly what the business sector and the general public wanted.</p>
<p>At least Steinmeier has publicly <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/german-president-steinmeier-admits-mistakes-over-russia-policy/a-61362153" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declared</a> that he was wrong. But as for Russia’s war of annihilation and its relentless atrocities against Ukrainians, they are on all of us.</p>
<p>To Scholz’s credit, he and his government took power with an ambitious domestic transformation agenda. Four days after Russia’s invasion, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ffc46030-51c6-4d87-b81b-457a31fbcdc9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the chancellor acknowledged</a> the need for a <em>Zeitenwende</em>, or turning point, in German energy and security policy as well, and he promised to support Ukraine. It is hard to imagine Merkel, his Christian Democratic predecessor, doing either. Unfortunately, none of Germany’s short-term options for helping Kyiv and preventing a Kremlin victory is good.</p>
<p>Because <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c95634ad-e01a-4af5-b7e8-4616618b7431" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Germany’s hydrocarbon imports</a> fuel the Russian war machine, Berlin wants to stop importing coal by the summer, and oil by the end of the year. But it <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/e82b11a1-cf1f-4543-9f9f-6ab70da6b746" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fears</a> that cutting off gas imports now — instead of in 2024, as initially planned — could create a massive recession and political turmoil. On that point <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7e1307f8-6ec6-4a12-a7f1-a97c23a6167e" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Janet Yellen</a>, the U.S. treasury secretary, seems to agree.</p>
<p>Ukraine is begging for heavy weapons, as Russia steps up <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4351d5b0-0888-4b47-9368-6bc4dfbccbf5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its offensive in Donbas</a>. But on this question Scholz has dithered, prevaricated and thrown up smoke, to mounting anger among Germany’s allies and his coalition partners. The shortfall of usable German military kit is real, and so is pressure from the SPD’s intransigently pacifist left wing. In a belated compromise, Berlin is acting <a href="https://www.thedefensepost.com/2022/04/21/germany-east-european-weapons-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to backfill weaponry</a> provided to Kyiv by other NATO allies.</p>
<p>Scholz is not helped by a speaking style that runs the gamut from stoical to gnomic. Some of his ministers are weaker than others. But his real problem lies elsewhere. As a parliamentary democracy, Germany has a federal executive that is weak by design. The chancellery staff is tiny compared with those of other major democracies. Scholz’s most senior advisers are spreading themselves thin. It shows.</p>
<p>For Scholz’s volatile “traffic light” coalition to survive and wield power effectively, it must change the way it governs. The foreign ministry is working on <a href="https://www.tagesschau.de/inland/innenpolitik/nationale-sicherheitsstrategie-101.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a national security strategy</a>, Germany’s first such document. In principle this will help articulate strategic goals more coherently.</p>
<p>But even more urgently, the chancellery needs a proper national security staff that can advise and assist the head of government to weather an age of continual disruptions. It matters all the more because Germany has a special responsibility to put a stop to the evil unleashed by Putin.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-25T151204Z_186991290_RC2EUT9JHD8U_RTRMADP_3_GERMANY-POLITICS.jpg?w=283" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" label="Russia's Invasion of Ukraine" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/russias-invasion-of-ukraine/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much popular support does Tunisia’s president really have?</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/opinions/how-much-popular-support-does-tunisias-president-really-have/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sharan Grewal, Mohamed Dhia Hammami]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=opinion&amp;p=1603621</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Sharan Grewal, Mohamed Dhia Hammami</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-10T020603Z_1212598309_RC22KT9XVLPV_RTRMADP_3_TUNISIA-POLITICS-PIX.jpg?w=292" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Tunisia" label="Tunisia" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/tunisia/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-Japan relations in an era of economic statecraft</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/events/us-japan-relations-in-an-era-of-economic-statecraft/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=event&amp;p=1598564</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[National security and economic globalization are increasingly intertwined. Amid rapid technological change and increased tension in the international system, the United States and Japan are each honing their own economic policies with a new emphasis on industrial policy to nurture advanced manufacturing and science and innovation, strengthening supply chains, and reducing dependence on China. In&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>National security and economic globalization are increasingly intertwined. Amid rapid technological change and increased tension in the international system, the United States and Japan are each honing their own economic policies with a new emphasis on industrial policy to nurture advanced manufacturing and science and innovation, strengthening supply chains, and reducing dependence on China. In addition to the renewed focus on economic security, Japan and the U.S. are also promoting economic connectivity through shared activities in the Quad and the proposed Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, while Japan continues to play a leadership role in the Comprehensive and Progressive Trans-Pacific Partnership. More recently, the two allies have engaged in an unprecedented coordination of economic sanctions against Russia for its invasion of Ukraine. How do Japanese and American visions of economic statecraft overlap, and what are the future opportunities for the allies to work together in this space?</p>
<p>On May 4, the Center for East Asia Policy Studies at the Brookings Institution hosted a panel of policy practitioners from Japan and Washington, D.C.-based experts to discuss how the United States and Japan can coordinate their industrial policies effectively and promote science and tech collaboration. Panelists discussed the challenges of reconciling economic security with economic connectivity, and the contours of a redefined relationship with China at a time when deglobalization trends are strengthening.</p>
<p>After the discussion, panelists took questions from the audience. Online viewers submitted questions via e-mail to <a href="mailto:events@brookings.edu">events@brookings.edu</a> or via Twitter at <strong>#USJapan</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong>Brookings requires all staff and visitors to show proof that they are </strong><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/stay-up-to-date.html?s_cid=11747:fully%20vaccinated%20guidelines"><strong>fully vaccinated</strong></a><strong> against COVID-19 via vaccines approved by the FDA or WHO. After submitting your registration, please proceed to the provided link on the confirmation page to complete the registration process by verifying your vaccination information.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2015-04-28T000000Z_1510607227_TB3EB4S14251T_RTRMADP_3_USA-JAPAN.jpg?w=265" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Japan" label="Japan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/japan/" />
      <event:locationSummary>Washington, DC</event:locationSummary>
      <event:type>past</event:type>
      <event:startTime>1651674600</event:startTime>
      <event:endTime>1651679100</event:endTime>
      <event:timezone>America/New_York</event:timezone>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Biden, don’t pass up the opportunity for a reset with Shahbaz Sharif’s Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/04/22/president-biden-dont-pass-up-the-opportunity-for-a-reset-with-shahbaz-sharifs-pakistan/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Bruce Riedel, Madiha Afzal]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 19:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?p=1598644</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The end of American involvement in Afghanistan and the change in leadership in Pakistan presents the United States with an opportunity to reset its long-troubled relationship with the world’s fifth most populous country. President Joe Biden should initiate a high-level dialogue with new Prime Minister Shahbaz Sharif, who will be in power for up to&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Bruce Riedel, Madiha Afzal</p><p>The end of American involvement in Afghanistan and the change in leadership in Pakistan presents the United States with an opportunity to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/25/opinion/pakistan-biden-khan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reset its long-troubled relationship</a> with the world’s fifth most populous country. President Joe Biden should initiate a high-level dialogue with new Prime Minister Shahbaz Sharif, who will be in power for up to a year before the next election is held.</p>

<p>For most of the last 40 years, American policy toward Pakistan <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/deadly-embrace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revolved around our interests in the wars in Afghanistan</a>. In the 1980s, we partnered with the military dictator Zia ul-Haq to <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/what-we-won/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arm the Afghan mujahideen against the Soviets</a>. Then we sought Pakistani cooperation to fight al-Qaida and the Taliban, often with mixed results. Karachi port was crucial in both wars to get supplies to our Afghan allies and NATO forces in Afghanistan. Pursuing these wars was Washington’s top priority, edging out all other issues.</p>
<p>Because our policy was focused on fighting wars in Afghanistan, our primary partners in Pakistan were the intelligence service and the military. Less attention was devoted to the civilian government. Unintentionally this helped destabilize the always fraught civil-military balance in Pakistan, bolstering Pakistan’s military at the expense of its civilian governments.</p>
<p>The withdrawal of American and NATO forces from Afghanistan last August, a badly flawed operation, has essentially freed up American policy toward this important nuclear-armed Muslim country of <a href="https://www.census.gov/popclock/world" target="_blank" rel="noopener">243 million people</a>. Now Washington can engage with Islamabad without prioritizing Afghanistan issues at the expense of our broader interests in regional stability with India and China, encouraging development in South Asia, and supporting the strengthening of the elected democratic forces in Pakistan. America also has an interest in balancing somewhat the influence of China, Pakistan’s closest ally, on decisionmaking in Islamabad.</p>
<p>The Biden administration, and in particular the White House, has given Pakistan a relative cold shoulder to date — <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/10/13/post-afghanistan-us-pakistan-relations-stand-on-the-edge-of-a-precipice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">irked</a> by the war in Afghanistan <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/08/24/pakistans-problematic-victory-in-afghanistan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ending with a Taliban takeover</a> and ostensibly with then-Prime Minister Imran Khan <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/u-s-really-messed-it-up-in-afghanistan-says-pakistan-prime-minister-imran-khan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">publicly criticizing the U.S.</a> as it happened; more broadly, Pakistan has <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/04/12/under-biden-pakistan-and-the-us-face-a-dilemma-about-the-breadth-of-their-relationship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">simply not been high on the priority list</a> of an administration aiming to counter China via its relationships in the Indo-Pacific and now focused on Russia’s war on Ukraine.</p>
<p>Biden did not call Khan while he was prime minister. Last fall, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/events/the-future-of-us-pakistan-relations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we argued</a> he should. Khan in turn <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/12/13/pakistan-skipped-the-us-summit-for-democracy-why/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declined to attend</a> Biden’s Summit for Democracy. The White House should call Shahbaz Sharif. Sharif is a three-time former chief minister of Punjab, Pakistan’s largest and most prosperous province, and brother of three-time former Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif. The Sharifs have been marred by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/11/pakistan-prime-mininster-shehbaz-sharif/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">corruption allegations</a>, key to Imran Khan’s arguments against them, but they are also pragmatic men eager to develop Pakistan’s infrastructure and economy. (One of us, Bruce, has known them for over 30 years.) They have generally refrained from foreign adventures and <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/book/avoiding-armageddon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conflict with India</a>. Their (belated) opposition to the reckless military operation in Kargil in 1999 is what led to the overthrow of Nawaz’s administration later in 1999.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Imran Khan is an ideologue. He relied on anti-American rhetoric both in his rise to power as well as in his recent fall, <a href="https://www.thechicagocouncil.org/commentary-and-analysis/podcasts/after-khan-pakistans-political-instability-meets-great-power" target="_blank" rel="noopener">denouncing alleged American interference</a> in Pakistani politics this spring first to try to stay in power and now to try to get back in charge. He has been an outspoken critic of American operations against al-Qaida and the Taliban.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, American warnings that supporting the Afghan Taliban would lead to a stronger threat from the Pakistani Taliban to Pakistan have proven to be all too accurate. Pakistan’s <a href="https://responsiblestatecraft.org/2022/04/18/deadly-pakistan-strikes-in-afghanistan-reflect-growing-cross-border-tensions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clashes with both have intensified</a> in recent days. The Afghan Taliban has ignored Pakistan’s entreaties to control their Pakistani Taliban allies.</p>
<p>The Afghan people could be a beneficiary of improved relations between America and Pakistan. Washington has shown no real leverage on the new regime in Kabul. Afghan girls are <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/03/23/1088202759/taliban-afghanistan-girls-school" target="_blank" rel="noopener">barred from attending secondary school</a> and <a href="https://www.economist.com/asia/2022/04/02/the-taliban-are-pushing-females-out-of-public-life" target="_blank" rel="noopener">increasingly constrained</a> in the workplace. Islamabad has more influence in Kabul than any outside player, albeit within limits. For example, it controls the importation of oil to its neighbor. Pakistan has been at the forefront of <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2021/10/13/post-afghanistan-us-pakistan-relations-stand-on-the-edge-of-a-precipice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">calling for engagement</a> with the Taliban regime. Working with Islamabad may help ease the misery of the Afghan people over time. It’s worth exploring.</p>
<p>The Sharif government has a moderate military leadership to work with in the months ahead. Chief of Army Staff General Qamar Javed Bajwa has <a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/pakistan-army-chief-blasts-russia-aggression-against-ukraine/6512372.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">openly criticized</a> Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, a marked shift from Khan’s posture of “neutrality” on the war. Khan was coincidentally <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/03/09/imran-khan-pakistan-picks-terrible-time-make-friends-with-vladimir-putin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in Moscow</a> when the invasion began. Given that his relationship with the Biden administration was non-existent, Khan’s relationship with Russian President Vladimir Putin — who <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamNoahWho/status/1496147475597602828?s=20&amp;t=bJhpDQeyhEYwXvTIy9027Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">called him three times</a> since August — and Chinese President Xi Jinping looked like a leaning away from America toward Russia and China. With his reliance on a U.S. conspiracy narrative as his government was about to fall, he solidified that position. On the other hand, Bajwa has <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1683055" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spoken publicly</a> about improving <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/defence/pakistan-army-chief-general-qamar-javed-bajwas-remarks-on-us-may-affect-pak-russia-ties/articleshow/90650134.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">relations with America</a>, as has <a href="https://twitter.com/MadihaAfzal/status/1514229194066120707?s=20&amp;t=HAdmFUQSZrfWdZMm0NZGMw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shahbaz Sharif</a>. They will have to walk a delicate balance in engaging with the United States given Khan’s U.S. conspiracy narrative, which the army and Sharif have rebuffed but which Khan’s supporters buy wholesale.</p>
<p>The opportunity for the Biden administration for this engagement is not open ended. Shahbaz Sharif inherits a weak economy which is now his primary problem, and his runway is limited. Imran Khan, meanwhile, is determined to get back in power. His support is substantial; he has led <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/15/world/asia/imran-khan-rally-pakistan.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">huge rallies</a> in Pakistan’s major cities, relying on demagoguery and anti-American rhetoric. He is trying to undermine the new government’s legitimacy by calling it an “imported government” and railing about the corruption cases against its members. His party has <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1684501" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resigned</a> from parliament. In the end, the prize for both the Sharifs and Khan is the next election. Pakistan’s politics is increasingly uncertain; it’s an urgent time to open a dialogue.</p>
<p>A major priority for sustained presidential engagement with Pakistan should be to strengthen the democratic process in the second-largest Muslim country in the world. No elected prime minister has served out five years in office; too often the military has intervened to bring down the elected government. By underscoring American support for civilian rule by engaging primarily with Sharif and his foreign minister, Hina Rabbani Khar, Biden’s team would belatedly make Pakistan a part of the president’s policy of strengthening democracy against autocracy. This should usher in a new era of stability in the U.S.-Pakistan relationship, that has seen too many highs and lows — essentially because the relationship has been predicated on America’s goals in Afghanistan. That would mean engaging with civilian governments regardless of which leader is in power — which will benefit Pakistan itself and the U.S.-Pakistan relationship in the long-run.</p>
<p>In terms of what should be on the immediate agenda, first would be the notion that the relationship with Pakistan can no longer be focused solely on security, though that would be one necessary dimension, with the Taliban in power in Afghanistan, a rise in attacks by the Islamic State Khorasan group and the Pakistani Taliban, and given Islamabad’s nuclear arsenal and difficult relationship with New Delhi. Another aspect of the agenda could be to explore avenues for strengthening the economic relationship in a way that uses Pakistan’s untapped economic potential (ultimately to both Pakistan and America’s benefit), for instance with Pakistan’s small but growing tech sector. An important effect is that this gives Pakistan something other than the <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/at-all-costs-how-pakistan-and-china-control-the-narrative-on-the-china-pakistan-economic-corridor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">China-Pakistan Economic Corridor</a> to look to in terms of investment; a stronger economy also loosens the military’s hold on the country. It’s a big opportunity to fundamentally alter U.S.-Pakistan relations.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Sharif_001.jpg?w=270" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Pakistan" label="Pakistan" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/pakistan/" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trans-Atlantic Scorecard — April 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.brookings.edu/research/trans-atlantic-scorecard-april-2022/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 06:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.brookings.edu/?post_type=research&amp;p=1597887</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Welcome to the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s Center on the United States and Europe (CUSE). To produce the Scorecard, we poll Brookings scholars and other experts on the present state of U.S. relations with Europe — overall and in the political, security, and economic&hellip;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/center/center-on-the-united-states-and-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center on the United States and Europe (CUSE)</a>. To produce the Scorecard, we poll Brookings scholars and other experts on the present state of U.S. relations with Europe — overall and in the political, security, and economic dimensions — as well as on the state of U.S. relations with five key countries and the European Union itself. We also ask about several major issues in the news. The poll for this edition of the survey was conducted from April 5 to April 8, 2022. The experts’ analyses are complemented by CUSE Director <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/experts/thomas-wright/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas Wright</a>’s take on what to watch in the coming months.</p>
<div class="size-article-fullbleed" title="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/FP_20220421_bbti_survey_responses.csv">

<div id="bbti-snapshot" class="bbti__tab">
<h2>What to Watch</h2>
<h3 class="accordion__title active">A message from CUSE Director Thomas Wright</h3>
<div class="accordion__content">
<p><em>Center on the United States and Europe Director <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/experts/thomas-wright/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas Wright</a> lays out events, issues, and potential developments to watch for in the months ahead.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am delighted to share with you the fifteenth edition of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard, a quarterly evaluation of U.S.-European relations produced by Brookings’s <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/center/center-on-the-united-states-and-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center on the United States and Europe</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The first quarter of 2022 in trans-Atlantic relations has been dominated by the Russian troop buildup on the border with Ukraine and launch of the invasion on February 24. This iteration of the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard offers a snapshot of the impact of the war on U.S.-Europe relations to date, as well as other developments from the quarter.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By the end of the quarter, five weeks into Russia’s war in Ukraine, U.S.-European relations had significantly improved since the end of the fourth quarter of 2021, from an average of 6.5 on a 1-10 scale to 8.1 at the end of the first quarter of 2022. Political and security relations are also up roughly 1.5 points each at 8, while economic relations increased more modestly to an average of 7. 85% of our survey pool saw U.S.-Europe relations trending positively overall, and respondents unanimously agreed that U.S.-European security relations had improved. Bilateral relations between the US and Germany, the US and France, the US and the U.K., the US and Turkey, and the US and EU all increased by over 1 point since the end of 2021, while US-Russia relations suffered a 0.6-point decrease, from the already quite low 1.9 to 1.3.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the questions specific to events and developments of this quarter, respondents unanimously disagreed that there would be a full Russia-Ukraine ceasefire before April 30, 2022. 85% believe that the war in Ukraine will expedite Europe’s green energy transition, while 80% agreed that China’s position on Russia would damage EU-China relations (10% were neutral and 10% disagreed). 89% thought that U.K.-EU relations had improved since the Russian invasion of Ukraine. On the question of whether Macron would face widespread discontent, weakening his capacity for reforms, even if reelected, respondents were divided. 60% agreed, while 10% disagreed and 30% were neutral.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the second quarter of 2022, our attention remains fixed on Russia and Ukraine. We will continue to closely follow trans-Atlantic security relations in the coming months, including how Germany’s historic shift in defense policy influences European security debates and possible Finnish and Swedish accession to NATO. With the French two days away from going to the polls to choose between the incumbent Emmanuel Macron and the far-right populist Marine Le Pen at the time of writing, we will also be watching the outcome of the election and impact on Europe and the world. Finally, as we look ahead to late spring and early summer, we will be watching the G-7 and NATO summits in June.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thank you again for reading the Trans-Atlantic Scorecard.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-08T000000Z_584036144_MT1ABCPR805556006_RTRMADP_3_ABACA-PRESS.jpg?w=258" type="image/jpeg" />
      <atom:category term="Europe" label="Europe" scheme="https://www.brookings.edu/topic/europe/" />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>