<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>TIME</title>
    <atom:link href="https://time.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://time.com</link>
    <description>Current &amp; Breaking News | National &amp; World Updates</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:27:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">162509141</site>
    <item>
      <title>After Supreme Court Leak, Republican-led States Ready Legislation to Ban or Criminalize Abortion</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174148/republican-states-abortion-bans-roe-v-wade/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Abigail Abrams]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174148</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Less than 48 hours after a leaked draft decision showing the Supreme Court set to overturn Roe v. Wade, Republicans in the Louisiana House of Representatives advanced a bill classifying abortion as homicide from &#8220;the moment of fertilization&#8221; and allowing prosecutors to charge both patients and providers with murder. &#8220;We cannot wait on the Supreme&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174148"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174148/republican-states-abortion-bans-roe-v-wade/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than 48 hours after a leaked draft decision showing the Supreme Court set to overturn </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Republicans in the Louisiana House of Representatives advanced a bill classifying abortion as homicide from &ldquo;the moment of fertilization&rdquo; and allowing prosecutors to charge both patients and providers with murder.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;We cannot wait on the Supreme Court,&rdquo; State Rep. Danny McCormick, the bill&rsquo;s sponsor, said during a committee hearing on Wednesday. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Louisiana already has a trigger law in place that would let the state immediately ban abortion if the final Supreme Court decision does in fact overturn <em>Roe v. Wade. </em>But Brian Gunter, a pastor who worked with McCormick on the bill, characterized the complete ban as &ldquo;woefully insufficient.&#8221; Financial penalties for violating the law were not enough, he explained. &ldquo;No compromises, no more waiting,&rdquo; he said at the hearing. The bill passed out of the committee with a 7-2 vote. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>While the Louisiana bill is more extreme than most other states&#8217; proposed legislation, it exemplifies a larger trend sweeping Republican-led state legislatures nationwide. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Emboldened by the leaked Supreme Court draft opinion, many states are scrambling to shore up their anti-abortion legislation or preparing to revive old laws that impose significant penalties. Consequences include lengthy prison sentences for providers, suspending physicians&#8217; medical licenses, and sizable fines on people who perform abortions. Even as national Republicans emphasize that fears of prosecutions are overblown, state lawmakers are readying laws that will not just ban abortion, but criminalize it. </span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/danny-mccormick-lousiana.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Chris Graythen&mdash;Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >Louisiana State Representative Danny McCormick speaks to protesters in Baton Rouge as they gather outside the state capitol to rally against Louisiana&#8217;s stay-at-home order and economic shutdown, April 25, 2020.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;If the draft opinion that we saw earlier this week is anything close to the actual opinion, it&rsquo;s going to give state legislatures carte blanche to restrict, ban abortion in all sorts of different ways,&rdquo; says David S. Cohen, a law professor at Drexel University&rsquo;s Kline School of Law. &ldquo;It says &lsquo;Get prepared with the most extreme bills possible. And when we give you the go ahead, hit the ground running.&rsquo;&rdquo;</span></p>
<p>Conservative state lawmakers&#8217; eagerness to act aggressively stands in contrast to most Republican in the U.S. Congress, who<span style="font-weight: 400;"> largely avoided talking about the substance of the Supreme Court draft this week, in favor of focusing on the leak. Some Republican governors also pumped the brakes, saying they wanted to see how the Supreme Court ultimately rules before calling special legislative sessions. </span></p>
<p>But it&#8217;s clear that as soon as the Supreme Court hands down its final decision in <a href="https://time.com/6116072/mississippi-abortion-supreme-court-jackson-womens-health/" ><em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women&#8217;s Health Organization</em></a>, the case over a Mississippi abortion law challenging <em>Roe</em>, that anti-abortion state legislators will be ready. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Conservative-led states had already passed more than <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/article/2022/03/2022-state-legislative-sessions-abortion-bans-and-restrictions-medication-abortion"  target="_blank">500 abortion restrictions</a> from Jan. 1</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> through April 15 of this year. If the Supreme Court does overturn <i style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Roe, </i></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">about </span><a href="https://time.com/6173196/abortion-trigger-laws-bans-roe-v-wade/" style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;" >half of the states in the U.S. </a><span style="font-weight: 400;">will likely quickly ban abortion. That</span><i style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"> </i><span style="font-weight: 400;">includes 13 states that have trigger laws, which would make abortion illegal soon after the decision comes down. But some of these laws require different actions to make them take effect, and abortion opponents are using this time before the final decision to get their strategies and paperwork in place.</span></p>
<h2>Anti-abortion state lawmakers seize the moment</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Louisiana lawmakers and advocates who spoke in favor of the bill making abortion a homicide this week appeared emotional at the prospect of successfully implementing their goal. Critics said the bill was unconstitutional and warned about its unintended consequences. The way the bill is written, experts believe in vitro fertilization and emergency contraception pills could also trigger criminal charges. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Louisiana bill differs from other states&#8217; proposed legislation because it appears to allow the prosecution of the pregnant person as well, not just abortion providers. That&#8217;s something abortion opponents have avoided in recent years, but last month a Texas woman, Lizelle Herrera, was arrested over an alleged self-induced abortion, and if <em>Roe </em>is overturned, experts predict more states will explore additional types of penalties. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Arkansas, the state&rsquo;s trigger ban will make abortion a felony except to save the life of the mother. To take effect, the state&rsquo;s attorney general must certify that the Supreme Court has in fact overturned </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6160143/anti-abortion-roe-wade-supreme-court/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Battle Over the Future of the Anti-Abortion Movement if the Supreme Court Overturns Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arkansas State Sen. Jason Rapert, who introduced the trigger law, took to Facebook Live after the leaked draft this week to outline the plan. &ldquo;As soon as that decision is released, we&rsquo;ll end all abortion in Arkansas except to save the life of the mother,&rdquo; he told his listeners. &ldquo;What&rsquo;s required as soon as that decision is, within minutes, the attorney general of the state of Arkansas should certify that the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> decision is legitimate and that immediately we see that we&rsquo;ll end abortion.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rapert told TIME he was initially concerned about whether the state&#8217;s leadership would act because Arkansas earlier this year rejected a Texas-style bill that would allow private citizens to file lawsuits to enforce an abortion ban. So he wrote to the attorney general&#8217;s office this week to remind them of the responsibility added on the Facebook video that he would personally make sure his state followed through. &ldquo;If we have anybody within the state of Arkansas, just like they had at the U.S. Supreme Court, that would try to interfere, that would try to disrupt the enforcement of Act 180, I will call for the legislature to convene and to impeach any such official immediately,&rdquo; he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Arkansas Attorney General Leslie Rutledge, a fellow Republican, indicated she is ready to certify the trigger law too. &ldquo;It will be my honor and a privilege of my lifetime to do just that,&rdquo; she told reporters this week. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Missouri, which also has a trigger ban in place, the state&rsquo;s attorney general said he would also be prepared &ldquo;immediately&rdquo; to issue the opinion to put the state&rsquo;s law into effect. North Dakota Governor Kristi Noem <a href="https://twitter.com/govkristinoem/status/1521303498545061889"  target="_blank">said</a> she would call for a special legislative session, and lawmakers in Nebraska and Indiana have called on their governors to do so too. Oklahoma has a trigger ban and its state also moved ahead with additional legislation this week. Oklahoma Gov. Kevin Stitt signed a <a href="https://time.com/6093905/texas-abortion-ban-abortion-rights/" >Texas-style abortion ban</a> on Tuesday that prohibits abortions after about six weeks of pregnancy and allows private citizens to sue abortion providers. &ldquo;I want Oklahoma to be the most pro-life state in the country,&rdquo; Stitt tweeted upon signing the legislation. The ban took effect immediately, and the Oklahoma Supreme Court denied an emergency request to stop the bill.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6173091/democrats-roe-v-wade-codify-abortion-unlikely/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Democrats Vow to Protect Reproductive Rights But Can&#8217;t Actually Do Much</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Ohio, where the state legislature remains in session, state legislators are still considering two trigger ban bills that they could move before the Supreme Court rules. In the meantime, Republican Gov. Mike DeWine said on Tuesday he would have the state&rsquo;s attorney general seek to revive a 2019 state law that bans abortions after fetal cardiac activity is detected, which happens as early as six weeks into pregnancy, before many people know they are pregnant. The law has been blocked by courts since soon after DeWine signed it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;I&#8217;m asking him to immediately go into court and ask the federal court to lift the stay that is on the bill that I have already signed,&#8221; DeWine </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EFi4JETCIMM"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">said Tuesday</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> after he won his primary race. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Idaho, which has a trigger law set to take effect 30 days after the Supreme Court issues its ruling, is also still pursuing a <a href="https://time.com/6157455/idaho-abortion-ban-texas-impact/" >new law the state recently passed</a> that allows Texas-style civil lawsuits against abortion providers. The state Supreme Court had blocked the law while a legal challenge against it proceeds, but last week the Idaho attorney </span><a href="https://idahocapitalsun.com/2022/05/03/state-asks-idaho-supreme-court-to-rescind-order-delaying-abortion-laws-implementation/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">asked the court to lift the stay</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and let the law take effect.</span></p>
<h2>Resurrecting pre-<em>Roe </em>abortion bans</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some states already have abortion bans on the books that were passed before the 1973 </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> decision established the constitutional right to abortion. In those cases, some states may be able to simply begin enforcing those laws again immediately. If a judge has ruled them unconstitutional, officials would need to ask a court to allow them to go into effect.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That&rsquo;s the case in West Virginia, where the state&rsquo;s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> trigger law dates back to the mid-1800s and makes abortion a felony punishable with three to 10 years in prison. That old law was never formally repealed; a 1975 court ruling merely blocked the law on the grounds that it was unconstitutional under the precedent established by <em>Roe v. Wade</em>. So if the Supreme Court overturns <em>Roe</em>, state officials would just have to request that the state supreme court lift the injunction.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://time.com/6165848/abortion-pills-republican-states-roe-wade/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Republican States Crack Down on Access to Abortion Pills as Supreme Court Decision Looms</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That could happen extremely quickly, says Anne Lofaso, a law professor at West Virginia University&rsquo;s Supreme Court Clinic. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">&ldquo;The attorney general would immediately go to court and ask them to lift the injunction junction,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;They could do it in days. It could be a day.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abortion rights supporters could challenge that move in court, Lofaso adds. But even in that case, West Virginia&rsquo;s Republican-led legislature could pass new legislation fairly quickly. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other states have passed abortion restrictions more recently that have been blocked by courts but which they will try to bring back in the absence of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Georgia does not have a trigger law, but in 2019 it <a href="https://time.com/5753300/heartbeat-bill-civil-rights-law/" >passed a law that would ban nearly all abortions</a> after about six weeks. That law was challenged and is on hold at the 11th Circuit Court of Appeals pending the Supreme Court decision. State Rep. Ed Setzler, who sponsored the law, told TIME he is confident the law is &ldquo;exactly where it needs to be&rdquo; to go into effect. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;As soon as Dobbs comes out, I think one can expect that the 11th will issue their opinion on the Life Act in Georgia, based on the Dobbs holding,&rdquo; he says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The law also provides &ldquo;full legal recognition&rdquo; to fetuses after cardiac activity by allowing parents to claim the fetus as a dependent on their state taxes and saying fetuses will be included in &ldquo;population based determinations&rdquo; for the state. Setzler would ideally like to prohibit abortions beginning at conception, but sees putting his law into effect as a good next step.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;As people become more aware and come face to face with the value of life in utero, perhaps we can get where we need to be, which is that we protect all life in the womb,&rdquo; he says. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where many abortion opponents would like to go, and where experts say states are likely to eventually head if there is no federal protection for the right to abortion.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174148</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The True Story Behind Operation Mincemeat</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174289/operation-mincemeat-netflix-true-story/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eloise Barry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174289</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The historical drama—which drops on Netflix May 11—chronicles a World War II plot by the British intelligence services to dupe the Nazis.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174289"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174289/operation-mincemeat-netflix-true-story/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operation Mincemeat</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&mdash;a historical drama chronicling an audacious World War II plot by the British intelligence services to dupe the Nazis&mdash;drops on </span><a href="https://time.com/6172680/netflix-streaming-future/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netflix</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> May 11. Starring Colin Firth and</span> <a href="https://time.com/6127997/succession-season-3-finale-what-happens-next/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Succession</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo;s Matthew Macfadyen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the movie dramatizes a mission that played a crucial role in turning the tide in the Allied forces&rsquo; favor in the war&rsquo;s later years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What may come as a surprise to many viewers is that despite its far-fetched plot&mdash;which features a corpse with a fake identity, a briefcase stuffed with false documents, and </span><a href="https://time.com/6103054/no-time-to-die-ending-james-bond-future/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">James Bond</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> creator</span> <a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ian Fleming</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&mdash;the movie is largely faithful to the real historical events. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here&rsquo;s the true story behind </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operation Mincemeat</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<h2><b>What was Operation Mincemeat?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 1943, Allied forces comprising Britain, France, Canada, the U.S., and Australia planned to launch an offensive on the Italian island, Sicily, to topple Benito Mussolini&rsquo;s fascist regime, which supported the Nazis in the war.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To ensure the success of the invasion, </span><a href="https://www.iwm.org.uk/history/the-war-on-paper-operation-mincemeat#:~:text=Operation%20Mincemeat%20was%20a%20deception,the%20Allied%20invasion%20of%20Sicily."  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">two British intelligence officers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> came up with an elaborate plan to deceive the Nazis and draw their allied armies away from the Italian coast. Charles Cholmondeley (Matthew Macfadyen) and Captain Ewen Montagu (Colin Firth) decided to plant a dead body disguised as a member of the British royal marines off the coast of Spain. At the time, Spain was ruled by the dictator Francisco Franco, and although it was officially neutral in the war, the country shared intelligence with the Nazis. The corpse had a </span><a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">briefcase</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> stuffed with what appeared to be top secret documents suggesting that the Allies next target would be Greece&mdash;which had been occupied by the Italians and Nazis since 1941&mdash;and a different Italian island, Sardinia.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the dead marine, called Major William Martin, and the documents he held were entirely fabricated. The corpse was in fact Glyndwr Michael, a 34-year-old man who had become homeless after moving to London from Wales and</span> <a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">died after ingesting rat poison</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With the help of a London coroner, Cholmondeley and Montagu chose Michael as he had no known relatives looking for him&mdash;his </span><a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">identity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> wasn&rsquo;t revealed publicly until the 1990s.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The briefcase also contained a photograph of Major Martin&rsquo;s supposed fianc&eacute;e, a receipt for an engagement ring, and a theater ticket stub&mdash;all</span> <a href="https://www.iwm.org.uk/history/the-war-on-paper-operation-mincemeat#:~:text=Operation%20Mincemeat%20was%20a%20deception,the%20Allied%20invasion%20of%20Sicily."  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">planted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to suggest authenticity. When the Spanish found the supposedly drowned marine, the British authorities </span><a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">scrambled</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to retrieve the briefcase he was found with to convince the Nazis of the enclosed documents&rsquo; validity.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="operation-mincemeat" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg 6000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/OM_GK_13032020_05202.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Giles Keyte/Courtesy See-Saw Films and Netflix, and Haversack Films Limited</span><span class="caption" >Matthew Macfadyen and Colin Firth in &#8216;Operation Mincemeat&#8217;</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2><b>Did Operation Mincemeat work?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Nazis recovered the briefcase from the Spanish, and a copy of the fake documents </span><a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">went straight to Adolf Hitler himself. Fearful of the Allies&rsquo; supposed plan to take back Greece, he redirected Nazi troops to defend the territory. As a result of the false information, the Nazis were caught off guard when, in July 1943,</span> <a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">160,000 Allied troops</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> invaded Sicily and took control of the island in just over a month. The British leader </span><a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">received a telegram informing him of the operation&rsquo;s success, saying: &ldquo;Mincemeat swallowed rod, line and sinker.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The successful invasion wa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">s </span><a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">considered</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">a turning point in the war, accelerating Mussolini&rsquo;s downfall later that month and supporting the Allies in their eventual victory in Europe in September 1945.</span></p>
<h2><b>What were the roles of Colin Firth and Matthew Macfadyen&rsquo;s characters?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cholmondeley (pronounced &ldquo;Chumley&rdquo;), played by Macfadyen, was an eccentric secondee to the intelligence unit from the Royal Air Force, despite having </span><a href="https://www.historyextra.com/period/second-world-war/operation-mincemeat-what-happened-hitler-tricked-who-william-martin-glyndwr-michael/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">never flown. Montagu, played by Firth, had been a lawyer before signing up with naval intelligence during the war. Together, they led a team known as Section 17M based in a basement room of the British naval headquarters in London.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cholmondeley and Montagu had worked for the secret XX Committee in the British secret service, where they were regularly confronted with double agents, counter-espionage, counter-intelligence, and misinformation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Montagu and Cholmondeley both received military awards for their role in the operation.</span></p>
<h2><b>What parts of the movie are made up?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the movie, suspicions fall on Montagu as the British intelligence service believe that his brother Ivor, played by Mark Gatiss, is a Russian spy. Cholmondeley is enlisted to spy on Montagu during the operation to assess the threat his brother may pose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In reality, Montagu&rsquo;s brother Ivor was a</span> <a href="https://www.radiotimes.com/movies/operation-mincemeat-true-story/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">committed communist</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and had once worked for the Russian secret service. While the British were suspicious of him and even tapped his phone, his impact on the operation was thought to be limited. There&rsquo;s also no evidence to suggest that Cholmondeley was spying on his colleague.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another embellished subplot of the movie is a love triangle between Cholmondeley, Montagu, and Jean Lesley, played by Kelly Macdonald. Lesley worked as a secretary for the British secret service, and her </span><a href="https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/jean-leslie-qx0k0hrrm85"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">photograph</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">was planted in the briefcase as the &ldquo;fianc&eacute;e&rdquo; of the fabricated marine. Although Lesley knew the two men, there&rsquo;s no evidence that they were vying for her affections.</span></p>
<p><em>For more of TIME&rsquo;s culture coverage, subscribe to our entertainment newsletter, More to the Story, by clicking <a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=more-to-the-story?source=mtts_article"  target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln%3Dmore-to-the-story?source%3Dmtts_article&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1651945322663000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0GXF5PcDGMj4s_bFA64aeL">here</a>.</em></p>
<h2><b>How was James Bond author Ian Fleming involved?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The movie is narrated by Ian Fleming (Johnny Flynn), the James Bond author who worked for the British naval intelligence division during the war.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Around the time of Operation Mincemeat, Fleming was assistant to Admiral Godfrey, the head of naval intelligence. Fleming </span><a href="https://www.radiotimes.com/movies/operation-mincemeat-true-story/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">suggested</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the corpse plot to Godfrey as a clever way to trick the Nazis after reading a similar storyline in a novel. Cholmondeley and Montagu ran with the idea, expanding it to the fantastical scale depicted in the movie.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inspired by his time in the intelligence unit, Fleming later went on to write 14 novels revolving around the fictional spy, James Bond. It&rsquo;s been</span> <a href="https://www.historyhit.com/on-her-majestys-secret-service-ian-fleming-and-the-creation-of-james-bond/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">suggested</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">that Admiral Godfrey was Fleming&rsquo;s basis for Bond&rsquo;s boss, &ldquo;M&rdquo;, while another agent involved in Operation Mincemeat, Charles Fraser-Smith, </span><a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">inspired</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Bond&rsquo;s gadget-making colleague, &ldquo;Q.&#8221; Fraser-Smith </span><a href="https://www.history.com/news/what-was-operation-mincemeat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">designed</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">a special container to preserve the fake marine&rsquo;s corpse during its time in the water, which was then released into the sea from a British submarine.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174289</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indiana Man Charged With Wife’s Murder Prevails in Local GOP Primary</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174389/indiana-murder-gop-primary/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Indiana]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[nationpod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[wire]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174389</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Andrew Wilhoite has been held in jail without bond since his arrest in late March in the death of 41-year-old Elizabeth “Nikki” Wilhoite]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174389"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/6174389/indiana-murder-gop-primary/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>LEBANON, Ind. &mdash; A central Indiana man charged with murder in connection with the March death of his wife is one of three candidates who advanced in a primary election this week for a township board.</p>
<p>Andrew Wilhoite, 40, of Lebanon received 60 of the 276 total votes Tuesday for Republicans for three positions on the Clinton Township Board, Boone County election results show.</p>
<p>Indiana township boards consist of three members, state officials said. The local Republican primary race drew only three candidates and no candidates filed for the Democratic primary ticket, <a href="https://www.indystar.com/story/news/2022/05/05/andrew-wilhoite-accused-killing-wife-clinton-township-indiana-primary-winner/9659893002/"  target="_blank">The Indianapolis Star</a> reported.</p>
<p>Wilhoite was arrested in late March in the death of 41-year-old Elizabeth &ldquo;Nikki&rdquo; Wilhoite. He&rsquo;s been held since then in the Boone County Jail without bond.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6167723/back-booth-midterms-inflation/" ><em>Swing-District Voters Decide Elections, Not Pundits</em></a></p>
<p>Indiana State Police have said Andrew Wilhoite struck Nikki Wilhoite in the head with a blunt object, knocking her out. He then put her in a vehicle and drove to a creek a few miles from their home and dumped her body there, police said.</p>
<p><a href="https://apnews.com/article/lebanon-arrests-indiana-b4a4296506757241d316412fc229d250"  target="_blank">Police found Nikki Wilhoite&rsquo;s body on March 26</a> partially submerged in about 3 feet (1 meter) of water.</p>
<p>Court records indicate Nikki Wilhoite filed for divorce on March 17. The couple had been married for 12 years.</p>
<p>Andrew Wilhoite&#8217;s jury trial is scheduled for Aug. 29, online court records show.</p>
<p>If he is convicted of a felony before the Nov. 8 general election, he would automatically be removed from the ballot. No <a href="https://time.com/6173552/democratic-party-grassroots-abortion/" >Democrats</a> have filed for the Clinton Township Board.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Under our legal system, every person is innocent until proven guilty,&rdquo; said Brad King, co-director of the Indiana Election Division.</p>
<p>A message seeking comment on the charges Wilhoite faces was left Friday by The Associated Press for Wilhoite&rsquo;s attorney.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174389</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain Pushes Tough Tech Rules Under New Digital Watchdog</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174373/britain-tech-digital-watchdog/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[wire]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174373</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Big tech companies would have to comply with tough rules under a new digital watchdog aimed at giving consumers more choice online ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174373"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/6174373/britain-tech-digital-watchdog/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>LONDON &mdash; <a href="https://time.com/6168761/congress-big-tech-monopoly-antitrust/" >Big tech</a> companies like Google and Facebook parent Meta would have to comply with tough British rules under a new digital watchdog aimed at giving consumers more choice online &mdash; or face the threat of big fines.</p>
<p>The United Kingdom government on Friday outlined the powers it&#8217;s planning for its Digital Markets Unit, a regulator set up last year to take on the dominance of tech giants. It didn&#8217;t specify when the rules would take effect, saying only that legislation would come &ldquo;in due course.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Authorities in Britain and across Europe have been leading the global push to clamp down on tech companies amid rising concern about their outsized influence and harmful material proliferating on their platforms.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>The new U.K. watchdog would enforce rules that make it easier for people to switch between <a href="https://time.com/6172193/apple-supply-shortages-slash-sales/" >iPhones</a> and Android devices or between social media accounts without losing their data and messages.</p>
<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/6160241/how-big-tech-weaponizes-our-shame/" ><em>How Big Tech Weaponizes Our Shame</em></a></p>
<p>The government&#8217;s digital department said smartphone users would get a wider choice of search engines and <a href="https://time.com/5872868/big-tech-regulated-here-is-4-ways/" >more control over how their data is used</a>. Tech companies would have to warn small companies that do much of their business online about changes to algorithms that could affect their web traffic and revenue.</p>
<p>The watchdog also would get the power to solve pricing disputes between online platforms and news publishers to ensure media companies get paid fairly for their content, the government said.</p>
<p>Tech companies would face fines worth up to 10% of their annual global revenue <a href="https://time.com/5566501/facebook-regulation-zuckerberg/" >for breaking the rules</a>, which for the biggest companies would amount to billions of dollars.</p>
<p>Google and <a href="https://time.com/6146178/meta-facebook-eu-withdraw-data/" >Meta</a> did not respond immediately to requests for comment.</p>
<p>The U.K. rules are on top of a separate online safety law that is in the works, which would give users more power to block anonymous trolls and step up requirements for digital platforms to take down illegal material like posts involving child sexual abuse or terrorism.</p>
<p>The European Union has similar laws in the pipeline. The 27-nation bloc&#8217;s <a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-business-police-social-media-reform-52744e1d0f5b93a426f966138f2ccb52"  target="_blank">Digital Services Act</a> will require big tech companies to police their platforms more strictly for harmful or illegal content and services, while its <a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-business-social-media-european-union-facebook-434781764c3eae4d8b8603344d429794"  target="_blank">Digital Markets Act</a> is aimed at reining in online &ldquo;gatekeepers.&#8221; Both threaten big fines for violations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174373</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Nation Is Still Divided Along the Battle Lines of the Civil War</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174297/america-divided-civil-war/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeremi Suri]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174297</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Worries about a new civil war in the United States are misplaced because the Civil War never fully ended. That is essential knowledge for understanding current political divisions, especially the recriminations surrounding the leaked draft Supreme Court Roe decision, negating constitutional protections of a woman&#8217;s abortion rights. For abortion and many other issues, our nation&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174297"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174297/america-divided-civil-war/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>Worries about a <a href="https://time.com/6141468/trump-us-civil-war/" >new civil war</a> in the United States are misplaced because the Civil War never fully ended. That is essential knowledge for understanding current political divisions, especially the recriminations surrounding the leaked draft <a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" >Supreme Court Roe decision</a>, negating constitutional protections of a woman&rsquo;s abortion rights.</p>
<p>For abortion and many other issues, our nation is still divided largely along the battle lines of the Civil War: one party remains rooted in the old Confederacy; the other draws its energy from the diverse voters in northern and coastal states. Critics of federal power continue to resist protecting voting rights, women&rsquo;s rights, and educational access, while progressive proponents endorse national voting, health, and education standards. White supremacy pervades these divisions&mdash;the color of one&rsquo;s skin remains one of the best predictors of which side you are on.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>The first opportunity to heal these divisions came after the surrender of the Confederacy in April 1865, but the war weary Union did not make the necessary commitments to change the behaviors, institutions, and beliefs of the South. Responding to pressures from families and businesses in the North, the federal government reduced its military presence in the South, cut back on spending for law enforcement, and began pardoning secessionists and readmitting their states to the Union. The former Confederate states wrote new constitutions beginning in 1868, and they included African-American elected officials for a short time, but they quickly reverted to exclusive white rule with few repercussions from the federal government. Ten years after the surrender at Appomattox, the Southern leaders in Congress, state houses, and police forces looked the same as they did before the war.</p>
<p>Although there were major changes&mdash;especially the end of slavery and the passage of constitutional amendments guaranteeing equal protection and universal male voting&mdash;the Confederates who returned from the battlefields were largely allowed to rule again. They still owned most of the property and they still wielded deadly force in the South. By the 1870s the old Confederates re-enforced white rule, as they excluded and attacked African-Americans and other supporters of the federal government. Those who demanded fair treatment for vulnerable citizens were slandered, bullied, and sometimes killed. Hundreds of black and white men were lynched by organized mobs in the second half of the nineteenth century for daring to challenge the color line. Juries regularly acquitted the cold-blooded killers.</p>
<p>Mainstream politicians from the North, including forgettable presidents like Rutherford Hayes and James Garfield, tolerated violent white rule in the South because it promised political stability. They would not win votes in the region, but they would not face a rebellion either. In exchange for regional autonomy, Southern politicians begrudgingly accepted Northern presidents at the end of close, contested elections. Then they did everything they could to curtail presidential power, including de-funding federal law enforcement. The country fell into a long period of frozen division that although peaceful on the surface, embedded systemic violence toward African-Americans, women, and numerous minorities.</p>
<p>This history is at the center of our current troubles. The habits and laws protecting white minority rule are preventing American democracy from pursuing <a href="https://time.com/5925180/election-reform-2021/" >necessary reforms</a>. States remain free to limit voting through old techniques, including difficult-to-reach polling locations, burdensome registration and identification requirements, and increasing harassment of voters. The states have also perfected traditional gerrymandering practices, drawing districts that deny certain groups any chance at representation. The promotion of these techniques, accompanied by baseless claims of &ldquo;voter fraud,&rdquo; have worked because they are familiar. Their history gives them legitimacy in many eyes.</p>
<p>Our laws are indeed a central part of the problem because they reflect this history. The Posse Comitatus Act, forced upon President Hayes by Southern politicians in 1878, severely constrains the use of military power at home. The Act has encouraged a strong presumption that federal forces would stay out of disputes over elections. It should not surprise us that although the Pentagon was quick to clear Lafayette Square of demonstrators in June 2020, it was slow to react when violent insurrectionists threatened the certification of the new president.</p>
<p>The certification was vulnerable in the first place because of the <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-electoral-count-act-of-1887-is-showing-its-age-heres-how-to-help-congress-certify-a-presidential-election-with-more-certainty-175222"  target="_blank">Electoral Count Act of 1887</a>&mdash;a compromise authored by Democrats and Republicans after a disputed election in 1876, and two very close elections in 1880 and 1884. The Act created a series of convoluted procedures designed to give more power to governors and state legislatures in determining the electoral votes for president. They count the votes of citizens, allocate electors, and then attest to the votes of the electors. Congress retained the ability to object to state electoral ballots, but only with a majority in both houses. The weeks from Election Day to certification are filled with opportunities for various local and state officials to influence the outcome. That was precisely the intention of politicians in the nineteenth century, and it contributed to the extended and violent dispute around the 2020 presidential election, despite the clear victory by Joe Biden.</p>
<p>According to the Fourteenth Amendment, elected officials who encourage the kind of <a href="https://time.com/6137604/history-insurrection-jan-6/" >insurrectionary violence</a> witnessed on January 6, 2021 are subject to a permanent ban from office. Immediately after ratification in 1868, however, this law was undermined by blanket pardons granted to former Confederates by President Andrew Johnson. Elected officials who helped violent groups, like the Ku Klux Klan, attack federal institutions were never held accountable.</p>
<p>That precedent surely encouraged some current members of Congress to believe that they could assist efforts to stop the certification of Joe Biden&rsquo;s presidency without penalty. Senator Ted Cruz, for example, invoked the history of Southern white resistance to majority rule when he called on his colleagues to delay the certification of the 2020 presidential election and create a special commission to investigate the lies about fraud that he and his allies were circulating. He and many others continue to believe that they can serve in elected office and provoke insurrection.</p>
<p>These poisoned inheritances are not small blemishes on American democracy; they are deep scars that imperil the health of the entire republic. They are easy to ignore in highly partisan debates and self-serving efforts to glorify the nation, but they are obvious to anyone who diagnoses our history carefully. We cannot afford to censor the uncomfortable evidence of systematic exclusion and division. We must accept the evidence, recognize the scars, and work to heal. That means changing laws and institutions to increase fairness for all citizens.</p>
<p>Historical reckoning is a necessary medicine for strengthening democracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174297</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Unbearably Hot Schools Show We Must Climate-Proof Education</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174322/india-schools-heat-climate-change/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ciara Nugent]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Climate Is Everything]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174322</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A heat wave has forced schools in Northern India to close again after two years of disruption by COVID-19]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174322"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174322/india-schools-heat-climate-change/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">School&rsquo;s about to be out for the summer in India&mdash;weeks earlier than planned. The sweltering spring heatwave that has built across the subcontinent since March</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has in recent days forced several north Indian states to change schooling hours, revive lockdown-era online classes, and bring forward annual summer vacations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Air conditioning is rare in Indian schools&mdash;a </span><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/punjab-village-school-looks-to-turn-fully-ac-to-retain-new-admissions-during-covid-times-6561725/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">selling point</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the few that offer it&mdash;and <a href="https://time.com/6173769/india-heatwave-climate-change-coal/" >heat-related </a></span><a href="https://time.com/6173769/india-heatwave-climate-change-coal/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">power outages </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">have left classrooms unable to run electric fans. Teachers in Gurgaon, a city near Delhi, </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/gurgaon/schools-feel-the-heat-want-timings-changed/articleshow/91243552.cms"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reported </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">students fainting during lessons. Students in Kolkata </span><a href="https://www.telegraphindia.com/my-kolkata/news/icse-examinees-find-it-difficult-to-focus-in-sizzling-kolkata-heat/cid/1862318"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">complained</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> they were unable to focus during exams. On April 29, the government in </span><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/education/heat-wave-punjab-govt-prepones-summer-vacations-for-govt-schools/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Punjab</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a northern state where temperatures reached nearly 115&deg;F this week, said that it will send students home on May 16 for two weeks of online classes. Until then, school hours are shifting forward, so that students can learn from 7 a.m. to 12.30 p.m., and return home for the hottest part of the day. The states of </span><a href="https://news.careers360.com/summer-vacations-chhattisgarh-schools-from-april-24-heatwave-heat-wave-in-india-bihar-telangana-odisha-andhra-pradesh"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chhattisgarth </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/gurgaon/schools-feel-the-heat-want-timings-changed/articleshow/91243552.cms"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Haryan</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">announced similar plans.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shutdowns like these save lives in India. The country is no stranger to <a href="https://time.com/6078019/city-heat-climate-change-inequity/" >extreme heat</a>, and authorities rely on </span><a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/news/india-and-pakistan-act-save-lives-from-extreme-heat"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">monitoring and warning systems</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to prevent people from exerting themselves when temperatures get dangerously high. And states have brought forward school holidays</span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/may/04/delhi-schools-ordered-to-close-early-for-summer-as-temperatures-soar"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the past</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But with severe heat waves now regularly arriving weeks before the official start of summer, and after two years of COVID-19 closures that </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/27/world/asia/india-schools.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">severely disrupted </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indian children&#8217;s education, some teachers say the country needs to do more to make its schools resilient to climate change. </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/Gurbachan-Singh"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gurbachan Singh</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Punjab-based math teacher and representative for educators union the Democratic Teachers Front (DTF), accused the state of resorting to &ldquo;easy shortcuts,&rdquo; by shutting down schools. &ldquo;The government should give priority to holding regular classes and giving the schools proper power supply and weather-appropriate infrastructure instead of shutting them down,&rdquo; </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/Gurbachan-Singh"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Singh</span></a> <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/ludhiana/school-timings-change-teachers-oppose-extended-summer-break/articleshow/91298531.cms"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">told </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">the Times of India</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">on Wednesday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">India is not the only country where weather extremes pose a challenge for schools. &ldquo;Climate change is increasingly having a very real impact on children&#8217;s opportunity to learn globally,&rdquo; says Robert Jenkins, UNICEF&rsquo;s director of education. &ldquo;We in the education sector are waking up too late to this challenge.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a</span><a href="https://www.unicef.org/rosa/media/11296/file/Rising%20to%20the%20Challenge.pdf"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 2020 survey</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by UNICEF of 25,000 students in eight <a href="https://time.com/longform/jacobabad-extreme-heat/" >South Asian countries</a>, 78% said climate change had impacted their education: 5% said climate impacts made their school unsafe, 19% said their journeys to school had been affected, and 25% said heat or flooding had left them unable to concentrate or forced them to drop out of classes. Heat is not the only culprit: in 2017, Vietnam had to close more than 325 schools in four provinces for nine days after a cyclone, and in 2015, a typhoon in the Philippines shuttered 803 schools for two weeks. The Global North is <a href="https://time.com/extreme-heat-climate-change/" >not immune</a> either. In the U.S., almost </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">one in five students attended school districts that suffered federally-declared natural disasters </span><a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-22-104606.pdf"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">between 2017 and 2019</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Such events are now happening &ldquo;with an increasing frequency, for a longer duration and over broader areas,&rdquo; Jenkins says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The long-term implications for countries on the frontlines of climate change is worrying. A </span><a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w24639"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by U.S. nonprofit, the National Bureau of Economic Research, found that students in hotter countries performed worse than those in cooler countries on international standardized math tests. Within the U.S., researchers found a 1</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&deg;F </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">increase in the average temperature over a school year decreases test scores by 0.002 standard deviations&mdash;the equivalent of just under 1% of a year&rsquo;s worth of learning. It&rsquo;s hard to quantify the <a href="https://time.com/6093845/how-heat-hurts-the-economy/" >economic impact of climate change</a> on education systems, which includes everything from the cost of repairing damaged infrastructure to the knock-on effects on students&rsquo; future livelihoods, but the U.N.</span><a href="https://www.unicef.org/eap/media/4596/file/It%20is%20getting%20hot:%20Call%20for%20education%20systems%20to%20respond%20to%20the%20climate%20crisis.pdf"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> estimates </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">the number is &ldquo;likely to be in the scale of trillions of dollars.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite that, governments have been slow to address threats to education as part of their climate plans, Jenkins says. In the short term, UNICEF is working with 145,000 schools in India on programs to share information about ways to stay safe while learning, and helping northern states to create heat action plans, which help schools determine risk levels at different temperatures. Some</span><a href="https://www.nrdc.org/sites/default/files/ahmedabad-heat-action-plan-2016.pdf"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cities </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">offer pamphlets on heat risks for schools to send home to parents.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But those steps only go so far. To keep children learning, many schools urgently need large-scale infrastructure improvements, Jenkins says, such as increased access to drinking water and sanitation, which is still lacking in large parts of rural India. Newly built schools need to be designed to be climate resilient&mdash;on stilts if they are in flood-prone areas, and with climate-specific architecture to mitigate heat risks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">COVID-19 lockdowns have given many schools experience in running lessons remotely, but in Punjab, teachers&rsquo; unions </span><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/ludhiana/school-timings-change-teachers-oppose-extended-summer-break/articleshow/91298531.cms"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">have urged</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the government not to view online classes as a long-term solution to rising heatwaves. They cited lasting &ldquo;steep declines&rdquo; in student engagement due to &ldquo;ineffective online classes,&rdquo; and warned of a lack of access to internet and devices in low-income homes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jenkins agrees that school closures &ldquo;should be avoided at all times.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s not only because of the risk of deepening educational inequalities, he argues, but also because schools, as the main way children and parents interact with local government in many parts of the world, can be a crucial platform for sharing information about safety precautions during climate disasters. &ldquo;Schools can be a really positive influence during those times, because children can engage their parents and their communities in the best way to deal with climate change.&rdquo;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174322</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I Have Earned Where I Am Right Now.’ Symone Sanders Talks to TIME Ahead of the Launch of Her MSNBC Show</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174321/symone-sanders-msnbc-kamala-harris/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Elliott]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The D.C. Brief]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174321</guid>
      <description><![CDATA["Hillary Clinton was the most qualified person, period, to ever seek the presidency. I don't care what the hell anybody says."]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174321"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174321/symone-sanders-msnbc-kamala-harris/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article is part of The D.C. Brief, TIME&rsquo;s politics newsletter. Sign up </span></i><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to get stories like this sent to your inbox.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If ever there were doubts that Symone Sanders doesn&rsquo;t phone anything in, they quickly dissipated in a stunning moment on a March night a little over two years ago when anti-dairy protesters </span><a href="https://time.com/5795522/jill-biden-protesters-rally/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">overtook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> then-candidate Joe Biden&rsquo;s security perimeter and seemed heading toward Sanders&rsquo; boss. In an instant, Sanders&mdash;with an assist from Jill Biden&mdash;stepped in with the block and wrestled one of the belligerents off the stage.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s that fierce sense of action that has made Sanders into one of the stars of her generation, and then the entire Democratic Party. She made her national name in 2015 and 2016 as Senator Bernie Sanders&rsquo; top spokeswoman, parlayed that into a CNN contributor gig and a memoir at age 30, and then landed on everyone&rsquo;s must-hire list for 2020. Even as she was a progressive rock star, a millennial badass and the all-too-rare Black woman with a seat at the table, she surprised Washington when she signed on with Biden, a white septuagenarian who represented the very establishment that she spent 2016 attacking.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Symone Sanders saw Biden&rsquo;s potential. She was one of his top aides and counseled the candidate on how to patch his rough spots with voters of color, women, and younger voters. When he won the election, Sanders chose to move with the team of Vice President-elect Kamala Harris, the first woman to win the role and the first Black and Indian-American to serve there. Sanders served as Harris&rsquo; chief spokeswoman and a senior adviser until December, when she </span><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/12/01/politics/symone-sanders-leaving-white-house-harris/index.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announced</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> her departure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Saturday at 4 p.m., MSNBC will debut Sanders&rsquo; new weekend show, a weekday version of which will air on NBC Universal&rsquo;s Peacock streaming service. And on Sunday, she will deliver a commencement speech to graduates of American University in Washington.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She also clearly has the </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/10/business/media/symone-sanders-msnbc.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">attention</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the network brass, who plan to have her step in as a guest </span><a href="https://deadline.com/2022/03/symone-sanders-msnbc-show-1234976407/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">anchor</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for other shows. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The D.C. Brief chatted by phone with Sanders this week. The conversation has been edited.</span></p>
<p><b>So congratulations on the show and Sunday&rsquo;s American University commencement. This is a big weekend for you. It&rsquo;s a long way from Omaha. What&rsquo;s going through your head right now?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am just a little bald Black girl from North Omaha, Nebraska, who wanted to move to Washington because I wanted to do politics. A dream of mine was to eventually have my own show. I used to pretend I was hosting my own show. My TV name was Donna Burns. Now I don&#8217;t have to pretend anymore, but it also comes with an enormous responsibility. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;ve worked in this White House, I&#8217;ve worked for the current president of the United States, the current vice president. I&#8217;ve worked for an icon in the progressive movement, Bernie Sanders. I&#8217;ve worked on more than 20 campaigns. I&#8217;m not here to be a spokesperson for the administration. I had that job already. If I still wanted to be a spokesperson, I should have kept my old job.</span></p>
<p><b>I caught your comments from South by Southwest, likening the new weekend show to a non-political group chat. Do those even exist any longer? Even </b><b><i>Housewives</i></b><b> group chats on my phone have taken on a political angle. </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I say the non-political group chats, I&#8217;m talking about the people who are not professional politicos like you and I. There are a number of people out there who are not tuned in to the 24-hour political news cycle. But they still care. They want to know what is happening and what&#8217;s going on. They have lots of thoughts about what&#8217;s happening in politics, but they don&#8217;t necessarily care to watch Senator Joe Manchin on C-SPAN or waking up early to catch all the Sunday shows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While they care about politics, they are talking about how what is happening at Netflix connects to the broader cultural conversation. They had dismal numbers from last week and </span>are <a href="https://www.essence.com/news/netflix-black-women-terminations/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">laying off</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a number of creators that they recently hired. And the majority of those creators are women of color. So they are having political conversations in a non-political way. And I want to talk to those people.</span></p>
<p><b>So how are you going to calibrate this tone? You bring up the Netflix situation. Everything takes on an overtone of politics. How do you deal with that?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So much is happening every single day. We are having mock episodes. And one of the things that we did yesterday in our mock show, we did the Netflix thing, but I did it under the banner of culture. We&rsquo;re going to dig a little deeper. We&#8217;re going to talk about James Corden </span><a href="https://deadline.com/2022/04/james-corden-leaving-late-late-show-2023-final-year-1235011646/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">leaving</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> late night, and how late night used to be the final destination for so many people, but now it seems like it&#8217;s a pit stop on a larger journey. And that spiraled into a conversation about how the changing social media and streaming landscape has allowed for more voices and more people, but also has allowed people to tune out news entities and outlets that they don&#8217;t necessarily want to consume.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m not a White House reporter, right? I&#8217;m not a Capitol Hill reporter. I got a business management degree from a school in the Midwest. So it is important to me to have the folks that know on my show. They have credentials. I have to ensure that I am going to inform my audience. I want people to know that when they turn on my show, they&#8217;re going to learn something.</span></p>
<p><b>Do you see yourself as a journalist in this role?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m a part of the media apparatus. I am not a trained journalist. No. But I have a responsibility as a member of the media apparatus to uphold journalistic standards. My executive producer is the former managing news editor at </span><a href="https://www.nbcwashington.com/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">WRC Washington</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is the NBC affiliate here in Washington, D.C. She is a real news lady. She&#8217;s regularly talking to me about standards. We&rsquo;ll get the standards under control. I have surrounded myself with a team of people who have done this for a while and can help me tease out what I&#8217;m trying to do in a way that is responsible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I was a commentator, I was very concerned by the fact that I was sitting in a Green Room with people and we would have a conversation and then we would go on television and they would say things that I know they don&#8217;t believe. They didn&#8217;t get fact-checked. Then people repeat what they said in their non-political and political group chats. They&#8217;re talking about it in their communities.</span></p>
<p><b>You&rsquo;re not the first to move from administration insider to trusted journalist. You might have been the quickest to go from being on the inside to getting your own show. There are so many young people out there who are like you were, hosting pretend shows with a spoon for a microphone. Tell them: How did you make that dream real?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am the recipient of a lot of goodwill and grace and blessings. I also did the work and I cannot underscore enough about the value of doing the work. I took risks. I remember when I moved to Washington, D.C., and didn&#8217;t even have an apartment. I took a risk when I went to work for Senator Sanders on his campaign. I distinctly remember people that I respect so much, mentors of mine, telling me that I was going to ruin my political career. If I went to work for Senator Sanders, I would be branded as a progressive forever. Back in the day, in 2015, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">progressive</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was a dirty word. Now, everybody wants to be a progressive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I became a commentator on CNN and then I decided I wanted to go back on the campaign trail. And people told me I was stupid. Why would I give up a platform to go work for somebody that may not even be President? I went into the White House and people were, like, you&#8217;re working for the Vice President; don&#8217;t you want to work for the President? They didn&rsquo;t understand that I had the opportunity to help make history every single day with the first woman, the first Black woman, Vice President of the United States of America. And when I left the administration, people said I was stupid. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think people see me and they think I just catapulted out nowhere, but I have worked at every level of politics. I have earned where I am right now. </span></p>
<p><b>Everyone who has worked with you respects that. I guess the question is: everyone knows you from your activism and advocacy. So why should audiences trust you to </b><b><i>not </i></b><b>bring that framework into the studio? Or will you bring it, just with transparency?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;m not going to shy away from who I am. They know me from my activism and advocacy. I make no qualms about the fact that the reason I wanted to work on a campaign in 2016 and in &lsquo;20 is because I thought that Donald Trump was a danger to democracy. I am not here to force my views on the viewer. I want to have a conversation. That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m going to have Republicans on, so we can have a well-rounded conversation and maybe every now and then, maybe more than that.</span></p>
<p><b>You were one of the Vice President&rsquo;s top aides. There must have been moments when the press coverage must have been maddening. </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was at a lot of events for the White House Correspondents&rsquo; Association dinner and I made a joke: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think everybody at this table, I have cursed out at one moment or time, all all in the name of doing my job.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> And we all laughed because it was true.</span></p>
<p><b>Tell me then, what is the biggest error in our coverage of her? You&rsquo;re not on the payroll anymore.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me just preface it with this: Vice President Harris is the first woman of color, the first Black woman that I have worked for. Now that I think about my career, I have worked for older white men and maybe two Black men. Working for a woman, particularly a Black woman, allowed me to see that people cover women differently. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hillary Clinton was the most qualified person, period, to ever seek the presidency. I don&#8217;t care what the hell anybody says. Hillary Clinton was more qualified than all these em-effers.</span></p>
<p><b>I do have to note, though, that you say Hillary Clinton was the most qualified candidate for President ever. You worked on the other side of the Democratic primary to deny her the nomination. So I do feel I can&#8217;t let that one go by.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just because she&#8217;s qualified doesn&#8217;t mean no one can run against her, you know? The media talked about her in a way as though she wasn&rsquo;t. The fact that the biggest scandal about Hillary Clinton was her emails should tell you everything you need to know.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can be critical of Vice President Harris, but you can also say that the coverage around her has a little sexism and a little racism, too.</span></p>
<p><b>You&rsquo;re one the sharpest political minds in the Democratic Party. Why take yourself out of the game for a cable show? </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why television? Why now? I think that this is probably one of the most important moments in our history in the United States of America. There is not a voice like mine that is out there. There is not someone with my experience and my direct knowledge of the current situation at hand, who intimately knows the President and Vice President and the leader of the progressive movement, Bernie Sanders. There&#8217;s not someone like me currently on television, who has worked at every single level and that can provide the insight that I can. </span></p>
<p><b>Finally, I have to ask: Will you be bringing the same ferocity to your guests when they step out of line as when you tackled that protester who rushed then-candidate Joe Biden in March of 2020?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8203;&#8203;I&#8217;m going to bring that same ferocity to my show. If people want to come on and not tell the truth, if they want to say we really just need to get Build Back Better done, I&rsquo;ll correct them. Why do you keep saying that? Because it ain&#8217;t happening.</span></p>
<p><b>You&rsquo;ll say that on the air?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sweeping Build Back Better bill that y&#8217;all have all written about it is dead. It&#8217;s true. The White House knows it. As we knew it last year, it does not exist.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make sense of what matters in Washington. </span></i><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sign up for the D.C. Brief newsletter</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174321</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>She Lost Her Family in the Holocaust. She Finally Knows the Name Her Parents Gave Her</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6172605/holocaust-survivor-birth-name/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia B. Waxman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[nationpod]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6172605</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Decades after the end of World War II, a Florida Holocaust museum tracked down a Holocaust survivor's birth name]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6172605"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6172605/holocaust-survivor-birth-name/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>More than 75 years since V-E Day&mdash;the May 8, 1945, celebrations marking the end of World War II in Europe and the surrender of Nazi Germany&mdash;Holocaust survivors are still recording their stories for future generations. One recently found out her own story is still being written: At the<span class="il"> age of 95, she finally learned the name her parents gave her.</span></p>
<p>Mary Wygodski of St. Petersburg, Fla., always knew she was named after her grandmother, but last year she learned that her birth name is Mera.</p>
<p>Ursula Szczepinska, Director of Education &amp; Research at the Florida Holocaust Museum in St. Petersburg, found that name listed in a birth register in the Lithuanian State Historical Archives, which emailed an image of it to Szczepinska, who could read the Polish and Hebrew on the document.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>&#8220;The truth came to light, after all these years,&#8221; Wygodski tells TIME.</p>
<p>Part of Szczepinska&#8217;s job is helping local survivors search for information about what happened to their relatives during the Holocaust, and she started searching for Wygodski&#8217;s birth name to prepare her for an interview for the USC Shoah Foundation&#8217;s Dimensions in Testimony program last April. Through that program, Holocaust survivors are recorded answering hundreds of questions about their experience during World War II, and the result is an interactive installation that allows museum visitors to ask any question to a digital version of the survivor and then receive a response back in real time. In preparation for the recording, Wygodski received some questions in advance, and one of them was about her birth name, which she did not know. As the sole survivor of her immediate family during the Holocaust, she had no one to ask, and the question never came up.</p>
<p>&#8220;Without this project and the preparation for the interview, we might never have known that [Mary] doesn&#8217;t know her real name,&#8221; says Szczepinska.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Born Mera Tabachowicz in 1925 in Vilna, Poland (now Vilnius, Lithuania), Wygodski lived in the Vilna ghetto and pretended to be her cousin Mila Kovner in order to stay in the ghetto under Mera&#8217;s uncle&#8217;s work permit. Mila had already been murdered at <a href="https://encyclopedia.ushmm.org/content/en/gallery/ponary"  target="_blank">Ponary</a>, a forest in Nazi-occupied Lithuania where as many as 75,000 people, mostly Jews, are believed to have been shot to death. Wygodski&#8217;s uncle&#8217;s wife and other children were also murdered there. <a href="https://encyclopedia.ushmm.org/content/en/article/vilna"  target="_blank">After the ghetto was liquidated</a>, Mary survived three concentration camps, <a href="https://encyclopedia.ushmm.org/content/en/article/riga"  target="_blank">Kaiserwald</a>, <a href="https://encyclopedia.ushmm.org/content/en/article/stutthof"  target="_blank">Stutthof</a>, and <a href="https://voices.library.iit.edu/camp/Magdeburg-Brabag"  target="_blank">Magdeburg.</a> At Kaiserwald, she tried to end her own life by jumping into the Dvina River after being separated from her family.</span></p>
<p>Wygodski was in <span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"><a href="https://voices.library.iit.edu/camp/Magdeburg-Brabag"  target="_blank">Magdeburg</a> when it was liberated, and after the war </span>moved to what was then Palestine, where she went by her Hebrew name, Miriam; Szczepinska found her name listed as such via the website of the Israel Genealogy Research Association. There, she met her husband Morton Wygodski, an engineer, and the two moved to Florida in 1957 where she&#8217;s lived ever since. She&#8217;s a mother of two and has three grandchildren.</p>
<p>Wygodski also remembered being called Mercia by her parents and her friends, but Szczepinska concluded it must have been a nickname. Mary always thought her name was Mary because her name is listed as such on an identification card from Magdeburg and an identification card from a displaced persons camp in Belgium she lived in briefly after the war ended in 1945. She donated those cards to the Florida museum, and Szczepinska believes the camps anglicized Mary&#8217;s name.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Despite learning her birth name, Wygodski, who has turned 96 since the discovery was made, has no plans to start going by it.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think it would be right,&#8221; she says. &#8220;People know me [by Mary].&#8221;</p>
<p>She hopes the story of how she lost track of her birth name because of the death of her family during the Holocaust will raise awareness about preserving survivors&#8217; memories. These days, seeing the news out of Ukraine reminds her of what she lived through during World War II, and she worries that Holocaust denial persists. As she puts it, &ldquo;Holocaust <span class="il">denial</span> and distortion is the greatest threat for the shrinking population of Holocaust survivors.&#8221;</p>
<p>She hopes by sharing the revelation that came up by telling her story, other survivors will be inspired not only to share more of their stories, to remind the world what they endured, but also in order to learn more about their own personal histories.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6172605</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness Can Tell Us About the Future of the Marvel Cinematic Universe</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174219/doctor-strange-2-mcu-future/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[James Grebey]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[culturepod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174219</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Here’s a brief guide to the MCU multiverse, and where it stands to go next.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174219"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174219/doctor-strange-2-mcu-future/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><b><i>Warning: Major spoilers ahead for </i></b><b>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At this point, the &ldquo;Marvel Cinematic Universe&rdquo; is a misnomer. Recent films, like </span><a href="https://time.com/6128276/spider-man-no-way-home-future/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man: No Way Home</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the just-released </span><a href="https://time.com/6172935/doctor-strange-multiverse-madness-review/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, have thrown their characters&mdash;and the franchise&mdash;into a vast and complex multiverse, as have </span><a href="https://time.com/6080431/loki-finale-explained-mcu/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">TV shows like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Disney</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">+. It&rsquo;s a lot to keep track of, especially since this all started with a simple movie about one guy building an iron suit. The latest Marvel movie, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">further complicates the MCU and takes audiences to new universes with some familiar-seeming characters. Here&rsquo;s a brief guide to the MCU multiverse, and where it stands to go next.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<h2><b>Wait, what is a multiverse?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverses&mdash;alternate worlds that may be identical, subtly altered, or radically different than the ones our heroes normally operate in&mdash;have been a part of superhero comics for decades, arguably going back to a 1961 issue of DC Comics&rsquo; </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Flash, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">where two different versions of the speedster crossed paths. The narrative device soon became popular, and why wouldn&rsquo;t it? Multiple worlds gave comic writers a near-infinite canvas to play &ldquo;what if?&rdquo; and Marvel Comics did just that with its similarly titled </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Comics and, more recently, Disney+ show. Multiverses mean time travel is possible, there can be duplicates of characters, there can be alternate versions of characters, and you can explain just about anything by attributing it to an infinite number of parallel worlds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the MCU didn&rsquo;t start out as a multiverse. With the exception of the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thor</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> movies&rsquo; talk of &ldquo;realms,&rdquo; which are more akin to mythically connected regions of the cosmos than parallel worlds, the first several films of the MCU take place on Earth or, occasionally, in space. It wasn&rsquo;t until the first Doctor Strange movie that the Ancient One (played by Tilda Swinton) explicitly mentioned the existence of other universes.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg 4096w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=300,126 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=768,322 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=600,251 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1536,644 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=2048,858 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=550,230 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1100,461 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=280,117 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=560,235 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=419,176 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=838,351 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1920,804 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=407,171 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=814,341 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=190,80 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=380,159 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=263,110 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=526,220 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=61,26 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1200,503 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=640,268 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=760,318 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1520,637 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=700,293 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1000,419 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=74,31 74w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=840,352 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1680,704 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1012,424 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=2024,848 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=320,134 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=730,306 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=192,80 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=597,250 597w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=479,201 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=958,401 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=767,321 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1534,643 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=800,335 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/VTR0980_comp_v154.1187.jpg?resize=1600,670 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Photo courtesy of Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >A scene from Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the </span><a href="https://time.com/6169255/cinematic-multiverse-list/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiverse</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the Ancient One was talking about isn&rsquo;t quite the multiverse that MCU fans commonly understand these days. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> introduced the Astral Plane, Mirror Dimension, and Dark Dimension, but in practice, they seem to be aspects of the main Marvel Universe rather than their own entities, though this is debatable. An episode of the Disney+ </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> show featured an alternate version of Doctor Strange who seemed to have visited his own reality&rsquo;s version of the Dark Dimension, for instance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other movies and shows added new &ldquo;dimensions&rdquo; to the MCU, including The Ancestral Plane (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Black Panther</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), the Quantum Realm (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ant-Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), Soulworld (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infinity War</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), Ta Lo (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), and the Duat </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(Moon Knight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">). All of these are unique places that seem to exist in tandem with the main reality of the MCU, though it&rsquo;s somewhat hard to say, as terms like dimension, world, plane, reality, and universe are all used somewhat interchangeably with little concrete explanation of what they actually are in the grander scale. Regardless of how multiverserally unique these realities are, they are not what fans are talking about when they talk about the multiverse. That involves timelines, warped versions of the universe we know, and the possibility of bringing other movies and characters into the MCU&rsquo;s fold.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6174199/doctor-strange-2-characters/" ><em>Breaking Down Every Significant Character Who Appears in </em>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</a></p>
<h2><b>Which Marvel films and shows do I need to watch to understand the multiverse?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While a trip to the Dark Dimension is neat, it doesn&rsquo;t generate the same excitement as seeing a same-but-different version of a familiar character. For that, the MCU turned to time travel&mdash;at least at first. In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avengers: Endgame</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the heroes use the </span><a href="https://time.com/5576656/avengers-endgame-time-travel/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quantum Realm</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to travel through time, and a past version of the Ancient One explains that time travel creates branching realities. These realities are, functionally, alternate universes.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?w=560&w=560" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg 3000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/loki-tom-hiddleston-sophie-dimartino.jpeg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Chuck Zlotnick&mdash;Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >Tom Hiddleston and Sophia Di Martino in <i>Loki</i></span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> TV show went a step further with the </span><a href="https://time.com/6080568/loki-villain-kang-the-conqueror/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Time Variance Authority and the reveal of He Who Remains</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Viewers learned that there are an infinite number of parallel universes and timelines. Most of them are more or less the same as the main MCU timeline, but there are variations. In one universe, for instance, Loki is a woman. In another, he killed Thor. In yet another, he&rsquo;s an alligator. The TVA monitors all these various universes to protect the &ldquo;Sacred Timeline&rdquo;&mdash;in reality pruning branches that would lead to a multiversal war that would screw up the entire timeline. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki uses parallel universes to tell a twisty story, but </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man: Far From Home</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> used the multiverse for other purposes: To maximize Intellectual Property. That movie had Peter Parker (Tom Holland) turn to Doctor Strange (Benedict Cumberbatch) for a spell that would alter memories (and reality) by harnessing the power of the multiverse. Peter&rsquo;s edits and Strange&rsquo;s hastiness led to a botched version of that spell that brought characters from other universes to the main MCU universe. The Spider-Men from the two Sony Spider-Man movie series, Tobey Maguire and Andrew Garfield, as well as five villains from the five old movies&mdash;movies that, before this, were not at all connected to the MCU. (Tom Hardy&rsquo;s Venom was also pulled into the MCU, but only for a </span><a href="https://time.com/6129030/spider-man-no-way-home-end-credits-scenes/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">funny post-credits cameo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="https://time.com/6163101/morbius-spider-man-end-credits-mcu/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Morbius&rsquo;</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> post-credits scene</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> pulled </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man: Homecoming</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo;s villain, Michael Keaton&rsquo;s Vulture, into whatever cinematic universe Sony&rsquo;s building.)</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?w=560&w=560" alt="Tom Holland stars as Peter Parker/Spider-Man and Benedict Cumberbatch stars as Doctor Strange in Columbia Pictures' SPIDER-MAN: NO WAY HOME." srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg 7252w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=300,165 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=768,423 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=600,331 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1536,846 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=2048,1128 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=550,303 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1100,606 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=280,154 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=560,309 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=419,231 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=838,462 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1920,1058 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=407,224 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=814,449 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1815,1000 1815w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=190,105 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=380,209 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=263,145 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=526,290 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=61,34 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1200,661 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=640,353 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=760,419 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1520,838 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=700,386 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1000,551 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=56,31 56w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=840,463 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1680,926 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1012,558 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=2024,1115 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=320,176 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=730,402 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=192,106 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=454,250 454w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=479,264 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=958,528 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=767,423 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1534,845 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=800,441 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Spider-Man-No-Way-Home.jpeg?resize=1600,882 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Matt Kennedy&mdash;Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >(l-r) Tom Holland and Benedict Cumberbatch in <i>Spider-Man: No Way Home</i></span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By establishing that the Sony Spider-Man movies were universes that existed as part of the MCU&rsquo;s multiverse, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Way Home</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> retroactively made them MCU canon&mdash;that is to say, part of the official storyline. They are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">however, part of the Marvel Cinematic Universe&rsquo;s main universe. It was a game-changer for fans&#8217; understanding of what a multiverse implied. Now, a multiverse wasn&rsquo;t just a plot-specific alternate realm, like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo;s Dark Dimension, nor was it a funhouse mirror timeline, like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo;s parallel realities. Now, the multiverse was a chance to make </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anything</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> canon in the MCU. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which was</span><a href="https://www.inverse.com/entertainment/professor-x-mcu-doctor-strange-2-marvel-x-men-97"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> teasing the appearance of Patrick Stewart&rsquo;s Professor X</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from the X-Men movies and characters from the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;? </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">show, seemed poised to further expand the multiverse and bring more old faces into the MCU fold. However, it subverts almost all of those expectations by making those highly anticipated characters into more of a prank than building blocks for the franchise&rsquo;s future</span></p>
<h2><b>So, what does </b><b><i>Doctor Strange 2</i></b><b> mean for the multiverse?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness does not introduce the X-Men to the MCU, and it&rsquo;s not a &ldquo;sequel&rdquo; to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as many suspected. Instead, America Chavez (Xochitl Gomez), who has the ability to travel the multiverse at will (though she can&rsquo;t control her powers at first) sends Doctor Strange and herself to another universe that has quite a few differences from the main MCU. That universe&rsquo;s version of Christine Palmer explains that this universe is Universe 838 and the MCU we&rsquo;re familiar with is Universe 616. (Incidentally, Mysterio called the MCU 616 in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man: Far From Home</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but since he was lying about being from another universe and had no real knowledge of the multiverse, chalk the coincidence up to an Easter egg, as the main Marvel comics continuity is also deemed 616.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Universe 838, Earth&rsquo;s Mightiest Heroes formed a team called the Illuminati, not the Avengers, and their roster is different from the group we&rsquo;re used to. There&rsquo;s a Captain Marvel, but apparently in this universe Maria Rambeau (Lashana Lynch) got the powers instead of Carol Danvers (Brie Larson); a Captain Carter (Hayley Atwell), but seemingly a different version of the character than the one in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> show; a Professor X (Stewart) who seems to take more after the &lsquo;90s X-Men cartoon than the Fox movies; a Black Bolt who probably isn&rsquo;t the same as the one from the maligned and forgotten </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inhumans</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> show, despite being played by Anson Mount; and Mr. Fantastic (John Krasinski) of the Fantastic Four, Marvel&rsquo;s first family who have yet to make their proper debut. All of them are brutally and hilariously killed by Scarlet Witch.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6172935/doctor-strange-multiverse-madness-review/" >Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness<em> Is Extravagant, Messy, and Over-the-Top Crazy</em></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, while the X-Men appear to exist in the MCU&rsquo;s multiverse, there&rsquo;s no confirmation that the X-Men of the Fox movies exist (Stewart reprising his role is more of a casting gag the way </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">WandaVision</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo;s casting of Evan Peters as &ldquo;Fake Pietro&rdquo; was), and the X-Men certainly don&rsquo;t exist in the main 616 universe yet. Mutants are out there, somewhere, in the Marvel Cinematic Universe. Just not </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">this</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> universe. And, it sure doesn&rsquo;t seem that any of the Illuminati are going to be major players in the future of the MCU because, well, they&rsquo;re all dead. </span></p>
<h2><b>What can </b><b><i>Doctor Strange 2</i></b><b> tell us about the future of the multiverse in the MCU?</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> doesn&rsquo;t actually expand the multiverse as much as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Way Home</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> did, and for all the cameos the various universes introduced, they don&rsquo;t really impact the main MCU continuity at all. However, it does reveal some new information about how the multiverse functions. We learn that dreams are actually visions of something that&rsquo;s happening in another universe, as seen in Wanda&rsquo;s dreams of a reality where her two children in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">WandaVision</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were actually real. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More importantly, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> introduced the concept of incursions&mdash;disastrous, potentially mutually universe-destroying events that can happen when two universes cross streams. (In retrospect, what happened at the end of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Way Home</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> may have been an incursion.) Incursions, taken from comics writer Jonathan Hickman&rsquo;s incredible </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avengers</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> run in the mid &lsquo;10s, are seemingly going to be a problem in the MCU going forward. The post-credits scene where Clea (Charlize Theron) appeared to enlist Strange&rsquo;s help in fixing an incursion, suggests the hero&rsquo;s next adventure will involve multiversal incursions.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6174104/doctor-strange-2-end-credits/" ><em>Let&rsquo;s Talk About the </em>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness<em> End-Credits Scenes</em></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We might need to wait a while to see what&rsquo;s next for the MCU&rsquo;s multiverse. The next Marvel films on the schedule for this year, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thor: Love and Thunder</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wakanda Forever</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, seem likely to take place primarily in just the 616 universe. It won&rsquo;t be too long until heroes are popping between dimensions again, as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ant-Man: Quantumania</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will almost certainly explore the multiverse, and there&rsquo;s a second season of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and another </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> adventure in the cards as well. Given that, it&rsquo;s hard to predict exactly what will happen next, from a storytelling perspective. The biggest and most immediate change </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse of Madness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> made to the MCU&rsquo;s multiverse is that it, somewhat unexpectedly, lowered the stakes. The multiverse in this movie was more of a fun storytelling tool rather than a worldbuilding mechanism, which opens up the possibility that future trips to the multiverse can be goofy rather than load-bearing.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg 4096w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=300,126 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=768,322 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=600,251 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1536,644 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=2048,858 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=550,230 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1100,461 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=280,117 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=560,235 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=419,176 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=838,351 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1920,804 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=407,171 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=814,341 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=190,80 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=380,159 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=263,110 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=526,220 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=61,26 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1200,503 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=640,268 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=760,318 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1520,637 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=700,293 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1000,419 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=74,31 74w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=840,352 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1680,704 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1012,424 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=2024,848 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=320,134 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=730,306 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=192,80 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=597,250 597w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=479,201 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=958,401 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=767,321 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1534,643 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=800,335 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/DoctorStrangeMagic.jpg?resize=1600,670 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >Benedict Cumberbatch as Dr. Stephen Strange in DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trying to keep all of the various universes and dimensions in the MCU is, as the Doctor Strange sequel&rsquo;s title suggests, maddening. Looking at the arc of the multiverse&rsquo;s film history, you can see it grow more complicated and possibly contradictory. That&rsquo;s OK, as long as the filmmakers and the viewers have some sort of handle on the rules and the stakes as they pertain to the specific story that&rsquo;s being told. After that, it can get kind of messy, as any longtime comics reader will tell you. The important thing to do then is to relish in it and have fun, just as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multiverse</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> director Sam Raimi surely did. You can&rsquo;t introduce a universe&rsquo;s worth of hyped-up heroes and then kill them off for laughs unless you&rsquo;re having a ball playing in the multiverse. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174219</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down Every Significant Character Who Appears in Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6174199/doctor-strange-2-characters/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Shannon Carlin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[culturepod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6174199</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Strange crosses paths with familiar faces from the Marvel Cinematic Universe, as well as the comics.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6174199"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6174199/doctor-strange-2-characters/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><b><i>Warning: Major spoilers ahead for </i></b><b>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are no Spider-men in </span><a href="https://time.com/6172935/doctor-strange-multiverse-madness-review/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">but there are four Doctor Stranges, two Christine Palmers, and one Scarlet Witch. When Doctor Stephen Strange (</span><a href="https://time.com/3597674/go-behind-times-benedict-cumberbatch-cover-with-photographer-dan-winters/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Benedict Cumberbatch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) and </span><a href="https://time.com/6128276/spider-man-no-way-home-future/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peter Parker (Tom Holland)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> accidentally opened the multiverse in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2021&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://time.com/6128825/spider-man-no-way-home-cameos-andrew-garfield-tobey-maguire/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man: No Way Home</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">all hell broke loose. The </span><a href="https://time.com/6171012/marvel-movies-shows-upcoming/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">madness continues</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">sequel. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the Sam Raimi-directed film, which marks his return to Marvel 20 years after the Tobey Maguire-led </span><a href="https://time.com/4834213/spiderman-movie-ranking/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> trilogy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> premiered, Wanda Maximoff (Elizabeth Olsen) is no longer one of the most powerful Avengers. She&rsquo;s the villainous Scarlet Witch, who is on an any means necessary mission to reunite with Billy and Tommy, the twin boys she created with her magic in the Disney+ TV series </span><a href="https://time.com/5942708/wandavision-what-happened/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">WandaVision</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">To stop her from destroying </span><a href="https://time.com/6169255/cinematic-multiverse-list/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">the multiverse</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is made up of at least 73 different parallel universes, Doctor Strange must dabble in the dark arts himself. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his darkest timeline travels, Strange crosses paths with familiar faces from the Marvel Cinematic Universe, as well as the comics. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below, is a list of the notable characters that show up in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><b>Who is America Chavez? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She&rsquo;s a teen with the ability to hop the multiverse, which is the exact power the Scarlet Witch needs to reconnect with her sons. America (played by Xochitl Gomez) is still learning to hone her powers, which is why she comes looking for help from Doctor Strange. Specifically the one living in </span><a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Earth-616"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the 616, known as the &ldquo;prime universe&rdquo;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to comic fans, which is the most similar to our reality. He encourages her to trust her own abilities and it&rsquo;s America who ends up defeating the Scarlet Witch and saving the day.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg 4940w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/SRV-10046_R.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Jay Maidment&mdash;&copy;Marvel Studios 2022. </span><span class="caption" >Xochitl Gomez as America Chavez in Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of the film, America is seen training with the Masters of the Mystic Arts in Kamar-Taj, just as Doctor Strange did. In the comics, she&rsquo;s the first openly queer Latinx character to headline her own comic book series.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6172935/doctor-strange-multiverse-madness-review/" >Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness<em> Is Extravagant, Messy, and Over-the-Top Crazy</em></a></p>
<h2><b>Who are the Illuminati? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A powerful group of superheroes who band together to help secretly protect Earth. This United Nations of superbeings shows up in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the parallel universe known as the 838, which, in the comics, is the reality in which </span><a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Earth-TRN838"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loki steals the powers of Santa Claus</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In this movie, Doctor Strange created the group. (It&rsquo;s Iron Man who does so in the comics.) But after being corrupted by the Darkhold, Strange willingly gives up his leadership and his life, knowing it&rsquo;s the only way to stop him from destroying the multiverse. The residents of Earth-838 don&rsquo;t know about Strange&rsquo;s heel turn, they believe he gave his life fighting Thanos. </span></p>
<h2><b>Who are the Marvel characters that make up the Illuminati?</b></h2>
<h3><b>Baron Karl Mordo</b></h3>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=768,588 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=600,459 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1536,1175 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=2048,1567 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=480,367 480w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=959,734 959w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=244,187 244w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=489,374 489w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=353,270 353w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=731,559 731w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=706,540 706w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1412,1080 1412w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1882,1440 1882w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=407,311 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=814,623 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=280,214 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=560,428 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1307,1000 1307w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=190,145 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=380,291 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=263,201 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=526,402 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=61,47 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1200,918 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=640,490 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=760,581 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1520,1163 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=700,536 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1000,765 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=41,31 41w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=550,421 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1100,842 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=840,643 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1680,1285 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1012,774 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=2024,1548 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=320,245 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=637,487 637w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=192,147 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=523,400 523w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=261,200 261w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=167,128 167w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=327,250 327w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=479,366 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=958,733 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=767,587 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1534,1174 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=800,612 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-05.jpg?resize=1600,1224 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >JAY MAIDMENT&mdash;&copy;Marvel Studios 2022. </span><span class="caption" >Chiwetel Ejiofor as Mordo in Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MUTLIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange&#8217;s nemesis and former ally of the Ancient One, who is played by Chiwetel Ejiofor becomes the Sorcerer Supreme after Strange&rsquo;s execution, which earns him admission into the Illuminati. In this universe, he&rsquo;s no longer interested in wiping out the Masters of the Mystical Arts, but he still holds a grudge against Stephen Strange. That parallel universe pettiness leads to Scarlet Witch&rsquo;s decimation of the Illuminati.</span></p>
<h3><b>Captain Carter</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peggy Carter (Hayley Atwell) is the first Avenger in this alternate universe, not Captain America. This was also the case in the </span><a href="https://disney.fandom.com/wiki/What_If..._Captain_Carter_Were_The_First_Avenger%3F"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disney+ TV series </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If&hellip;?</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">(Atwell&rsquo;s Peggy has appeared in a number of Marvel movies and on two ABC shows, </span><a href="https://entertainment.time.com/2013/09/24/agents-of-s-h-i-e-l-d-5-things-you-need-to-know/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://time.com/3654678/review-agent-carter-delivers-a-super-heroine/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agent Carter</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.) Captain Carter may wear a Union Jack supersuit, but she still carries the shield, which helps her defend herself against the Scarlet Witch. Unfortunately, Captain Carter isn&rsquo;t strong enough to kill the magical villain, who ends up slicing her in half with her own signature weapon. </span></p>
<h3><b>Captain Marvel</b></h3>
<p><a href="https://screenrant.com/wandavision-maria-rambeau-death-legacy-lashana-lynch-response/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lashana Lynch&#8217;s Maria Rambeau</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, not Brie Larson&#8217;s Carol Danvers, is the intergalactic superhero in this universe, which earns her a seat on the Illuminati board. The former Air Force pilot and mom to Monica (played by Teyonah Parris in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">WandaVision</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) comes closest to physically besting the Scarlet Witch, but is crushed to death before she can hit her enemy with a fatal blow. </span></p>
<h3><b>Black Bolt</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Marvel character, played by Anson Mount</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">may not be as well</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">known to the casual MCU fan, but he&rsquo;s the King of the Inhumans. (Mount previously portrayed the character on ABC&rsquo;s short-lived </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1sYF1SXcWqQ"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marvel&rsquo;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inhumans</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">His power lies in his voice, which can release a shockwave that can destroy cities. It&rsquo;s why he mostly uses sign language to communicate to keep from triggering a catastrophic event. The Scarlet Witch ends up using his powers against him, forcefully shutting his mouth, causing his head to explode. </span></p>
<h3><b>Reed Richards</b></h3>
<p><a href="https://time.com/5524168/emily-blunt-john-krasinski-romance/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">John Krasinski</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> makes his debut as Mr. Fantastic, the leader of the Fantastic Four known for his smarts. Mr. Fantastic tries to reason with the Scarlet Witch who shreds him to death. Despite his brutal demise, it&rsquo;s hard to believe this is the last time fans will see Krasinski in the role. Especially with the MCU&rsquo;s upcoming plans for </span><a href="https://screenrant.com/fantastic-four-movie-problem-stretching-powers-not-casting/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fantastic Four </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">movie</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h3><b>Professor X</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patrick Stewart&rsquo;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">X-Men </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">character Charles Xavier returns, looking like he does in the &#8217;90s cartoon with his</span><a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Hoverchair"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> signature yellow hoverchair</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Professor X is leader of the Illuminati and the only one who believes this Doctor Strange has </span><a href="https://youtu.be/buK45NW_ikI?t=103"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the ability to change</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He also believes the Scarlet Witch can change too, inhabiting her mind in hopes of saving Wanda from being overtaken by the witchy version of herself. Unfortunately, the Scarlet Witch one-ups him in the telekinesis department and breaks his neck mid-mind meld. The Professor may not make it out of this film alive, but his appearance does confirm that the X-Men exist in the MCU. </span></p>
<h3><b>Which Doctor Strange variants show up in the film?</b></h3>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg 4096w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=300,126 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=768,322 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=600,251 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1536,644 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=2048,858 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=550,230 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1100,461 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=280,117 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=560,235 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=419,176 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=838,351 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1920,804 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=407,171 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=814,341 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=190,80 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=380,159 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=263,110 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=526,220 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=61,26 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1200,503 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=640,268 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=760,318 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1520,637 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=700,293 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1000,419 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=74,31 74w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=840,352 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1680,704 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1012,424 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=2024,848 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=320,134 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=730,306 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=192,80 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=597,250 597w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=479,201 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=958,401 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=767,321 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1534,643 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=800,335 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/KTH2580_TRL_comp_v209.1025_R.jpg?resize=1600,670 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Photo courtesy of Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >Benedict Cumberbatch as Dr. Stephen Strange in Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are three other Doctor Stranges that pop up in the movie. All of which are deemed evil for their inability to resist the powers of the Darkhold. The 838 Strange is executed by Black Bolt for causing an &ldquo;incursion&rdquo; or the collapse of a whole reality while Dreamwalking, the forbidden practice of possessing the body of an alternate version of one&rsquo;s self. Sinister Strange developed a third eye while guarding the Darkhold and warns 616 Stephen that the book takes a serious toll on its user. Zombie Strange lost his life earlier in the film when he attempted to kill America for her powers. He&rsquo;s not all bad though; the undead Strange teams up with America to defeat the Scarlet Witch.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6174219/doctor-strange-2-mcu-future/" ><em>What </em>Doctor Strange and the Multiverse of Madness <em>Can Tell Us About the Future of the Marvel Cinematic Universe</em></a></p>
<h2><b>Who from </b><b><i>Doctor Strange </i></b><b>returns for the sequel?</b></h2>
<h3><b>Doctor Nic West</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dr. West (played by Michael Stuhlbarg) makes a brief appearance at Christine&rsquo;s wedding to ask Doctor Strange whether he made the right choice in the battle against Thanos. West lost his two cats and his brother during the blip. He mourns them in that order. </span></p>
<h3><b>Wong</b></h3>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/doctor-strange-multiverse-of-madness-06.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Jay Maidment&mdash;&copy;Marvel Studios 2022. All Rights Reserved.</span><span class="caption" >Benedict Wong as Wong in Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange&#8217;s magical partner in multiversal crime, who is played by Benedict Wong, is now the Sorcerer Supreme and deserves his damn respect, which Stephen finally gives him in the final moments of the film. </span></p>
<h3><b>Christine Palmer</b></h3>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg 3840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=300,126 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=768,322 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=600,251 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1536,644 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=2048,858 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=550,230 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1100,461 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=280,117 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=560,235 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=419,176 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=838,351 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1920,805 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=407,171 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=814,341 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=190,80 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=380,159 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=263,110 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=526,220 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=61,26 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1200,503 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=640,268 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=760,318 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1520,637 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=700,293 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1000,419 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=74,31 74w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=840,352 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1680,704 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1012,424 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=2024,848 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=320,134 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=730,306 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=192,80 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=597,250 597w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=479,201 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=958,401 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=767,321 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1534,643 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=800,335 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/CWC7000_TRL_comp_v005.1032_C_R.jpg?resize=1600,670 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Photo courtesy of Marvel Studios</span><span class="caption" >Rachel McAdams as Dr. Christine Palmer in Marvel Studios&#8217; DOCTOR STRANGE IN THE MULTIVERSE OF MADNESS. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rachel McAdams plays two versions of the character who Stephen pines away for in every universe. She is a newlywed in the 616 who questions whether Strange is really happy. In the 838 universe, she&#8217;s a research fellow for the </span><a href="https://marvel-movies.fandom.com/wiki/Baxter_Foundation"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baxter Foundation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an institute for science prodigies that appears in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fantastic Four, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">opening up the possibility that Christine could one day team up with Mr. Fantastic and his crew.</span></p>
<h3><b>Who is the three-eyed Doctor Strange who appears at the end of the film?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike Sinister Strange, this Doctor Strange with a third eye appears to still be a good guy. At least, for now. The former surgeon&rsquo;s extra eye could mean that he has found a way to possess the </span><a href="https://marvelcinematicuniverse.fandom.com/wiki/Eye_of_Agamotto"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eye of Agamotto</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a powerful relic he is seen wearing in the film that helps its wearer see through disguises or illusions and create portals to other dimensions. But the mystical item can be a dangerous weapon if it ever lands in the wrong hands. Let&rsquo;s hope those hands aren&rsquo;t the three-eyed Doctor Strange&rsquo;s. His multiversal self did warn him of the dangerous effects the Darkhold could have on him.</span></p>
<h3><b>Who is Clea? </b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She&rsquo;s the mysterious woman played by </span><a href="https://time.com/6102630/vaccine-inequity-charlize-theron-darren-walker/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Charlize Theron</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> who shows up in the mid-credits scene. The sorceress from the Dark Dimension has played a significant role in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctor Strange </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">comics since her debut in 1964. She&rsquo;s been Strange&rsquo;s ally, mentee, and an unconventional love interest. In this short scene, she&rsquo;s his traveling companion, who has come looking for him to help her fix the incursion he caused.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/6174104/doctor-strange-2-end-credits/" ><em>Let&rsquo;s Talk About the </em>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness<em> End-Credits Scenes</em></a></p>
<h2><b>Does Bruce Campbell appear in the movie?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Raimi&rsquo;s go-to actor since 1981&rsquo;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evil Dead </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was a delightful staple in the director&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X1r4SMfwsQE"  target="_blank"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spider-Man </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">trilogy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, popping up as three different minor characters: a wrestling announcer, waiter, and Broadway usher. Here, he makes a noteworthy cameo as Pizza Poppa, a street vendor who Stephen puts a rather immature spell on. Stick around to the very end to see if this daddy ever stops hitting himself.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6174199</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>