<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
    <description>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</description>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rawstory.com/feeds/world.rss" rel="self">
    </atom:link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:43:23 -0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNDk4MDQwMC9vcmlnaW4uanBnIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTcwODk2ODc0NH0.CAuDKCrYnLogkIrRCoHwZj7vOQ_5oq7DyFBijbdG0dE/image.jpg?width=210</url>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/</link>
      <title>Raw Story - Celebrating 18 Years of Independent Journalism</title>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine spies claim Russian troops are intentionally sabotaging their own 'stupid' invasion</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657277543/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29770205&width=600&coordinates=175%2C0%2C175%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The Security Service of Ukraine (SBU) claims to have intercepted recordings of Russian troops’ phone calls in which they discuss sabotaging Vladimir Putin's invasion of Ukraine, <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/intercepted-calls-catch-russian-troops-sabotaging-vladimir-putins-war-plans-by-breaking-tanks?ref=scroll" target="_blank">The Daily Beast reported</a> on Friday.  </p><p>“I don't follow stupid orders, I simply refuse,” one person on the recording can be heard telling another. “The motherf*cker sent me to tanks, motherf*cking piece of shit. I f*cked it up and that's it.”</p><p>“We have one tank left in the regiment. In short, we broke our tank ourselves in the morning so as not to go," another alleged Russian soldier can be heard telling a family member. </p><p>According to the Beast's Shannon Vavra, a mainstay of Russia's Ukraine invasion has been documented accounts of Russian troops abandoning their equipment and weapons. </p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/racist-trump-inspired-school-presentation-ignites-outrage-in-iowa-what-in-the-hell/" target="_self">Trump-inspired school presentation ignites outrage in Iowa</a></em></strong></p><p>"Russian military morale has been low from the beginning of the invasion, and it’s not getting any better; <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/vladimir-putin-put-on-blast-over-pathetic-first-aid-kits-for-russian-troops-in-ukraine?ref=author" target="_blank">Russian troops have begun posting on social media</a> begging for donations to the war effort, showing a side-by-side comparison between their dismal first-aid kits and the Ukrainians," Vavra writes. "The Russian war effort isn’t only being hampered from the inside. Inspired by the Russians’ intercepted phone calls, Ukraine’s government encouraged other Russian troops to disobey orders and refuse to attack, echoing earlier calls to surrender and abandon the war path."</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-invasion-of-ukraine-2657277543/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sky Palma</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29770205&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'The Rock' diamond dazzles in Geneva</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/the-rock-diamond-dazzles-in-geneva/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-rock-white-diamond-could-fetch-20-30-million-or-more-fabrice-coffrini-afp.jpg?id=29769872&width=600&coordinates=77%2C0%2C78%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The biggest white diamond ever to be sold at auction, dubbed "The Rock", will go under the hammer in Geneva on Wednesday and could fetch up to $30 million -- or more.</p><p>The 228.31-carat stone is up for grabs alongside a historic intense yellow diamond associated for more than a century with the Red Cross, which will receive some of the profits from its sale.</p><p>The Rock is "a truly exceptional pear-shaped diamond", said Max Fawcett, head of the jewels department at Christie's auction house in Geneva.</p><p>It is "the largest white diamond ever to be offered at auction", he told AFP at a preview on Friday.</p><p>The Rock is currently in the hands of an unnamed owner from North America.</p><p>It could even break records when it goes under the hammer.</p><p>"It's perfectly symmetrical and is estimated at $20 to $30 million -- and I expect there be fireworks on Wednesday," Fawcett said.</p><p>The equivalent in euros is 19 to 28 million.</p><p>The expert said that there were only a handful of diamonds of similar size and quality to The Rock. The Christie's record for a similar white diamond is $33.7 million, fetched in Geneva in 2017 for a 163.41-carat gem.</p><p>Larger than a golf ball, The Rock was extracted from a mine in South Africa in the early 2000s. It has been shown in Dubai, Taipei and New York ahead of the sale in Geneva.</p><h2>Red Cross gem</h2><p>Bidders will also be vying for The Red Cross Diamond, a cushion-shaped, 205.07-carat canary yellow jewel, which has a price estimate of seven to 10 million Swiss francs ($7.09 to $10.13 million).</p><p>"I expect that it will achieve much more on the day of sale," said Fawcett.</p><p>A large chunk of the proceeds will be donated to the International Committee of the Red Cross, which is headquartered in Geneva.</p><p>The original rough stone was found in 1901 in a De Beers company mine in South Africa and is said to have weighed around 375 carats.</p><p>As well as ranking among the largest diamonds in the world, a striking feature is its pavilion, which naturally bears the shape of a Maltese cross.</p><p>The stone was first put up for sale on April 10, 1918 at Christie's in London. It was offered by the Diamond Syndicate in aid of the British Red Cross Society and the Order of St John.<br/></p><p>The Red Cross Diamond fetched £10,000 -- approximately £600,000 ($740,000) in today's money. It was bought by the London jewelers S.J. Phillips.</p><p>It was sold again by Christie's in Geneva in 1973, fetching 1.8 million Swiss francs, and is now being offered by the auction house for a third time.</p><p>"For nearly half a century, our family has had the privilege of safeguarding The Red Cross Diamond," the gem's anonymous private owner said in a statement.</p><h2>Russia restrictions</h2><p>Several other diamonds will be auctioned on Wednesday, plus a tiara that belonged to princess Irma of Furstenberg (1867-1948), a member of one of the most pre-eminent aristocratic families in the Habsburg Empire.</p><p>It is estimated to go for 400,000 to 600,000 Swiss francs.</p><p>"The diamond market at the moment is very, very strong," said Fawcett.</p><p>He said rising demand, supply constraints due to "geopolitical issues" and inflationary pressure on commodities, including precious stones, was pushing the market to highs not seen since its 2013-2014 peak.</p><p>The Russian invasion in Ukraine has had a major impact.</p><p>More than 40 percent of the world's diamonds are mined in Russia, including the famous Alrosa mine, but international markets no longer have access to Russian gems, said Fawcett.</p><p>The supply constraint has created major price hikes and with the sanctions imposed on Moscow following the February 24 invasion, "prices will only continue to increase", he said.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/the-rock-diamond-dazzles-in-geneva/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-rock-white-diamond-could-fetch-20-30-million-or-more-fabrice-coffrini-afp.jpg?id=29769872&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive blast rips through Havana hotel</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/massive-blast-rips-through-havana-hotel/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/a-powerful-explosion-ripped-through-a-hotel-under-refurbishment-in-central-havana-adalberto-roque-afp.jpg?id=29769790&width=600&coordinates=142%2C0%2C0%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Rescuers searched for victims Friday after a powerful explosion ripped through a hotel under refurbishment in central Havana, with no casualties immediately reported.</p><p>Shortly after 11:00 am, a cloud of dust and smoke billowed from the Saratoga Hotel after the blast that ripped off parts of the facade. The cause of the blast was not known.</p><p>AFP reporters witnessed rescuers at the scene going through the debris.</p><p>At least two ambulances and five fire trucks rushed to the hotel, and police cordoned off the area, dispersing people who swarmed to the site after hearing the blast.</p><p>According to the website of the Saratoga Hotel, it is a five star establishment with 96 rooms, two bars, two restaurants, a spa and gym.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/massive-blast-rips-through-havana-hotel/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/a-powerful-explosion-ripped-through-a-hotel-under-refurbishment-in-central-havana-adalberto-roque-afp.jpg?id=29769790&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How ‘Babushka Z’ became the unlikely icon of Russian propaganda</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/how-babushka-z-became-the-unlikely-icon-of-russian-propaganda/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/screenshots-of-messages-celebrating-babushka-z-on-pro-russian-propaganda-accounts-c-graphics-studio-france-medias-monde.jpg?id=29769645&width=600&coordinates=0%2C0%2C354%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Russian soldiers occupying Mariupol unveiled a strange statue in the embattled Ukrainian city on Thursday. The statue, of a Ukrainian peasant woman holding a Soviet flag, is of “Babushka Z” – who appeared in a video recorded by Ukrainian soldiers and has now become the unlikely latest icon of Russian propaganda. </p><p>In recent weeks, the elderly Ukrainian woman – whose image is a throwback to a stereotypical peasant woman of the Soviet era – has become the new face of Kremlin propaganda as well as a star among pro-war Russians. Giant placards depict her waving a Soviet flag in Moscow while postcards of her with the same banner are being sold all over Russia.</p><p>No one calls her by her real name in <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/tag/russia/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Russia</a>, she has simply become “Babushka Z’” or “Babushka (“grandmother” in Russian) of victory”. The “Z” symbol is used by Russian forces taking part in the invasion of Ukraine, often painted on armored vehicles.</p><p>In early April, she was the subject of <a href="https://www.1tv.ru/news/2022-04-07/425829-v_odnoy_iz_dereven_otkazalis_brat_gumanitarnuyu_pomosch_ot_ukrainskih_silovikov" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">several reports</a> on <a href="https://t.me/opersvodki/3067" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Russian television</a>. According to the English-language <a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/05/04/explainer-how-a-ukrainian-pensioner-became-a-pro-war-symbol-in-russia-a77573" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Moscow Times</a>, a Russian artist has made wooden sculptures of her. In Mariupol, the occupying Russian forces <a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/05/05/top-kremlin-official-unveils-pro-war-statue-in-ukraines-mariupol-a77590" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">unveiled the “Babushka Z” statue</a> on May 5 in the presence of Sergei Kiriyenko, Russian President Vladimir Putin’s deputy chief of staff. </p><p>According to Joanna Szostek, an expert in Russian media and political communication at the University of Glasgow, the Babushka story “fits the Russian propaganda narrative perfectly”.</p><h2><strong>‘Babushka’ believes she is welcoming ‘Russian liberators’</strong><strong> </strong></h2><p>Babushka Z first appeared in a strange video recorded in early April by Ukrainian soldiers. The video shows the soldiers approaching a small farm in the Donbas region and an old woman proudly holding the Soviet flag at arm's length. </p><p>Surprised but not dismayed, the Ukrainians give her some food and take the flag from her. She first accepts but then gives it back to them when she understands she is not dealing with the “Russian soldiers who have come to liberate her” but with Ukrainians who, in a supreme insult, are trampling on the flag. </p><p>Since then a second video has been posted on the Telegram app that identifies the woman as Anya and says she lives near Dvorichna, 5 kilometers from the front line. </p><p>The initial video “illustrates the clash of memories that has been weaponized by Putin”, said Jaroslava Barbieri, an expert on Russian relations with former Soviet bloc nations at Birmingham University. </p><p>“On the one hand you see this old woman who regrets the collapse of the Soviet Union and still looks at Russians as liberators. Then you have the opposite view of the Ukrainian soldiers, shocked to see that some Ukrainians could see it this way," Barbieri observed.</p><p>“It's an ideal story for the Kremlin because it has emerged on the grassroots and is a rare example of popular support that fits with Putin's narrative,” said Professor Stephen Hutchings, a Russian media expert at Manchester University. </p><p>Babushka Z lends credence to Putin's outlandish claims that the Russian soldiers have come to “liberate” Ukraine from fascism. </p><h2><strong>A new icon of ‘Mother Russia’?</strong><strong> </strong></h2><p>It is also a godsend for the Russian media. </p><p>“There are a couple of reasons that this particular story and image has been so widely reproduced in Russian state media,” said Dr. Precious Chatterje-Doody, an expert in political communication and international relations at the UK’s Open University.</p><p>“First, Russian TV is now almost wall-to-wall ‘special operation’ coverage. Human interest stories help to make this more engaging. Second, it’s a valuable example for the Kremlin of a positive reception. Most Ukrainians (even in Russian-speaking regions) have not welcomed Russian soldiers but actively resisted them, and state media is promoting this image to try and hide that fact,” she added. </p><p>Babushka Z offers another benefit for the Kremlin, Szostek said: “it’s a more rare example of down-top propaganda as opposed to top-down.”</p><p>The video, which has been authenticated by Ukrainian media, is not a creation of the Russian authorities that was then promoted on social networks by Russian trolls on the Internet.</p><p>“From the beginning the propaganda machine in Moscow has tried to give a bottom-up twist of their messaging, and this is just perfect for them,” Hutchings said. </p><p>What more could one ask for? The Soviet flag is the icing on this propaganda cake. According to Hutchings, it is also important “because of the iconography of the Soviet flag and the old lady which resonate for every Russian who is familiar with the WWII postcard of ‘Mother Russia’”. </p><p>Barbieri agreed that the nostalgic Babushka Z imagery must be extremely pleasing to those at the Kremlin.</p><p>“It's the glorification of an older generation to call the newer generation to repeat the success of the past. Putin is very much into glorifying the Soviet past because it lets him hide that he has no perspectives to offer for the Russian people,” Barbieri said.</p><p>“The fact that it is a Ukrainian woman that incarnates ‘Mother Russia’ shows that it is one people despite being two countries. It resonates with the new narrative of <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/international/3267060-de-ukrainization-is-genocide-biden-was-right-to-sound-the-alarm/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">de-ukrainisation</a> instead of denazification of Ukraine,” Hutchings said. </p><p>“The glorification of a humble woman speaks to the living condition of Russia’s common people that the Kremlin says it represents. It gives the people a sense of meaning while it lets the government hide the kleptocracy,” Barbieri said.</p><p>Babushka Z also comes at the best possible time for Russia. On May 9, the country will hold its annual parade celebrating the Soviet victory over the Nazi regime during World War II – a day filled with pageantry and wartime symbolism. “I would be very surprised if this video is not used during the May 9 celebrations,” Hutchings said.</p><p><em>This article has been translated from the </em><a href="https://www.france24.com/fr/europe/20220505-guerre-en-ukraine-babouchka-z-l-improbable-nouvelle-coqueluche-de-la-propagande-russe" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>original in French</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/how-babushka-z-became-the-unlikely-icon-of-russian-propaganda/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/screenshots-of-messages-celebrating-babushka-z-on-pro-russian-propaganda-accounts-c-graphics-studio-france-medias-monde.jpg?id=29769645&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon denies helping Ukraine sink Moskva</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-denies-helping-ukraine-sink-moskva-2657276752/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-moskva.jpg?id=29769585&width=600&coordinates=151%2C0%2C152%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The Pentagon on Friday denied reports that it helped Ukrainian forces sink the Russian warship Moskva in the Black Sea last month in a stunning setback for Moscow's invasion.</p><p>"We did not provide Ukraine with specific targeting information for the Moskva," Pentagon spokesman John Kirby said in a statement.</p><p>Kirby said the US had "no prior knowledge" of the plan to strike the ship, which sank April 13, leaving a still-unclear number of Russian sailors dead or missing.</p><p>"We were not involved in the Ukrainians’ decision to strike the ship or in the operation they carried out," Kirby said.</p><p>"The Ukrainians have their own intelligence capabilities to track and target Russian naval vessels, as they did in this case," he said.</p><p>US media have reported in recent days that the United States has helped Ukraine identify and target the Moskva as well as Russian generals while they are in the field.</p><h1>Gerasimov targeted?</h1><p>Wary of being seen as too closely involved in Ukraine's war against the Russian invasion, the US military says it shares battlefield intelligence to help Ukrainians defend their country but denies helping them pick targets or carry out attacks.</p><p>Ukraine has been particularly successful in attacking Russian command positions, and, according to reports, came close last week to striking a location near the front lines in the Donbas region where Russia's top general, Valery Gerasimov, was believed to be visiting troops.</p><p>Ukraine's forces may have shelled the location just a few hours after Gerasimov had left, the unconfirmed reports said.</p><p>On Thursday Kirby insisted that reports that the Ukrainians used specific US intelligence to kill several Russian generals were false.</p><p>"We do not provide intelligence on the location of senior military leaders on the battlefield or participate in the targeting decisions of the Ukrainian military," Kirby said.</p><p>He said Ukraine makes its own decisions on whether to target a Russian leader or not.</p><p>"Ukraine combines information that we and other partners provide with the intelligence that they themselves are gathering on the battlefield," he said.</p><p>"Then they make their own decisions, and they take their own actions."</p><h1>Propaganda coup</h1><p>The deaths of the generals and the attack on the Moskva have proven significant propaganda coups for the Kyiv in the war, which began when Russian forces invaded the country on February 24.</p><p>The Moskva, which sailed normally with a crew of around 500, was struck by two Ukrainian anti-ship missiles as it sailed south of Odesa. Still on fire, in sank several hours later on April 14 as rescue vessels attempted to tow it to safety.</p><p> One week later Moscow reported that 396 crew members were rescued and that one was killed and 27 missing. It blamed the loss on a tragic fire onboard, rather than a strike by the Ukrainians.</p><p>Washington is supplying billions of dollars' worth of military equipment and munitions to Ukraine and is training their forces on how to operate them. </p><p>It is also providing Kyiv with information garnered from satellites, electronic surveillance operations and other sources of intelligence.</p><p>But the White House and Pentagon have sought to limit knowledge of the full extent of the US assistance, hoping to avoid provoking Russia into a broader conflict beyond Ukraine's borders.</p><p>Even so, Washington's support for Ukraine has only grown, and become more forthright, since the Russians invaded on February 24.</p><p>At the beginning of the conflict the United States said it wanted only to help Ukraine survive.</p><p>But now Washington says its goal in the war is to debilitate Russia for the long term.</p><p>"We want to see Russia weakened to the degree that it can't do the kinds of things that it has done in invading Ukraine," US Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin said after a visit to Kyiv in late April.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-denies-helping-ukraine-sink-moskva-2657276752/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/the-moskva.jpg?id=29769585&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil deforestation shatters April record</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/brazil-deforestation-shatters-april-record/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/amazon-deforestation.jpg?id=29769442&width=600&coordinates=124%2C0%2C125%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Deforestation in the Brazilian Amazon last month shattered the record for April, destroying more than 1,000 square kilometers of the world's biggest rainforest, nearly double the previous high, according to official figures published Friday.</p><p>The record -- the third in four months -- is the latest damning statistic on the accelerating loss of the Amazon under President Jair Bolsonaro.</p><p>Satellite images show a total area of destroyed forest cover of 1,012.5 square kilometers (391 square miles) from April 1 to 29, with the last day of the month yet to be analyzed, according to the Deter monitoring system run by the national space agency, INPE.</p><p>The area, equivalent to 1,400 football fields, is by far the biggest for April since record-keeping began in 2015.</p><p>Deforestation is usually slower in April, the rainy season in the Amazon. The previous record for the month was 580 square kilometers, set last year -- also under Bolsonaro.</p><p>"This figure is extremely high for this period of the year," Mariana Napolitano, science director at the World Wildlife Fund's Brazil office, said in a statement.</p><p>"It's an alert of the immense pressure the forest is under."</p><p>Experts warn Brazil may have its fourth straight year of decade-high deforestation this year, after also setting monthly records in January and February.</p><p>Since Bolsonaro took office in 2019, average annual deforestation in the Brazilian Amazon has risen more than 75 percent from the previous decade, to an area roughly the size of Qatar.</p><p>"The Bolsonaro administration is abetting deforestation and environmental crime, and what we harvest are these terrible, scary, revolting numbers," Marcio Astrini, head of the Climate Observatory, a coalition of environmental groups, told AFP.</p><p>The far-right president, an ally of the powerful agribusiness industry blamed for driving the destruction, has faced international condemnation over the damage to the Amazon.</p><p>Last week, actor and environmentalist Leonardo DiCaprio urged young Brazilians to vote in October elections in which Bolsonaro is up for re-election.</p><p>"Brazil is home to the Amazon and other ecosystems critical to climate change," he tweeted.</p><p>"What happens there matters to us all and youth voting is key in driving change."</p><p>"Thanks for your support, Leo!" Bolsonaro tweeted back sarcastically.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/brazil-deforestation-shatters-april-record/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/amazon-deforestation.jpg?id=29769442&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Unique in the world': France's Dijon opens gastronomy complex</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/unique-in-the-world-france-s-dijon-opens-gastronomy-complex/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/dijon-hopes-the-new-site-will-attract-one-million-visitors-a-year-jeff-pachoud-afp-file.jpg?id=29769328&width=600&coordinates=0%2C0%2C352%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Devotees of French food and wine can flock to a new temple following the opening Friday of a gastronomy and wine complex in the capital of France's central Burgundy region, Dijon.</p><p>"It's astounding. It's a marriage of gastronomy, wine, culture and education," said former French president Francois Hollande during whose tenure the project was launched.</p><p>"It's not unique in France. It's unique in the world," he added at the inauguration.</p><p>The city famed for its mustard and rolling vineyards hopes to lure one million visitors a year to the site resembling a village with expositions, a culinary school, shops, restaurants and even a cinema.</p><p>"I have no doubt that one million is a completely attainable objective," Socialist Dijon mayor Francois Rebsamen told AFP, adding that Dijon boasted 3.5 million annual visitors before the Covid-19 pandemic hit.</p><p>The project began after UNESCO added the "French gastronomic meal" to its intangible cultural heritage list in 2010.</p><p>The inclusion on the prestigious list sparked the launch of sites in Paris, Lyon, Tours and Dijon designed to showcase different aspects of the country's rich food and wine culture.</p><p>Meals are a big deal in France, where 2,000 books on wine or cooking are published every year.<br/></p><p>The French will typically sit down together to tuck in unlike Americans "who often eat standing next to the kitchen counter" and alone, says Tours University sociologist Jean-Pierre Corbeau.</p><p>The gastronomic meal is "this ritual good food that brings together the French to celebrate the good life together", said European Institute for the History and Cultures of Food founder Francois Chevrier in his book on the Dijon complex.</p><p>-'Experimental kitchen'-</p><p>The massive Dijon site spreads across 6.5 hectares and combines modern structures with buildings with glazed tiles from the mediaeval times.</p><p>"We wanted to enhance the existing heritage while adding contemporary architectural touches to it," architect Anthony Bechu said.</p><p>The overall project cost 250 million euros ($265,000) with the private sector financing 90 percent.</p><p>Visitors can meander through four sections on the history of French meals, baking, Burgundy's vineyards and the art of cooking.</p><p>Once an appetite is worked up, tourists can eat to their heart's content in two restaurants run by triple-starred chef Eric Pras.</p><p>And they can wash the meal down with wine from a cellar that offers "one of the widest selections in the world, with 250 wines by the glass among more than 3,000 references," according to its director Anthony Valla.</p><p>The site also includes a butcher's shop and a bakery, an "experimental kitchen" offering demonstrations and workshops, and a branch of the world-renowned Ferrandi culinary school.</p><p>Such a huge project has raised some eyebrows, especially after the Lyon site closed down only nine months after its inauguration.</p><p>"We learned our lesson from the failure of Lyon, which offered something a little down-market and very expensive," Dijon mayor Rebsamen said.</p><p>The Dijon site includes "a whole cultural and heritage section that is free", he added.</p><p>The French-style meal is in danger because "people think cooking is a waste of time", according to Paris-Sorbonne professor Jean-Robert Pitte.<br/></p><p>Pitte is one of the architects of the campaign that led to the UNESCO inscription, designed to restore "the taste for cooking".</p><p>He believes "eating well is not superfluous, but necessary for health, sociability, the economy and culture".</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/unique-in-the-world-france-s-dijon-opens-gastronomy-complex/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/dijon-hopes-the-new-site-will-attract-one-million-visitors-a-year-jeff-pachoud-afp-file.jpg?id=29769328&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amnesty documents over 60 possible war crimes around Kiev</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/amnesty-documents-over-60-possible-war-crimes-around-kiev/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/ukraine-demands-accountability-for-russian-war-crimes-as-west-prepares-sanctions.jpg?id=29640808&width=600&coordinates=133%2C0%2C133%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"></div><p>Human rights group Amnesty International released a report on Friday accusing Russia of over 60 cases of war crimes around the Ukrainian capital of Kiev.</p>
<p>Labelling the move by Amnesty as "historic," secretary general Agnès Callamard made a presentation in Kiev documenting the allegations.</p>
<p>Amnesty believes more than 40 civilians were killed by airstrikes in Borodyanka and there were 22 cases of unlawful killings in and around Bucha.</p>
<p>Callamard stressed that in her view, the attacks on civilians were deliberate decisions and therefore unacceptable.</p>
<p>Russia invaded Ukraine nearly two and a half months ago. Areas north and north-west of Kiev were under Russian occupation for just under a month before Moscow switched its focus to the east of the country.</p>
<p>According to Ukrainian figures, more than 1,200 civilians have been killed in the Kiev area, about a third of them in Bucha alone.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/amnesty-documents-over-60-possible-war-crimes-around-kiev/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>Rights</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/ukraine-demands-accountability-for-russian-war-crimes-as-west-prepares-sanctions.jpg?id=29640808&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Trump ambassador regrets not pushing back against Giuliani on Ukraine: 'I was a doofus'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/gordon-sondland-2657275826/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/gordon-sondland-and-jared-kushner.jpg?id=29769193&width=600&coordinates=0%2C0%2C350%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Gordon Sondland was briefly a household name after he confirmed during testimony before the House Intelligence Committee in 2019 that former President Donald Trump had insisted on a quid pro quo deal with Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy: Zelenskyy wanted a meeting with Trump and Trump wanted Zelenskyy to announce an investigation of an energy company associated with Joe Biden’s son Hunter. </p><p>Since being fired by Trump, the hotelier has returned to the business that made him wealthy and largely stayed out of the public spotlight.</p><p>But now the former European Union ambassador, like many former Trump advisers, has penned a book about his time in the administration. He recently sat for interviews with <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/2022/05/06/gordon-sondland-trump-quid-pro-quo/" target="_blank">The Washington Post</a> and had this harsh self-assessment of his performance: "I was a doofus."</p><p>Sondland disclosed that he regrets not pushing back against Rudy Giuliani as he attempted to pressure the Ukraine president to help dig up dirt on Hunter Biden's business dealings in the country as part of the effort to win the 2020 presidential against Biden.</p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/supreme-court-leak-2657275664/" target="_self">Evidence that Supreme Court leak came from the right laid out by New York magazine columnist</a></em></strong></p><p>The 64-year-old told the Washington Post that he "was swept along on that continuum while focused solely on one goal: getting Trump and Zelensky together to spark a friendship and strengthen the alliance." He added, “My own mistake was probably buying into the whole Giuliani narrative and allowing a non-governmental actor to interfere in a very ambiguous way with U.S. foreign policy.”</p><p>Sondland is suing the U.S. government for not paying his nearly<strong> </strong>$1.8 million in legal fees related to the impeachment. His memoir, due out in October, is going through a security review. It reportedly doesn't contain any bombshell revelations. The working title is “The Envoy: Mastering the Art of Diplomacy with Trump and the World.”</p><p>“I think he’s sort of the poster child of why donor-ambassadors aren’t a great idea,” Max Bergmann, who worked in the State Department under Barack Obama and is now director of the Europe program for the Center for Strategic and International Studies, told the Washington Post. "It’s not like he’s a bad guy. He seemed like someone who was energetic, which can be rare in this sphere, and wanted to be involved in U.S. foreign policy. But he has no experience, no knowledge of how these things work," and "then gets involved in what was a shakedown of a foreign country."</p><p>“Yes, I’m the quid pro quo guy,” Sondland writes in the memoir, “but you know what? Everything in life is some kind of a quid pro quo.”</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/gordon-sondland-2657275826/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Timothy Evans</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/gordon-sondland-and-jared-kushner.jpg?id=29769193&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine wheat harvest set to drop by third: satellite imagery</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-wheat-harvest-set-to-drop-by-third-satellite-imagery/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/before-the-war-ukraine-accounted-for-about-12-percent-of-the-world-s-wheat-exports-bulent-kilic-afp-file.jpg?id=29768945&width=600&coordinates=115%2C0%2C116%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Ukraine's wheat production is likely to be down by at least a third from last year due to the Russian invasion, a data analysis firm that uses satellite imagery said Friday.'</p><p>Ukraine is a major producer and exporter of wheat, but the invasion has disrupted planting, which is still underway, both due a lack of fuel for equipment and farmers having to deal bombardments and unexploded ordnance.</p><p>French firm Kayrros said near-infrared and infrared imagery allows for determination of crop coverage and can accurately predict wheat production.</p><p>"Production this year is expected to be at least 35 percent lower than last year," analysis of the latest data showed, Kayrros said.</p><p>It forecast that at this stage Ukraine will be capable of producing 21 million tonnes of wheat this year, a drop of 12 million tonnes from 2021, and a 23 percent drop from the average harvest over the past five years.</p><p>"Given that the fighting is ongoing and that a large part of the country’s wheat production comes from areas of eastern Ukraine where the conflict is most intense, the real production figures are likely to be lower than the current crop cover might suggest," the firm added.</p><p>Kayrros analyzed images taken by the US space agency NASA between April 14 and 22, less than two months after the start of the conflict.</p><p>Even if Ukrainian farmers manage to grow and harvest their wheat they face difficulties getting it to market given that Russia has destroyed transportation infrastructure and blockaded the port of Odessa from which most grain was exported.</p><p>Before the war Ukraine accounted for about 12 percent of the world's wheat exports, and the conflict has sent the prices of food commodities soaring.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/ukraine-wheat-harvest-set-to-drop-by-third-satellite-imagery/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/before-the-war-ukraine-accounted-for-about-12-percent-of-the-world-s-wheat-exports-bulent-kilic-afp-file.jpg?id=29768945&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU prepares to slap sanctions on Putin's suspected girlfriend: report</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-sanctions-2657273038/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/alina-kabaeva.jpg?id=29721343&width=600&coordinates=185%2C0%2C185%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>On Friday, CNN <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/06/europe/putins-reputed-girlfriend-alina-kabaeva-eu-sanctions-intl/index.html" target="_blank">reported</a> that Alina Kabaeva, the woman long suspected to be <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/vladimir-putin-oligarchs/" target="_blank">Russian President Vladimir Putin's</a> girlfriend, is now on the European Union's <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/putins-girlfriend-sanctions/" target="_blank">proposed list for sanctions</a>.</p><p>"At this stage names can be taken off or added at member state discretion, an EU Commission source told CNN," reported Luke McGee. "The EU has not officially signed off on the draft proposal but could do so as early as Friday morning at a meeting of EU ambassadors -- currently underway in the EU's headquarters in Brussels, Belgium."</p><p>"Kabaeva, who was born in 1983, was first linked to Putin more than a decade ago, while she was a medal-winning gymnast," said the report. "Putin has denied a relationship with her."</p><p>Although the U.S. and Europe have slapped sanctions on numerous Russian billionaires accused of enriching themselves off state resources with Putin's help — the so-called "oligarchs" — they have until this point held off on going after Kabaeva. A report last month <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/putins-girlfriend-sanctions/" target="_blank">indicated</a> that U.S. officials were worried this would be too personal of an attack on Putin and would complicate diplomacy with the Kremlin.</p><p><strong>IN OTHER NEWS: </strong><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ammon-bundy-idaho-2657275351/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self" title="view post: Cops push back against ‘un-American’ Ammon Bundy's run for governor"><strong>Cops push back against ‘un-American’ Ammon Bundy's run for governor</strong></a></p><p>Other Russians who are being marked for sanctions is Patriarch Kirill of the Russian Orthodox Church, a <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/why-is-russias-church-backing-putins-war-church-state-history-gives-a-clue/" target="_blank">longtime ally of Putin</a> who has used his ecclesiastical position to push Russian propaganda about the invasion of Ukraine, CNN's sources say.</p><p>"The EU has been ratcheting up its economic action against Russia since the start of the war in Ukraine," noted the report. "Most recently, the bloc has <a href="https://cnn.com/2022/05/04/business/eu-russia-oil-ban/index.html" target="_blank">proposed a ban on Russian oil imports</a>, something that would have a major impact on Russia's economy, though Hungary, an EU member state with close links to Putin, is likely to scupper any such plans."</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/russia-sanctions-2657273038/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/alina-kabaeva.jpg?id=29721343&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star architect Foster to help plan Ukraine reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/star-architect-foster-to-help-plan-ukraine-reconstruction/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768839&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="69caa31b15fd64b559103850bfc13ed2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="24f26" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768848&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>GENEVA (Reuters) - Renowned British architect Norman Foster will help plan Ukraine's reconstruction from the devastation caused by Russia's invasion, officials said on Friday while outlining the work of a United Nations task force coordinating the project.</p>
<p>Kharkiv, Ukraine's second-biggest city which has been pounded by Russian bombardment, will be at the vanguard of the campaign, Mayor Ihor Terekhov and Foster said via videolink presentations in Geneva.</p>
<p>"This is an extraordinary opportunity to combine the best, the most loved aspects of a city with the city of the future, which has been described to me very eloquently by the mayor," said Foster, whose works include London's "Gherkin" tower and the modernist HSBC headquarters in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Terekhov said the focus would be on developing unique neighbourhoods and high-tech industrial parks to give the city a new feel.</p>
<p>"About 25% of the housing stock of the city of Kharkiv is now destroyed because the bombings of Kharkiv have not come to an end yet," he said.</p>
<p>Infrastructure sites, administrative buildings, schools and kindergartens will also have to be rebuilt.</p>
<p>Work started last month on Kharkiv's master plan, which officials said could be a blueprint for other Ukrainian cities.</p>
<p>Russia's invasion of Ukraine, now in its 11th week, has killed thousands of people, displaced more than 11 million and flattened towns and villages.</p>
<p>Moscow calls its actions in Ukraine a "special operation" to disarm Ukraine and protect it from fascists. Kyiv and its Western backers say this is a false pretext to wage an unprovoked war of aggression.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Michael Shields; Editing by Gareth Jones)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="64bab3879adb4f7525b787d0c85ffdfc" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="6a518" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768851&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 12:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/star-architect-foster-to-help-plan-ukraine-reconstruction/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768839&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky to join G7 summit on Sunday to brief leaders on Ukraine war</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/zelensky-to-join-g7-summit-on-sunday-to-brief-leaders-on-ukraine-war/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768228&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="174fed025eedf7a35a5ac1126edddd81" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="d7299" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768232&width=980"/><figcaption>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky participates in the Wall Street Journal CEO Council Summit via video link from the situation room. -/Ukraine Presidency via ZUMA Press Wire Service/dpa</figcaption></figure></div><p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky is set to join the leaders of the G7 to discuss the situation in Ukraine at an online conference to be held on Sunday, according to a spokesperson for the German government on Friday.</p>
<p>The meeting was taking place on a historic day, the spokesperson said, as nations around the world celebrate the end of World War II in Europe and the end of National Socialism on May 8.</p>
<p>The G7 group includes Britain, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Canada and the US. Germany currently holds the presidency.</p>
<p>In addition to the crisis in Ukraine, other topics are also likely to be discussed, though no further details - including the exact timing of the meeting - were immediately made available.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz was also scheduled to give a televised speech focusing on the war in Ukraine to mark the anniversary of the end of World War II on Sunday, according to his spokesperson.</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 11:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/zelensky-to-join-g7-summit-on-sunday-to-brief-leaders-on-ukraine-war/</guid>
      <category>Russia</category>
      <category>En</category>
      <dc:creator>DPA</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29768228&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separatists take down Ukrainian road signs in Mariupol</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/separatists-take-down-ukrainian-road-signs-in-mariupol/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-forces-have-for-weeks-sought-to-wrest-full-control-over-mariupol-donetsk-people-republic-ministry-of-transport-afp.jpg?id=29768131&width=600&coordinates=159%2C0%2C158%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Moscow-backed separatists in southeastern Ukraine said they had taken down traffic signs spelling out the name of the besieged city of Mariupol in Ukrainian and English and replaced them with Russian ones.</p><p>"Updated road signs have been set up at the entrance to Mariupol," the transportation ministry of the self-proclaimed Donetsk People's Republic said in a statement on Thursday.</p><p>The ministry released pictures of municipal workers in orange vests carrying away a road sign saying Mariupol in Ukrainian and English and installing a similar sign in Russian.</p><p>"Work to change road signs across liberated territory will continue," the statement said, adding that similar work had been carried out in smaller settlements.</p><p>Mariupol is one of the most battered cities in Ukraine and Russian forces have for weeks sought to wrest full control.</p><p>On Thursday, Sergei Kirienko, first deputy chief of President Vladimir Putin's administration, visited the now-flattened city and other "liberated territories," a separatist leader said on social media.</p><p>Locals wanted to see proof that "Russia has come back here forever," wrote Denis Pushilin, head of Ukraine's breakaway region of Donetsk.</p><p>Seizing the strategically located port city would allow Moscow to create a land bridge between the separatist pro-Russian regions in eastern Ukraine and Crimea, which it annexed in 2014.</p><p>Mariupol's sprawling Azovstal steel plant has become the last pocket of resistance, with Ukrainian troops staging a last stand there.</p><p>Hundreds of civilians have been holed up for weeks under heavy bombardment, many taking shelter in the plant's Soviet-era underground tunnels.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 11:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/separatists-take-down-ukrainian-road-signs-in-mariupol/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-forces-have-for-weeks-sought-to-wrest-full-control-over-mariupol-donetsk-people-republic-ministry-of-transport-afp.jpg?id=29768131&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documents found by Fiji on superyacht implicate its Russian owner: FBI</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/documents-found-by-fiji-on-superyacht-implicate-its-russian-owner-fbi/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767219&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="ec9123e074ce8f26f8e0375e96046024" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="50fc4" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767220&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Kirsty Needham</p>
<p>SYDNEY (Reuters) -Fiji authorities searching a yacht they seized on behalf of the United States as it presses Russia over the invasion of Ukraine have found documents implicating its suspected owner, Russian oligarch Suleiman Kerimov, in breaking U.S. law, the FBI said.</p>
<p>The Amadea arrived in Fiji on April 13, after an 18-day voyage from Mexico, and has since been the focus of a U.S. bid to seize it as part of U.S. sanctions against Russia.</p>
<p>Fiji police and FBI agents seized the Amadea at a wharf on Thursday, two days after a Fiji court granted a U.S. warrant that linked it to money laundering.</p>
<p>Fiji's High Court on Friday refused a stay application by the vessel's registered owner, Millemarin Investments, to stop U.S. authorities removing it from Fiji, Fiji's public prosecutor said in a statement.</p>
<p>The $300 million superyacht had been handed over to U.S. authorities, it said.</p>
<p>The FBI said in an affidavit attached to the U.S. seizure warrant that Fiji authorities had found documents on the Amadea showing breaches of U.S. law because Kerimov was sanctioned by the United States in 2018.</p>
<p>"There is probable cause to believe that Kerimov and those acting on his behalf and for his benefit caused U.S. dollar transactions for the operation and maintenance of the Amadea to be sent through U.S. financial institutions, after a time which Kerimov was designated by the Treasury Department," the FBI said.</p>
<p>The vessel had running costs of $25 million to $30 million, it said.</p>
<p>Lawyers for its registered owner, Cayman Islands company Millemarin Investments, have denied it is owned by Kerimov. The vessel's lawyer, Feizal Haniff, declined to comment to Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>The U.S. alleges Kerimov has beneficially owned the Amadea since August 2021 but evidence for this claim was redacted in the warrant.</p>
<p>The FBI said the Amadea had tried to avoid being seized "almost immediately" after Russian troops entered Ukraine.</p>
<p>"Amadea turned off its automated information systems (AIS) on February 24, 2022, almost immediately after the start of the Russian invasion of Ukraine," the FBI said.</p>
<p>Russia calls its actions in Ukraine a "special operation" to disarm Ukraine and protect it from fascists. Ukraine and the West say the fascist allegation is baseless and that the war is an unprovoked act of aggression.</p>
<p>The vessel's paperwork showed the next destination would be the Philippines but the FBI believed it was headed to the Russian Pacific port of Vladivostok.</p>
<p>Many Russian oligarchs have attempted to move their yachts to Russia to escape U.S. sanctions since March, the FBI said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Justice Department's Taskforce KleptoCapture has focused on seizing yachts and other luxury assets to put the finances of Russian oligarchs under strain in a bid to pressure Russian President Vladimir Putin over the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>FBI Director Christopher Wray, commenting on the seizure of the Amadea in Fiji, said in a statement: "The FBI, along with our international partners, will continue to seek out those individuals who contribute to the advancement of Russia's malign activities and ensure they are brought to justice, regardless of where, or how, they attempt to hide."</p>
<p>(Reporting by Kirsty Needham;Editing by Robert Birsel)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 11:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/documents-found-by-fiji-on-superyacht-implicate-its-russian-owner-fbi/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilots say new Mexico City airport causing safety issues</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pilots-say-new-mexico-city-airport-causing-safety-issues/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/felipe-angeles-international-airport-located-north-of-mexico-city-is-one-of-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-s-flagship-projects-rodrigo-arangua-afp-file.jpg?id=29768100&width=600&coordinates=101%2C0%2C102%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The opening of a second international airport for Mexico City has resulted in safety incidents including warnings that aircraft were in danger of flying into the ground, a pilot association said.</p><p>Air traffic controllers appear to have received little training and support on how to operate the new configuration, the International Federation of Air Line Pilots' Associations (IFALPA) said in a safety bulletin dated May 4.</p><p>The organization said it had "been made aware of several incidents involving aircraft" at Mexico City International Airport, since Felipe Angeles International Airport opened north of the capital on March 21.</p><p>They included planes arriving "with low fuel states due to unplanned holding, diversions for excessive delays, and significant GPWS (ground proximity warning system) alerts," it said.</p><p>"One crew almost had a controlled flight into terrain," it added.</p><p>The International Air Transport Association defines such an incident as "an in-flight collision with terrain, water, or obstacle without indication of loss of control."</p><p>IFALPA urged crews to consider carrying additional fuel in case they have to wait for permission to land or divert to another airport, and to exercise heightened terrain situational awareness.</p><p>Experts have previously highlighted the challenges of operating two airports in a city surrounded by mountains and at an altitude of more than 2,200 meters (around 7,300 feet) above sea level.</p><p>So far airlines are operating only a small number of daily flights from Felipe Angeles International Airport, a flagship project of President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador built at a military air base north of the capital.</p><p>The existing Mexico City International Airport, also known as Benito Juarez, is one of the busiest airports in Latin America.</p><p>It handled a record 50.3 million passengers in 2019 before the Covid-19 pandemic.</p><p>Lopez Obrador announced this week a plan to reduce arrivals and departures at Benito Juarez and transfer more operations to Felipe Angeles.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 11:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pilots-say-new-mexico-city-airport-causing-safety-issues/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/felipe-angeles-international-airport-located-north-of-mexico-city-is-one-of-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-s-flagship-projects-rodrigo-arangua-afp-file.jpg?id=29768100&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dirty tricks allegations mar last days of Philippine election campaign</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/dirty-tricks-allegations-mar-last-days-of-philippine-election-campaign/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/former-philippine-senator-ferdinand-bongbong-marcos-jr-holds-a-huge-lead-over-his-nearest-rival-and-nemesis-leni-robredo-jam-sta-rosa-afp-file.jpg?id=28882647&width=600&coordinates=194%2C0%2C194%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>Philippine election rivals traded allegations of dirty tricks and vote-rigging Friday, in the final stretch of an acerbic campaign that is tipped to bring the son of former dictator Ferdinand Marcos to power.</p><p>After months of fierce campaigning marked by relentless misinformation and an online whitewashing of the country's violent history, rivals Ferdinand Marcos Jr and Leni Robredo implicated each other in underhand tactics.</p><p>Marcos Jr -- the son the late dictator and notoriously kleptocratic first lady Imelda Marcos -- is predicted to win Monday's poll by a landslide.</p><p>The Marcos campaign on Friday urged supporters to "protect their votes" against unspecified attempts at vote-rigging.</p><p>"We've already won!" Marcos Jr said. "Just make sure you guard the votes on Monday -- don't sleep... we know that when we sleep, a lot of undesirable things happen."</p><p>The Marcos campaign also accused Robredo of being "toxic, divisive and acrimonious" and having "associated themselves" with shadowy political groups.</p><p>Robredo has campaigned on a promise to clean up the Philippines' chronically corrupt politics.</p><p>The 57-year-old lawyer, and current vice president, has attracted fevered support from progressive young Filipinos.</p><p>Despite her deficit in opinion polls, few are ready to completely rule her out, as febrile rumours swirl about the accuracy of polls that currently put her on 23 percent of the vote versus Marcos' 56 percent.</p><p>With all still to play for, her campaign took legal action on Friday to bat back potentially damaging rumours that she is in league with the Communist Party.</p><p>Unproven allegations that party founder Jose Maria Sison, who lives in exile in the Netherlands, was advising her campaign resurfaced this week in Marcos-allied media.</p><p>In a complaint affidavit filed with the prosecutor's office Robredo's spokesman called the allegations "fabricated" and "fictitious".</p><h2>Echoes of the dictator</h2><p>Despite a lack of evidence, the allegations have circulated widely on Facebook, which is extremely popular in the Philippines, gaining hundreds of thousands of interactions.</p><p>Communist rebels have waged a decades-long insurgency in the country.</p><p>Red-tagging -- accusing someone of being a communist sympathizer -- has intensified under President Rodrigo Duterte and has resulted in the deaths of many activists, journalists and lawyers.</p><p>The allegations against Robredo carry echoes of the elder Ferdinand Marcos's tactics of discrediting enemies, justifying his dictatorial rule and retaining US Cold War support by playing up the specter of a looming Red Peril that was hell-bent on taking over the country.<br/></p><p>For much of the campaign, Marcos Jr has eschewed detailed policy pronouncements, instead framing himself as uniquely qualified to "unify" the nation.</p><p>He also portrayed his father's rule -- which saw widespread human rights abuses, rampant corruption, international opprobrium and the cratering of the Philippine economy -- as a gilded age.</p><p>Behind the scenes, he has built a potent coalition of the country's ruling families who can deliver blocks of votes on mass.</p><p>Marcos' running mate is Sarah Duterte, the daughter of the outgoing president, who has strong domestic support for his unvarnished political style and a bloody drug war that rights groups estimate has killed tens of thousands in extrajudicial executions.</p><p>The duo's campaign on Friday promised to reopen the economy after Covid-19 lockdowns, invest in infrastructure and continue Rodrigo Duterte's "campaign against illegal drugs and criminality" which is subject to an investigation by the International Criminal Court.</p><p>Saturday will see both sides hold enormous rallies in Manila -- with hundreds of thousands projected to gather just a few kilometers (miles) apart to cheer their political idols and enjoy a barrage of Pinoy pop.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/dirty-tricks-allegations-mar-last-days-of-philippine-election-campaign/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/former-philippine-senator-ferdinand-bongbong-marcos-jr-holds-a-huge-lead-over-his-nearest-rival-and-nemesis-leni-robredo-jam-sta-rosa-afp-file.jpg?id=28882647&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon denies helping Ukraine 'target' Russian generals</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-denies-helping-ukraine-target-russian-generals/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-chief-of-the-general-staff-general-valery-gerasimov-l-pictured-with-defence-minister-sergei-shoigu-was-reportedly-targeted-by-an-unsuccessful-ukrainian-strike-last-week-as-he-visited-the-war-torn-donbas-region-alexey-nikolsky-sputnik-afp.jpg?id=29768037&width=600&coordinates=254%2C0%2C30%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The US Defense Department denied Thursday that it provided intelligence on the locations of Russian generals on the battlefield so that Ukrainian forces could kill them.</p><p>Reacting to an explosive New York Times report on US support for Ukraine's military, Pentagon Spokesman John Kirby said it was true that the United States supplies Kyiv's forces with military intelligence "to help Ukrainians defend their country."</p><p>"We do not provide intelligence on the location of senior military leaders on the battlefield or participate in the targeting decisions of the Ukrainian military," Kirby said.</p><p>In a separate revelation, US media reported later Thursday that the United States had shared intelligence that helped Ukraine sink the Russian warship Moskva last month, in a huge blow to President Vladimir Putin.</p><p>However a US official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told AFP that the United States does not "provide specific targeting information on ships."</p><p>"We do provide a range of intelligence to help the Ukrainians understand the threat posed by Russian ships in the Black Sea and to help them prepare to defend against potential sea-based assaults," the official said.</p><p>In a story first published by NBC, anonymous officials said Ukraine asked Washington about a ship sailing in the Black Sea, whose location the United States helped confirm, in addition to identifying it as the Moskva.</p><p>However, the United States did not know that Ukraine would target the flagship vessel, the officials cited by NBC said.</p><p>Ukraine has been particularly successful in attacking Russian command positions, and, according to reports, came close last week to striking a location near the front lines in the Donbas region where Russia's top general, Valery Gerasimov, was believed to be visiting troops.</p><p>Ukraine forces may have shelled the location just a few hours after Gerasimov had left, the unconfirmed reports said.</p><h2>'They make their own decisions'</h2><p>The New York Times article that Kirby refuted said that of the approximately dozen Russian generals killed by Ukrainian forces, "many" had been targeted with the help of US intelligence.</p><p>The newspaper said the United States had provided details on the Russian military's mobile headquarters, which frequently change location.</p><p>It also reported that Ukrainian forces used that information in tandem with their own to conduct attacks on senior Russian officers.</p><p>Kirby said Ukraine makes its own decisions on whether to target a Russian leader or not.</p><p>"Ukraine combines information that we and other partners provide with the intelligence that they themselves are gathering on the battlefield," he said.</p><p>"Then they make their own decisions, and they take their own actions."</p><p>The White House National Security Council slammed the New York Times report as "irresponsible."</p><p>"The United States provides battlefield intelligence to help the Ukrainians defend their country," NSC spokesperson Adrienne Watson said.</p><p>"We do not provide intelligence with the intent to kill Russian generals."</p><p>Washington is supplying billions of dollars' worth of military equipment and munitions to Ukraine and is training their forces on how to operate them.</p><p>It is also providing Kyiv with information garnered from satellites, electronic surveillance operations and other sources of intelligence.</p><p>But the White House and Pentagon have sought to limit knowledge of the full extent of the US assistance, hoping to avoid provoking Russia into a broader conflict beyond Ukraine's borders.</p><p>Even so, Washington's support for Ukraine has only grown, and become more forthright, since the Russians invaded on February 24.</p><p>At the beginning of the conflict the United States said it wanted only to help Ukraine survive.</p><p>But now Washington says its goal in the war is to debilitate Russia for the long term.</p><p>"We want to see Russia weakened to the degree that it can't do the kinds of things that it has done in invading Ukraine," US Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin said after a visit to Kyiv in late April.</p><p>© 2022 AFP</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 10:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/pentagon-denies-helping-ukraine-target-russian-generals/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/russian-chief-of-the-general-staff-general-valery-gerasimov-l-pictured-with-defence-minister-sergei-shoigu-was-reportedly-targeted-by-an-unsuccessful-ukrainian-strike-last-week-as-he-visited-the-war-torn-donbas-region-alexey-nikolsky-sputnik-afp.jpg?id=29768037&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel searches for Palestinians suspected of killing 3 in attack</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-searches-for-palestinians-suspected-of-3-in/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767954&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="222d514c9c0ae3274a4e1efe41b3ad9b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="061bf" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767959&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>JERUSALEM (Reuters) - Israeli security forces launched a massive manhunt on Friday for two Palestinians suspected of killing three people in an attack in a central Israeli city, police said.</p>
<p>The attack on Thursday night, Israel's Independence Day, is the latest in a recent upsurge of Israeli-Palestinian violence that has raised fears of a slide back to wider conflict.</p>
<p>"We will get our hands on the terrorists and their supportive environment, and they will pay the price," Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett said after the attack in the city of Elad, about 15 km (9 miles) from Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Witnesses and emergency responders said the attackers used axes. Four other people were seriously injured, medics said.</p>
<p>Police identified the assailants as two Palestinians from the Jenin area of the Israeli-occupied West Bank and said they likely fled the scene in a car. Police set up roadblocks, deployed a helicopter and requested the public's help in finding the suspects.</p>
<p>Israeli Defense Minister Benny Gantz extended a closure on the West Bank and Gaza, imposed ahead of the national holiday to prevent Palestinians from entering Israel, until Sunday.</p>
<p>U.S Secretary of State Antony Blinken in a statement on Thursday condemned the "horrific attack targeting innocent men and women."</p>
<p>Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas also condemned the attack and said "the killing of Palestinian and Israeli civilians will only lead to more deterioration," the Palestinian news agency WAFA reported.</p>
<p>Since March, Palestinians and members of Israel's Arab minority have killed 18 people, including three police officers and a security guard, in attacks in Israel and the West Bank that have mostly targeted civilians.</p>
<p>Israel has responded with arrest raids in Palestinian towns and villages which have often sparked clashes and brought the number of Palestinians killed by Israeli forces since the beginning of the year to at least 40.</p>
<p>The casualties include armed members of militant groups, lone assailants and bystanders.</p>
<p>Hamas, the Islamist Palestinian group that controls Gaza, praised the Elad stabbing but did not claim responsibility. It said the attack was a response to Israeli actions at Al-Aqsa Mosque compound in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Over the past month, Palestinians and Israeli police have repeatedly clashed at the compound, one of the most sensitive sites in the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p>
<p>Palestinians and Jordan, the custodian of the site that is the third-holiest in Islam, accuse Israel of not doing enough to enforce a long-standing ban on non-Muslim prayer there, which Israel denies. The compound is Judaism’s holiest site and the vestige of two ancient Jewish temples.</p>
<p>Israel captured the West Bank, Gaza and East Jerusalem in a 1967 Middle East War. Palestinians seek these territories for a future state.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Ammar Awad, Rami Amichay, Ari Rabinovitch, Nidal al-Mughrabi and Ali Sawafta; Editing by Ghaida Ghantous, William Maclean)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 10:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/israel-searches-for-palestinians-suspected-of-3-in/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767954&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northern Ireland poised for watershed election result as counting begins</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/northern-ireland-poised-for-watershed-election-result-as-counting-begins/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767580&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Amanda Ferguson BELFAST (Reuters) - Sinn Fein sought to become the first Irish nationalist party to win the most seats in British-ruled Northern Ireland on Friday as counting began in an election that could mark an historic political shift. A Sinn Fein triumph would be a victory for a party wanting Northern Ireland to leave the United Kingdom 24 years after the Good Friday peace accord that ended three decades of sectarian bloodshed between those seeking unity with Ireland and those wanting to remain part of the UK. Though a poll that could lead to unity with the neighbouring Republic of Ir...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 08:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/northern-ireland-poised-for-watershed-election-result-as-counting-begins/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767580&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French left-wing parties seal coalition deal to take on Macron</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/french-left-wing-parties-seal-coalition-deal-to-take-on-macron/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767233&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b1b164ea8d3629a514fc7398f6056a43" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5f48b" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767234&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>PARIS (Reuters) - France's Socialist Party on Friday sealed a coalition deal with the hard-left La France Insoumise (LFI) party to run together in June's parliamentary elections to try to deprive newly re-elected President Emmanuel Macron of a majority.</p>
<p>"From now on, we are going to campaign together," said Socialist Party leader Olivier Faure.</p>
<p>The coalition pact, which the French Greens and Communists approved earlier this week, will be the first time the broader left wing of French politics has united in 20 years - but with the eurosceptic LFI in the driving seat this time around.</p>
<p>Parties on both the left and right wings of France's political spectrum are eyeing alliances to try to beat Macron's party - which has been renamed Renaissance - in the June 12 and June 19 votes for the lower house of France's parliament.</p>
<p>Macron won a second presidential mandate last month, but he will need a majority in parliament if he is to push through policies including raising the retirement age to 65 from 62 currently, opposed by both the left and right.</p>
<p>The left-wing bloc's alliance has taken shape under the leadership of LFI's firebrand chief Jean-Luc Melenchon, who narrowly missed out on making it to the final round of the French presidential election run-off vote last month.</p>
<p>Melenchon came third with around 22% of votes in the first round of the election, just behind far-right candidate Marine Le Pen. The Socialists' presidential candidate, Anne Hidalgo, only claimed around 1.7% of votes.</p>
<p>(Reporting by Camille Raynaud and Sudip Kar-Gupta; Editing by Kenneth Maxwell)</p>
</div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 05:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/french-left-wing-parties-seal-coalition-deal-to-take-on-macron/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767233&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boris Johnson's UK party suffers early losses in local elections — key tests for Conservatives to come</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/british-pm-johnson-s-conservatives-suffer-early-losses-in-local-elections-key-tests-to-come/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767074&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>
		 Early English local election results showed Boris Johnson's Conservatives suffered early losses in a ballot held against the backdrop of a cost-of-living crisis and fines imposed on the Prime Minister for breaking his own COVID-19 lockdown rules.
	</p><p>
		Early results showed the Conservative Party had lost 53 council seats. The main opposition Labour Party had gained 1 seat and the Liberal Democrats 27 seats.
	</p><p>
		The overall tally due later on Friday will offer the most important snapshot of public opinion since Johnson won the Conservative Party's biggest majority in more than 30 years in the 2019 general election.
	</p><p>
		The ballot is the first electoral test for Johnson since he became the first British leader in living memory to have broken the law while in office. He was fined last month for attending a birthday gathering in his office in 2020, contravening social distancing rules then in place to curb COVID's spread.
	</p><p>
		"These results are confirming that the Conservatives have suffered something of a rebuff from the electorate," said John Curtice, a professor of politics at the University of Strathclyde.
	</p><p>
		Votes held on Thursday will decide almost 7,000 council seats, including all those in London, Scotland and Wales, and a third of the seats in most of the rest of England.
	</p><p>
		The night's most closely watched results in London's 32 boroughs had yet to be fully declared, but some initial counts showed Labour was gaining in some areas in the capital.
	</p><p>
		Partial results showed Johnson's party could lose control of Wandsworth borough, its flagship council in London.
	</p><p>
		(Reporting by Andrew MacAskill; Editing by Kenneth Maxwell)
	</p><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 02:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/british-pm-johnson-s-conservatives-suffer-early-losses-in-local-elections-key-tests-to-come/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29767074&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin is weaponizing disinformation to break Ukraine -- here's how</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-disinformation/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-spokesperson-denies-rumors-of-fatherhood-and-health-issues.jpg?id=24484880&width=600&coordinates=135%2C0%2C135%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>On Thursday, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/05/opinion/russia-ukraine-propaganda.html" target="_blank">writing</a> for <em>The New York Times</em>, the paper's former Moscow bureau chief Serge Schmemann outlined how Vladimir Putin is trying to use disinformation and propaganda to undermine Ukrainian society — and win his war against the country.</p><p>In many ways, argued Schmemman, the West has learned from the "active measures" campaigns by Russia — such as <a href="https://time.com/5573537/mueller-report-russia-election-interference/" target="_blank">interference in the 2016 U.S. presidential election</a> — and worked to combat false information in real time. But that doesn't mean Russia's disinformation machine has been defeated.</p><p>"In these first information battles, the Americans and Ukrainians showed that they had learned the lessons of 2014, when Russia had the upper hand in propaganda," wrote Schmemann. "But the information war, like the physical war, is far from decided. Ten weeks into the war, many Russians seem to accept Mr. Putin’s narrative. Around the world, many countries remain on the sidelines or, like China, are on Russia’s side. While Washington’s public comments have served to bolster the Ukrainians and rally their allies, some of those comments have played directly into Mr. Putin’s claims of a malign America determined to neuter Russia, as when President Biden said of Mr. Putin, 'This man cannot remain in power,' and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin declared that America’s goal is a 'weakened' Russia."</p><p>Examples of the disinformation, wrote Schmemann, include Russia's ongoing lie that the Ukraine war is simply a "special operation" to <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/factcheck/2022/03/30/fact-check-why-putins-claims-justifying-war-ukraine-baseless/7089270001/" target="_blank">eradicate neo-Nazis</a> and liberate so-called "independent republics" declared by Kremlin-backed separatist forces, with the Russian orthodox patriarch declaring that "we broke the back of fascism."</p><p>"The info war has also reached Asia, Africa and South America, where Russia has mobilized diplomats and state-controlled media like the global RT network to press its case," wrote Schmemann. "The goal isn’t necessarily to win support, but to keep unaligned countries on the sidelines. While some countries, most notably China, have taken Russia’s side, others, like India, have avoided antagonizing Russia so as not to lose Russian military or energy contracts."</p><p>Ultimately, he concluded, the war to defend the truth is only going to get harder.</p><p>"As the war enters a new phase, as the images and horrors become familiar and the costs rise, it will become ever more difficult for the Biden administration and for Mr. Zelensky to sustain their early lead in the information war," concluded Schmemann. That makes it all the more imperative for the West to press the message that this is not a war Ukraine chose and that the cost of allowing Mr. Putin to have his way in Ukraine would be far higher than the sacrifices required to block him."</p><p>You can read more <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/05/opinion/russia-ukraine-propaganda.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-disinformation/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Matthew Chapman</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-spokesperson-denies-rumors-of-fatherhood-and-health-issues.jpg?id=24484880&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch HBO’s new trailer for 'Game of Thrones' Prequel 'House of the Dragon'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/watch-hbos-new-trailer-for-game-of-thrones-prequel-house-of-the-dragon/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766244&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Carl Caminetti On Thursday, May 5, HBO got fans of its breakthrough fantasy epic Game of Thrones looking forward to the end of August with the release of a new trailer for the network’s forthcoming prequel House of the Dragon. Though HBO previously dropped a teaser for the show back in October, the fresh look at Westeros offers more details about what to expect from the spinoff series when it premieres on August 21. With each episode estimated to cost around $20 million, House of the Dragon has big boots to fill if it hopes to live up to GoT, which won 59 Emmys over eight seasons before wra...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/watch-hbos-new-trailer-for-game-of-thrones-prequel-house-of-the-dragon/</guid>
      <dc:creator>InsideHook</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766244&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIA chief told Bolsonaro government not to mess with Brazil election: sources</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/exclusive-cia-chief-told-bolsonaro-government-not-to-mess-with-brazil-election-sources-say/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766507&width=980"/><br/><br/><div class="nordot-body"><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="f00ed1ba41b26792dd941abb4d980c3b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="80926" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766512&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><p>By Gabriel Stargardter and Matt Spetalnick</p>
<p>RIO DE JANEIRO/WASHINGTON (Reuters) -The U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) director last year told senior Brazilian officials that President Jair Bolsonaro should stop casting doubt on his country's voting system ahead of the October election, sources told Reuters.</p>
<p>The previously unreported comments by CIA Director William Burns came in an intimate, closed-door meeting in July, according to two people familiar with the matter, who spoke on condition of anonymity. Burns was, and remains, the most senior U.S. official to meet in Brasilia with Bolsonaro's right-wing government since the election of U.S. President Joe Biden.</p>
<p>A third person in Washington familiar with the matter confirmed that a delegation led by Burns had told top Bolsonaro aides the president should stop undermining confidence in Brazil's voting system. That source was not certain whether the CIA director himself had voiced the message.</p>
<p>The CIA declined to comment. Brazil's Institutional Security Cabinet (GSI), which is part of the president's office and led by National Security Adviser Augusto Heleno, said in a statement that the Burns meeting had been publicly announced.</p>
<p>"The matters dealt with in intelligence meetings are confidential," it said. "The GSI does not receive messages from any country in the world, nor does it transmit them."</p>
<p>Later, in a weekly social media address, Bolsonaro and Heleno denied such a message had been delivered.</p>
<p>"That conversation about elections never happened," Heleno said.</p>
<p>Burns arrived in Brasilia six months after the Jan. 6 assault on the Capitol following former U.S. President Donald Trump's election loss.</p>
<p>Bolsonaro, a far-right nationalist who idolizes Trump, has echoed the former U.S. leader's baseless allegations of fraud in the 2020 U.S. election. He has also cast similar doubts about Brazil's electronic voting system, calling it liable to fraud, without providing evidence.</p>
<p>That has raised fears among his opponents that Bolsonaro, who is trailing leftist former President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva in opinion polls, is sowing doubts so he can follow Trump's example, rejecting any loss in the Oct. 2 vote.</p>
<p>On multiple occasions, Bolsonaro has floated the idea of not accepting the results, and has repeatedly attacked the country's federal electoral court. Last week, in his latest broadside, Bolsonaro, a former army captain, suggested the military should conduct its own parallel ballot count alongside the court.</p>
<p>Two of the sources warned of a potential institutional crisis if Bolsonaro were to lose by a narrow margin, with scrutiny focused on the role of Brazil's armed forces, which ruled the country during a 1964-85 military government that Bolsonaro celebrates.</p>
<p>During his unannounced trip, Burns, a career diplomat nominated by Biden last year, met at the presidential palace with Bolsonaro and two senior intelligence aides - Heleno and Alexandre Ramagem, then-head of Brazilian intelligence agency Abin. Both were Bolsonaro appointees.</p>
<p>Burns also dined at the U.S. ambassador's residence with Heleno and Bolsonaro's then-Chief of Staff Luiz Eduardo Ramos, both former generals. Brazil's military has historically enjoyed close ties with the CIA and other U.S. intelligence services.</p>
<p>At the dinner, according to one of the sources, Heleno and Ramos sought to dismiss the significance of Bolsonaro's repeated allegations of voter fraud. In response, the source said, Burns told them that the democratic process was sacred, and that Bolsonaro should not be talking in that way.</p>
<p>"Burns was making it clear that elections were not an issue that they should mess with," said the source, who was not authorized to speak publicly. "It wasn't a lecture, it was a conversation."</p>
<p>In a letter dated Sept. 2, sent by Heleno to Brazilian lawmaker Luciano Bivar, the national security adviser said he was present at the dinner hosted by the U.S. ambassador. In the letter, posted on the website of the lower house of Congress, Heleno said it was a "courtesy event and, naturally, took place with informal conversations on topics of mutual interest between Brazil and the United States of America."</p>
<p>BIDEN ENVOY</p>
<p>It is unusual for CIA directors to deliver political messages, the sources said. But Biden has empowered Burns, one of the most experienced U.S. diplomats, to be a low-profile mouthpiece for the White House.</p>
<p>Last month, for example, Burns said in a public address that in November, four months after visiting Brasilia, Biden dispatched him to Moscow "to convey directly to (Russian President Vladimir) Putin and several of his closest advisers the depths of our concern about his planning for war, and the consequences for Russia" if they proceeded.</p>
<p>The tenor of his comments in Brasilia was reinforced the month after his trip, when U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan visited Bolsonaro and raised similar concerns about undermining trust in elections. However, the Burns delegation's message was stronger than Sullivan's, the Washington-based source said, without elaborating.</p>
<p>"It is important that Brazilians have confidence in their electoral systems," a U.S. State Department official said in a statement when asked for comment, adding that the United States is confident of Brazil's institutions, including free, fair and transparent elections.</p>
<p>On Saturday, however, in a fresh sign of disquiet among some of Washington's foreign policy establishment, the most recent U.S. consul in Rio wrote in a Brazilian newspaper that the United States should make it clear to Bolsonaro that any effort to undermine elections would trigger multilateral sanctions.</p>
<p>Biden and Bolsonaro have yet to speak.</p>
<p>During the 2020 U.S. presidential campaign, the two clashed over Bolsonaro's environmental record, and he was one of the last world leaders to recognize Biden's victory over Trump.</p>
<p>Officials in Washington have sought to improve ties with Brasilia in recent weeks, and the presidents of the two largest nations in the Western Hemisphere may soon meet in person if Bolsonaro attends June's Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>(Writing by Gabriel StargardterAdditional reporting by Jonathan Landay and Ricardo BritoEditing by Brad Haynes and Rosalba O'Brien)</p>
<div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="db8a4210b7b19279f15d6415711c2594" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0e86a" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766514&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div><div class="nordot-image"><figure><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a6f2073985d09a756089744159ecc4c9" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9b075" loading="lazy" src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766518&width=980"/><figcaption></figcaption></figure></div></div><script src="https://static.solutionshindsight.net/teju-webclient/hindsight-webclient.min.js"></script>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/exclusive-cia-chief-told-bolsonaro-government-not-to-mess-with-brazil-election-sources-say/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766507&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battles rage at Ukrainian plant as U.N. rushes to evacuate civilians</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/battles-rage-at-ukrainian-plant-as-u-n-rushes-to-evacuate-civilians/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766538&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>By Alessandra Prentice and Natalia Zinets ZAPORIZHZHIA, Ukraine (Reuters) -Scores of Ukrainians remained trapped on Thursday in a Mariupol steel works that has been rocked by heavy explosions as Russian forces fought for control of Ukraine's last stronghold in the ruined city and the United Nations rushed to evacuate civilians. Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said more civilians had been rescued from Mariupol but Russia was shelling the Azovstal steel plant where an estimated 200 civilians were still in underground bunkers with little food or water. President Vladimir Putin said Russia...</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/battles-rage-at-ukrainian-plant-as-u-n-rushes-to-evacuate-civilians/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Reuters UK</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766538&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump suggested 'secret' missile strike on Mexico in 2020: Former Pentagon chief</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/trump-suggested-firing-missiles-into-mexico-in-2020-former-pentagon-chief/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/trump-tries-to-take-credit-for-firing-top-adviser-who-said-he-quit-over-megyn-kelly-food-fight.jpg?id=24720193&width=600&coordinates=185%2C0%2C185%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://www.rawstory.com/mark-esper-book-blocked/">The forthcoming book</a> by Trump-era Secretary of Defense Mark Esper reveals a discussion of attacking Mexico late in the administration.</p><p>"Former President Donald J. Trump asked Mark T. Esper, his defense secretary, about the possibility of launching missiles into Mexico to 'destroy the drug labs' and wipe out the cartels, maintaining that the United States’ involvement in a strike against its southern neighbor could be kept secret, Mr. Esper recounts in his upcoming memoir," Maggie Haberman <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/05/us/politics/mark-esper-book.html" target="_blank">reported</a> for <em>The New York Times. </em>"Those remarkable discussions in 2020 were among several moments that Mr. Esper described in the book, <em>A Sacred Oath</em>, as leaving him all but speechless when he served the 45th president."</p><p>The book says Trump asked at least twice if the military could "shoot missiles into Mexico to destroy the drug labs."</p><p>Esper served as secretary of defense until Nov. 9, 2020 when Trump announced in a tweet he had been "<a href="https://www.rawstory.com/2020/11/trump-abruptly-fires-defense-secretary-mark-esper-after-reports-surface-about-his-resignation-letter/" target="_blank">terminated</a>."</p><p>"Mr. Esper, the last Senate-confirmed defense secretary under Mr. Trump, also had concerns about speculation that the president might misuse the military around Election Day by, for instance, having soldiers seize ballot boxes. He warned subordinates to be on alert for unusual calls from the White House in the lead-up to the election," the newspaper reported. "Mr. Esper describes an administration completely overtaken by concerns about Mr. Trump’s re-election campaign, with every decision tethered to that objective. He writes that he could have resigned, and weighed the idea several times, but that he believed the president was surrounded by so many yes-men and people whispering dangerous ideas to him that a loyalist would have been put in Mr. Esper’s place."</p><p>Esper says Trump even knew the exact missile he wanted to use, although he listed one from America's missile defense system. And Trump also suggested just brazenly lying about the military strike.</p><p>"When Mr. Esper raised various objections, Mr. Trump said that 'we could just shoot some Patriot missiles and take out the labs, quietly,' adding that 'no one would know it was us.' Mr. Trump said he would just say that the United States had not conducted the strike, Mr. Esper recounts, writing that he would have thought it was a joke had he not been staring Mr. Trump in the face," the newspaper reported. "Mr. Esper writes that he never believed Mr. Trump’s conduct rose to the level of needing to invoke the 25th Amendment. He also strains to give Mr. Trump credit where he thinks he deserves it. Nonetheless, Mr. Esper paints a portrait of someone not in control of his emotions or his thought process throughout 2020."</p><p>The book is scheduled to hit bookstore shelves on Tuesday.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/trump-suggested-firing-missiles-into-mexico-in-2020-former-pentagon-chief/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Bob Brigham</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/trump-tries-to-take-credit-for-firing-top-adviser-who-said-he-quit-over-megyn-kelly-food-fight.jpg?id=24720193&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three killed in attack in central Israel's Elad</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/three-killed-in-in-central-israel-s-elad/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766234&width=600&coordinates=0%2C0%2C350%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>At least three people were killed in an attack in the central Israeli city of Elad as the Jewish state marked its independence day on Thursday, following a brief lull in deadly unrest.</p><p>The Magen David Adom emergency response service, which confirmed the deaths, said two others were in a serious condition after the incident, which comes following a series of fatal attacks committed by Palestinians and Israeli Arabs in recent weeks.</p><p>Two others suffered moderate or light injuries, according to the MDA, which is Israel's version of the Red Cross.</p><p>Police said a manhunt had been launched, including helicopters and roadblocks, to find a vehicle that had fled the scene, without providing details on the alleged perpetrators.</p><p>Police said that it appeared the attack had played out at several spots in one area.MDA Paramedic Alon Rizkan, a first responder, described it as a "complex scene," identifying all of the dead as men in their early 40s.</p><p>Those who suffered serious injuries men aged between 35-60, according to the MDA.</p><p>The majority of Elad's 50,000 residents are members of Israel's ultra-Orthodox Jewish community, known as haredim.</p><p>Another majority haredi city, Bnei Brak, which also lies on the outskirts of the coastal city of Tel Aviv, was targeted in March.</p><p>It was one of the areas hit in the string of attacks since March 22 that, prior to Thursday's incident, had killed 15 people including an Arab-Israeli police officer and two Ukrainians, in separate attacks inside Israel.</p><p>Two of the deadly attacks were carried out in the Tel Aviv area by Palestinians.</p><p>A total of 27 Palestinians and three Israeli Arabs have died during the same period, among them perpetrators of attacks and those killed by Israeli security forces in West Bank operations.</p><p>For Palestinians, the anniversary of Israel's 1948 declaration of independence marks the Nakba, or "catastrophe", when more than 700,000 fled or were expelled during the war surrounding Israel's creation.</p><p>Hamas Islamists who control the Gaza strip and Islamic Jihad, another Palestinian armed group, praised the Elad attack as a consequence of unrest at Jerusalem's Al-Aqsa mosque compound.</p><p>Fresh clashes broke out at earlier Thursday at Al-Aqsa, which is also the holiest site in Judaism, where it is known as the Temple Mount.</p><p>The latest morning violence at the flashpoint site came following a tense April, in which nearly 300 people were injured in clashes between police and Palestinians at Al-Aqsa.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/three-killed-in-in-central-israel-s-elad/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766234&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colombian drug lord 'Otoniel' pleads not guilty in US court</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/colombian-lord-otoniel-pleads-not-guilty-in-us-court/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766230&width=600&coordinates=284%2C0%2C66%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>One of Colombia's most notorious drug lords pleaded not guilty to trafficking charges in a New York court Thursday following his extradition to the United States.</p><p>Dairo Antonio Usuga, known as "Otoniel," did not ask for bail during the arraignment in Brooklyn.</p><p>The 50-year-old Usuga was the leader of Colombia's largest narco-trafficking gang, known as the Gulf Clan.</p><p>The United States accuses Usuga and the Gulf Clan of illegally bringing at least 73 tons of cocaine into the country between 2003 and 2012.</p><p>He was the most-wanted person in Colombia until he was arrested last October in the northwest of the country after a massive military operation.</p><p>On Wednesday afternoon, a convoy of five bulletproof police vehicles transported him from a prison in the capital Bogota to a military airport, where he was handed over to US Drug Enforcement Administration officials.</p><p>He landed in New York around 11:30 PM (0330 GMT Thursday).</p><p>Usuga wore orange prison garb and was handcuffed during his first appearance in the Brooklyn federal court.</p><p>He has been charged with criminal enterprise and international cocaine manufacturing and distribution.</p><p>Usuga asked to be held in detention until his trial and judge Vera Scanlon set a date of June 2 for the defendant's next court appearance.</p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/colombian-lord-otoniel-pleads-not-guilty-in-us-court/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Agence France-Presse</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/image.jpg?id=29766230&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia probably won't use nukes — but it looks more likely they might now: Harvard professor</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-russia-nuclear-possibilities/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&width=600&coordinates=83%2C0%2C84%2C0&height=600"/><br/><br/><p>The Russian invasion of Ukraine took a turn on Feb. 27 when President Vladimir Putin put Russia’s nuclear forces on alert. International and military experts were cautious but dismissive that he would go that far.  </p><p>"I don't think that the Russian leadership and Putin are irrational actors," John Erath, senior policy director for the Center for Arms Control and Non-Proliferation, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/putin-still-rational-man-who-wont-use-nuclear-weapons-top-experts-say-1687297" target="_blank">told Newsweek on March 12</a>. "The use of a nuclear weapon would lead to the possibility of a response that would be disastrous for all."</p><p>"In my opinion, he is rational. Given that he is rational, I strongly believe he will not intentionally use nuclear weapons against the West. I say intentionally because indiscriminate shelling near a nuclear power plant can cause an unintentional nuclear disaster in Ukraine," said former Russian Minister of Foreign Affairs Andrei Kozyrev, who served from 1990 to 1996. <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/putin-isnt-insane-and-wont-use-nuclear-weapons-says-ex-russian-foreign-minister-161816208.html" target="_blank">That was on March 7. </a></p><p>Just under two months later, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/05/03/russia-ireland-nuclear-weapons-video-ukraine/" target="_blank">Russia pushed out a video</a> showing Britain and Ireland being blown up by a nuclear bomb. </p><p><strong><em>IN OTHER NEWS: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/trump-loving-candidate-blames-special-state-house-election-loss-on-coup-from-rino-establishment/" target="_self">Trump-loving candidate blames election loss on 'coup' from 'RINO establishment'</a></em></strong></p><p><span></span>It prompted Harvard international affairs <a href="https://twitter.com/stephenWalt/status/1522297673587605504" target="_blank">Professor Stephen Walt to say</a> that he still doesn't believe that Putin will break out the nukes, "but I am more worried about it than I was a couple of months ago."</p><p>Writing for <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/05/05/why-washington-should-take-russian-nuclear-threats-seriously/?tpcc=recirc_latest062921" target="_blank">ForeignPolicy.com he explained</a> that when he was speaking about the war back in February that he found the idea difficult to believe. "To its credit, the Biden administration has been somewhat mindful of the risk of escalation," he wrote on Thursday. </p><p>The initial thought was that as long as the United States keeps troops from going into a ground war and shooting at Russian soldiers, Putin wouldn't be triggered into a fury. Now it seems he might be crazier than was anticipated. </p><p>"To be clear: I have no idea if anyone in the Kremlin is thinking seriously along those lines, and this point is <em>not</em> an argument for sending U.S. troops to Ukraine as a deterrent shield," wrote Walt. "My point is that keeping American personnel out of the fight does not eliminate all incentives to escalate, and it might make nuclear use appear less risky if those other incentives began to loom large in Moscow’s calculations."</p><p><strong><em>READ MORE: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/ted-cruz-and-sheldon-whitehouse-clash/" target="_self">Ted Cruz and Sheldon Whitehouse clash at hearing: ‘If you’re going to criticize my brief – read it!’</a></em></strong></p><p>There's also a concern because of Putin's tendency to make good on his threats. There was his 2008 demand Ukraine and Georgia never be part of NATO. An attack broke out and it's kept Georgia away ever since. He went on to threaten Ukraine in 2014 and ultimately invaded and took over Crimea. In 2021, he warned Ukraine they better not take weapons from the west, and when they did he staged his troops on the border. </p><p>The U.S. cowboy bravado is easy. "Just blow him up" is emotionally appealing as the horrifying images and videos roll in from Ukraine. </p><p>"Many would like to punish Putin for the suffering he’s inflicted on Ukraine," Walt explained. "Unfortunately, trying to inflict a decisive defeat on Russia creates precisely the circumstances that would encourage a rational leader to contemplate other options, such as a demonstration strike with a small nuclear weapon. The purpose of such an action would be what the late theorist Thomas Schelling <a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300246742/arms-and-influence/" target="_blank">called</a> a 'competition in risk-taking': one side takes an obviously dangerous action in order to demonstrate how much it cares about the issue at hand, and to persuade its opponent(s) to back off."</p><p>There's an ongoing concern that if Putin thinks he's losing, his willingness to go to the extreme deepens. After all, if he's going to be removed from power or Russia is about to collapse, why wouldn't a man with nothing left to lose embrace mutually assured destruction? </p><p><strong><em>RELATED: <a href="https://www.rawstory.com/putin-apologized-for-russia-hitler-claims-israel-pm-s-office/" target="_self">Putin apologized for Russia Hitler claims</a></em></strong></p><p>"It would be a gamble for sure, but he’s gambled before," wrote Walt. "And he probably cares more about avoiding those outcomes than the opposing coalition cares about inflicting them on him. He won’t order a large-scale nuclear attack, because that would be suicidal, but a demonstration strike against a non-nuclear adversary, though not without serious risks, is another matter."</p><p><a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/05/05/why-washington-should-take-russian-nuclear-threats-seriously/" target="_blank">Read the full column at ForeignPolicy.com. </a></p>]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.rawstory.com/putin-russia-nuclear-possibilities/</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sarah K. Burris</dc:creator>
      <media:content url="https://www.rawstory.com/media-library/vladimir-putin-afp.jpg?id=29524219&amp;width=980" medium="image" type="image/jpeg">
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>