<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>360Quadrants</title>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com</link>
    <description>Official Blog</description>
    <lastBuildDate>
	Fri, 06 May 2022 06:22:19 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.13</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/KBVrKl-_400x400-150x150.png</url>
      <title>360Quadrants</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Trends in Banking Industry</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-banking-industry/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-banking-industry/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 06:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2822</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Banking industry is one of the most susceptible sectors to cyber-attacks. The prime reasons for being one of the prime targets for cyber criminals includes massive amount of money and enormous of data at stake, compromising which can lead to a major disruption across the entire economy. Cyber-attacks such as malware, phishing, ransomware, DDoS, and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-banking-industry/">Cybersecurity Trends in Banking Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Banking industry is
one of the most susceptible sectors to cyber-attacks. The prime reasons for
being one of the prime targets for cyber criminals includes massive amount of
money and enormous of data at stake, compromising which can lead to a major
disruption across the entire economy. Cyber-attacks such as malware, phishing,
ransomware, DDoS, and Botnet attacks amongst others are the most prominent
attacks observed in the banking sector. Financial institutions therefore need
to adopt robust cybersecurity frameworks in order to detect and mitigate the
cyber threats in real-time for its customers to experience a secure trading.</p>



<p>With the ongoing technological
advancements using artificial intelligence, machine learning, cloud and big
data, cyber-attacks are also becoming more sophisticated and are turning into a
prime concern for the financial institutions. Organizations are now introducing
cybersecurity at every phase of the banking process. For example, multi-factor
authentication, one time password, firewalls, threat intelligence,
vulnerability management and data analytics are some of the measures which are in
place to constantly monitor the transactions and to eliminate the potential threats
of the cyber-attacks. There are several trends which create the dire need of
strong cybersecurity solution. </p>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity Trends in Banking</strong></p>



<p><strong>Digitalization- the start of the new era</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>With the ongoing
corona virus pandemic, banking sector is witnessing a paradigm shift through
digitization, resulting to which the entire banking processes are now being
virtualized. Financial institutions are introducing new banking options such as
contactless banking, easy payment options and remote access to escalate the
digital transformation across the entire banking chain. However, there is trade
off when it comes to securing these processes. Cyber criminals have made
several attempts such as social engineering and phishing, therefore banking
institutions need to employ new cybersecurity norms to keep up with the pace of
rapid digitization.</p>



<p><strong>Adoption of blockchain technology to lower the risks of data breach</strong></p>



<p>The decentralized
nature and cryptographic hashes are making blockchain technology the most
promising channel for a secure data transfer. Further, blockchain offers higher
levels of transparency across the system and the records of the transactions
made are immutable. Thus, blockchain technology bears the potential of secure
cyber framework which could secure the digital transactions and enhance the
customer privacy. </p>



<p><strong>Shift to the virtual culture</strong></p>



<p>The pandemic has
accelerated the world of the online spendings. These higher rates of online
transactions are one of the prime reasons, that the customer’s banking cards
details are being compromised. Cyber-attacks such as identify theft and fraud,
credentials leak and phishing frauds are the results of these compromised
online transactions, generating the need of strong cyber frameworks.</p>



<p><strong>Top Cybersecurity Companies offering solutions for Banking Sector</strong></p>



<p>In order to manage the
cyber-attacks, cybersecurity entities are enforcing several approaches and
strategies to timely detect the cyber-attacks and implement the mandatory steps
required to mitigate those. Below is a list of few of the <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top
cybersecurity companies</a> offering solutions for banking industry.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/ibm-corporation">IBM</a></strong></p>



<p>Founded in 1911, IBM
is headquartered in Armonk, New York, United States. The company offers banking
cybersecurity solutions such as data security and protection solutions, IBM
Security QRadar SIEM, Cloud identity and access management (IAM) solutions, and
IBM Cloud Pak for Security.</p>



<p>The company has
partnered with Tech Mahindra in order to expand its cybersecurity offerings for
local enterprises which will include managing security compliance and
bolstering business information systems.</p>



<p><strong>Palo Alto Networks </strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>



<p>Founded in 2005, Palo
Alto Networks Inc. is headquartered in Santa Clara, California, US. It is one
of the leading <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity
companies</a> globally. Palo Alto’s portfolio of solutions includes Network
Security, Secure Access Secure Edge (SASE), Cloud-Native Security, Security
Operations, Work from Home and Threat and Consulting solutions. These solutions
ensure data privacy law compliance, reduce latency to internet and cloud-based
applications, manage vendor and supply chain risk with Zero Trust security.</p>



<p>In April 2022, the
company recently introduced SASE to protect home networks through its Okyo<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11.2.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />
Garde Enterprise Edition. This edition is designed to protect businesses from
home network vulnerabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Fortinet</strong></p>



<p>Fortinet is
cybersecurity solution provider founded in 2000 is headquartered in Sunnyvale,
California, United States. The company offers its services for electronic
trading platforms and for the infrastructure. The cybersecurity solutions
offered by Fortinet for financial services include FortiGate high-end
firewalls, FortiGate internal segmentation firewalls, FortiManager, Fortinet
Security Fabric and FortiAnalyzer.</p>



<p>In April 2022, the
company announced new features of FortisOS 7.2 which unifies the convergence of
networking and security across NGFW, SD-WAN, LAN Edge, 5G, ZTNA.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/microsoft-corporation">Microsoft</a></strong></p>



<p>Microsoft was founded
in 1975 and is headquartered in Redmond, Washington, United States. The company
is one of the prominent leaders in the cybersecurity space. Microsoft
Security’s product portfolio includes Microsoft Azure, Microsoft 365, and Power
BI. Additionally, the company also offers High-performance computing (HPC),
Backup and archive and Cloud-scale analytics solutions. Microsoft Azure, a
cloud-based solution, is designed to optimize the risk management and simplify
the regulatory compliance. It further aids the banking system by facilitating
the cloud resources to extend the on-premises capacity on demand. The banking
clientele of Microsoft’s banking security solutions include D Bank, Temenos,
Nedbank, Redwood Bank amongst others.</p>



<p>Recently, in February
2022, Microsoft offered its services to Axis Bank in order to secure its
digital transformation by using Microsoft Azure and Microsoft 365 for its email
security which is prone to mail-based phishing and spamming attacks.</p>



<p><strong>Allot&nbsp; </strong></p>



<p>Allot, a network and
security solutions provider, was founded in 1996 and is headquartered in Hod
Hasharon, Israel. The company offers Allot Traffic Intelligence and Assurance
platform for critical network visibility across financial organizations. The
platform is powered by its Secure Service Gateway and Service Gateway products.
The solution offers traffic classification, protection against DDoS attack, and
digital experience monitoring and other such services to strengthen the
financial institutions in real-time. Some of its customers are Banco
International, Danamon, Leumi, and OCBC Bank.</p>



<p><a><strong>Qualys</strong></a></p>



<p>Founded in 1996 and headquartered in Foster
City, California, United States is an IT security company which offers
vulnerability management solutions. The company’s product portfolio includes
Asset Management, IT Security, Compliance Services, Cloud/Container Security
and Web App Security. Amongst these solutions vulnerability management solution
is most utilized by the banking institutions in order to manage cyber threats.</p>



<p>In April 2022, Qualys announced Multi-Vector
EDR 2.0 with additional capabilities of threat-hunting and risk mitigation to
improve alert prioritization and reduce the threat response time.</p>



<p><strong>Kaspersky</strong></p>



<p>Kaspersky is another prominent entity in the
cybersecurity solutions space. The company was founded in 1997 and is
headquartered in Moscow, Russia. The company’s products include Targeted attack
detection, Endpoint, ATM and POS systems security, Hybrid Cloud Security and
Threat intelligence for isolated networks. These solutions are designed to oversee
the targeted attacks, data center attacks, ransomware attacks and tracks for
any malicious insider activity.</p>



<p>Kaspersky launched Endpoint Security Cloud Pro
with added capabilities of automated response options and additional set of
security controls in April 2022.</p>



<p><strong>Cisco</strong></p>



<p>Founded in 1984 and headquartered in San Jose,
California, United States, Cisco is a technology conglomerate which offers
cloud-based cybersecurity solutions. It provides solutions such as Secure
Firewall, Umbrella (secure gateway), Secure Endpoint, Duo (Multifactor
authentication), AnyConnect, Identity Service Engine, Secure Workload, Secure
Email, Analytics, Kenna Security and DDoS Protection.</p>



<p>Cisco entered a strategic partnership with
Comcast. Comcast is intending to explore new security frameworks such as SASE
and zero trust, which integrates SD-WAN with advanced security solutions, in
order to secure business infrastructure.</p>



<p><strong>Webroot</strong></p>



<p>Webroot is a cybersecurity software solution
provider which was founded in 1997 and is headquartered in Broomfield,
Colorado, United States. The company’s product portfolio includes Endpoint
Protection, DNS Protection, Mobile Security SDK and Secure Anywhere Antivirus.
The mobile security SDK is designed to prevent mobile fraud by embedding
security features into banking applications. Such active monitoring protects
from cyber threats in real-time.</p>



<p>Additionally, the company also offers threat
intelligence services which includes Real-Time Anti-Phishing, Streaming Malware
Detection and Cloud Service Intelligence.</p>



<p><strong>Bitdefender</strong></p>



<p>Bitdefender founded in 2001 is headquartered in
Bucharest, Romania. The company offers cybersecurity solutions to various
sectors including telecom, energy and utilities, banking, and technology
sector. The company’s financial cybersecurity services portfolio consists of
Cloud and Server Security, Endpoint Detection and Response. These solutions are
based on ML and automatically detect and prevent advanced cyber threats.</p>



<p>In April 2022, Bitdefender announced its
enhanced Premium VPN Services. The enhanced features included encryption for
all web traffic, built-in ad blocker, anti-tracker, and addition of whitelist
trusted websites.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>In the near future, it
can be expected that with the growing number of applications in the banking
sector, several new complexities will be introduced, leading to higher cyber
risks. Moreover, it will become more important for the banking companies to
maintain the customer’s data privacy. Banking organizations should utilize the
potentials of blockchain technology to address the exponentially increasing
cyber issues. With the strong algorithms and decentralized nature of the
blockchain technology, it becomes difficult for the cyber attackers to hack
these, however, adoption of blockchain by the regularized banks is far from
near now. </p>



<p>The cyber-attacks are
lucrative for the cyber criminals, therefore banking organizations should
continuously perform the vulnerability management tests for its infrastructure
and should invest heavily in developing a robust cyber framework.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-banking-industry/">Cybersecurity Trends in Banking Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-banking-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Cybersecurity Company Shares to watch in 2022</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 06:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cybersecurity Companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best Cybersecurity Company]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2818</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity is one of the most important advanced technologies in the internet age, as well as for Web 3.0 and 5G to come. All modern cyberattack tactics to steal confidential data from businesses or individuals are on the lookout for weak links to begin an attack against. It has resulted in the necessity for tens [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/">Best Cybersecurity Company Shares to watch in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cybersecurity is
one of the most important advanced technologies in the internet age, as well as
for Web 3.0 and 5G to come. All modern cyberattack tactics to steal
confidential data from businesses or individuals are on the lookout for weak
links to begin an attack against. It has resulted in the necessity for tens of
thousands of cybersecurity firms to address the problem with a variety of
strategic cybersecurity solutions. <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">Top Cybersecurity
companies</a> have begun to offer profitable cybersecurity stocks in order to
profit on the global tech market&#8217;s stability. Let&#8217;s look at the best 10
cybersecurity stocks to buy in 2022 if you want to make a decent return.</p>



<p><strong>The following are the top 10 cybersecurity stocks to watch in 2022:</strong></p>



<ol><li>Microsoft (NASDAQ: MSFT)</li><li>Palo Alto Networks (NASDAQ: PANW)</li><li>Fortinet (NASDAQ: FTNT)</li><li>Check Point Software
Technologies (NASDAQ: CHKP)</li><li>Cloudflare, Inc. (NYSE: NET)</li><li>Darktrace Plc. (LSE: DARK)</li><li>SentinelOne (NYSE:S)</li><li>Splunk (NASDAQ: SPLK)</li><li>CrowdStrike Holdings (NASDAQ: CRWD)</li><li>Zscaler (NASDAQ: ZS)</li></ol>



<p><strong>1. Microsoft
(NASDAQ: MSFT)</strong></p>



<p>By no means is
Microsoft a pure-play cybersecurity stock. MSFT stock, on the other hand, is
not to be overlooked, as that segment of the company generates $10 billion in
revenue. One reason for that is the company’s ability to incorporate its
security solutions into its Office 365 software which is already located in the
cloud.</p>



<p>And, if previous
acquisitions are any indicator, Microsoft isn&#8217;t averse to expanding through
acquisition. Microsoft paid around $500 million for RiskIQ in July 2021. This
was in addition to its July acquisition of CloudKnow Security.</p>



<p>In 2021,
Microsoft stock is up 50%, with the company&#8217;s Teams collaboration software
accounting for a large part of that increase. The corporation, on the other
hand, is continuing to expand into other high-growth areas like the metaverse.
Nonetheless, MSFT stock is a good buy for individuals who want to invest in
cybersecurity businesses but have a low risk tolerance.</p>



<p><strong>2. Palo Alto
Networks (NASDAQ: PANW)</strong></p>



<p>Palo Alto
Networks has a proprietary security technology called App-ID that categorises
network traffic by application, user, and content, as the name implies.
Customers gain in-depth access into all traffic and applications, allowing for
better monitoring of possible risks and threats. Consumers can get end-to-end
security without having to use another company because the company&#8217;s platforms
are stand-alone solutions.</p>



<p>Following the
introduction of two new platforms earlier this year, the earnings report may
have verified to investors that the company is beginning to produce recurring
revenue. Mark Cash of Morningstar recently improved the company&#8217;s moat rating
from narrow to wide, raising its fair value estimate to $585 per share from
$550.</p>



<p><strong>3. Fortinet
(NASDAQ: FTNT)</strong></p>



<p>Current price:
US$344.52</p>



<p>Market cap:
US$56.33 billion</p>



<p>When it comes to
cybersecurity stocks, Fortinet should undoubtedly be considered. In today&#8217;s
hyperconnected environment, Fortinet provides a clear benefit to consumers. In
mid-December, FTNT stock was added to the Nasdaq-100 index. Fortinet provides
VPN services, among other things.</p>



<p>The stock of
FTNT has risen 135% this year, and it&#8217;s safe to assume that if you&#8217;re not a
shareholder, you&#8217;ve probably lost out on the biggest gains. The <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity
vendors</a> stock has now closed positive for four weeks in a row and is at
all-time highs. Nonetheless, this is a high-quality stock that soared by 1,138%
in its first ten years on the market. Fortinet is a good purchase for 2022 and
beyond, given the high demand for the company&#8217;s goods and services.</p>



<p><strong>4.Check Point
Software Technologies (NASDAQ: CHKP)</strong></p>



<p>In terms of
market capitalization, CHKP is a smaller player in the cybersecurity complex.
It is, nonetheless, one of the world&#8217;s major providers of internet security
solutions. Check Point specialises in internet, intranet, and extranet
infrastructure security.</p>



<p>Year to far, the
stock has outpaced its peers, rising 18.9% to over $138.61 per share. Due to
geopolitical tensions between Russia and Western countries, this upward momentum
is unlikely to slow down. In the next two years, net sales are expected to
increase moderately, rising 5.7% to $2.29 billion in 2022 and 4.9% to $2.4
billion in 2023.</p>



<p>Long-term
investors, on the other hand, will be interested in the company&#8217;s strong
profitability. In 2022, CHKP&#8217;s estimated net margin would be 34.7 percent, down
from 37.6 percent in 2021. It also has a sizable cash pile of $3.78 billion at
the end of 2021, which is a positive sign in this inflationary environment for
the corporation. </p>



<p><strong>5.
Cloudflare, Inc. (NYSE: NET)</strong></p>



<p>Current price:
US$116.42</p>



<p>Market cap:
US$37.68 billion</p>



<p>NET stock is a
global cloud services provider that improves the performance and security of
applications. Cloudflare&#8217;s security products include API shields, bot
management, distributed denial-of-service protection, page shields, rate
limiting, secure sockets layers, and transport layer security encryption, among
others.</p>



<p>NET is one of
the largest cybersecurity stocks in this panel, with a market capitalization of
roughly $30.27 billion. Given the company&#8217;s enormous market capitalization, it
has a spectacular equity growth narrative, with net sales expected to increase
41.9% to $931 million in 2022 and 33.7% to $1.24 billion in 2023, respectively.
NET shares, on the other hand, are predicted to generate a marginal free cash
flow of 0.62 million this year, rising to $34.6 million in 2023.</p>



<p><strong>6. Darktrace
Plc. (LSE: DARK)</strong></p>



<p>Current price:
US$452</p>



<p>Market cap:
US$3.16 billion</p>



<p>Last April,
Darktrace, a company that utilises artificial intelligence to detect threats
and vulnerabilities inside IT networks rather than building perimeter barriers,
floated its shares at 250 pence. Darktrace is a leading cybersecurity company
that develops cyber-threat defence technology solutions all over the world.
Enterprise immune system, industrial immune system, cyber-AI analyst, Darktrace
antigena, and other cybersecurity solutions are among the company&#8217;s offerings.</p>



<p>Financial
services corporations, healthcare organisations, media and entertainment,
education, and important national infrastructure organisations are all served
by this cybersecurity firm. Across all geographic areas and customer sizes, the
company saw substantial revenue growth. Its client base increased by 39.6% to
6,531.</p>



<p><strong>7.
SentinelOne (NYSE:S)</strong></p>



<p>SentinelOne is
another pure-play <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity
vendor</a> that has recently gone public. SentinelOne&#8217;s IPO, which took
place in June 2021 and raised $1.2 billion in cash and valued the firm at $10
billion, was the largest ever for a cybersecurity company.</p>



<p>This small firm
competes with CrowdStrike by providing a cloud-based endpoint security
technology. Its capacity to detect and resolve cybersecurity risks
automatically has been positively appreciated by the market. SentinelOne is a
fast-growing corporation that saw its sales more than double in 2020 due to the
pandemic.</p>



<p><strong>8. Splunk
(NASDAQ: SPLK)</strong></p>



<p>Splunk, a
long-time leader in data analytics, makes software that helps businesses sift
through logs of data, monitor digital activity, and organise data breach
responses. Even though its platform predates cloud computing, the company has
been rapidly transferring users to newer cloud-based versions of its software.</p>



<p>Splunk is a
crucial aspect of a rising number of enterprises&#8217; security and monitoring
activities, and data analytics is a fast-growing section of IT management. In
the next few years, the company anticipates its annualised recurring revenue to
double. Splunk is a value stock, especially when considering the company&#8217;s
business fundamentals like as sales and profitability, which are still in the
works.</p>



<p><strong>9.
CrowdStrike Holdings (NASDAQ: CRWD)</strong></p>



<p>Current price:
US$195.21</p>



<p>Market cap:
US$44.77 billion</p>



<p>CrowdStrike is a
cloud-native software firm that specialises in endpoint security, which
includes protection for devices like laptops, PCs, and servers, as well as any
other device linked to a network. CrowdStrike is especially well-suited for
facilitating remote work because it is cloud-based.</p>



<p>Machine learning
(a sort of artificial intelligence) is used by CrowdStrike&#8217;s software to detect
security breaches and track down attackers. It&#8217;s also simple to roll out to the
millions of people who work from home and the billions of machines that are
online. To better serve its customers, the company has continuously extended
the number of modules available on its platform, as well as new integration
agreements with other IT firms to ensure that data protection is uniform across
an organization&#8217;s IT infrastructure.</p>



<p>CrowdStrike has
experienced rapid growth, and the firm is now the largest pure-play security
vendor in terms of market valuation. CrowdStrike is primed to continue growing
at a rapid pace in an increasingly mobile environment with more devices coming
online all the time.</p>



<p><strong>10. Zscaler
(NASDAQ: ZS)</strong></p>



<p>Current price:
US$239.15</p>



<p>Market cap:
US$33.50 billion</p>



<p>Zscaler, another
cloud-native security firm, works with endpoint security services to keep data
safe. Another of the major pure-play cybersecurity stocks, the company has been
rapidly boosting its sales.</p>



<p>Zscaler began
with a cloud computing security software-as-a-service platform, but it has
subsequently expanded to include internet security and end-user monitoring.
With so many individuals working from home, end-user monitoring is becoming
more common. Zscaler is well positioned to profit from this tremendous market,
with worldwide spending on cloud computing estimated to top $1 trillion yearly
this decade.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/">Best Cybersecurity Company Shares to watch in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoey — High-End B2B Ecommerce Platforms</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/zoey-ecommerce-platforms/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/zoey-ecommerce-platforms/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 12:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[E-Commerce Platforms]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best ECommerce Platforms]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[eCommerce platforms]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zoey]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zoey eCommerce Platforms]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2815</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>For B2B and wholesale organizations, Zoey is a strong commerce platform. It is a SaaS-based B2B eCommerce solution for small and medium-sized enterprises that lets wholesalers, franchisees, and distributors take orders on any device, at any time. Zoey is a best-in-class solution that blends great B2B features with current B2C capabilities. Quote creation, customer groups, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/zoey-ecommerce-platforms/">Zoey — High-End B2B Ecommerce Platforms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For B2B and
wholesale organizations, Zoey is a strong commerce platform. It is a SaaS-based
B2B eCommerce solution for small and medium-sized enterprises that lets
wholesalers, franchisees, and distributors take orders on any device, at any
time. Zoey is a best-in-class solution that blends great B2B features with
current B2C capabilities. Quote creation, customer groups, access limitations,
rapid order capabilities, and more Zoey B2B features are available. Merchants
can also use B2C-standard features to help their customers’ self-serve basic
demands like reordering, order status, and account management. On any device,
the Zoey mobile app allows you to check up information and place orders at any
time.</p>



<p><strong>Zoey – High-End B2B Ecommerce Platforms</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms/zoey">Zoey</a>
is a lesser-known ecommerce solution than some of its competitors, but it has a
lot of useful features. Most of the North American Companies use Zoey&#8217;s
services for B2B and wholesale transactions.</p>



<p>Zoey is a mobile software that allows B2B enterprises to accept orders, produce sales quotes, and look up product and pricing info while on the road. The software also includes a self-service order site for buyers to place web orders. The <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms">Best eCommerce Platforms</a> assist businesses in creating websites that increase visibility to current and new consumers.</p>



<p>Zoey is
distinct from some of the other market-leading platforms because it is
specifically developed for B2B. Zoey has you covered if you want to take orders
online, on any device, at any time. You may set up a web-based environment to
allow customers to serve themselves online, as well as a Zoey Android or iPhone
app to assist you access information no matter where you are.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms/zoey">Zoey eCommerce platforms</a> is not specifically designed for startups. Its extensive features are only suitable for B2B companies who have already made a name for themselves before moving to Zoey. Zoey can service advanced small businesses as well as their mid-sized B2B counterparts with ease. We can dig deeper into the types of <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms/">ecommerce platforms</a> you can create using Zoey and what makes it so appealing.</p>



<p><strong>Customer Management</strong></p>



<p>Zoey has
implemented a variety of customer management techniques. For starters, Zoey has
a Request-a-Quote feature that allows you to submit possible orders for
assessment and quotation. It essentially allows customers to create draft orders,
which are subsequently fine-tuned by customer service teams to set all critical
factors such as cost and shipping. By restricting visitor access to certain site
features and items, you can manage what your prospects can view and order.</p>



<p>Customer
segmentation is another service offered by Zoey. You may provide customized
buying experiences by categorizing clients into different groups. This applies
to every step of the process, including product display, pricing, order volume,
payment, and shipment.</p>



<p>If you sell
both B2B and B2C, this feature will come in handy for customizing experiences
for each group of purchasers, such as frequent consumers and businesses. When it
comes to B2B buyers, they prefer to order in bulk. In fact, one of the main
reasons why B2B outsells B2C in terms of sales volume is because of this.</p>



<p><strong>Zoey&#8217;s Mobile App for iOS 3.0 </strong></p>



<p>The Zoey
mobile sales rep app is designed to allow salespeople to work on any device, at
any time. The new iOS 3.0, Zoey improves the salesperson experience by adding
more functionality to the Zoey App, making it easier to create and manage
Drafts, Quotes, and Orders. It is designed to function in tandem with Zoey Web
and Zoey Admin&#8217;s new drafting capabilities.</p>



<p>One can now
convert a Quote to an Order within the App, in addition to converting a Draft
to a Quote or Order on the Zoey Admin and Web. &nbsp;Before converting to order, you can also edit
Quotes on the App to make any necessary changes. Quotes and Orders can be
deleted as needed from the App.</p>



<p>Zoey supports
multiple currencies, languages, and packaging options. When seeking information
or creating orders on behalf of their customers, salespeople can use the same
tools. In addition, Zoey included Multi-Packaging capability, allowing orders
in amounts determined by your company&#8217;s varied packaging scenarios.</p>



<p>Salespeople
can use the Zoey App to search for products based on their qualities. Other
data management improvements made by Zoey App include sales reps being able to
mark Default Addresses for Accounts to speed up order creation. They can also
update the Sales Reps associated with Accounts (with the Account Owner&#8217;s
approval).</p>



<p><strong>Integrations</strong></p>



<p>Zoey has over
100 interfaces with the most common business systems, ensuring that data can be
obtained in the most efficient manner possible at all times. Zoey has a library
of pre-built apps and connections that allow it to connect to a variety of
powerful technologies. Subscriptions, POS, marketing, inventory management,
accounting, and payment processing are only a few of the major areas. There are
more than 30 payment processing alternatives available. Google, Facebook, eBay,
and Amazon are just a few of the important sites that can be integrated with
Zoey.</p>



<p>The Zoey REST API allows you to
manage a variety of functionalities, including customer management, customer
addresses management, product management, sales order retrieval, and inventory
management. It authenticates the application to access the Zoey service using
the three-legged OAuth 1.0a protocol. The response formats supported by the
Zoey API are XML and JSON.</p>



<p>The Zoey REST API has four verbs to
manage resources: GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE. One can use HTTP GET to get the
data&#8217;s contents, HTTP DELETE to delete the data, and POST/PUT to create or edit
the data. Customers, customer addresses, sales orders, inventory, and goods may
all be managed via the Zoey REST API.</p>



<p>The Zoey
Platform also includes features that allow businesses to create websites that
improve visibility for current and potential customers. Zoey blends the
anticipated capabilities that buyers normally expect from an online commerce
Platform with B2B capabilities that are meticulously crafted. Zoey will assist
you with integrating with some of the industry&#8217;s most popular platforms –</p>



<p><strong>Oracle NetSuite and Zoey </strong></p>



<p>Zoey makes it
simple to receive online orders from customers and for salespeople to create
orders on their behalf, all within a solution that works seamlessly with
NetSuite as your data hub. Zoey assists you in getting up and running quickly
by making it simple to set up your different business rules, such as customer
segmentation around pricing, catalogue, and more, as well as linking to your
NetSuite installation to transfer data seamlessly between the two platforms.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms/salesforce">Salesforce</a>
and Zoey</strong></p>



<p>Any
Salesforce object may be mapped to Zoey products, orders, customers, or quotes
with the Zoey Salesforce connector. It allows you to control the direction and
timing of synchronization. Salesforce Relational and Formula fields are
supported. Users may synchronize and regularly update product prices and
inventory from Salesforce to Zoey, as well as create new goods from Salesforce
in Zoey.</p>



<p><strong>Zoey is a QuickBooks Online user</strong></p>



<p>Zoey makes it
simple to accept online orders from customers and for salespeople to create
orders on their behalf, all within a solution that integrates seamlessly with
QuickBooks Online as your accounting software. Zoey assists you in getting up
and running quickly by making it simple to set up your various business rules,
such as customer segmentation around pricing, catalog, and more, and linking to
your QuickBooks Online account to transfer data seamlessly between the two
platforms.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/zoey-ecommerce-platforms/">Zoey — High-End B2B Ecommerce Platforms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/zoey-ecommerce-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Trends in Telecom Industry</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-telecom-industry/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-telecom-industry/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 13:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2808</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The telecommunications industry is the pillar of ongoing digital transformation and cybersecurity is one of the biggest threats to it. The telecom industry is continuously evolving and is expected to achieve unprecedented level of faster communications, however, it is also heavily susceptible to cyber-attacks due to massive amount of data generation and the critical communication [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-telecom-industry/">Cybersecurity Trends in Telecom Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The telecommunications
industry is the pillar of ongoing digital transformation and cybersecurity is one of the
biggest threats to it. The telecom industry is continuously evolving and is
expected to achieve unprecedented level of faster communications, however, it
is also heavily susceptible to cyber-attacks due to massive amount of data generation and the
critical communication infrastructure. The most common cyber-attacks observed
in telecom space include Phishing, Malware, DDoS, Access Breach, Integrity
Compromise, Social Engineering among few others. Such cyber-attacks result in
traffic flooding, hardware vandalism, communication hijacking, data breach, implanting
malicious codes in the software etc., causing major disruption across the
communication network and data compromise by the user.</p>



<p>With the onset of 5G, a fully connected environment is expected through several IoT devices, such as autonomous vehicles and industrial automation, smart grid, smart cities etc. However, it will in turn make telecom operators more vulnerable to cyber-attacks and offer cyber attackers with new ways to infiltrate the network and other system vulnerabilities, thereby indicating the dire need of a robust cybersecurity framework.  Several attempts are being made both by the telecom operators and <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity vendors</a> to build robust solutions adhering to the network specification as allocated by the 3GPP. There are several trends which to lead to focusing the cybersecurity aspects on the current telecom industry.</p>



<h3>Trends</h3>



<h4>Increased usage of Artificial Intelligence and
Machine Learning techniques to strengthen the network security and management</h4>



<p>Most of the
telecommunication companies rely on the usage of artificial intelligence-based platforms to enhance
the network security, data security
analytics. The technology offers massive benefits such as network
automation, predictive maintenance, and network management, however, managing
the enormous amount of data generated by the telecom operators is a huge
challenge. These AI and ML algorithms record the anomalies observed in the
regular data patterns of the network and minimizes the risks of data breach
both in real-time and future. Such potentials of the AI technology are not
hidden from the cybercriminals. By using these techniques, they incorporate
several malicious software on the customer’s device, resulting in the
compromised data security
of the user.</p>



<h4>Proliferation of IoT devices for a more
connected network</h4>



<p>The shift towards the
hybrid work culture has fueled the usage of IoT devices. By using a fully
connected network IoT is transforming the way businesses functions. Devices
such as smart watches, autonomous vehicles, smart grid, to smart cities are
witnessing an up surge, thereby generating the need of a ubiquitous and secure
network. However, due to complicated nature of IoT devices they have become a
prime target for the cyber criminals. The essential security concerns with the
proliferation of IoT devices includes ensuring network level security, data
security, endpoint
protection of the IoT devices and tracking and managing security of IoT devices on a
constant basis. DDoS and botnet attacks are the majorly observed cyber-attack
on the connected devices. Cybersecurity companies such as Microsoft, Trend
Micro are now implementing Zero Trust approach to ensure security across all
network layers and to verify security and analyze the telemetry in order to
secure the digital networks from sophisticated cyber-attacks.</p>



<h3>Adoption of multi-access edge computing (MEC) with
onset of 5G </h3>



<p>Realizing the
potential of MEC, telecom companies are shifting their working model towards cloud-based
networks architectures. With MEC at the edge of the network, CSPs can easily
reduce the volume of the traffic flow offloaded at core network and therefore
minimize the operational costs. &nbsp;However,
adoption of MEC and cloud-based model for a complex industry like telecom will expose
it to cyber-attacks and further make it prone to vulnerabilities associated
with network virtualization, interoperability within networks, privacy and
insider threats and other such cyber-attacks. This demands for a strong
security solution at the edge in order to experience a smooth migration from 4G
to 5G.<br></p>



<h4><strong>Top Cybersecurity Companies in Teleocm and
their offerings</strong></h4>



<p>In order to manage the cyber-attacks, cybersecurity entities are enforcing several approaches and strategies to timely detect the cyber-attacks and implement the mandatory steps required to mitigate those. Below is a list of few of <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity companies</a> offering solutions for telecom industry.</p>



<h4>1.1.1&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/palo-alto-networks-inc">Palo Alto Networks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </h4>



<p>Founded in 2005, Palo
Alto Networks Inc. is headquartered in Santa Clara, California, US. It is one
of the leading cybersecurity companies globally and offers a comprehensive portfolio
of cybersecurity solutions across cloud, networks and mobile devices. AT&amp;T,
a telecom vendor utilizes Palo Alto’s Next-Generation Firewall to support its
5G-enabled IoT, OT and IT use cases. Palo Alto has also collaborated with
NVIDIA for creating a security solution which includes Palo Alto
Next-Generation Firewall with the NVIDIA’s BlueField-2 Data Processing Unit
(DPU) for security in virtualized software-defined networks.</p>



<p>Palo Alto’s portfolio
of solutions includes Network Security, Secure Access Secure Edge, Cloud-Native
Security, Security Operations, Work from Home and Threat and Consulting
solutions. Recently, in February 2022, the company launched its AI-driven
platform Cortex® XSIAM, which is designed to accelerate the threat response. The
company also upgraded its PAN-OS software, developed to collect, analyze and
interpret potential zero-day threats in real time using inline deep learning
technique.</p>



<p>In October 2021, the
company collaborated with IBM to build secure 5G networks and address the
unique security requirements of the telecom operators deploying 5G networks and
edge services. The collaboration is focused on protecting the 5G network slice
from the network attacks through end-to-end slice validation and towards
enhancing integrated security solutions and services such as automation
spanning multifunction network devices and VNFs, container and control plane
security. </p>



<h4>1.1.2&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/microsoft-corporation">Microsoft</a></h4>



<p>Microsoft was founded
in 1975 and is headquartered in Redmond, Washington, United States. The company
is one of the prominent leaders in the cybersecurity space. Microsoft
Security’s product portfolio includes App and email security, Compliance
services, Endpoint security, Identity and Management Access, Network Security,
Privacy Management, Security Posture and SIEM and XDR services. Additionally,
the company also offers Azure Private 5G Core, which is designed to secure the
private 5G core network on an Azure managed edge platform. The solution
supports both 4G and 5G standalone radio access network and provides centralized
orchestration and automation of 5G core software, service management for
configuration, and monitoring.</p>



<p>Recently in March
2022, Microsoft revealed its Azure Operator Distributed Services which is built
by combining AT&amp;T’s Network Cloud technology with Azure’s security,
monitoring, machine
learning, and analytics.</p>



<h4>1.1.3&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
Allot &nbsp;</h4>



<p>Allot, a network and
security solutions provider, was founded in 1996 and is headquartered in Hod
Hasharon, Israel. The company has wide portfolio of security services, which
includes Network Secure, 5G Net Protect, IoT Secure, Service Gateway, ClearSee
Network Analytics and Smart5G among other services. The company clientele
includes major telecom vendors such as Vodafone, Telenor, Telefonica, Jio,
Rakuten and Dish.</p>



<p>In February 2022, the
company collaborated with AWS to jointly develop cloud-based 5G Network
Intelligence and cybersecurity solutions.</p>



<h4><a>1.1.4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
Trend
Micro</a></h4>



<p>Founded in 1989, Trend Micro is cybersecurity
software company which is headquartered in Shibuya City, Tokyo, Japan. The
company offers solutions AI and ML based solutions such as Hybrid Cloud
Security, MEC Security, Enterprise 5G Security Management, Network Security,
User Protection and Detection and Response. The company also incorporates the
zero-trust strategy and helps in securing private mobile networks, such as 5G,
4G/LTE, and NB-IoT, with end-to-end security. Trend Micro recently disclosed
its unified cybersecurity platform which is designed by integrating its native
services to work in an ecosystem where it will co-share its space with third-party
partners and competitors such as Google Cloud, Microsoft, Palo Alto Networks
and other such companies.</p>



<h4>1.1.5&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/kaspersky-lab">Kaspersky</a></h4>



<p>Kaspersky is another prominent entity in the
cybersecurity solutions space. The company was founded in 1997 and is
headquartered in Moscow, Russia. The company’s products include Endpoint
Security for Business, Hybrid Cloud Security, Endpoint Detection and Response
Optimum, Security for Internet Gateway, Private Security Network, DDoS
Protection and others. Telecom companies like Tele2 and VimpleCom are the
clients of Kaspersky’s Endpoint Security and Security for Mail Server services
respectively.</p>



<p>Kaspersky acquired Brain4Net, an SD-WAN and NFV
orchestration software developer in October 2021, to strengthen its cloud
security capabilities and XDR offerings.</p>



<h4>1.1.6&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/fortinet-inc">Fortinet</a></h4>



<p>Fortinet is cybersecurity solution provider
which was founded in 2000 and is headquartered in Sunnyvale, California, United
States. The company offers its services for both enterprises and small
businesses. Its product portfolio includes services such as Network Security,
Networking and Communications, Cloud Security, Zero Trust Access and FortiGuard
Security, Secure SD-WAN, Fortinet Security Fabric and others.</p>



<p>In April 2022, the company announced new
features of FortisOS 7.2 which unifies the convergence of networking and
security across NGFW, SD-WAN, LAN Edge, 5G, ZTNA.</p>



<h4>1.1.7&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/cisco-systems-inc">Cisco</a></h4>



<p>Founded in 1984 and headquartered in San Jose,
California, United States, Cisco is a technology conglomerate which offers
cloud-based cybersecurity solutions. It provides solutions such as SD-WAN
Security, Cisco Secure Application, Secure Data Center, Cisco Umbrella Mobile Protect and
others. The solutions are designed to prevent malware and phishing attacks
through predictive threat
intelligence based on ML and statistical analysis of data. It also offers
a secure infrastructure, Cisco SecureX which combines solutions such as SASE,
XDR, and zero trust.</p>



<p>Cisco entered a strategic partnership with
Comcast. Comcast is intending to explore new security frameworks such as SASE
and zero trust, which integrates SD-WAN with advanced security solutions, in
order to secure business infrastructure.</p>



<h4>1.1.8&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
Bitdefender</h4>



<p>Bitdefender was founded in 2001 and is
headquartered in Bucharest, Romania. The company offers cybersecurity solutions
to various sectors including telecom, energy and utilities, banking and
technology sector. The company’s telecom product portfolio consists of Cloud
and Server Security, Gravity Business Security Enterprise, Managed Detection
and Response Services and Gravity Zone Security for Workstations. These
solutions are based on ML and automatically detect and prevent advanced cyber threats.</p>



<p>In April 2022, Bitdefender announced its
enhanced Premium VPN Services. The enhanced features included encryption for
all web traffic, built-in ad blocker, anti-tracker and addition of whitelist
trusted websites.</p>



<h4>1.1.9&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/imperva">Imperva</a></h4>



<p>Imperva is cybersecurity service provider which
was founded in 2002 and is headquartered in San Mateo, California, United
States. The company offers protection against DDoS and botnet attacks amongst
other network security services. The product portfolio includes Application Security,
Data Security, Network Security, Cloud-Native Security and Security Automation.</p>



<h4>1.1.10&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Verizon</h4>



<p>Founded in 2000, Verizon is headquartered in New
York, United States. Verizon is a telecom network operator and offers cybersecurity solutions
along with its other services. The cybersecurity portfolio includes Mobile
Device &amp; Endpoint Security, Network &amp; cloud security, Cyber risk management, Web
Security through firewall and Bot Management among other solutions.</p>



<p>Verizon partnered with Atos in order to power
intelligent IoT solutions with private 5G multi-access edge computing for
various critical operations. The solution “5G Edge Solution “developed by the
two companies is supposed to manage the operational efficiency, mitigate risk
and increase revenue.</p>



<h4>Conclusion</h4>



<p>The cybersecurity
landscape is continuously evolving and with 5G rollouts in place several new
security challenges will arise. The modern network architecture will offer
malicious actors with numerous ways to infiltrate the system, therefore with
proper understanding of the cybersecurity challenges associated with 5G
deployment, organizations can effectively optimize their network configurations
and manage data security. Strategies such as Zero Trust and Network Slicing
should be considered as the key for a robust cybersecurity framework in the
telecom industry. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-telecom-industry/">Cybersecurity Trends in Telecom Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cybersecurity-trends-in-telecom-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 15 AI-enabled cybersecurity companies in 2022</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-15-ai-enabled-cybersecurity-companies-in-2022/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-15-ai-enabled-cybersecurity-companies-in-2022/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 06:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2802</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Technology advancements are fueled by severe competition, which forces every supplier to include new ideas to stay ahead of the competition. As more new and innovative businesses enter the market, the demand for new approaches grows even more. Cybersecurity is a very busy topic right now, with new approaches and attack protection strategies sprouting daily. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-15-ai-enabled-cybersecurity-companies-in-2022/">Top 15 AI-enabled cybersecurity companies in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Technology advancements are
fueled by severe competition, which forces every supplier to include new ideas
to stay ahead of the competition. As more new and innovative businesses enter
the market, the demand for new approaches grows even more. Cybersecurity is a
very busy topic right now, with new approaches and attack protection strategies
sprouting daily. Artificial Intelligence (AI) has begun to appear in a variety
of IT products, including cybersecurity, as a result of the advancement of AI
methodologies. At the forefront of cybersecurity, an elite group of
forward-thinking companies are using artificial intelligence (AI) in their
products to defeat attackers and win clients.</p>



<p>The integration of cutting-edge technology like artificial intelligence and computer vision into IoT devices has resulted in a huge increase in cybersecurity measures. Several <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity companies</a> are gaining traction in the fight against corporate intrusions. Various cybersecurity vendors that use artificial intelligence to defend internet-connected systems or other IoT devices exist. Artificial intelligence and machine learning can enhance a company&#8217;s cybersecurity by constantly monitoring for suspicious activity and resolving the problem before it becomes a big issue. To beat attackers and attract customers, an elite group of inventive <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity companies</a> is incorporating artificial intelligence into their products.</p>



<p><strong>The leading AI <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity
vendors</a> </strong></p>



<p>The cybersecurity sector has been
changed by machine learning and flexible workflows. Here are the specifics on
how each of the key players is contributing to this progress –</p>



<ol><li>FireEye</li><li>Fortinet</li><li>Webroot</li><li>Check Point</li><li>Darktrace</li><li>Sophos</li><li>Cylance</li><li>Symantec</li><li>CrowdStrike
</li><li>Vectra</li><li>SAP
National Security Services, Inc. (SAP NS2)</li><li>Vade
Secure</li><li>Cynet
</li><li>Callsign</li><li>Blue
Hexagon</li></ol>



<ol><li><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/fireeye-inc">FireEye</a></strong></li></ol>



<p>FireEye, which
was founded in 2004, delivers threat intelligence technology that provides
context and prioritizes attacks, allowing it to proactively protect against
future threats. Threat detection, prevention, and response are all part of
FireEye&#8217;s comprehensive platform of services and intelligence. The company has
expanded into the manufacture of cybersecurity technologies that employ AI to
monitor networks and discover anomalies as a result of innovation and
acquisitions. This strategy, together with the transition from a fee-based to a
subscription-based Software-as-a-Service model, has made the company profitable
and changed what was beginning to appear to be an overvalued novelty into a
sought-after investment. To protect customers from cyber-attacks, FireEye now
offers a full portfolio of security solutions, intelligence, and services.</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/fortinet-inc">Fortinet</a></strong></li></ul>



<p>Fortinet,
founded in California, combines automated, self-healing networks with Al-driven
security for quick and efficient operations. Fortinet&#8217;s AI capabilities include
analyzing billions of cyber-attacks and sending intelligence based on that
analysis to its clients via its FortiGuard Labs. FortiWeb, their AI-based
firewall, detects threats with unprecedented precision using machine learning
and two levels of statistical probabilities.</p>



<p>The Fortinet
Security Fabric platform protects many of the world&#8217;s major enterprises,
service providers, and government agencies. As the security fabric&#8217;s core
analytical engine, the business created an AI-based Self-Evolving Detection
System (SEDS). To be able to activate automatic defense operations to block any
detected threats, the defense mechanism needs access to network resources such
as firewall rules and operating systems.</p>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/webroot-inc">Webroot</a></strong></li></ul>



<p>Webroot uses
artificial intelligence to block zero-day threats in real-time, offering threat
intelligence to businesses around the world and endpoint and network
protection. The company uses AI to combat phishing assaults and malware,
particularly JavaScript malware, as well as other online threats such as
botnets. To broaden its awareness of the threat landscape, Webroot&#8217;s machine
learning capabilities provide greater insight into why particular attacks are
problematic.</p>



<p>Other phishing
solutions exist to detect a phishing site; many of them are based on metadata
or URLs, relying on the classic list-based approach. To detect a phishing site,
other organizations look for patterns in the URL. Webroot&#8217;s phishing solution,
on the other hand, works in real-time, allowing it to open the URL and stop it
there.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Check
Point</strong></li></ul>



<p>Check Point is
a renowned cyber security solution supplier. Intellistore, Check Point&#8217;s fully
customizable platform, is one of the most comprehensive and easy single-point
control systems available, allowing users to select real-time threat
intelligence that best meets their needs. This Israeli firm has long been a
pioneer in the application of artificial intelligence in cybersecurity. Check
Point provides its customers with the option of customizing threat intelligence
received via the IntelliStore platform, allowing for customized security
tailored to the needs of the business.</p>



<p>Rather than
developing a single AI-based threat management product, the company invested in
three AI-driven platforms that support several of the company&#8217;s major services.
Campaign Hunting, Huntress, and Context-Aware Detection are three of them
(CADET). Campaign Hunting is a centralized service that provides the most
up-to-date attack vectors and mitigation techniques to client-site threat
detection systems. The Huntress AI-based system analyses the performance and
behavior of the software in question and communicates any irregularities to
Check Point&#8217;s central system. The CADET AI engine collects event data in real-time,
allowing attackers to prevent attack paths that exploit seemingly unrelated
resources at the same time. The threat database is fine-tuned by CADET&#8217;s
unsupervised machine-learning function, which reduces debilitating false
positives. It establishes a digital security analyst and immediately initiates
preventative measures.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Darktrace</strong></li></ul>



<p>Darktrace, based
in the United Kingdom, was created by mathematicians in 2013. Thousands of
firms across a wide range of industries have used Darktrace&#8217;s technologies to
battle cyber-attacks in real-time. Darktrace&#8217;s services include machine
learning-based analysis of real-time company data. This enables the study of
any variations from normal behavior that could indicate that a company&#8217;s system
is in jeopardy. Darktrace detects and neutralizes threats across networks, the
cloud, and IoT using self-learning AI.</p>



<p>With its
Enterprise Immune System and Darktrace Antigena systems, Darktrace uses
artificial intelligence to identify a wide range of threats at their early
stages, including cloud-based vulnerabilities, insider attacks, and
state-sponsored espionage. Enterprise Immune System serves as a foundation for
all of the company&#8217;s cybersecurity offerings. EIS employs AI techniques and
uses unsupervised machine learning to populate status rule bases.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Sophos</strong></li></ul>



<p>Sophos, based in
the United Kingdom, offers a diverse range of innovative solutions and services
to protect users, networks, and endpoints against ransomware, malware,
exploits, and phishing. Sophos is a global leader in cybersecurity solutions
for the next generation. SophosLabs and SophosAI provide threat intelligence,
AI, and machine learning for this portfolio. Intercept X for endpoint
protection and the XG Firewall for network protection are the two key AI-based
Sophos products.</p>



<p>Intercept X
employs artificial intelligence to eliminate the requirement for a centralized
threat database. A deep learning neural network developed by Invincea, which
was acquired by Sophos in February 2017, is at the heart of the service. This
software keeps track of normal behavior on the protected device and sends out
notifications when something unusual happens. When exploits and viruses are
found, Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) sets in motion workflows and
actions to shut them down and isolate them. The XG firewall is a network hardware
device. Its dashboard provides information on current network events and
traffic, but its real value is in its automated response mechanisms, which
enforce security without the need for human participation.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Cylance</strong></li></ul>



<p>Cylance, a
BlackBerry Limited division, is said to be the first cybersecurity protection
provider to use artificial intelligence in its system. Malware, file-less
attacks, and zero-day payload attacks are among the dangers that BlackBerry
Cylance&#8217;s AI security technology safeguards against.</p>



<p>All of
Cylance&#8217;s products include artificial intelligence. Cylance Protect, Cylance
Optics, Cylance Threat Zero, and Cylance Smart Antivirus are the company&#8217;s
primary offerings. Endpoint security is provided by Cylance Protect.
Essentially, this is an AI-based anti-malware solution that searches for
changes in patterns of activity on the device rather than relying on an AV
provider&#8217;s threat list transmitted via the internet. This technology not only
monitors activity, but it also restricts access to the device. Cylance Optics
is Cylance Protect&#8217;s corporate version. Cylance Threat Zero is the company&#8217;s
consulting branch. Another AI-based antivirus product that is ideal for home
users and small companies is Cylance Smart Antivirus.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Symantec</strong></li></ul>



<p>Symantec, currently
known as NortonLifeLock, assists a wide spectrum of enterprises in protecting
their infrastructures against threats. Symantec has used artificial
intelligence (AI) to broaden its threat detection and prevention efforts.
Symantec&#8217;s AI-powered security services include everything from endpoint
protection to email and cloud application defense.</p>



<p>Accenture
Security bought Symantec’s cyber security from Broadcom in January 2020, making
it one of the major providers of managed security services and boosting its
ability to help businesses predict, detect, and respond to cyber threats more
quickly. The Symantec Targeted Attack Analytics (TAA) program models network
behavior and creates a baseline of performance using unaided machine learning.
Any deviation from the norm sets off an alarm. TAA&#8217;s AI functionalities are
built on top of the Symantec Cyber Defense Platform, which can collect
performance data from several points across the network at the same time. TAA
is now only available in the Symantec Advanced Threat Protection family of
products, but it will most likely be included in all Symantec cybersecurity
packages in the future.</p>



<ul><li><strong>CrowdStrike
Holdings Inc.</strong></li></ul>



<p>CrowdStrike was
founded in 2011. Three of the top 10 global firms by revenue are among
Crowdstrike&#8217;s clientele. Crowdstrike is a company that makes cloud-based
endpoint protection software. The CrowdStrike Falcon system, also known as user
and entity behavior analytics, is an AI-based detection system (UEBA). The UEBA
concept is one of the most significant advances in the system security
business, allowing it to escape the defective AV detection approach that was
allowing too many new viruses onto systems.</p>



<p>The Falcon
platform employs artificial intelligence to provide users with better
visibility and protection throughout their whole business, with a focus on
preventing endpoint threats. Falcon goes beyond simple threat detection by
researching abnormalities automatically, taking the guessing out of threat
analysis. CrowdStrike can provide real-time security, actionable threat
intelligence, and managed threat hunting around the clock with Falcon.
Crowdstrike offers a unique technique for detecting hacked systems that
incorporates a lot of machine learning. The AI technique used by CrowdStrike
monitors all activity on an endpoint, analyzing each user&#8217;s activity and
keeping track of all system operations that execute on a daily basis.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Vectra</strong></li></ul>



<p>Vectra Networks
Inc is a cybersecurity software company that was founded in 2010. For the
cloud, data center, IoT, and organizations, Vectra AI provides AI-driven threat
detection and response. The Cognito technology from Vectra combines human
intelligence, data science, and machine learning to detect threats in real-time.
It also automates security procedures that would otherwise be performed by
analysts, cutting down on the amount of time it takes to examine threats.
Cognito is a threat detection system that uses artificial intelligence (AI) to
create a baseline of activity throughout an organization and spot anomalies. The
system isn&#8217;t unified threat management or an intrusion prevention system
because it doesn&#8217;t include automatic reactions to recognized threats.</p>



<ul><li><strong>SAP National Security Services, Inc. (SAP NS2)</strong></li></ul>



<p>SAP NS2 is a
wholly owned subsidiary of SAP, a global enterprise software company that
provides a full suite of SAP enterprise applications, analytics, database,
cyber security, cloud, and mobile software solutions, as well as specialized
levels of security and support to meet the mission requirements of US national security
and critical infrastructure customers. SAP NS2 is a cybersecurity system that
uses data analytics and fusion technologies. AI and machine learning are also
used by corporation to defend cloud platforms for a variety of customers. SAP
NS2 AI and ML technology assist security professionals in processing large
amounts of data and protecting sensitive information as it travels across
several locations.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Vade Secure</strong></li></ul>



<p>Vade Secure is
one of the world&#8217;s largest email defense firms, using artificial intelligence
and machine learning to defend over 600 million mailboxes in 76 countries
against advanced threats such as spear phishing, ransomware, and malware. It
assists MSPs and SMBs in defending their Office 365 subscribers against
sophisticated email threats. To safeguard inboxes all around the world, Vade
Secure will continue to invest in an AI-based threat detection engine. The
company intends to expand its position as an industry leader in email security
for ISPs.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Cynet </strong></li></ul>



<p>Cynet uses
artificial intelligence in its network threat detection systems, which analyze
threats and act automatically. Cynet believes that advanced threat protection
should be as simple to use as any other system monitoring tool. Cynet 360 is a
cybersecurity software that uses artificial intelligence to automate and
centralize breach defense.</p>



<p>Cynet 360 is a
comprehensive cybersecurity solution that encompasses everything from antivirus
endpoint protection to device detection, threat prediction, user behavior
modeling, and vulnerability management. A discovery phase of the system is used
to discover all network devices and endpoints using standard network topology
mapping methodologies. The system examines event logs and traffic patterns to
create a baseline model of typical network activity. Organizations without
specialized cybersecurity workers might benefit from the Cynet network
protection suite, which provides easy-to-use threat protection.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Callsign</strong></li></ul>



<p>Callsign
employs artificial intelligence and machine learning to verify a person&#8217;s
identification based on a swipe on a touchscreen, the number of keystrokes on a
keyboard, the number of locations visited, and other actions. Thousands of data
points, including behavioral, device, locational, and telecoms, are collected
by the platform to correlate identification attributes, which are then combined
with threat analysis information to confirm that the data has not been hacked.</p>



<p>Intelligence-driven
authentication, Callsign&#8217;s trademark platform, integrates multi-factor
authentication with fraud analytics powered by deep learning technology to
combat fraudulent activity ranging from identity fraud to SMS phishing. Other
authentication businesses may employ artificial intelligence to detect fraud,
whereas Callsign generates individual identity profiles. Because no two people
are alike, the organization does not use general predictive models.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Blue Hexagon</strong></li></ul>



<p>Customers can
get real-time network threat prevention from Blue Hexagon, which can detect
threats in less than a second. Blue Hexagon employs artificial intelligence to
generate malware based on global threat data and the dark web, all in the name
of putting its systems to the test and pushing its capabilities to their
limits. Blue Hexagon&#8217;s technologies function in networks and the cloud,
protecting against a wide range of attacks on a variety of platforms.</p>



<p>Blue Hexagon
firewalls and controls can&#8217;t keep up with changing threats since they need to
know what&#8217;s dangerous before they can block it. The key problem that Blue
Hexagon solves here is using AI and machine learning to look at risks coming
in, even if they are unknown, and mark them immediately. That allows us to deal
with a million different things every day, which is what is driving all of the
breaches.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-15-ai-enabled-cybersecurity-companies-in-2022/">Top 15 AI-enabled cybersecurity companies in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-15-ai-enabled-cybersecurity-companies-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Cybersecurity Companies You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/21-cybersecurity-companies-you-need-to-know/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/21-cybersecurity-companies-you-need-to-know/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 07:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[360Quadrants]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2795</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity guards against cyber-attacks on Internet-connected systems, including hardware, software, and data. It encompasses the complete range of vulnerability reduction, threat reduction, recovery policies, and operations by focusing on people, processes, and technologies. Cybersecurity also covers computer network operations, information security, and law enforcement, among other things. These services have grown increasingly important to businesses, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/21-cybersecurity-companies-you-need-to-know/">21 Cybersecurity Companies You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cybersecurity guards against cyber-attacks on
Internet-connected systems, including hardware, software, and data. It
encompasses the complete range of vulnerability reduction, threat reduction,
recovery policies, and operations by focusing on people, processes, and technologies.</p>



<p>Cybersecurity also covers computer network operations, information security, and law enforcement, among other things. These services have grown increasingly important to businesses, regardless of their industry. Because everyone can be a victim of cybercrime nowadays, using the services of cybersecurity vendors is unquestionably a sensible investment. The following is a hand-curated list of the <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">Top CyberSecurity Companies</a>. There is both open-source (free) and commercial (paid) software on the list.</p>



<p><strong>1) CHECK
POINT SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGIES LTD</strong></p>



<p>Check Point Software Technologies offers
best-in-class cybersecurity solutions to protect against malware, ransomware,
and other types of assaults on systems. This company provides solutions for cloud, network, and
mobile device security to government and commercial organizations. It also
provides solutions for various types of businesses and has a multi-level
security architecture.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel</p>



<p>Established: 1993</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 5001-10000</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $1 Billion</p>



<p>Cybersecurity services: Cloud security, Network
security, Mobile security, and Security management.</p>



<p><strong>2) CISCO</strong></p>



<p>Cisco offers IT, networking, and cybersecurity
solutions. They offer Internet security services to businesses of all sizes.
The company&#8217;s major focus is on protecting your digital assets and sensitive
data.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: San Jose, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1984</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 40,000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $49 Billion</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: Firewall, Cloud Security, Malware
protection, Email security, Multi-factor authentication Endpoint, etc.</p>



<p><strong>3) CIPHER CIS</strong></p>



<p>Cipher CIS is a cybersecurity consultancy
that offers comprehensive, white-glove protection for businesses. This cyber
security service provider company combines deep cyber expertise with a thorough
understanding of physical and IoT security to create a one-of-a-kind offering.
They provide companies and families with trustworthy protection based on the
most innovative solutions, and they have a global presence in 25 countries.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Miami, Florida, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2000</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 201-500 employees</p>



<p>Annual Income: $20-$50 Million per year</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: Managed Security Services, Cyber
Intelligence Services, Managed Detection and Response, Governance Risk and
Compliance, and Cybersecurity Technology Integration.</p>



<p><strong>4) PALO ALTO
NETWORKS</strong></p>



<p>Palo Alto Networks is a computer security
service company that uses analytics to automate everyday actions to keep
hackers out. Cortex, Palo Alto&#8217;s AI-based continuous security technology, is
also available.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Santa Clara, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2005</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 7000+</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Palo Alto Networks assist you in
cloud security, advanced firewall, endpoint protection, and threat detection
and prevention. </p>



<p><strong>5) VIPRE</strong></p>



<p>Vipre is a cybersecurity solutions provider
that provides unrivaled protection against today&#8217;s most dangerous internet
threats. Security awareness training is also available through this online
cybersecurity firm.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Los Angeles, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1994</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 51-200</p>



<p>Annual Income: $18 M per year</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: Network Protection, Endpoint
Protection, Email Protection, User and Data Protection, etc.</p>



<p><strong>6) IBM</strong></p>



<p>IBM is a cybersecurity service provider that
provides computer hardware, software, and middleware, as well as hosting and
consulting. This company provides cybersecurity solutions to the federal
government of the United States.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Armonk, New York, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1911</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 10,000+ employees</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $79 Billion.</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Mobile Security, Biometrics, Situational
awareness and response, and easy access management.</p>



<p><strong>7) MCAFEE</strong></p>



<p>McAfee is a leading network security company
that provides protection for a variety of industries. McAfee also provides
cybersecurity for devices and the cloud. They provide cybersecurity services to
both consumers and enterprises. </p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Santa Clara, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1987</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 10,000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $2 Billion.</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Network Security, Endpoint
Protection, Anti-Virus, Server Security, Security Management, Database
Security, Data Protection &amp; Encryption, etc.</p>



<p><strong>8) MICROSOFT</strong></p>



<p>Microsoft also provides intelligent security
solutions as well as cloud security benefits. Their cybersecurity services
assist you in protecting yourself from spyware, malware, and other dangerous
software.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Redmond, Washington, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1975</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 10,000 + employees</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $110 Billion.</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: &nbsp;Microsoft&#8217;s cloud infrastructure and services,
as well as its own devices and products, as well as its own corporate resources,
aids in the detection of dangers and the recovery from incidents.</p>



<p><strong>9) AMAZON</strong></p>



<p>Amazon is a firm that specializes in
e-commerce, AI, and cybersecurity. This computer security service company also
provides data center and network design with cloud security.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Seattle, Washington, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1994</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $177 Billion.</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: Infrastructure security, Data
Encryption, Identity, and Penetration testing.</p>



<p><strong>10) CYBERARK
SOFTWARE</strong></p>



<p>CyberArk Software develops software that aids
in the removal of cyber threats. This network security service provider
provides technologies such as Password Vault and Identity Manager to help you
protect your information assets, infrastructure, and applications.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Newton, Massachusetts, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1999</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $261 Million.</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 1001-5000 employees</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Security &amp; Risk Management
for Cloud &amp; DevOps, Access Security, Application Identity Manager, etc.</p>



<p><strong>11) SYMANTEC
ENTERPRISE</strong></p>



<p>NortonLifeLock, formerly known as Symantec,
is a cybersecurity vendor
that helps enterprises, governments, and individuals protect their data,
regardless of where it resides. Through endpoints, cloud, and infrastructure,
this Internet security service provider protects against complex and deadly
assaults.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Mountain View, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 1982</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 10,000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $2.49 Billion</p>



<p>Cybersecurity Services: Information Protection,
Endpoint, Email Security, Advanced Threat Protection, Network security, and
Cloud security.</p>



<p><strong>12) IMPERVA</strong></p>



<p>Imperva secures your data and apps
on-premises or in the cloud. It also assists you in identifying, evaluating,
and mitigating current and prospective hazards. This cybersecurity firm assists
you in protecting over three million datasets and preventing thousands of app
attacks per second.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Redwood Shores, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2002</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 1001-5000 employees</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $321 Million</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Application Security &#8211; Web
Application Firewall, DDoS Protection, and Data Security -Data Protection, Data
Risk Analysis, File Security, and Vulnerability Discovery.</p>



<p><strong>13) PROOFPOINT</strong></p>



<p>Proofpoint is a cybersecurity company that delivers solutions to
the federal government for the financial and healthcare industries. They offer
a variety of cloud-based security solutions to protect against a variety of
threats, including those sent by email, social media, and mobile apps.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Sunnyvale, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2002.</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 1001-5000 employees</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $660 Million</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Cloud App Security, Digital Risk
Protection, Advanced Threat Protection, and Information Protection.</p>



<p><strong>14) FIREEYE</strong></p>



<p>FireEye is in <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity vendors</a> that provides a variety of security technologies. It also provides security evaluations, upgrades, and transformation services. FireEye assists you in creating an ecosystem of cutting-edge cybersecurity solutions.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Milpitas, California, United States</p>



<p>Annual Revenue: $941M</p>



<p>Established: 2004</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 3000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $779 Million</p>



<p>Cybersecurity solutions: Enterprise Security, Managed
Defense, and Threat Intelligence.</p>



<p><strong>15) KNOWBE4</strong></p>



<p>KnowBe4 is a cybersecurity tool that provides
phishing and ransomware training in a realistic environment. This network
security company provides tests and tools to help you detect weak passwords,
domain doppelgangers, and mail server security.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Clearwater, Florida, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2010</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 1000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: $174.9 M</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Network Security, Risk &amp;
Compliance, Internet Security Awareness Training, Ransomware Simulator,
Cybersecurity Webinars, and Cybersecurity Whitepapers.</p>



<p><strong>16) FORTINET</strong></p>



<p>Fortinet is listed in the <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software"><strong>cybersecurity companies</strong></a> that offers firewall, antivirus, intrusion prevention, and endpoint security solutions. This network security service provider provides consumers with effective cybersecurity and compliance solutions across all channels, including email, the web, the cloud, and social media.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Sunnyvale, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2000</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 5,000+</p>



<p>Annual Income: Around U.S. $1 Billion</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Multi-Cloud Security, Web
Application Security, Network security, Advanced Threat Protection, Endpoint
Security, Management, and Analytics.</p>



<p><strong>17) CROWDSTRIKE</strong></p>



<p>CrowdStrike is a cybersecurity company with
offices in the United States, Europe, and Asia. This cyber security service
provider company provides superior security, performance, and value. This
enables you to simplify the process of eliminating on-premises infrastructure
and consolidating end-points agents.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Sunnyvale, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2011</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 1001-5000 employees</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Threat intelligence, ransomware
blocking, next-generation antivirus, and endpoint detection and response are
among the company&#8217;s Internet security offerings.</p>



<p><strong>18) FIDELIS</strong></p>



<p>Fidelis Cybersecurity is a Bethesda,
Maryland-based cybersecurity firm. Their staff specializes in cybersecurity and
IT strategy, as well as computer security.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Bethesda, Maryland, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2002.</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 250 – 999 Employees</p>



<p>Project Size Minimum: $5,000+</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: They specialize in cybersecurity
and I.T. strategy consulting services such as threat detection and data loss
prevention. With dynamic Deception technology, you can cut down on dwell time.</p>



<p><strong>19) TESTARMY</strong></p>



<p>Testarmy is a quality assurance and software
testing firm based in Wroclaw, Poland. For small and midmarket businesses, they
offer cybersecurity services such as application testing, UX/UI design, and
cybersecurity services.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Wroclaw, Poland</p>



<p>Established: 2010</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: $1,000+</p>



<p>Project Size Minimum: $1,000+</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Cybersecurity, UX/UI Design, and
Application Testing services.</p>



<p><strong>20) SOPHOS</strong></p>



<p>Sophos is a global leader in information
technology security and data protection. They provide extensive network access
control and provide complete protection for enterprises by guarding against
known and unknown viruses, spam, data leakage, and offering comprehensive
network access control.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Abingdon, Oxford shire, England</p>



<p>Established: 1985</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 3,600+</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: IT Security, Endpoint Security, Mobile
Device Management, Email and Web Protection, Free Tools, Antivirus, Network
Security, and Server Protection.</p>



<p><strong>21) SUGARSHOT</strong></p>



<p>SugarShot is a technology firm based in Los
Angeles. The company primarily offers managed IT services, with a focus on
security, disaster recovery, and network segments.</p>



<p><strong>Figures of
Interest:</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Los Angeles, California, United States</p>



<p>Established: 2018</p>



<p>Employee Capacity: 10 – 49 Employees</p>



<p>Project Size Minimum: $5,000+</p>



<p>Product categories for cyber-security: Network Security, Dark Web
Scanning and Development, Security Audit, Security Reporting, Remote &amp;
Onsite Support.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/21-cybersecurity-companies-you-need-to-know/">21 Cybersecurity Companies You Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/21-cybersecurity-companies-you-need-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Businesses with Top Cybersecurity Companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/protecting-businesses-with-top-cybersecurity-companies/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/protecting-businesses-with-top-cybersecurity-companies/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 04:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2792</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Businesses are particularly vulnerable to large-scale data breaches that steal or corrupt sensitive information. As a result, we must act quickly to safeguard ourselves online. This is why, in recent years, cybersecurity has taken center stage. By 2024, the worldwide cybersecurity market is expected to be worth more than $300 billion. Enterprise-level enterprises account for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/protecting-businesses-with-top-cybersecurity-companies/">Protecting Businesses with Top Cybersecurity Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Businesses are particularly
vulnerable to large-scale data breaches that steal or corrupt sensitive
information. As a result, we must act quickly to safeguard ourselves online.
This is why, in recent years, cybersecurity has taken center stage. By 2024,
the worldwide cybersecurity market is expected to be worth more than $300
billion. Enterprise-level enterprises account for 60% of the market for
cybersecurity.</p>



<p>Cybercrime, a long-standing worry
for firms in every industry, is increasing in complexity and cunning, with the
possibility of bringing business to a halt. Cybersecurity solutions keep
essential data safe while limiting further risk and alleviating the burden on
internal IT workers as firms devote more operational power to their digital
transformation aspirations. We become more exposed to privacy threats as the
variety of new technology and platforms we use to conduct our digital lives
grows, from smartphone apps to cloud computing software to pacemakers.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">Top
Cybersecurity Companies</a></strong></p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/microsoft-corporation">Microsoft</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Redmond, Washington,
United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1975</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $110 Billion</p>



<p>Microsoft is a company that
produces computers, software, and consumer goods. Microsoft offers intelligent
security solutions as well as a security edge in the cloud. Microsoft&#8217;s
cybersecurity compliance and identity management solutions safeguard the entire
enterprise while allowing employees to work across platforms and cloud
environments. By developing a Zero Trust security architecture and checking
identities and device compliance for each access request, these solutions
reduce risks.</p>



<p>Microsoft Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics (ATA), Identity
and Access Management, UEBA, Threat Protection, Information Protection,
Security Management, Cloud Security, Microsoft Defender, Ddos Protection, and
Application Gateway.<strong><br>
</strong></p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/amazon-web-services-inc">Amazon
Web Services</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Seattle, Washington,
United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1994</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $177 Billion</p>



<p>Amazon is a firm that specializes
in e-commerce, cloud computing, AI, and computer hardware. Data centers and
network design benefit from Amazon&#8217;s cloud security. The AWS Trusted Advisor
will give you real-time information. AWS solutions identify threats by
continuously monitoring network and account activity in the user&#8217;s cloud
environment.</p>



<p>Amazon Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: AWS Security, Identity, and Compliance, Data
Encryption, AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM), Infrastructure security, Amazon
Cloud Directory, DDoS mitigation, Amazon Cognito, Amazon GuardDuty, and
Penetration testing.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/intel-corporation">McAfee</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Santa Clara,
California, United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1987</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $2 Billion</p>



<p>McAfee also offers cybersecurity
for devices and the cloud. Both consumers and organizations can benefit from
the security solutions. Endpoint and mobile security products from McAfee
protect end-user devices from malware, while network security products and
services safeguard enterprise servers, databases, and data centers. McAfee
offers security software for residential users to secure their mobile devices
and computers. McAfee also collaborates with governments all across the world,
using its McAfee Global Threat Intelligence to keep businesses, governments,
and consumers’ one step ahead of hackers.</p>



<p>McAfee Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: McAfee Complete Data Protection, McAfee Total
Protection for Data Loss Prevention, McAfee Device Control Database Security,
McAfee Security Scanner for Databases Endpoint Protection, McAfee Complete
Endpoint Protection, McAfee Active Response Network Security, McAfee Network
Security Platform, and McAfee Advanced Threat Defense Security Management<strong><br>
</strong></p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/palo-alto-networks-inc">Palo
Alto Networks</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Santa Clara,
California, United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 2005</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $2 Billion</p>



<p>Palo Alto offers cloud, network,
and mobile device cybersecurity solutions. The company&#8217;s core Security
Operating Platform uses analytics to automate regular activities and
enforcement, making security easier to manage so clients can focus on securing
users, apps, and data. Financial services and healthcare are among the
industries for which the platform is well-suited.</p>



<p>Palo Alto Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: Next-Generation Firewall, UEBA, Cloud Security,
Network Security, Zero Trust, Threat Detection and Prevention, Application
Framework, Endpoint Security, User and Entity Behavior Analytics (UEBA), Intrusion
Detection and Prevention Systems (IDPS), Extended Detection and Response (XDR),
Container and Kubernetes Security, and Iot Security.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/ibm-corporation">IBM</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Armonk, New York,
United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1911</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $79 Billion</p>



<p>IBM&#8217;s enterprise security
products, services, and solutions are among the most extensive and integrated
in the market. The technologies developed by IBM assist in the detection and
prevention of sophisticated attacks. It automatically detects and responds to
threats across the organization. IBM protects the entire enterprise network
from known and unknown threats. It also provides you with real-time visibility
and control over the operations of your app and its users. The IBM solution
increases total visibility and provides real-time information on Internet
threats.</p>



<p>IBM Core Cyber Security Product
and Services Categories: Situational Awareness And Response, Cognitive Security,
Mobile Security, Identity Access Management (IAM), Security Analytics, Patch
Management, Enhanced Fraud Detection, Cloud Security, Identity and Access
Management, Encryption, Application Security, SIEM, Security Orchestration,
Fraud Protection, Network Security, Mainframe Security, Data Protection, Threat
Intelligence, Application Security, Endpoint Protection, Identity and Access
Management, Authentication, Database Security, and Mainframe Security.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/malwarebytes">Malwarebytes
Inc</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Santa Clara,
California, United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 2008</p>



<p>Revenue: $180 Million</p>



<p>Malwarebytes Inc. is a
cybersecurity firm that protects users from malware, ransomware, threats, and
tainted websites. Malware and other threat protection for personal computers,
cellphones, and companies is the company&#8217;s specialty. One of the most
well-known and well-respected endpoint cleanup solutions is Malwarebytes
Incident Response. By reducing response times and enabling for speedy and
complete cleanup, the solution aids your company&#8217;s digital flexibility and
incident response process.</p>



<p>Malwarebytes Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: Malwarebytes All-In-One Protection, Cloud-Based
Security Modules, Security &amp; Antivirus, Cloud-Based Security Modules Anti-Rootkit
Scanner, Online Privacy, Next-Gen Antivirus For Small Businesses, Free Virus
Scanner, Vulnerability &amp; Patch Management, Free Spyware Scanner, Free
Trojan Scanner, Free Antivirus, Free Ad Blocker, Internet Security, and Anti
Ransomware Protection.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/fireeye-inc">Mandiant
Solutions</a></strong> <strong>(FireEye)</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Reston, Virginia, United
States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 2004</p>



<p>Revenue: $483 million</p>



<p>Mandiant Solutions makes security
products that protect against cyber-attacks from all angles. Threat Analytics
Platform (TAP) is a cloud-based cybersecurity technology that protects
sensitive data from a number of threats. TAP is a well-known name in the world
of cyber threat intelligence, and it aims to improve detection and event
investigation. It assists a company in meeting its security needs by
continuously monitoring and recognizing threats. It assists in threat detection
by generating alerts and conducting a quick response if threats are detected
across networks.</p>



<p>Mandiant Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: Network, Email Security, Mobile, Security
Management, Incident Response, Cloudvisory Security Solution, Threat
Intelligence, Helix Security Platform, MDR, Endpoint Security, Breach and
Attack Simulation, File Management and Storage, Email Security, Detection On
Demand, Network Security, and Forensics </p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/check-point-software-technologies-ltd">Check
Point Software Technologies Ltd</a> </strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Tel Aviv, Israel,
and San Carlos, California, United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1993</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $1 Billion</p>



<p>Check Point is a software and
hardware-software company that specializes in IT security, including network
security, endpoint security, cloud security, mobile security, data security,
and security management. It offers cloud, network, and mobile device security
solutions to government and business enterprises. It has a multi-level security
architecture and can be customized to fit any business size.</p>



<p>Check Point Software Core Cyber
Security Product and Services Categories: Network Security, Cloud Security, Mobile
Security, Endpoint Security, Security Management, Advanced Threat Prevention,
Next Generation Firewall, UTM, Encryption, Secure Gateway Appliances, Endpoint
Protection, Remote Access, Cloud Security, Mobile Security, Zero Trust, and
Incident Response.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/trend-micro-incorporated">Trend
Micro Inc</a>.</strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: Shibuya, Tokyo,
Japan</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1988</p>



<p>Revenue: $1.69 billion</p>



<p>Cloud settings, small and medium
organizations, networks, and data centers all benefit from Trend Micro&#8217;s
enterprise data protection and cybersecurity solutions. Trend Micro&#8217;s
enterprise data protection and cybersecurity solutions assist cloud
environments, small and medium businesses, networks, and data centers.</p>



<p>Trend Micro Core Cyber Security
Product and Services Categories: Network Security, Hybrid Cloud Security, Xgen,
User Security, Endpoint Security, Email Security, Encryption, Intrusion
Prevention, Iot Security, Threat Intelligence, Advanced Threat Protection, Deep
Security, Web Security, Extended Detection &amp; Response Capabilities, and Saas
Application Security.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/cisco-systems-inc">Cisco</a></strong></p>



<p>Headquarters: San Jose,
California, United States</p>



<p>Year Founded: 1984</p>



<p>Revenue: Around US $49 Billion</p>



<p>Cisco is a company that
specializes in IT, networking, and cybersecurity. Cisco cybersecurity solutions
keep track of devices, protect and automate processes, and process and manage
data. Cisco&#8217;s products are available to companies of all sizes. Its simple,
scalable, and comprehensive security solution protects your organization and
responds to advanced threats without interrupting your work. Small and midsized
businesses can rely on Cisco to protect their network infrastructure, manage
connected devices, and make better business decisions.

Cisco Core Cyber Security Product and Services Categories:
Cybersecurity Product Categories: Next-Generation Firewalls, Next-Generation
Intrusion Prevention, CASB, Web Gateway, NAC, Advanced Malware Protection,
Email Security, Endpoint Security, Cloud Security, Multi-Factor Authentication,
Security Management, VPN, and Security Services.



</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/protecting-businesses-with-top-cybersecurity-companies/">Protecting Businesses with Top Cybersecurity Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/protecting-businesses-with-top-cybersecurity-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide to the Top Cybersecurity Companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/a-complete-guide-to-the-top-cybersecurity-companies/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/a-complete-guide-to-the-top-cybersecurity-companies/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 06:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2785</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>In 2021, data breaches cost companies&#160;$4.24 million&#160;per incident. Can your company afford this huge hit? Probably not. You&#8217;ve worked hard to build your business from the ground up, so don&#8217;t let one data breach take it down. It&#8217;s always a good idea to have the best technology installed on all devices, such as top firewalls [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/a-complete-guide-to-the-top-cybersecurity-companies/">A Complete Guide to the Top Cybersecurity Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber1-1024x618.jpg" alt="Top Cybersecurity Companies" class="wp-image-2786" srcset="https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber1-1024x618.jpg 1024w, https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber1-300x181.jpg 300w, https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber1-768x463.jpg 768w, https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber1.jpg 1379w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>In 2021, data breaches cost companies&nbsp;<a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2021-07-28-IBM-Report-Cost-of-a-Data-Breach-Hits-Record-High-During-Pandemic" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$4.24
million</a>&nbsp;per incident.</p>



<p>Can your company afford this huge hit? Probably
not.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve worked hard to build your business from the
ground up, so don&#8217;t let one data breach take it down.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s always a good idea to have the best technology
installed on all devices, such as top firewalls and antivirus programs.
Having&nbsp;<a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/grc-software" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GRC software</a>&nbsp;helps as
well. But the best way to upgrade your online safety is to work with
cybersecurity companies, as they&#8217;ll have the expertise to keep you safe and
secure.</p>



<p>There are quite a few of them around, so it might
be difficult to whittle down your options. So keep reading for a guide to the
top cybersecurity companies around.</p>



<p><strong>IBM</strong></p>



<p>IBM is a household name that&#8217;s been around since
1911. Today,&nbsp;it&#8217;s present in over 171 countries, which is a testimony to
its success.</p>



<p>In 2020, Forrester recognized IBM as a leader in
global managed security services. This company is also a Level 1 MSSP
Competency Partner for Amazon Web Services (AWS).</p>



<p>It&#8217;s true that IBM focuses on a wider range of
technology, but ultimately, it also offers comprehensive cybersecurity services
that are tough to beat. They&nbsp;have&nbsp;services like data monitoring,
encryption, zero-trust services, application security, and more. And not only
that, but&nbsp;it&#8217;s also fantastic to partner with if you need enterprise
security services.</p>



<p>IBM has an online self-assessment test that&#8217;s easy
for companies to use. Add in their flexibility and power, and IBM is
practically unmatched in quality.</p>



<p><strong>McAfee</strong></p>



<p>McAfee&#8217;s another household name in cybersecurity,
seeing as the company&#8217;s been around since 1987. There&#8217;s a good chance that
you&#8217;ve used their individual antivirus solutions in your home. It should then
come as no surprise that McAfee also has cybersecurity solutions for
organizations and enterprises.</p>



<p>McAfee&#8217;s got great features in addition to
antivirus protection, such as gaming security, identity protection, and a
secure virtual private network (VPN). As for enterprise security, you&#8217;ll enjoy
integration with Microsoft Dynamics 365 and McAfee LiveSafe support for Samsung
computers.</p>



<p>McAfee has regular updates to its services to
ensure all current threats are covered.</p>



<p><strong>Microsoft</strong></p>



<p>Microsoft is already a big name in the tech space,
so naturally, it&#8217;s got its reach in cybersecurity as well. Because it&#8217;s such a
giant in this industry, Microsoft doesn&#8217;t disappoint with its capabilities.</p>



<p>For individual plans, you&#8217;ll get features like
parental controls and safe driving reports. And as for enterprise plans, you&#8217;ll
benefit from advanced threat protection, as well as file activity monitoring
and customizable access permissions.</p>



<p>Not only does Microsoft have top-of-the-line
cybersecurity features, but you&#8217;ll also get their handy programs bundled
together. For example, you&#8217;ll get Word, Excel, and PowerPoint. Additional
features include cloud storage and premium creative content.</p>



<p>Current customers say the 365 threat protection
tool is amazing. Not only is it cost-effective, but it has a wide variety of
defense mechanisms against the toughest of threats.</p>



<p><strong>VMware Carbon Black</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/355907/remote-work-persisting-trending-permanent.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">45%
of full-time</a>&nbsp;American employees worked from
home at least part of the time in 2021, and this trend won&#8217;t go away. In fact,
it&#8217;ll only increase, as more employers realize the importance of remote work.</p>



<p>Because of this, you&#8217;ll need endpoint security.
This is protection for your network when it&#8217;s accessed through remote devices
(e.g. smartphones, laptops, and other wireless devices).</p>



<p>VMware Carbon Black is focused completely on
endpoint security. Like many other companies in this article, it aims to
proactively find threats before they can cause havoc. This is done through
analyses of attackers&#8217; behavior patterns.</p>



<p>When looking at next-generation antivirus vendors,
VMware Carbon Black has the least false positives.</p>



<p><strong>KnowBe4</strong></p>



<p>An important part of cybersecurity is employee
awareness.&nbsp;The workforce acts as the first line of defense; if they know
what to look for, then things like antivirus software don&#8217;t even need to kick
in.</p>



<p>To provide your company with comprehensive
cybersecurity training, count on KnowBe4. In 2020, Forrester Research
recognized this company as a leader in security awareness. Considering the SEO started
the business in 2011 by hiring the world&#8217;s most wanted hacker (Kevin Mitnick),
you can bet that this company knows cybersecurity inside and out.</p>



<p>Not only does KnowBe4 have training modules, but it
also has a simulated phishing program. As with the other companies on this
list, it&nbsp;receives regular updates so you can have peace of mind knowing
that you&#8217;re staying on top of the latest threats.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re on the fence about starting a paid
account with this business, you can always start with a free demo. This will
allow you to see if their services fit your needs without a financial
commitment.</p>



<p><strong>Darktrace</strong></p>



<p>This English company focuses on the power of
artificial intelligence (AI). While yes, it&#8217;s important for humans to recognize
the warning signs of data breaches, Darktrace aims to harness AI so we don&#8217;t
have to do the heavy lifting.</p>



<p>This cybersecurity agency has developed an
Enterprise Immune System, which can detect and eliminate online threats, much
like human immune systems. This is thanks to its machine learning and AI, which
thoroughly understand how a company works and what threats to look for.</p>



<p>This is a piece of technology you want on your
side, especially if your organization is often targeted for cyberattacks.</p>



<p><strong>Choose From the Top
Cybersecurity Companies</strong></p>



<p>There&#8217;s a good selection of <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity companies</a> to work with. Each has its own strengths, which makes it a good idea to pick and choose those best for your company&#8217;s needs.</p>



<p>Creating a good mix of technology is vital to your
business&#8217;s success. Make sure your digital defenses are up to scratch by only
going with the best.</p>



<p>You now know about the best cybersecurity options
around. Upgrade your data security even further by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">signing
up</a>&nbsp;for 360Quadrants today. We&#8217;ve got the right software for your
company.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/a-complete-guide-to-the-top-cybersecurity-companies/">A Complete Guide to the Top Cybersecurity Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/a-complete-guide-to-the-top-cybersecurity-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber-Attacks in Corporate World – Banking, Manufacturing, IT and Telecommunications</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cyber-attacks-in-corporate-world-banking-manufacturing-it-and-telecommunications/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cyber-attacks-in-corporate-world-banking-manufacturing-it-and-telecommunications/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 06:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2783</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cyber-attacks have been ranked as the sixth most dangerous threat, and they have become the new normal in both the public and private sectors. In 2022, this dangerous industry will continue to grow, with IoT cyber-attacks alone anticipated trebling by 2025. As a result of the COVID-19 epidemic, cybercrime has increased 600%, including everything from [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cyber-attacks-in-corporate-world-banking-manufacturing-it-and-telecommunications/">Cyber-Attacks in Corporate World – Banking, Manufacturing, IT and Telecommunications</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cyber-attacks have been ranked as the sixth most dangerous
threat, and they have become the new normal in both the public and private
sectors. In 2022, this dangerous industry will continue to grow, with IoT
cyber-attacks alone anticipated trebling by 2025. As a result of the COVID-19
epidemic, cybercrime has increased 600%, including everything from theft and
embezzlement to data hacking and destruction. Almost every industry has been
compelled to embrace new ideas, forcing businesses to adapt swiftly.</p>



<p>Around the world, today&#8217;s digital world faces tremendous challenges and cybercrime. Cybercrime is expected to cost businesses globally $10.5 trillion per year by 2025, up from $3 trillion in 2015. <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">Cybersecurity vendors</a> also claim that cybercrime constitutes the greatest transfer of economic value in history, with a growth rate of 15% year over year.</p>



<p><strong>Cyber Attacks by
Industry</strong></p>



<p>Some industries are more vulnerable to cyber-attacks than
others due to the nature of their business. While any company is vulnerable to
a data leak, organizations that are intimately intertwined with people&#8217;s daily
lives are particularly vulnerable. Hackers frequently target companies that
store sensitive data or personally-identifying information. The following
businesses are the most vulnerable to cyber-attacks:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber.png" alt="Cyber Incidents by Industry " class="wp-image-2784" srcset="https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber.png 614w, https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber-150x150.png 150w, https://blog.360quadrants.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/cyber-298x300.png 298w" sizes="(max-width: 614px) 100vw, 614px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity in the
Banking and Financial Services Sector </strong></p>



<p>The financial services industry is one of the most vulnerable
to cyber-attacks. Cyber-attacks are roughly three times more common in this
industry than any other. Customer data is sensitive and reveals a lot of
information about transactions; if it falls into the wrong hands, fraud is
immediately pursued, posing a serious threat to your personal information.</p>



<p>Malicious code and software are being used by cybercriminals
to change computer code, logic, or data, causing disruption. Millions of users&#8217;
financial information are being stored in the Bank&#8217;s database. It&#8217;s crucial to
understand that data from hard drives can be exploited in cybercrime. To make
money, cybercriminals use extortion, theft, and deception. Banks are constantly
under threat from malevolent occurrences. </p>



<p>The increased use of IoT-connected devices and sensor-based
technology is also introducing new possibilities for cyber-attacks to occur.
Cybercriminals typically utilize cloud-based botnets to take over processing
power, exploit Near Field Communications, cloud-based Distributed Denial of
Service (DD0oS) attacks, and multifactor authentication hacking.</p>



<p>A financial institution&#8217;s weakest link is its end-users.
Phishing (email, VOIP), malware (drive-by or targeted), and other security
flaws expose them to an unlimited attack surface. Everyone appears to be moving
away from cash in favor of digital money, such as debit and credit cards. A
shoddy cybersecurity system might easily cost you time and money in the form of
card cancellations, statement checks, and keeping a lookout for problems.</p>



<p>Blockchain technology has the potential to be extremely
beneficial to the banking and finance industries, as it has the potential to
cut bank infrastructure expenses. When compared to alternative database-driven
structures, they also provide higher security because there is no &#8216;hackable&#8217;
entrance or a single point of failure.</p>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity Threats
in Banking and Finance Sector</strong></p>



<ul><li>Unencrypted
Data &#8211; Because of insufficient encryption, sensitive data is exposed, and
stolen data is quickly accessible after it is stolen.</li><li>New
automation technology without security &#8211; If not protected, automation
technology such as CCTV cameras, connected devices, and toys can be turned into
bots.</li><li>Unprotected
Third-Party Services — Cyber attackers are more likely to gain access to
sensitive data through unprotected third-party services.</li><li>Unsecured
Mobile banking &#8211; The use of mobile phones in the banking industry is on the
rise. Because mobile devices have less complicated security systems,
specialists can obtain data from them.</li><li>New
Types of Hacking &#8211; Hackers don&#8217;t merely destroy data from consumers; they also
alter it or keep it captive for later use. Hackers are now employing new
methods to gain access to financial information.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Cyber Security
Threat in Manufacturing </strong></p>



<p>Any manufacturing process can be vulnerable to a security
compromise, especially when the amount of connection in modern production
environments is high. Manufacturing cyber security threats could include
proprietary information, unique formulae for generating a product faster,
product location identification, which could be used to steal merchandise
during shipment, loss of market control, and more. Because manufacturers rely
on profit margins to stay afloat, each of these scenarios results in an
increase in the price of the product for consumers. Consumers may end up paying
more for the identical product as a result of this process. Customers can place
orders for products online, and the manufacturer keeps track of their billing
information. Customer information is subject to cyber-attacks if the
manufacturer does not have adequate security measures.</p>



<p>Even if their processes are not immediately integrated with
the Internet, manufacturers must be considered a fully integrated setting. Many
breaches begin in IT networks and then spread to other sections of the
environment via connected devices. Furthermore, information on the
non-connected process may be included in some linked devices.</p>



<p>Manufacturers must go above and beyond in terms of developing
or updating cyber security rules, and they must avoid misunderstandings about
the organization&#8217;s needs. Security policies that are deemed unrealistic or
unlikely to occur are frequently avoided. In reality, hackers are more likely
to target unlikely places of vulnerability. As a result, manufacturers must
develop a novel cyber security policy scenario.</p>



<p>Cyberattacks have resulted in losses for major manufacturing
enterprises. A single breach ruins the entire perception of trust and rapport
with clients, as well as the possibility of losing important knowledge
regarding key manufacturing processes, particularly sensitive information.
Locating their own surface attack is also proving problematic for
manufacturers. Manufacturing facilities can be found in a variety of countries
and continents.</p>



<p>Manufacturing-related cybercrime is intended to either steal
intellectual property (IP) or cause physical interruption to a company&#8217;s
activities. These disturbances can cause severe material damage, resulting in
costly repair costs and downtime. Product ideas to digital printouts, trade
secrets to proprietary manufacturing techniques are all examples of
intellectual property (IP), and stolen IP can be very appealing to competitors.</p>



<p>As smaller and mid-sized manufacturers become aware of
cyber-attacks in the digital age of the Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT)
and Industry 4.0, adopting an attitude of &#8220;us against them&#8221; is
probably not a terrible idea. Mid-sized businesses are frequently targeted by
hackers as an entry point into a larger target.</p>



<p>Many manufacturing companies are struggling to keep up with
larger enterprises&#8217; advanced security technologies, security best practices,
and massive IT teams, leaving them vulnerable to trade secrets, intellectual
property, sensitive data loss, financial fraud, and business disruptions.
Manufacturing businesses must consider periodic vulnerability checks, provide
assistance on resolving vulnerabilities, and apply updates depending on
business risk in order to keep up with the competition.</p>



<p><strong>The Top Cyber Threats
for Manufacturing Companies </strong></p>



<p><strong>Phishing Attacks</strong> &#8211; Phishing is one of the most
well-known and widely used cybercrime strategies. Phishing emails in commercial
businesses frequently appear to come from within the company or from a company
that is likely to conduct business with the company. These emails appear
official, contain all of the appropriate logos, and can urge employees to offer
hackers a discrete access point into the network with a single click.
Unfortunately, this is merely the beginning of the threat. Once threat actors
get access to an organization&#8217;s network, they can typically travel discreetly
through it until they find information that allows them to carry out an attack.</p>



<p><strong>Ransomware</strong> &#8211; Ransomware is a type of malware
that encrypts network files and renders them unusable until hackers&#8217; demands
are met. If a ransom (sometimes millions of dollars) is not paid, these threat
actors may threaten to sell or leak important data. Another method by which
ransomware users attack manufacturing organizations is to make the company&#8217;s
network inaccessible until the ransom is paid. The downtime puts high pressure
on manufacturing organizations, this strategy is highly effective in this
industry.</p>



<p><strong>Internal Breaches</strong> &#8211; While external actors are
responsible for the majority of cyberattacks, workers and other staff with
access to the organization account for approximately 30% of all attacks. These
attacks, like those carried out by external hackers, are frequently motivated
by financial gain. However, out of rage or unhappiness, some current or former
employees commit attacks against a corporation. Internal threat actors do not
require network access. Instead, they can access sensitive data by using their
existing knowledge or credentials. With existing credentials, a threat actor is
more likely to carry out an attack discreetly and undetected. Unfortunately, if
passwords or entry methods aren&#8217;t changed to prevent such attacks, even past
employees can often acquire access.</p>



<p><strong>Equipment Sabotage</strong> &#8211; Manufacturing organizations can
profit from operational technology (OT) in a variety of ways. Unfortunately,
hackers may be able to exploit additional vulnerabilities as a result. OT
gadgets aren&#8217;t a new concept. They are, however, unfamiliar with current
communication systems&#8217; external connection technology. Previously, these
gadgets did not require security measures to keep them safe from outside
dangers. Regrettably, this implies that manufacturing companies continue to use
them with the same security flaws. While there are significant concerns about
assaults that use OT devices to obtain access to a network, the dangers
associated with equipment sabotage are far more serious. When devices are
managed and controlled through the use of linked devices, malevolent attackers
with the purpose to make equipment behave in a destructive manner might cause
damage.</p>



<p><strong>IP Theft</strong> &#8211; Theft of intellectual property
(IP) is a type of data theft that is more likely to go unnoticed than data
theft from customers. Nonetheless, it is a serious crime that can cause
enormous damage to a firm. Your business owns the intellectual property that
distinguishes your products or services. That data can be useful in a variety
of situations. The risks of potential IP theft are increasing as cyberattackers
learn new ways to join a network undetected and move laterally throughout the
system. Hackers can mine the information they require invisibly over time and
even leave the system without being detected. This can result in data being
stolen or altered without your knowledge until your company&#8217;s trade secrets are
exploited.</p>



<p><strong>Supply Chain Attacks</strong> &#8211; Attacks on supply chains damage
one link in a company&#8217;s supply chain, causing a major disruption that can
affect thousands of people. Long supply lines and fragmented security measures
make manufacturing organizations particularly vulnerable to supply chain
threats. Hackers can obtain access to major corporations through partners and
suppliers using a variety of weak endpoints. Attacks on supply chains are a
double-edged sword since, once the major company is forced to shut down
operations, any company it supplies is similarly impacted within days of the
initial attack.</p>



<p><strong>Nation-State Attacks</strong> &#8211; Nation-state attacks are
cyberattacks carried out by the government or threat actors employed by the
government of another country. They are among the most feared cyberattacks
today. The motivation for these attacks might range from monetary gain to
intellectual property theft of defense weaponry, as well as personal vendettas.
Hackers are on the lookout for any information that will help their country&#8217;s
economy and boost vital business and military initiatives. Government
institutions, important infrastructure, and nearly any industry with sensitive
data have all been targeted by nation-state hackers. For various reasons,
nation-state attacks are extremely risky. Threat actors from nation-states are
well-funded, well-trained, and have access to high-tech equipment, making them
more difficult to detect. Many manufacturing companies are interested in these
attacks because of international trade tensions and rising competition for key
goods.</p>



<p><strong>Cyber-Crime in IT
and Telecommunications sector</strong></p>



<p>Cybercrime is a type of online crime that occurs through the
use of computers and the internet. It is one among the world&#8217;s fastest
expanding illicit activities. Cybercrime is the theft of confidential
information maintained on the internet. Hackers employ a variety of techniques
to gain access to the computer system. Hacking, the transmission of harmful
viruses and malicious online content, online scams and fraud, identity theft,
computer system attacks, and unlawful or prohibited online content are all
examples of cybercrime.</p>



<p>Information security refers to the safeguarding of data and
information systems against unauthorized access, assessment, modification, or
deletion. This is similar to data security, which protects data from being
stolen or hacked. The information held in a computer system must be protected
from outside threats. Information security entails safeguarding data against
illegal access, use, disruption, modification, or destruction, whether the data
is kept electronically or physically. Any cybersecurity practitioner must have
a thorough understanding of technology and security challenges.</p>



<p>Cyber hackers are increasingly targeting the telecoms
industry as it helps them to disturb and control, and run the vital
infrastructure that is extensively utilized for communicating and storing vast
amounts of sensitive data. </p>



<p>Providing high levels of business process and data protection
with broad security capabilities is the most critical aspect of any company
security plan. Desktops, servers, information systems, data centers, and
virtual machines are part of an organization&#8217;s IT infrastructure. The company
needs a security system specifically designed to counter advanced threats and
attacks. The unique combination of technology and services helps companies
reduce cyber risk, including early detection of various forms of attacks and overall
security.</p>



<p>Attacks against leased infrastructure equipment, such as
residential routers, from Internet Service Providers pose a substantial danger
to the telecommunications industry (ISPs). They can steal data, launch
anonymous attacks, or gain access to pricey services like international phone calls
once the equipment has been hacked.</p>



<p><strong>Types of Cyber
Criminals in IT and Telecom</strong></p>



<p>Script kiddies &#8211; These hackers might be anyone who is
immature, has limited technological expertise, and uses force to run scripts in
order to cause software disruptions. This type of hacking does not necessitate
any technical knowledge to even comprehend what the software is intended to
achieve. These systems have a lot of security flaws.</p>



<p>Scammers &#8211; These are scammer emails that we receive on a
daily basis. We receive more emails from scammers every time we log into our
email inbox, offering various suggestions for reduced ads.</p>



<p>Spammers &#8211; These hackers aren&#8217;t outright criminals, but they
are masters at wasting people&#8217;s time. Spammers clog up email inboxes with
advertisements. Although they are not dangerous, they are always thought to be
inconvenient and time-consuming.</p>



<p>Hacker activist groups &#8211; Hacker activist groups are notorious
for stealing confidential material and publicizing it. These hacktivists labor
in secret and are in charge of developing tools that make hacking easier.</p>



<p>Phishers — Phishers engage in actions like as sending us
notifications that our account is about to expire and that we need to update
our information. However, this is not the case. This is a phisher&#8217;s strategy
for obtaining personal information or an individual&#8217;s identity.</p>



<p>Professional cybercriminals &#8211; These individuals have the
necessary technological knowledge and know exactly where and how to hurt data.
They are the most dangerous, and they have turned to cybercrime. They commit
the most crimes and cause the most damage to a variety of sectors and
industries.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion </strong></p>



<p>The impact of the cybersecurity event on your firm could last for weeks, if not months. Here are five areas where your company could lose money: productivity loss, reputation damage, legal liability, and business continuity issues. To assess and discover cyber security threats from vulnerabilities, <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity companies</a> must think outside the box.</p>



<p>Finally, identifying issues and dangers when they arise, as
well as having enough information to diagnose, analyze, and fix them, is
critical to achieving security service management goals. Massive connection and
Internet access bring with them a risk, which must be understood and managed in
order to detect, analyze, and respond to threats. To get access to a company&#8217;s
network, cybercriminals use a variety of methods. As a result, the security
solution must include a mix of education, best practices, technology, and a
healthy dose of common sense.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cyber-attacks-in-corporate-world-banking-manufacturing-it-and-telecommunications/">Cyber-Attacks in Corporate World – Banking, Manufacturing, IT and Telecommunications</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/cyber-attacks-in-corporate-world-banking-manufacturing-it-and-telecommunications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Developments of Top Electric Vehicle Charging Station Vendors</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/recent-developments-of-top-electric-vehicle-charging-station-vendors/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/recent-developments-of-top-electric-vehicle-charging-station-vendors/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2779</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>An electric vehicle charging station (EVCS) is the infrastructure that distributes electrical power for charging plug-in electric cars. The primary function of an EVCS is to provide electric energy for charging electric vehicles. Electric utility providers or private organizations install charging stations, also known as electric vehicle supply equipment (EVSE), in municipal parking lots or [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/recent-developments-of-top-electric-vehicle-charging-station-vendors/">Recent Developments of Top Electric Vehicle Charging Station Vendors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>An electric vehicle charging
station (EVCS) is the infrastructure that distributes electrical power for
charging plug-in electric cars. The primary function of an EVCS is to provide
electric energy for charging electric vehicles. Electric utility providers or
private organizations install charging stations, also known as electric vehicle
supply equipment (EVSE), in municipal parking lots or at retail shopping
centers. Special connectors are provided by these stations, which comply with a
range of electric charging connector standards. While some EV charging companies provide
advanced capabilities like smart metering, cellular capability, and network
access, others are more basic.</p>



<p>360Quadrants have evaluated and picked some of the <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station">Best EV Charging Companies</a> in the Electric vehicle charging station market. This evaluation helps EVCS platform buyers to learn in detail about the software and also make the right choice for their requirements. All the vendors of EVCS platforms in this analysis have been carefully compared against their product offerings as well as business strategies and were positioned on a quadrant, which is updated every quarter. 360Quadrants also provides a SWOT analysis and further enables these platform providers to get to know more about new probabilities and scope to progress.</p>



<h4><strong>Recent Developments of Top EVCS
Vendors</strong></h4>



<p><strong>ChargePoint
as a Service (CPaaS) Parntership with Goldman Sachs Renewable Power (GSRP)</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>In March 2022, Goldman Sachs Renewable Power (GSRP), a strategic, long-term investor in sustainable energy projects, has established a partnership with ChargePoint Inc. Both <strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station">EV charging companies</a></strong> are launching new customized financing alternatives as part of the ChargePoint as a Service (CPaaS) product family to help eligible customers lower the upfront costs of EV charging equipment. Customers may now choose the CPaaS option that best suits their needs thanks to this agreement, which now supports both funded and turnkey charges. Customers can pay for charging infrastructure as an operational expense with the new funded option, and customers that offer public charging can host a station at no cost to them with the turnkey option. Customers will be able to deploy a superior EV charging solution at no cost as a result of our agreement.</p>



<p><strong>BYD
Collaboration with Shell to enhance customer service for BYD&#8217;s battery electric
vehicles (BEVs) and plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs)</strong></p>



<p>In March 2022, BYD
and Shell have inked a collaboration agreement to help customers of BYD&#8217;s
battery electric vehicles (BEVs) and plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs) expedite
the energy transition and improve their charging experience. The relationship
will begin in China and Europe and will eventually expand to other parts of the
world. Shell and BYD will develop a pan-European Mobility Service Provider
(MSP) agreement for private and commercial clients, giving them access to
275,000 charging outlets through the Shell roaming network. Shell and BYD will
also work together in Europe to create Fleet Solutions and Depot Charging services
for BYD clients. Both EV
charging companies also plan to form a cooperative venture in China to
construct EV charging networks. The joint business will be responsible for a
network of more than 10,000 charging stations in Shenzhen, with plans to extend
to other Chinese cities.</p>



<p><strong>Tesla to
launch EV Charging points across India</strong></p>



<p>In December 2021, Tesla Power USA, the world&#8217;s <strong>top EV charging company</strong>, will soon add 5000 two-wheel EV charging points across India at its franchise-owned Tesla Power Shops. This pledge encourages the usage of electric vehicles and helps to ensure that the environment is as sustainable as possible. Tesla Power Shop is a hybrid and one-of-a-kind service, sales, and EV Charging Points business. This hybrid retail concept is gaining popularity across the country and around the world.</p>



<p><strong>BP PLC
brought&nbsp; AMPLY Power, an electric vehicle
(EV) charging and energy management service</strong></p>



<p>In December
2021, BP PLC has purchased AMPLY Power, an electric vehicle (EV) charging and
energy management service for fleets, to help it enter one of the world&#8217;s
fastest expanding fleet charging segments. BP intends to build AMPLY Power and
deliver its proven EV fleet charging services and energy management solutions
to customers all over the world by using its worldwide reach and partnerships.
This investment is in line with BP&#8217;s aim to grow out next-generation mobility
solutions for clients, including individual drivers and fleet operators, by
providing the fastest, most dependable, and convenient network of charging and
digital solutions.</p>



<p><strong>ABB launched
unique all-in-one electric vehicle (EV) charger</strong></p>



<p>In October 2021,
ABB has unveiled its unique all-in-one electric vehicle (EV) charger, which
offers the industry&#8217;s fastest charging experience. With dynamic power distribution,
the new Terra 360 modular charger can charge up to four EVs at once. The new
charger can fully charge any electric car in less than 15 minutes and has a
maximum power of 360kW. The Terra 360 meets the requirement for quick,
convenient, and easy-to-use charging infrastructure, driving worldwide
e-mobility adoption.</p>



<p><strong>360Quadrants Evaluation Methodology</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>360Quadrants very prudently picked and assessed some of the <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/e-commerce-platforms">Top EV Charging Companies</a>. These vendors were assessed based on more than 110 specifically selected data pointers which were finalized based on the product and business strategy of the software provider and the data received from the buyers as well as the industry experts. All of these data pointers were assigned a specific weightage, post which they were measured as well. This study also helps the analysts to calculate the total score based on which the <strong>EV charging providers</strong> were ranked and positioned on 360Quadrants.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/recent-developments-of-top-electric-vehicle-charging-station-vendors/">Recent Developments of Top Electric Vehicle Charging Station Vendors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/recent-developments-of-top-electric-vehicle-charging-station-vendors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5G Infrastructure Software trending attributes and 5G Infrastructure Companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-5g-infrastructure-software-trending-attributes-and-top-5g-vendors/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-5g-infrastructure-software-trending-attributes-and-top-5g-vendors/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 07:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[5G Infrastructure Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[5G Infrastructure Companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[5G infrastructure software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best 5G Infrastructure Companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Best 5G infrastructure software]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2759</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>As 5G rollout initiatives gain traction, the telecom network infrastructure sector environment is quickly changing. The governments of several nations are concentrating their efforts on speeding up the commercialization of 5G infrastructure software services. The advent of the Internet of Things (IoT) and linked devices is predicted to propel the telecom network infrastructure market forward. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-5g-infrastructure-software-trending-attributes-and-top-5g-vendors/">Top 5G Infrastructure Software trending attributes and 5G Infrastructure Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As 5G rollout initiatives gain traction, the telecom network
infrastructure sector environment is quickly changing. The governments of
several nations are concentrating their efforts on speeding up the
commercialization of <strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/semiconductor-and-electronics/5g-infrastructure">5G
infrastructure software</a></strong> services. The advent of the Internet of Things (IoT)
and linked devices is predicted to propel the telecom network infrastructure
market forward. With the rise in wireless connections, there is a growing
desire for better internet coverage and cellular connectivity. Telecom
companies are updating their network infrastructures to accommodate this
demand. In the next years, ongoing smart city improvements will open up new
options for operators.</p>



<p>The following are some of the most 5g trending attributes of the <strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/semiconductor-and-electronics/5g-infrastructure">best
5G infrastructure software</a> –</strong></p>



<p>Over the last few years, the number of internet users and wireless
connections has exploded. Telecom companies are constantly improving their
network infrastructures to satisfy the growing needs of cellular subscribers.
As a result, telecom operators control a massive portion of the market for
telecom network infrastructure. Operators throughout the world will benefit
from the implementation of 5G, which promises faster speeds, ultralow latency,
and seamless connection. </p>



<p>Because of the widespread use of smart home devices, the demand for
greater indoor network coverage in metropolitan areas is rapidly increasing.
The Internet of Things (IoT) and linked gadgets are making flawless coverage even
more important in interior spaces. Based on these considerations, the telecom
network infrastructure industry&#8217;s need for femtocell base stations is expected
to expand. Femtocells are used in places where a backhaul can be built quickly
or where there is already a network backhaul in place.</p>



<p>Because of the widespread use of smart home devices, the demand for
greater indoor network coverage in metropolitan areas is rapidly increasing.
The Internet of Things (IoT) and linked gadgets are making flawless coverage
more important in interior spaces. Based on these considerations, the telecom
network infrastructure industry&#8217;s need for femtocell base stations is expected
to expand at a CAGR of 5%. Femtocells are used in places where a backhaul can
be built quickly or where there is already a network backhaul in place.</p>



<p>Some of the world&#8217;s <strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/semiconductor-and-electronics/5g-infrastructure">top 5G infrastructure companies</a> </strong>include Huawei Technologies Co Ltd., Cisco Systems, Samsung, Ericsson, Fujitsu, T-Mobile, and Nokia Networks. These firms are updating their RAN network services through partnerships and other ways to satisfy evolving connection requirements. The introduction of new competitors in the telecom network infrastructure business will further heat the rivalry as these<br><strong><a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/semiconductor-and-electronics/5g-infrastructure"> 5G infrastructure companies</a></strong>  attempt to expand their market footprint.</p>



<p>The future trends</p>



<p>The network is well-positioned to enable large-scale deployment of
low-latency, huge IoT across all industries. Massive machine-type communication
(mMTC), mobile robots, and cloud robotics, to mention a few, will enable
large-scale process automation in businesses. From cloud gaming to telemedicine
use cases, 5G will bring improved quality of service, reduced latency, and
higher bandwidth in the future, helping to improve user experiences both in the
consumer and corporate arena.</p>



<p><strong>Best
5G Infrastructure software</strong></p>



<p><strong>Ericsson</strong></p>



<p>Ericsson is a multinational telecommunications services and
equipment supplier. The firm focuses on novel products such as 5G access and
transport modular system and 5G core system in 5G technology, providing clients
with end-to-end solutions. The firm collaborates closely with several telecom
providers to deploy 5G networks in the infrastructure industry. The 5G Radio
Prototype was created to meet the rising demand for high-speed data transfer
rates.</p>



<p><strong>Huawei</strong></p>



<p>Huawei offers a variety of technological solutions to assist
operators to develop end-to-end 5G networks, including the X-Ethernet
technology and the 5G-based mobile bearer solution X-Haul. In the wireless
network segment, the business also offers small cells and radio access networks
(RAN). Huawei has released the 5G network slicing router, which will be useful
for 5G services and network operators.</p>



<p><strong>Nokia </strong></p>



<p>Nokia is a global leader in 5G network development and
implementation. Beyond mobile access, Nokia&#8217;s 5G-enabled network is developed
from the ground up. The Nokia AirScale Radio Access portfolio enables 5G with
extreme capacity, huge connectivity, and ultra-low latency. AirScale Cloud RAN
provides cloud agility. Nokia&#8217;s 5G rollout will be able to manage the
complexity of many more use cases, allowing your company to better serve
consumers. Its end-to-end network is secure and cloud-native, providing industrial-scale
performance and strong revenue development potential.</p>



<p><strong>Samsung </strong></p>



<p>Samsung&#8217;s small cell, radio access network (RAN), and smart
media networks devices are all important parts of the 5G network architecture.
The firm offers a 5G radio frequency integrated circuit (RFIC) and
application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) modem chipset, as well as a 5G
home router, 5G radio base station, and next-generation core base
infrastructure. With industry-leading capacity and throughput, Samsung 5G
solutions boost performance. Its 64T64R 5G Massive MIMO radio can power densely
populated locations, increasing coverage and data throughput for better 5G
end-user experiences.</p>



<p><strong>Cisco </strong></p>



<p>Cisco is a technology company that develops, manufactures,
and distributes IP-based networking technologies for the information and
communication sector. Cisco provides mobile carriers with an ultra-services
mobile platform in the 5G industry. This platform includes technologies like
software-defined networking (SDN) and network virtualization, which allow
mobile network operators to better oversee the network&#8217;s entire functioning.
The firm offers a 5G unified enablement platform that assists network operators
in becoming ready for 5G.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-5g-infrastructure-software-trending-attributes-and-top-5g-vendors/">Top 5G Infrastructure Software trending attributes and 5G Infrastructure Companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-5g-infrastructure-software-trending-attributes-and-top-5g-vendors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Cybersecurity vendors</title>
      <link>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/</link>
      <comments>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/#respond</comments>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 09:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity Software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity software]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top cybersecurity companies]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Top Cybersecurity vendors]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2757</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cybercrime is becoming more sophisticated and ingenious, posing a danger to grind business to a halt. The cybersecurity vendors are dedicated to offering their valued clients with the most cutting-edge protection solutions. The different enterprise-level top cybersecurity vendors that provide Cyber Security services are listed below. Microsoft Microsoft is a company that produces computers, software, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/">Top Cybersecurity vendors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cybercrime is becoming more sophisticated and ingenious, posing a danger to grind business to a halt. The <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity vendors</a> are dedicated to offering their valued clients with the most cutting-edge protection solutions. The different enterprise-level <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">top cybersecurity vendors</a> that provide Cyber Security services are listed below.</p>



<p><strong>Microsoft</strong></p>



<p>Microsoft is a company that
produces computers, software, and consumer goods. It offers intelligent
security solutions as well as cloud security benefits. Through the preparation,
design, and implementation of Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics, Microsoft
Services assists in threat detection services. Microsoft Advanced Threat
Analytics (ATA) is a quick and easy approach to figure out what&#8217;s going on your
network. It has built-in intelligence that detects suspicious user and device
activities and offers clear and relevant threat information on a simplified
attack timeline.</p>



<p><strong>McAfee</strong></p>



<p>One of the most well-known
cybersecurity firms on the market is McAfee. McAfee Global Threat Intelligence,
a California-based security software company, also works with governments
throughout the world to protect businesses, governments, and consumers’ one
step ahead of hackers. Endpoint and mobile security products from McAfee defend
end-user devices from assaults, while network security products and services
safeguard corporation servers, databases, and data centers.</p>



<p><strong>AWS</strong></p>



<p>Amazon is a firm that specializes
in e-commerce, cloud computing, AI, and computer hardware. Data centers and
network design benefit from Amazon&#8217;s cloud security. The AWS Trusted Advisor
will provide you real-time information. AWS Security, Identity, and Compliance,
AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM), Amazon Cloud Directory, Amazon
Cognito, Amazon GuardDuty, and other AWS cybersecurity software packages are
available.</p>



<p><strong>IBM</strong></p>



<p>IBM is a technology company that
makes computer hardware, software, and middleware, as well as hosting and
consulting services for a variety of industries, including mainframe computers
and nanotechnology. The US federal government uses IBM&#8217;s cybersecurity
technologies. Situational awareness and reaction, Cognitive Security, Mobile
Security, Biometrics, and Identity access control are among its Core Cyber
Security Services.</p>



<p><strong>Palo Alto</strong></p>



<p>Palo Alto Networks is a
multinational <a href="https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software">cybersecurity
companies</a> with about 54,000 clients in around 150 countries. The company&#8217;s
core Security Operating Platform uses analytics to automate regular activities
and enforcement, making security easier to manage so clients can focus on
safeguarding users, apps, and data. Financial services and healthcare are among
the areas for which the platform is well-suited.</p>



<p><strong>Malwarebytes</strong></p>



<p>Malwarebytes Incident Response is
one of the most well-known and well-respected endpoint cleanup solutions. The
solution helps your company&#8217;s digital adaptability and incident response
process by shortening response times and allowing for rapid and full cleanup.
Malwarebytes Endpoint Protection provides entire malware defense and cleanup,
including precise threat detection, proactive threat blocking, and
comprehensive remediation, all powered by the cloud and simple to use for organizations.
Zero-day harmful downloads and ransomware are not prevented by these solutions.</p>



<p><strong>Mandiant&nbsp; </strong></p>



<p>Mandiant, formerly FireEye,
provides security solutions for all types of cyber-attacks. Helix security
platform, cloudvisory security solution, endpoint security, email security,
detection on demand, network security, and forensics are among the
cybersecurity solutions supplied by Mandiant (FireEye). TAP, or Threat
Analytics Platform, is part of FireEye&#8217;s deployment and integration services.
It creates a powerful cybersecurity system by combining analytics and
knowledge. TAP is a cloud-based platform designed by cybersecurity specialists
to safeguard a company&#8217;s sensitive data from numerous attacks.</p>



<p><strong>Check Point</strong></p>



<p>Check Point is a well-known
provider of security software solutions. Advanced security solutions for the
web, data, endpoints, and mobile devices are a top priority for the organization.
Check Point&#8217;s cybersecurity products assist businesses improve the security
layers of their external and internal networks. Security management, cloud
security, endpoint security, data security, Unified Threat Management (UTM),
mobile threat prevention, and network security are among the company&#8217;s security
products.</p>



<p><strong>Trend Micro</strong></p>



<p>Cloud settings, small and medium organizations,
networks, and data centers all benefit from Trend Micro&#8217;s enterprise data
protection and cybersecurity solutions. Trend Micro Cloud Migration gives
companies the freedom to defend their cloud during the migration and growth
process. It allows enterprises to obtain a deeper understanding of their cloud
infrastructures while also ensuring ongoing security. Trend Micro&#8217;s security
solutions include XGen, Trend Micro Endpoint Sensor, Trend Micro Deep Security,
and Trend Micro Hybrid Cloud Security.</p>



<p><strong>Cisco </strong></p>



<p>Cisco offers IT, networking, and cybersecurity solutions. Cisco solutions are accessible for businesses of all sizes. Cisco has solutions for networking, wireless and mobility, security, collaboration, data center, analytics, video, IoT, and software, among other categories. Security technology aids IT by reducing the complexity of security. Cisco networking technologies help small and midsized enterprises protect their network infrastructure, manage connected devices, and make faster business decisions. Some cybersecurity startups are tackling issues including avoiding data breaches on SaaS apps, detecting and inventorying cloud and on-premises systems, and identifying possible vulnerabilities, hazards, and holes in client infrastructure before a breach happens. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/">Top Cybersecurity vendors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.360quadrants.com">360Quadrants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://blog.360quadrants.com/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>