<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog – CyberDB</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.cyberdb.co/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.cyberdb.co</link>
    <description>Cyber Investments</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 07:37:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">113995802</site>
    <item>
      <title>Importance And Tips To Overcome Cybersecurity Challenges In Digital Marketing</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/importance-and-tips-to-overcome-cybersecurity-challenges-in-digital-marketing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 07:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Data leakage]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=167732</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The use of the net, portable devices, social networking sites, search engines, and other platforms to reach consumers is known as digital marketing. In comparison to conventional marketing, some marketing experts believe digital marketing to be a whole new undertaking that necessitates a fresh approach to clients and a new understanding of how customers behave. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/importance-and-tips-to-overcome-cybersecurity-challenges-in-digital-marketing/">Importance And Tips To Overcome Cybersecurity Challenges In Digital Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The use of the net, portable devices, social networking sites, search engines, and other platforms to reach consumers is known as digital marketing. In comparison to conventional marketing, some marketing experts believe digital marketing to be a whole new undertaking that necessitates a fresh approach to clients and a new understanding of how customers behave. Every marketer faces one or more threats while trying to develop a market for their brand in today&#8217;s ever-changing and ever-expanding digital world. One brand may have difficulty attracting enough traffic from social networking sites to their website, while another may have difficulty calculating the ROI of the most traffic-generating medium. </span></p>
<p><span id="more-167732"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A major threat to digital marketing stems from cybersecurity threats. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cyber attacks are dangerous and are expensive as it threatens the security of the user and can steal private information like that information may include his details or his business details and by this, it can also affect the security of his business. Cybersecurity experts predict that </span><a href="https://cybersecurityventures.com/annual-cybercrime-report-2017/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cyberattacks cost about $6 trillion in damages</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And these attacks are not done by differentiating between small businesses and big corporations. If anyone gets cyber attacked whether he/she is doing any business he/she will be known as the victim of a cyber attack.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To protect your digital </span><a href="https://www.digitalwebsolutions.com/digital-marketing-services/seo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">marketing SEO</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you must overcome the threat of cyber attacks. This article enlists multiple ways in which you can protect your digital marketing strategy from the same. Keep reading to find out.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Understanding Cybersecurity Threats</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cybersecurity has long been a topic of discussion, and with so much data at the tip of our fingers today, it appears that we&#8217;ve crossed a threshold where cyber attackers may gain an edge. Marketing is a vital topic that has the potential to either repel hackers or accidentally allow them in. Here&#8217;s why marketers are so vulnerable to cyber-attacks, and how marketing teams can help resist dangers. You may believe that cybersecurity is not something concerning and that it should be handled by the IT team. However, as a digital marketer, you are equally accountable for preserving your brand&#8217;s or company&#8217;s privacy and data.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact that you&#8217;re utilizing marketing strategies to reach a large audience makes you a tempting target for hackers. Reaching larger audiences can be achieved by utilizing keywords. Adopt the right </span><a href="https://www.rankwatch.com/tools/keyword-research" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">keyword research tool</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to help you do the same. Consider posting a relatively harmless link to your social media page and then having people click on it. If, however, the link contains a virus, all people who have clicked it will be affected. And the consequences would be far more severe if the attack is carried out through a reputable web source. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us look at some of the major cyber-threats that have occurred since 2020 include:</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Twitter</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter was the target of one of the most daring internet attacks in history. It took over the entire internet! High-profile figures including President Barack Obama, Bill Gates, and Elon Musk had their Twitter accounts verified by the hackers. From the 130 accounts targeted, they had been able to change the passwords for 45 of them. They then utilized these identities to send out fake tweets promising $2000 in exchange for $1,000 sent to an unidentified Bitcoin address. A total of $121,000 in Bitcoin was lost as a result of the fraud, which spanned about 300 transactions.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Microsoft</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A malfunction inside Microsoft Power Apps resulted in the release of a minimum of 38 million records on August 24, 2021. The data breach impacted Microsoft, American Airlines, J.B. Hunt, and the governments of Indiana, New York City, and Maryland. The identities of COVID-19 figures, social security numbers, and email accounts have been published.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Telegram</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In September 2020, hackers gained control over telegram messages and email data. They were looking for login codes that required two-factor authentication. The hackers allegedly intended to find cryptocurrencies, as per cybersecurity experts.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>LinkedIn</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On April 6, 2021, around 500 million LinkedIn user profiles were leaked on the Dark Web. Two million LinkedIn records were sold for $2 by the cybercriminals. They wanted to make sure the data in the stolen data was accurate. They did this by importing personal details from account users from the site into a repository.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Importance Of Cybersecurity In Digital Marketing</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For your firm to expand, you&#8217;ll need to have a solid digital marketing plan. However, the security of your entire marketing effort — from your website to emails to social media — must be taken into account. You and your client&#8217;s privacy may be jeopardized if you ignore this factor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are some examples of common cyberattacks using digital marketing:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A malware infection can occur as a result of files being downloaded or links being opened.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hijacking and redirection of browsers</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Theft of data and other confidential information</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Theft of one&#8217;s identity</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fake news is on the rise.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attacks on a website caused by a distributed denial of service (DDoS)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Virus in WordPress</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apart from these dangers, there are numerous other types of cyberattacks that almost all digital marketers are unaware of. Adopting a cybersecurity strategy can prove to be good for your business. One of the most clear advantages is having strong security against malware. It also safeguards your website as well as all of the information that your clients have entrusted to you. Cross-site scripting, SQL injection attacks, Denial-of-Service assaults, and password cracking are all protected.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With that being said, you will see that cybersecurity is just not solely the duty of your IT staff. If your company&#8217;s sensitive data has been breached or your servers have been assaulted, claiming ignorance will not address the problem. Everyone is responsible for cybersecurity.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>What are the challenges to digital marketing&#8217;s cyber security?</b><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Social Media</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The approach of social networking has changed people&#8217;s perceptions of social communication connections. The most serious concern and risk associated with social media marketing is identity theft. It can take the shape of illicit downloads or passwords that are too easy to guess. Hackers can use social media to steal personal information. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below mentioned are some solutions to this problem:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implement a robust password authentication strategy for users.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All social network actions must be tracked by the administrator.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make privacy settings as strict as possible.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>E-commerce</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To help businesses expand, digital marketers employ cutting-edge new technology. Consider machine learning, which improves conversion rates, or site-search analytics, which provide precise data on shopper activity. However, as online shops become more sophisticated, it&#8217;s more important than ever to stay on top of the serious security problems that come with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solutions to the problem:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) protocols and a two-step verification mechanism can be implemented.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make every attempt to provide clients with a secure payment method.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make certain that hackers do not obtain illegal access to a client&#8217;s bank account information.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Email</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email is a potent, albeit old-school, digital marketing tool. Unfortunately, this increases the likelihood of phishing attacks. Junk mail and malware emails can be sent from workplace email accounts by hackers. Hosts may blacklist and block the website if it is hacked. It will have an impact on the firm&#8217;s email marketing strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solutions to this problem:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid opening emails from senders you don&#8217;t recognize.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verify that the ISP and servers are trustworthy and reliable.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use security software to assess your email marketing requirements. To reduce the risk of a phishing attempt, encrypt your emails.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set up outbound filters to prevent emails with hidden viruses. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Include email security audits in network security audits.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Content Marketing</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Content management systems (CMS) make it easier to manage content marketing. Hackers, on the other hand, are acquainted with WordPress and can use it to propagate viruses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solutions to this problem:  </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On servers, only use security patches and current operating systems and software packages. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Content Management Systems can only be accessed via private networks. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The password authentication policy for users is very strict. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Admins must maintain control over the creation of new user accounts. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Educate users on how to use the CMS&#8217;s security features. As soon as updates become available, make sure they install them. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Only use a hosting company that prioritizes consumer security to host the organization&#8217;s website.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Customer Relationship Management</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Customer relationship management is an essential component of any company. It&#8217;s a mission-critical application that keeps track of crucial data. It keeps track of information as well as the procedures it oversees. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solutions to this problem: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security software with a firewall. VPNs, for example, are used to create private networks. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A strict password policy puts you at significant risk of being hacked.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Tips To Protect Your Digital Marketing From Cyber Attacks</b><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>The Internet and Social Media</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, billions of individuals use social media, making it among the most powerful digital marketing platforms available. Users of all ages frequent platforms such as YouTube, Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and WhatsApp. However, with great power comes great risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hackers prefer to attack social media accounts, not just those of celebrities, but also those of everyday people. By gaining access to their accounts, they are able to do more damage. In addition to stealing your personal information, hackers can use your login details to hijack accounts and publish objectionable content on your page. Some will ask for payment to stop the harassment, while others are frequently paid to do the dirty work by their competitors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because marketing teams frequently have numerous employees utilizing the same social media profile, the risk increases. You could either use a social media management tool to manage all of your social media tasks or a password manager to safeguard your authentication credentials to limit the distribution of your login credentials.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, your marketing team should be educated on the risks of unsolicited social media posts, particularly those that contain links. Hackers can use Facebook and other social media platforms to target your system, just as they can use emails to deceive you into revealing important information.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>WordPress</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The presence of WordPress on this list may appear surprising. However, if you keep up with the latest cybersecurity headlines, you&#8217;ll know that WordPress is among the most heavily attacked CMS platforms. In order to launch an attack, hackers frequently target the platform&#8217;s weaknesses. Other fraudsters make use of weaknesses in popular WordPress plug-ins.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aside from obsolete software, hackers can use a variety of methods to enter your site or cause it to malfunction, including:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DDoS Assault – This type of attack fills your website with a massive volume of traffic in order to bring your server and website to a halt.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cross-site Scripting (XSS) occurs when a hacker injects malicious code into your website in order to steal data from your server.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SQL assaults are attempts to get access to your website&#8217;s database by a hacker.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hackers can easily access your data if you use weak passwords such as your personal details, reused passwords, or simple characters.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping your WordPress account up to date is the best method to keep it safe from internet dangers. When you activate automatic updates, you will receive security fixes that address known vulnerabilities on a timely basis. Check to see if the plugins and addons you&#8217;re using are still up to date.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If feasible, use strong passwords and activate two-factor authentication. You can also put a Web Application Firewall in front of your website to protect it from dangerous content. By purchasing a digital certificate, you can also encrypt your website with SSL.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Email</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing may appear outdated, yet it remains one of the best ways to promote a company. It offers one of the best returns on investment in digital marketing, and it may assist boost website traffic and conversion rates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unfortunately, email is also considered to be a popular route of malware propagation. Emails account for more than 90% of all attacks. Hackers frequently use emails to discover their next victim by employing phishing techniques.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They frequently send out emails that appear to be legitimate but contain malicious attachments or links to phony websites. In order to obtain information from you, hackers spoof emails from reputable entities such as banks, Amazon, Paypal, Netflix, government agencies, etc. And the type of attack that follows is determined by the data you&#8217;ve provided. Because they are the ones who frequently deal with clients, your digital marketing staff is open to these types of attacks (or hackers acting as customers).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To keep your emails safe, teach everyone on your staff how to recognize a phishing email. Using a strong password and your email service provider&#8217;s spam filter can also help keep these risks at bay.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>CRM (Customer Relationship Management) Software</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CRM software is an essential component of digital marketing because it is where you store the information you collect from your clients. CRM software is used to analyze the acquired data and design a marketing plan for your organization, in addition to preserving it. Consider the consequences if hackers gained access to your CRM system. They will have access to sensitive information and will utilize it for nefarious purposes. You may not only lose money as a result of this breach, but you may also lose your brand&#8217;s reputation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using a complex password to secure your CRM software isn&#8217;t enough. It won&#8217;t be as successful as you think, therefore you&#8217;ll need to try something else. This is because the majority of breaches are caused by the inside. Restrict access to your CRM software to only trustworthy employees to secure the data. Make sure the people who have access to the information are reliable. Before entrusting your employees with the task of managing your customers&#8217; data, thoroughly vet them. It would be excellent if you could utilize a tracking tool to keep track of account logins. Finally, no Bring-Your-Own-Device (BYOD) policies are permitted. Workers should only use company-issued gadgets.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Conclusion</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The key message here is that digital marketers cannot overlook cybersecurity simply because it is not part of their job profile. It is the responsibility of everyone, from management to employees. A cyber attack not only puts your data at risk of being stolen, but it also puts all of your customers and business partners at risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every marketing plan should include the development of a sound cybersecurity strategy. The topics listed above should be given additional attention because they are frequently used by attackers as entry points. You may finally market your brand without worrying about your online security by resolving these problems.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/importance-and-tips-to-overcome-cybersecurity-challenges-in-digital-marketing/">Importance And Tips To Overcome Cybersecurity Challenges In Digital Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">167732</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Keep Your Backup Data Secure</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/how-to-keep-your-backup-data-secure/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 09:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber services]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=167701</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Backups are crucial for protecting data, and they should also be kept secure and available whenever needed. It’s not known when disaster will strike; and when it does, it happens within no time. It’s crucial to protect the data from things like fire, floods, cyberattacks, and any other disaster always. Many security breaches are associated [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/how-to-keep-your-backup-data-secure/">How To Keep Your Backup Data Secure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Backups are crucial for protecting data, and they should also be kept secure and available whenever needed. It’s not known when disaster will strike; and when it does, it happens within no time. It’s crucial to protect the data from things like fire, floods, cyberattacks, and any other disaster always.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many security breaches are associated with poor management of data backups. Putting up a solid backup infrastructure and a fallback plan in case of any security breach should be the number one consideration for every organization. Read through this article and </span><a href="https://www.securelogic.com.au/organisation-critial-backups/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">browse here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to learn how to keep data backup secure.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-167701"></span></p>
<ol>
<li><b> Make Use Of Encryption</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encryption is done by codifying information and distributing a set number of keys to authorized users to decode the files. It may not serve you much if you lose the keys, so you need to identify a safe place to keep them.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><b> Verify The Backup</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensure to verify by restoring data from the backup. Backup verification should be a regular activity during system maintenance. It’s also good practice to regularly confirm all media devices used for the backup.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><b> Protect Your Backups Using Passwords</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have your backup data password protected. As much as passwords may be interfered with, they allow some level of security because they restrain access to the data. Come up with a strong password that has a mixture of numbers and symbols, as well as uppercase and lowercase letters.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><b> Assign Duties</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s good practice to integrate storage and backup security measures with those that secure other infrastructure within the company. Even though it may be the responsibility of the storage team to be in charge of backup, you should have different people assigned specific duties. For instance, someone should be responsible for authorizing access and another for execution.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><b> Have Backup Systems As Part Of Your Disaster Recovery Strategy</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Backup systems must be a part of your </span><a href="https://www.cyberdb.co/cybersecurity-breach-response-4-critical-steps-to-take/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">disaster recovery plan</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. They could be destroyed in the event of a cyberattack, theft, or floods. Therefore, there should be a plan detailing what will be done to recover the backup in case of any disaster. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><b> Carefully Select Your Storage Location</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Find a secure place like a lockable cabinet or closet to store the server containing your backups. Local storage is also preferable where you keep your backup within the same premises but not near your office. This works best, especially when there’s an on-site disaster.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="7">
<li><b> Adhere To The 3-2-1 Rule</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disasters like floods, fires, and other natural occurrences could destroy your physical files. Following the 3-2-1 rule can be the most profitable way out. The rule means that an organization should have three recent backup copies, with two copies stored locally in different mediums and one copy stored off-site with a cloud storage provider that complies with industry regulations and is compatible with the encryption techniques.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="8">
<li><b> Be Consistent</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are different backup methods, and an organization is at liberty to use any that best works for them. However, you have to be consistent with the backup method you choose. Having different backup methods on other datasets to save storage space or money may be disastrous in the long run. It may be challenging to remember which method was used and for which dataset during restoration after a disaster. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When selecting a backup strategy, follow the KISS rule—keep it simple and straightforward. That way, you won’t have any challenges in remembering any of the procedures.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="9">
<li><b> Have Restrictions On Backup Access Rights</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensure that </span><a href="https://www.lifewire.com/online-backup-faq-2617892" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">backup access rights</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are assigned only to the team members who should have them, especially those in the data security department. Note that the more people with access to the backup, the greater the risk of damage or compromise. It’s advisable to assign rights to the specific team members in advance so they can act fast whenever any data restoration is required.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="10">
<li><b> Conduct A Risk Analysis Of The Backup Process</b></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s the responsibility of the managers to assess each step of the backup method to check for security weaknesses. Check whether there could be copies of backup tapes generated secretly or if they’re left in the open. Such deficiencies will affect backup done in cleartext.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Conclusion</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bearing in mind that backup is critical for an organization, it’s necessary to regularly audit the methods used so that gaps are identified and fixed. It may be a small loophole that you think may not cause any harm to overlook but may cost you dearly when you have to fix it. Consider the ideas mentioned here as you plan and prepare.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/how-to-keep-your-backup-data-secure/">How To Keep Your Backup Data Secure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">167701</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Reasons for Automating Cyber Security</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/top-reasons-for-automating-cyber-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 15:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=167627</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Given the increasing volume and complexity of today&#8217;s assaults, it&#8217;s no surprise that putting cybersecurity services and goods in place costs a lot of money. Insufficient security measures, on the other hand, can have devastating repercussions and have a substantial impact on a company&#8217;s reputation and budget when determining what degree of cybersecurity is required. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/top-reasons-for-automating-cyber-security/">Top Reasons for Automating Cyber Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given the increasing volume and complexity of today&#8217;s assaults, it&#8217;s no surprise that putting cybersecurity services and goods in place costs a lot of money. Insufficient security measures, on the other hand, can have devastating repercussions and have a substantial impact on a company&#8217;s reputation and budget when determining what degree of cybersecurity is required. One approach may be to automate disaster prevention, which would save money and remove the possibility of human error. In practice, however, successful cyber defense involves the integration of automated technologies and human labor.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-167627"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fundamental reason for this is that cybercrime is perpetrated by people. Attackers are continually devising new ways to circumvent security measures, inventing and deploying more sophisticated cyberattack strategies, and aggressively exploiting people&#8217;s vulnerabilities to get access to a company&#8217;s infrastructure such as hacking one’s </span><a href="https://woocasino.bet/au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Woo Casino login</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Because AI is based on previously acquired and gained experience, even the most advanced artificial intelligence (AI) can&#8217;t counteract the wide range of malevolent behaviors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With that being said, it&#8217;s critical to investigate and examine a variety of cybersecurity measures that necessitate human engagement.</span></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><b>Sensing Advanced Threats</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even the most finely calibrated sensors are incapable of detecting previously undetected harmful activity. Because such assaults normally consist of a succession of independent and valid acts that may be easily confused with system administrator or regular user actions, this is the case.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This isn&#8217;t to say that AI isn&#8217;t capable of detecting threats. In fact, it can effectively tackle 100% of potential attacks and, when set appropriately, may greatly decrease analyst workload. Special abilities, high-level analytic expertise, and continual algorithm modification are required for the joint force strategy of human engagement combined with artificial intelligence.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b>Advanced Security Evaluations</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assessments are necessary for gaining a comprehensive understanding of a company&#8217;s cybersecurity preparedness. Vulnerability assessments, for example, are automated solutions for this. This tool relies on a database of previously identified security flaws, but it is unable to assess security system resilience in the face of sophisticated assaults and unusual adversary behavior.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More comprehensive evaluation techniques should be created to verify that the organization is able to safeguard itself. For example, services like penetration testing and red teaming, which are primarily manual and rely on a specialist&#8217;s expertise and experience, may really imitate a cyberattack. These methods employ a combination of strategies, tactics, and processes that are tailored to the company&#8217;s particular cyber defensive capabilities, simulating actual attacker activity.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b>Security Alertness</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While cybercriminals are resourceful, an organization&#8217;s defensive staff cannot totally avoid security awareness training. The cybersecurity team must keep an eye on the relevance of their security education and come up with fresh and unusual ways to communicate critical information to their coworkers or outsource their training.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The all-or-nothing approach to AI should be reviewed when deciding whether or not to completely automate an organization&#8217;s cybersecurity demands. Rather, the answer is somewhere in the center. Comprehensive cyber protection can only be achieved by combining automated processes with human innovation, skills, and control.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/top-reasons-for-automating-cyber-security/">Top Reasons for Automating Cyber Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">167627</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business VPNs: Recommendations and Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/business-vpns-recommendations-and-alternatives/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 11:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cloud security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=167447</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The best VPN programs are used by more users today compared to the past. Working remotely has become a routine for most of us, which naturally makes it more important than ever to protect your privacy and security online with a Virtual Private Network. But as the commercial VPN market continues to grow, finding the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/business-vpns-recommendations-and-alternatives/">Business VPNs: Recommendations and Alternatives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best VPN programs are used by more users today compared to the past. Working remotely has become a routine for most of us, which naturally makes it more important than ever to protect your privacy and security online with a Virtual Private Network. But as the commercial VPN market continues to grow, finding the best VPN service to meet your specific needs can be a tough challenge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By learning all the details of VPN services such as </span><a href="https://nordlayer.com/business-vpn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NordLayer enterprise VPN solutions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we have brought together the most useful and reliable sources of recommendations and alternatives for you.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-167447"></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is a business VPN?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Network security is more important today than ever before. Therefore, for businesses, a Virtual Private Network (VPN) is now one of their most important requirements, less than an optional extra and more. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A VPN is a security solution that provides a tunnel between organizations’ resources and the employees accessing them. In essence, only employees connected to the VPN servers can access company resources on the network. Since this tunnel is encrypted end-to-end, businesses don’t need to worry about unwanted access or visibility into their network — ensuring complete protection and anonymity of all traffic.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">VPN has countless advantages for businesses which are as follows:</span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protection of Traffic</span></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to encryption, the possibility of misleading information is eliminated and the attack is blocked. It makes this possible by ensuring the integrity of the data and the authenticity of the sender.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Connection Reliability</span></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leading equipment manufacturers are developing VPN connection technologies that provide automatic recovery of VPN tunnels in case of short-term connection to the public network.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobility and Ease of Connection</span></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It makes it easier to connect to the company&#8217;s local network from anywhere in the world and from any modern device. Most multimedia device manufacturers have added VPN support to their products.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Redundancy and Load Balancing</span></h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you use two providers when connecting to the internet, it is possible to balance the traffic of VPN tunnels between the providers. In case one of the providers fails, the tunnel uses a redundant connection.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Makes The Best Business VPN?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are no two businesses identical, and each one will have unique requirements for its business VPN. However, there are a few characteristics that almost every organization will find beneficial, and they are generally quite different from consumer VPNs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First of all, make sure your corporate VPN has strong encryption. If you don&#8217;t, keep searching because there are many wonderful ones that fulfill this basic function. Unless you&#8217;re a single trader, you&#8217;ll probably need a dedicated static IP address on a personal server rather than the shared IPs found in most consumer VPNs. As mentioned before, these are useful as you can monitor activity with the help of a central software system and allow access to a private intranet or restricted company data.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take A Look at Business VPN Recommendations and Alternatives</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For some business and enterprise environments, a business VPN may not be the best appropriate choice. Luckily, there are various more recent alternatives and options for site-to-site connections between geographically distant offices and data centers:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud VPNs can be faster, more secure, and require less maintenance than traditional VPNs when set up using SD-WAN (software-defined wide area networking). SD-WAN cloud VPNs are best implemented with SASE which gives the organization a single, centralized view of the entire network.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA) solutions work at the application layer and are network-independent, unlike VPNs. Instead, based on user verification and device posture, users are connected directly to applications. Applications are hidden from the internet, which reduces the attack surface.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MPLS, or multi-protocol label switching, uses labels rather than public IP addresses to route traffic. It allows for traffic prioritization, is less susceptible to insecure IP lookups, and has lower latency than a site-to-site VPN. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leased circuits, also called leased lines, are private, permanent connections between two or more places. Unfortunately, leased circuits are costly and only suitable for very large businesses.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conclusion</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best VPNs will safeguard your organization from data leaks and cyberattacks by combining high-end security protocols with dedicated servers. These features are critical for maintaining your company&#8217;s good reputation and avoiding the legal consequences of data breaches. To sum up, it is essential that you have VPN solutions that are easy to use, such as 24/7 priority support, that will ensure your VPN experience is as smooth as possible.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/business-vpns-recommendations-and-alternatives/">Business VPNs: Recommendations and Alternatives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">167447</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You Need to Know About Website Security Certificates</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/what-you-need-to-know-about-website-security-certificates/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 06:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166740</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>If you find yourself shopping at a flee market in a dodgy neighborhood, you’re most likely to pay in cash, keep your wallet close and not even consider using your bank card. The same goes for using untrustworthy websites. Users are unlikely to share personal data with websites that don’t offer a reassuring level of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/what-you-need-to-know-about-website-security-certificates/">What You Need to Know About Website Security Certificates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you find yourself shopping at a flee market in a dodgy neighborhood, you’re most likely to pay in cash, keep your wallet close and not even consider using your bank card.</p>
<p>The same goes for using untrustworthy websites.</p>
<p>Users are unlikely to share personal data with websites that don’t offer a reassuring level of security. But what guarantees their security?</p>
<p>This is where website certificates enter the picture.</p>
<p><span id="more-166740"></span></p>
<h3><strong>What Are Website Security Certificates?</strong></h3>
<p>In short, a website certificate is its ID. It is a digital confirmation issued by a reputable third party (certificate authority, or CA) that the website is what it claims to be, that it belongs to whomever it claims to belong to, and that it is using an encrypted connection.</p>
<p>You might hear several different terms relating to more or less the same thing: <a href="https://sectigo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SSL certificate</a>, TLS certificate, HTTPS certificate, and SSL server certificate. Websites secured by certificates have a gray padlock in the URL bar. By clicking on this padlock the user can get more information about the website, such as its owner, CA that issued the certificate, its expiry date, etc.</p>
<p>By installing a security certificate on your website, not only do you instill trust in your customers, you are also ensuring that the communication between your website and the user will not be intercepted by cyber criminals, therefore protecting user information and privacy.</p>
<h3><strong>How Your Website Can Benefit From Security Certificates</strong></h3>
<p>With<a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2021-07-28-IBM-Report-Cost-of-a-Data-Breach-Hits-Record-High-During-Pandemic" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> IBM reporting</a> a whooping $9.05 million as an average price tag, data breaches are something companies should definitely worry about. About 44% of all data breaches reveal customers’ personal data, therefore incurring not only financial cost, but also a reputational one. It takes a long time for a brand to recover from a data breach, especially if the users are directly affected (<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/zakdoffman/2020/02/01/ashley-madison-hack-returns-to-haunt-its-victims-32-million-users-now-have-to-watch-and-wait/?sh=63bfbdfd5677" target="_blank" rel="noopener">remember the Ashley Madison scandal?</a>).</p>
<p>It is easy to conclude that security certificates are a must for any website that has two-way communication with its users. Certificates protect various types of user information, such as login credentials, bank account information, card transactions, personal info such as full name or date of birth, etc. The level of protection your website needs will depend on the type of information collected from users. The more data you collect and process, the higher level of protection you will need.</p>
<h3><strong>How Do Security Certificates Work?</strong></h3>
<p>The authentication process relies on the so called <a href="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/ibm-mq/7.5?topic=ssl-overview-tls-handshake" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TLS handshake</a>. When the user’s browser attempts to connect to a secured website, the browser requests the website server to identify itself. The web server sends over a copy of its SSL certificate, and the browser then checks if the certificate is valid.</p>
<p>If it is, the browser deems the website as secure and confirms that the connection can be established. The web server then sends a signal to start an encrypted session between the website and the user.</p>
<p>If, however, the certificate is non-existent, is invalid or has expired, the user&#8217;s browser issues a warning that the website is not safe to visit. If the user’s device is protected by firewall, they won’t be able to access the website at all.</p>
<h3><strong>How Can You Get a Security Certificate for Your Website?</strong></h3>
<p>A reliable SSL/TLS provider can help you secure your website with a certificate issued by a highly credible SSL certificate authority. Your provider will also help you choose the type of certificate and features that your website requires, as well as implement the certificate.</p>
<p>You should also look into setting up an automated system for maintaining and updating your certificates, to ensure uninterrupted website availability and the highest level of security.</p>
<h3><strong>Securing Your Website and Your Users</strong></h3>
<p>Security certificates are an affordable way to protect your assets and your users’ data from cyber criminal. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2020/07/28/four-security-measures-to-consider-for-your-e-commerce-website/?sh=25c3834a7127" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Putting security measures in place</a> is no longer a bonus, but a necessity for any company with an online presence.</p>
<p>Implementing security certificates alongside other preventative measures can save your company up to $1.49 million, according to IBM — customer trust and brand reputation are difficult to quantify, but equally important to protect.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/what-you-need-to-know-about-website-security-certificates/">What You Need to Know About Website Security Certificates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166740</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Cyber Security Tips for Business Owners</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/4-cyber-security-tips-for-business-owners/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 05:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166738</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Are you a business owner who could use some worthwhile suggestions about how to enhance cyber security? Fortunately, you don&#8217;t need to hire an in-house IT team to implement a few simple techniques that have the potential to make data safer, maintain device security, or avoid losing valuable files. Companies of all sizes can take [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/4-cyber-security-tips-for-business-owners/">4 Cyber Security Tips for Business Owners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you a business owner who could use some worthwhile suggestions about how to enhance cyber security? Fortunately, you don&#8217;t need to hire an in-house IT team to implement a few simple techniques that have the potential to make data safer, maintain device security, or avoid losing valuable files. Companies of all sizes can take advantage of B&amp;E strategies, namely using standard backup and encryption tools and techniques that cost little but do a lot. Standard fleet software is another tool that performs dozens of tasks in a seamless way.</p>
<p><span id="more-166738"></span></p>
<p>Other equally valuable methods employ password strategies and firewalls. Owners should not skimp on costs when it comes to digital safety. No-cost solutions like freeware often come with built-in threats and poor overall security. Every entrepreneur should make a point of using dedicated devices for work purposes to prevent spilling sensitive data during personal use. Here are details about the most useful suggestions for maintaining excellent digital security.</p>
<h2>Leverage the Power of Backup and Encryption</h2>
<p>Everyone has heard at least one horror story about a company that lost a huge cache of sensitive data because they neglected to back up the file before storing it. Backing up data and encrypting sensitive files are two low-cost, simple procedures that should be baked into your daily operations. If you don&#8217;t like doing the chore yourself, purchase an affordable software program that does it for you. The apps run in the background of your devices and automatically encrypt unless you instruct them to do otherwise. They also do backup files as frequently as you wish. At the end of each day, the software confirms that all your information has been successfully encrypted and duplicated.</p>
<h2>Use Fleet Software</h2>
<p>Software for companies that operate vehicle fleets is versatile and powerful. Not only do these programs like <a href="https://www.samsara.com/products/telematics/gps-fleet-tracking" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samsara&#8217;s fleet tracking technology</a> keep tabs on vehicles and cargo, they also produce daily reports, optimize routes, dispatch drivers, and warn of road hazards. GPS fleet tracking solutions are an ideal way for transport companies to solve multiple problems simultaneously. The suggestion for owners is to acquire and learn to use a program that suits the needs of the company, the size of the vehicle fleet, and the geographic range of the delivery area.</p>
<h2>Be Willing to Spend Money</h2>
<p>Never assume freeware is free. It usually comes with hidden costs and potential problems, particularly if you use it on devices that hold protected files and business documents. Not all freeware is bad, but you have no way of knowing which programs and apps contain malware and other harmful code that can wreak havoc with your company devices. Always use <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/best-firewalls-for-small-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top rated firewalls</a> and secure passwords when operating a company device. Leave the freeware behind.</p>
<h2>Use Dedicated Devices for Business Purposes</h2>
<p>When you want to <a href="https://www.cyberdb.co/5-tips-to-help-you-choose-the-best-business-it-solutions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">choose the best business IT solutions</a>, be sure to do specific research. Don&#8217;t use business computers for personal tasks. Likewise, don&#8217;t ever place sensitive work documents or files on your personal devices, even to send a quick email or text message. Once proprietary information escapes from the confines of encryption and safe business systems, you can&#8217;t prevent it from ending up in unwanted locations.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/4-cyber-security-tips-for-business-owners/">4 Cyber Security Tips for Business Owners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166738</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips To Help You Choose The Best Business IT Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/5-tips-to-help-you-choose-the-best-business-it-solutions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 11:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166303</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Your IT operations are central to the smooth running of your business. So, most times, it&#8217;s advisable you outsource the solutions by employing the best-managed service providers (MSPs). But choosing the best IT solutions company can be tricky, considering the surge in demand for such services in recent times.   While the right company will provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/5-tips-to-help-you-choose-the-best-business-it-solutions/">5 Tips To Help You Choose The Best Business IT Solutions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your IT operations are central to the smooth running of your business. So, most times, it&#8217;s advisable you outsource the solutions by employing the best-managed service providers (MSPs). But choosing the best IT solutions company can be tricky, considering the surge in demand for such services in recent times.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the right company will provide the most optimized IT services, the wrong one can lead to ineffective outcomes, or in worst cases, significant losses. Therefore, you&#8217;ll need tricks and tips to adopt IT solutions that align with your business needs.  </span></p>
<p><span id="more-166303"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you looking for the best IT solutions for your business? You could go for </span><a href="https://www.netgainit.com/managed-it-services-louisville-kentucky/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netgain&#8217;s IT services in Louisville</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or any IT services company near you. You could hire managed service providers online (MSPs). But before you do, here are some tips to help you make the best choice:  </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Clarify Expected Outcomes   </b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before choosing an IT solution for your business, it&#8217;s essential to clarify your expected outcomes. What do you seek to achieve by implementing the solution? What gaps will the solutions fill? What will key performance indicators tell if the implemented solution is effective enough? Knowing what you intend to achieve through an IT solution helps you recognize options that&#8217;ll fit your needs and yield the desirable returns.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without a clear objective, it&#8217;s easy to settle for the most appealing yet misfitting solution. Before saying yes to an IT solution provider, ensure you&#8217;re clear about what you want them to achieve for your business.</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Lookout For Relevant Experience   </b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While it may be tempting to work with newly established IT firms, it&#8217;s advisable to work with companies with years of relevant experience in providing the solution you seek. Experience counts a lot in service delivery.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes, business owners cannot tell what IT solution is needed or the best for their business. Experienced IT firms who have worked with several companies can analyze their dilemmas and recommend the most viable IT solutions.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides, in most cases, choices guided by experience and expertise turn out right and effective. And this is because experienced IT solutions providers can help you determine what IT solution is most optimal and </span><a href="https://www.cyberdb.co/7-cybersecurity-practices-protect-organizations-future-threats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cyber-proof</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for your business.   </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Consider Company Culture   </b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different businesses can integrate various IT solutions. However, when deciding on solutions to settle with, it&#8217;s essential to factor in the existing culture within the company. IT solutions that align with a business&#8217;s culture are more likely to be successfully implemented.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before IT consultants implement recommended solutions, they should feel the business culture. Meetings can be set up with the in-house team and department heads. The feedback that results from these interactions can inform decision-making. Regardless of how an IT solution fits other businesses, it has to work with yours to deliver expected outcomes.  </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Adaptability Matters   </b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The need for IT solutions to be adaptable to business operations cannot be overemphasized. Adaptability ensures that a solution is modified to fit into the business context within which it&#8217;s applied. IT solutions that seem to be alien to a business stands little chance of succeeding.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More so, the more adaptable a solution is, the better it can serve the company even as times and market demands change. IT solutions that quickly lose relevance due to slight alterations in the marketplace may not be the best option for your business.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While a solution may not be relevant forever, it&#8217;s advantageous to sustain its relevance through changes and help your business scale. So, you need to consider the adaptability of IT solutions presented to you.  </span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Consider User Experience   </b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best IT business solutions offer a rich user experience. If it is strictly for the in-house business team, it should deliver a smooth and enjoyable user experience. Solutions that come with excessive technicalities and incessant challenges eventually slow down the work process and impair performance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the customers are the users of the solution, they should also be guaranteed a seamless interaction with it. Solutions that offer rich user experience will attract more engagement than those that don&#8217;t. And, of course, </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/shephyken/2021/02/21/customer-engagement-is-your-secret-weapon-to-beat-the-competition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">improved engagement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> means one thing for your business: more sales and profits.   </span></p>
<p><b>Conclusion   </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are enough IT solutions in the market for business owners to choose from. However, businesses can only be guaranteed the best outcome when the IT solutions they choose are the best fit for their business needs. Making the best choice becomes stress-free by following tips such as those recommended in this article. That way, you can make your next choice the best one.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/5-tips-to-help-you-choose-the-best-business-it-solutions/">5 Tips To Help You Choose The Best Business IT Solutions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166303</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Advantages Of Managed IT Services</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/5-advantages-of-managed-it-services/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 11:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber services]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166300</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Like most entrepreneurs in the game, you probably don&#8217;t have time to worry about your IT needs. You&#8217;re busy taking care of the daily transactions, and the last thing you want to do is take time to manage your own IT department. Managed IT services can help you in this aspect. Managed IT services provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/5-advantages-of-managed-it-services/">5 Advantages Of Managed IT Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like most entrepreneurs in the game, you probably don&#8217;t have time to worry about your IT needs. You&#8217;re busy taking care of the daily transactions, and the last thing you want to do is take time to manage your own IT department. Managed IT services can help you in this aspect. Managed IT services provide several advantages for businesses of all sizes. This blog post will discuss some of the top benefits of managed IT services.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-166300"></span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Saves On Cost</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Chicago, running a business is not easy. Unlike some parts of the country, you will have to pay a lot for just about everything, including labor costs and equipment. </span><a href="https://www.osgusa.com/it-consulting-chicago/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">IT consulting in Chicago</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can help reduce the cost of running your business by allowing you to delegate maintenance and support tasks to experts capable of delivering quality services at affordable rates. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Managed service providers offer their clients access to skilled professionals without investing in infrastructure or hiring full-time employees. This way, businesses can save money as they only pay for what they use when it is needed instead of paying salaries even during periods with low workloads. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition, managed IT service providers handle all kinds of technical problems, allowing companies to focus on their core operations.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Peace Of Mind</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagine having a dedicated IT team that takes care of everything related to technology. You don’t have to overwork yourself with any issues because you know capable people are doing it for you. The best thing about managed IT service providers is that they are always on call and will come running as soon as an issue arises at your company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">IT professionals work with a range of industries, so there’s no doubt that they already have experience solving issues similar to the one you might be facing right now.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Low Downtime Moments</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For successful businesses, downtime can be a death sentence. Downtimes refer to periods of reduced activity, even inactivity, of your online tools. Low downtime means less time spent trying to fix the problem and more time spent making money. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/effects-of-internet-downtime-to-your-organization-1d9fc673a01e" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Downtime</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is also bad for your customers. Imagine having an e-commerce website that stops working during the holidays when everyone is shopping online? You&#8217;ll lose out on potential clients, and they will take their hard-earned money elsewhere.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With managed IT services, the downtime is minimal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&#8217;re outsourcing your IT services, they will monitor your networks 24/07, which means that problems are detected early and fixed quicker. A good MSP should minimize unplanned outages by at least 90%, saving you money and increasing productivity.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Keeps You Up-to-Date With The Trends</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In your day-to-day operations, you focus on your core business functions, grow your business, and keep up with market trends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, suppose you do not stay up-to-date with the latest trends in technology. In that case, an IT manager or small business owner who doesn’t know much about IT issues can make decisions without proper knowledge of their impact on your network and security infrastructure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With managed services providers (MSPs), they stay abreast of all kinds of new technologies and software upgrades that will keep crucial data protected from hackers. Therefore, your business will never fall victim to a ransomware attack or data breach.</span></p>
<p><b></b></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Improved Security</b></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the main </span><a href="https://www.cyberdb.co/7-benefits-of-professional-managed-it-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">benefits of professional managed IT services</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is improved security. Think about it, if you were a hacker looking for an easy target, who would you instead go after a business with in-house (and possibly inexperienced) IT staff or a company that has access to talented minds in cybersecurity? This benefit of using Managed Service Providers is pretty self-explanatory. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With their advanced knowledge and rich experience, MSPs can provide your organization with security solutions tailored specifically to your needs while also being proactive instead of reactive when it comes to monitoring threats against your network infrastructure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MSPs can help prevent data breaches by watching for emerging cybercriminal tactics such as phishing scams or ransomware attacks where malicious software is used to encrypt data until a ransom is paid. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Final Word</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The IT industry is increasing, and businesses are looking for ways to stay relevant. Managed IT services can be an efficient way of gaining leverage over your competitors. As mentioned above, managed IT services offer many advantages. However, you need to ensure that you select the right provider. Make sure to do your research and ask for referrals from trusted sources.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/5-advantages-of-managed-it-services/">5 Advantages Of Managed IT Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166300</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Software Testing Is Incorporated Into Cyber Security</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/how-software-testing-is-incorporated-into-cyber-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 16:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber services]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166277</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>With the ever-increasing number of cyberattacks, it&#8217;s more crucial than ever for companies to invest in cybersecurity. It seems like just about every day, there&#8217;s another major breach reported somewhere online or offline. This can lead to millions or billions of data points being compromised and stolen by hackers. In addition, these breaches are costly [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/how-software-testing-is-incorporated-into-cyber-security/">How Software Testing Is Incorporated Into Cyber Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the ever-increasing number of cyberattacks, it&#8217;s more crucial than ever for companies to invest in cybersecurity. It seems like just about every day, there&#8217;s another major breach reported somewhere online or offline.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This can lead to millions or billions of data points being compromised and stolen by hackers. In addition, these breaches are costly and take a long time to recover from. In this post, we&#8217;ll share seven ways that software testing should be incorporated into cyber security, including end-to-end testing, fuzzing, penetration testing, and more.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-166277"></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">End-to-end Testing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Software consists of modules and processes which interact with one another. It&#8217;s essential to check these interactions between elements when integrating new features or updates into an existing product because vulnerabilities lie at the code level and in how functions communicate with each other.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With </span><a href="http://prodperfect.com/blog/end-to-end-testing/what-is-end-to-end-testing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">end-to-end testing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, companies can check for gaps in these interactions before an update reaches production. This also allows companies to find bugs earlier, which saves them time and money when developing new features or updates for their products.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Penetration Testing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A penetration test is essentially a simulated attack against an IT infrastructure, website, or application where the tester acts as a malicious hacker to break into one or more systems. Penetration testing is vital because it provides teams real-world experience in how hackers work, what tools they use, and how they think about entering any system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This knowledge gained through penetration testing prevents cyber attacks by uncovering vulnerabilities that would otherwise be unknown until after something terrible has happened. With all of this in mind, penetration testing is performed in a controlled environment that helps companies identify and fix vulnerabilities that hackers could exploit once the product reaches production.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security Testing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s vital for security testing to be performed at all stages of a software development life cycle. It includes any time an update is being made, a new feature needs to be added, or even an upgraded package. When companies fail to do this, their products are more likely to contain security vulnerabilities, leading to costly breaches and high turnover rates among employees who have had their personal information stolen from the company&#8217;s systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With all of this in mind, consistency across all stages of the software development life cycle, including usability testing, helps ensure that sensitive information isn&#8217;t compromised by hackers ever again.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Configuration Management Testing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When updates need to be made, or new features need to be added, it becomes crucial for companies to ensure that configurations don&#8217;t get broken along the way. This is where configuration management testing comes in, providing </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2021/09/01/iso-5055-how-to-tell-if-your-software-is-efficient-and-safe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">proper software configuration</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and control by checking configuration changes before entering production environments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When companies fail to perform configuration management testing, their products are more vulnerable to cyber-attacks because of the increased risk of unwanted behaviors such as poor performance or crashes.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Usability Testing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies of all sizes and industries must test usability when developing any product, including websites, mobile applications, IoT devices, and more. When usability issues aren&#8217;t identified until a product has been released into production, this can cause a significant loss in revenue due to lower customer satisfaction rates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also leads to </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbeshumanresourcescouncil/2021/08/11/where-to-look-when-employee-turnover-rates-start-climbing/?sh=5f39f31d19ea" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">higher turnover rates</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as customers leave the company because of how difficult it is to use their products. With all of this in mind, usability testing ensures that a product is easy and efficient enough to use, which helps companies retain their customers and attract new ones.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fuzzing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When developing software, it&#8217;s essential to ensure that all inputs are validated and checked for errors before being processed. However, even when taking precautions like this, there still could be problems with how data is read or used later in a system since requirements often change throughout development.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To find these issues early in testing, a business can use fuzzing to test how inputs are passed around between different components in an application. This will flag any unexpected states within the application, including invalid memory accesses or preventing crashes, leading to security flaws allowing attackers unauthorized access into a system.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">SAAS, PAAS, &amp; IAAS</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to cyber security, a business can&#8217;t afford to be hacked. With all of this in mind, on-demand cloud computing models such as Software as a Service (SAAS), Platform as a Service (PAAS), Anything as a Service (XAAS), and Infrastructure as a Service (IAAS) have been gaining popularity over the past several years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With all of these services (</span><a href="http://codecapsules.io/docs/saas-vs-paas-vs-iaas-comparing-three-paradigms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SAAS, PAAS, &amp; IAAS</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), companies can access software and computing resources that are centrally managed with support for the latest technologies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To ensure complete security when testing on these platforms, companies should always download the latest version of their operating system (such as from PAAS providers) and re-test any code before uploading it to avoid vulnerabilities in the creation process.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developer Training</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s important to note these potential cyber security issues early on in the </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2020/08/11/16-strategies-for-fast-high-quality-software-development/?sh=ec97f3e78b5d" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">development process</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be addressed. There should be a greater awareness of security across teams, with developers training them how to write better code with fewer flaws, which would cut down on testing their products before release.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If companies can implement proactive security strategies throughout the development lifecycle, this should strengthen software security before it&#8217;s released to the market.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud Deployment </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The same applies to cloud deployments with features that have been added as part of a new update. In the past, software updates may have been made directly on a company&#8217;s servers themselves, but making these changes is more straightforward and accessible with cloud computing. However, businesses will still need to test these updates before they go live to make sure no issues occur since it could potentially affect many different customers at once.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conclusion</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By incorporating software testing into cyber security, companies can build more secure systems that are reliable enough to use throughout their organization. In addition, when development teams have processes to inspect their code for bugs before release, fewer chances of vulnerabilities are introduced. It is crucial since new online threats are created daily, which can be dangerous if they aren&#8217;t discovered beforehand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since many different roles within a company contribute to information technology, it&#8217;s essential not to forget how everyone can help keep products secure throughout the development process. Putting in the effort and investing time early in testing will help maintain a productive workflow when developing new digital products, so they don&#8217;t introduce any unexpected risks or flaws.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/how-software-testing-is-incorporated-into-cyber-security/">How Software Testing Is Incorporated Into Cyber Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166277</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What skills are needed for cyber security?</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberdb.co/what-skills-are-needed-for-cyber-security/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Chachak]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 08:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Attacks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Awareness]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber solutions]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cyberdb.co/?p=166241</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity is a high-demand, rapidly expanding area with a high need for competent personnel. It offers high median incomes, employment possibilities in a wide range of industries, and a fast-paced work environment for those who choose this career path. Even if you&#8217;re intrigued by the prospect of safeguarding organizations&#8217; digital assets and intelligence from security [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/what-skills-are-needed-for-cyber-security/">What skills are needed for cyber security?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity is a high-demand, rapidly expanding area with a high need for competent personnel. It offers high median incomes, employment possibilities in a wide range of industries, and a fast-paced work environment for those who choose this career path.</p>
<p>Even if you&#8217;re intrigued by the prospect of safeguarding organizations&#8217; digital assets and intelligence from security breaches, you should conduct thorough research into the field to determine whether you&#8217;re a good fit for the position. Learn more about typical cybersecurity jobs and the skills required for cybersecurity careers.</p>
<p><span id="more-166241"></span></p>
<p>If you want to pursue a career in cybersecurity, you&#8217;ll need a diverse range of technical, and functional skills, as well as the particular cybersecurity talents and critical soft skills in demand by employers. Because these will help you stand out from the crowd. We&#8217;ve compiled a list of the most important cybersecurity skills to give you a better understanding of what it takes to be a successful professional in the cybersecurity area.</p>
<h2>Must-Have Cybersecurity Skills</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s start with essential cybersecurity skills to have if you aim to work in this field:</p>
<h3>#1: Troubleshooting Skills:</h3>
<p>As a cybersecurity specialist, you will be required to solve a variety of problems regularly. In order to tackle and handle complex information security concerns across a wide range of present and upcoming technologies and digital environments, those working in the sector must think outside the box.</p>
<h3>#2: Security knowledge across a variety of platforms</h3>
<p>Cybersecurity isn&#8217;t just about computers: you&#8217;ll need to be comfortable working on a variety of operating systems, computer systems, mobile devices, cloud networks, and wireless networks &#8211; and you&#8217;ll need to stay on top of the latest developments in the field for each of these platforms and technologies.</p>
<h3>#3: Knowledge of Operating Systems and Virtual Machines:</h3>
<p>A cybersecurity expert should be well-versed in operating systems such as Windows, Linux, and MacOS. Knowledge of Networking and Security: As a cybersecurity specialist, feel at ease working on any operating system. Virtual environments (VMs) allow you to practice and do research in a controlled setting, allowing you to optimize your abilities.</p>
<h3>#4: Familiarity with Computer Forensics:</h3>
<p>Having a strong basis in <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/cyber-defense-forensics-analyst#:~:text=CISA%20Cyber%20Defense%20Forensics%20Analyst,of%20system%2Fnetwork%20vulnerability%20mitigation." target="_blank" rel="noopener">cyber forensics</a> may help you succeed in your cybersecurity profession. While computer forensics and cybersecurity are two distinct areas, they are closely intertwined. And having a strong foundation in computer forensics can help you thrive in your cybersecurity career. You must have a thorough grasp of what occurs if your efforts fail and how stolen data you retrieve to secure businesses&#8217; digital assets and avoid security breaches. Because of this, computer forensics will be a component of most cybersecurity degrees programs.</p>
<h3>#5: Deconstructing Hacking Concept</h3>
<p>To successfully defend an organization&#8217;s network and infrastructure, you must first understand how they might be attacked &#8211; which is why most cybersecurity experts must learn how to &#8220;ethically hack&#8221; to do their jobs properly. Essentially, you must possess the same abilities as a hacker in order to completely comprehend how a system may be hacked and, as a result, develop efficient countermeasures against such attacks.</p>
<h3>#6: Experience in Network Security</h3>
<p>Controlling the security of a network refers to the many steps that are implemented to increase the overall security of a network. You must understand how your network operates, including how routers, firewalls, and other devices function. To be an effective cybersecurity professional, you must employ a firewall to filter and block unapproved traffic from entering the network.</p>
<p>In addition, you must be familiar with intrusion detection systems, intrusion prevention systems, virtual private networks (VPNs), and remote access technologies. For example, run the <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/intrusion-detection-system-ids/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">intrusion detection system</a> (IDS) and identify any security policy breaches and hostile activity on your network.</p>
<h3>#7: Experience in Cloud Security</h3>
<p>The cloud security field is booming, and companies are searching for employees with security expertise that can apply to public and hybrid cloud platforms like AWS and Azure. Cloud computing is becoming increasingly used to store data and running applications. This covers the development and implementation of policies and technology to safeguard cloud-based systems and devices, for example. People with extensive expertise and understanding in operating large-scale platforms such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, and the Google Cloud Platform are in great demand in the cloud computing industry.</p>
<p>Start implementing your cyber security measures right away with your daily routine and research on the newly emerging topics in the field closely. So how do you get the cybersecurity concept into life?</p>
<h2>What measures do you take to ensure cyber security for yourself?</h2>
<h3>Maintaining software up to date:</h3>
<p>Software updates are often provided by product firms for three reasons: to add new features, to repair known flaws, and to improve the security of the software. Always make sure that you are running the most recent version of your software to protect yourself against new security flaws.</p>
<h3>Start using a virtual private network (VPN) to protect your connections:</h3>
<p>Use a virtual private network (VPN) to create a more secure and private network environment (<a href="https://www.wizcase.com/reviews/cyberghost-vpn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here you can find a good review on Cyberghost VPN</a>). It will encrypt your connection and keep your private information safe, even from prying eyes like those of your internet service provider.</p>
<h3>Do not open questionable emails:</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s best not to open any emails that appear odd, as they might contain malware or be phishing scams. The possibility exists that someone is posing as another individual or corporation to get access to your personal information. In other cases, the emails may also contain files or links that might infect your computer or device.</p>
<h3>Antivirus software:</h3>
<p>Protect yourself from malware by using anti-virus and anti-malware software. As long as you&#8217;re linked to the internet, it&#8217;s impossible to be completely and completely protected against malware. Although you cannot erase your susceptibility, you can considerably minimize it by ensuring that you have an anti-virus and at least one anti-malware program installed on your PCs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co/what-skills-are-needed-for-cyber-security/">What skills are needed for cyber security?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cyberdb.co">CyberDB</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">166241</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>