<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Cipher Brief</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com</link>
    <description>National Security is Everyone's Business.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 12:53:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/cropped-cropped-New-Project-32x32.png</url>
      <title>The Cipher Brief</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Kim Jong-un Doubles Down on Nuclear Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 12:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Nuclear]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ambassador Joe DeTranni]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Kim Jong-Un]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=37017</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OPINION &#8212; It should be crystal clear:&#160; North Korea has nuclear weapons not only for defensive deterrence purposes but, according to Kim Jong-un, to respond <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat">Kim Jong-un Doubles Down on Nuclear Threat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>OPINION</strong> &#8212; It should be crystal clear:&nbsp; North Korea has nuclear weapons not only for defensive deterrence purposes but, according to Kim Jong-un, to respond to any perceived threat to North Korea and its leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Kim made these comments at the April 25<sup>th</sup> military parade in Pyongyang, celebrating the 90<sup>th</sup> anniversary of the founding of the Korean People’s Army.&nbsp; Kim then doubled down on April 30, as reported by North Korea’s state media, warning that Pyongyang could preemptively use its nuclear weapons to counter hostile forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a significant paradigm shift for North Korea.&nbsp; During almost thirty years of negotiations with North Korea, their message was consistent:&nbsp; Their nuclear weapons were for deterrence, self-defense, never to be used against the United States or any other country.&nbsp; Kim’s recent pronouncements make it abundantly clear that their nuclear weapons could be used for offensive purposes, to include its preemptive use against any perceived threat.</p>



<p>Kim is sending the United States and South Korea a message:&nbsp; The self-imposed moratorium on intercontinental Ballistic Missiles (ICBM) and nuclear tests is over, and we are going to build more nuclear weapons and missiles to deliver them as far as the United States.&nbsp; The 13 missiles launched this year included the gigantic Hwasong-17, capable of reaching the whole of the United States, Hypersonic ballistic missiles potentially capable of defeating missile defenses, short-range solid fuel, and cruise missiles that threaten South Korea and Japan, and submarine-launched ballistic missiles.&nbsp; This is the overt part of North Korea’s nuclear program.&nbsp; What we don’t see is the continued production of fissile material for the nuclear weapons these missiles are capable of delivering.</p>



<p>It’s likely the North will conduct its seventh nuclear test within the next few weeks.  The last test was in 2017, assessed as a successful thermonuclear test.  And work continues at the Punggye-ri nuclear test site that was closed and partially dismantled in 2018, during the Trump-Kim summits and North Korea’s goodwill gesture to refrain from any nuclear and ICBM tests.  That did not, however, impede the North from testing short and mid-range ballistic missiles, an existential threat to our allies in South Korea and Japan and to Guam.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The Cipher Brief hosts expert-level briefings on national security issues for <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+Members</a> that help provide context around today’s national security issues and what they mean for business.  Upgrade your status to <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+</a> today.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>On May 10<sup>th</sup>, President-elect Yoon Suk-Yeol will be sworn in as South Korea’s new president, replacing Moon Jae-in.&nbsp; Yoon, a conservative member of the People Power Party, narrowly defeated his liberal opponent from the Democratic Party, Lee Jae-Myung. Yoon has made it clear that his focus will be on a close strategic alliance with the United State and improved relations with Japan.&nbsp; The message to North Korea is equally clear:&nbsp; Complete and Verifiable denuclearization is the goal and sanctions should not be lifted until the North moves forward with denuclearization. No doubt Yoon’s comment about a preemptive strike when the South detects signs of a (missile) launch from the North also got Pyongyang’s attention.&nbsp; Kim Jong-un’s powerful sister, Kim Yo Jong, had criticized in early April South Korea’s defense minister, Suh Wook, for publicly talking about preemptive strikes on North Korea, made after North Korea launched the Hwasong-17 on March 24, ending the North’s four-year moratorium on ICBM launches.</p>



<p>Russia’s February 24 invasion of Ukraine and the ongoing war in Ukraine has Kim Jong-un’s attention.&nbsp; In 1994, Ukraine gave up over 1,900 nuclear warheads to Russia, in exchange for security assurances from Russia, the United States and the United Kingdom.&nbsp; That agreement, the Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances, obviously didn’t prevent Russia from invading and annexing Crimea in 2014 and seizing part of the South-Eastern Donbas region of Ukraine.&nbsp; It certainly didn’t prevent Russia from its 2022 invasion of and war with Ukraine, an independent and sovereign country that willingly gave up its nuclear weapons for so-called security assurances – a commitment that Russia brazenly ignored.</p>



<p>So, assuming we get North Korea back to the negotiation table, it will prove that much more difficult convincing Pyongyang that relinquishing their nuclear weapons will make North Korea more secure and prosperous.&nbsp; Our negotiators will have to be flexible and creative, with the goal of building trust and confidence that a path to normal relations with the United States will provide North Korea with the security assurances and economic development opportunities that a heavily sanctioned North Korea with nuclear weapons will not have.&nbsp; But that’s a long way from here, especially now, when all indications are that North Korea has given up on negotiations and is determined to build more nuclear weapons and stay tethered to China and Russia.</p>



<p>China’s Special Representative on the Korean Peninsula, Ambassador Liu Xiaoming, arrived in Seoul on Sunday for meetings with officials in the Moon Jae-in government and the incoming Yoon Suk-yeol administration.&nbsp;&nbsp; At an impromptu news conference, Liu said the United States and North Korea are responsible for resolving the nuclear issue on the Korean Peninsula and China and South Korea are important cooperation partners in seeking a political solution.</p>



<p>Hopefully, in private discussions in Seoul, Liu also talked about China’s efforts to get North Korea to return to unconditional negotiations with the United States and to refrain from additional missile and nuclear tests.&nbsp; A China that provides North Korea with over 90% of its crude oil and petroleum products and over 90% of its foreign trade has the leverage to be successful – if they try.</p>



<p>Ignoring nuclear developments with North Korea is not an option.&nbsp; Whether we like it or not, North Korea is a priority issue that must be dealt with – by China, the United States, South Korea and Japan and the international community.&nbsp; When a nuclear weapons country like Russia puts their nuclear forces on high alert we correctly are concerned.&nbsp; When Kim Jong-un talks of preemptively using nuclear weapons we should also be concerned.</p>



<p><strong><em>This piece by Cipher Brief Expert Ambassador Joe DeTrani was first published in <a href="https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2022/may/4/north-koreas-preemptive-nuclear-threat/">The Washington Times</a></em></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a> because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat">Kim Jong-un Doubles Down on Nuclear Threat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/kim-jong-un-doubles-down-on-nuclear-threat/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Core of Putin’s Weakness</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 12:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36978</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OPINION &#8212; In 2017, I wrote a short piece for Foreign Policy asking if Putin was more a product of his KGB background and personal <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness">The Core of Putin&#8217;s Weakness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>OPINION &#8212; In 2017, I wrote a <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2017/12/06/vladimir-putin-isnt-as-russian-as-he-seems/">short piece</a> for <em>Foreign Policy</em> asking if Putin was more a product of his KGB background and personal circumstances, or whether he could be better described as acting in the longer cultural and historical tradition of Russian Tsars and Soviet Party bosses. I came down on the former explanation.</p>



<p>However, since that time, Putin has justified his actions – to include the invasion of Ukraine – in increasingly nationalist and historic terms. He has inveighed Russian myths and historical grievances, quoted chauvinist Russian philosophers and even claimed that Ukraine doesn’t exist, except as part of a greater historical Russia.</p>



<p>Of course, he has also continued his pattern of using KGB tricks of political and information warfare. In the lead up to the war, Putin’s Kremlin engaged in a torrent of disinformation, subversion, propaganda, support to fringe and violent groups, agitation, cyber theft, provocation, deception, conspiracy and even assassination. His goal was to intimidate western leaders in hopes that they would not find the will to push back against his invasion. As the war has continued, Russia has increasingly used lies and deception to deny its clear war crimes.</p>



<p>While the west took far too long to understand and respond to Russian disinformation following the 2016 US Presidential election, we have since become accustomed to Kremlin lies. However, despite their artlessness and credulity, too many people nonetheless fall for the deception. According to a recent Levada Center poll, Putin’s popularity rose from 71% to 83% following the start of the war. Similarly, Americans on the far right and left sadly seem gullible to accept conspiracies that reinforce their views.</p>



<p>However, as the war has continued, the shameless lying is of lesser concern than the daily butchery of the Russian Army. While the decision to invade an innocent country is Vladimir Putin’s alone, the rape, torture, looting and savage brutality by the Russian Army in Ukraine has spurred commentators to review Russian military activity over the decades and seek parallels. And there are many.</p>



<p>Credible accusations of Russian and Soviet war crimes are easily evident in Syria, Chechnya, Georgia, Afghanistan, Finland, Poland and the Baltic States, as well as against a variety of Soviet nationalities, and during WWII. A recent <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/17/world/europe/ukraine-war-russia-atrocities.html">article</a> in <em>The New York Times</em> described the deep historical roots of Russian brutality.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Today’s constant barrage of information makes it easy for countries to wage disinformation campaigns and your emotions are the weapon of choice.&nbsp; Learn how disinformation works and how we can fight it in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">short video</a>.&nbsp; This is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">one link</a> you can feel good about sharing.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>In a recent discussion with <em>New Yorker</em> editor David Remnick, Princeton historian Stephen Kotkin put the recent invasion in historical context. According to Kotkin, “What we have today in Russia is not some kind of surprise. It’s not some kind of deviation from a historical pattern. Way before NATO&nbsp;existed—in the nineteenth century—Russia looked like this: it had an autocrat. It had repression. It had militarism. It had suspicion of foreigners and the West. This is a Russia that we know, and it’s not a Russia that arrived yesterday or in the nineteen-nineties. It’s not a response to the actions of the West. There are internal processes in Russia that account for where we are today.”</p>



<p>And what are those 19<sup>th</sup> century parallels? To those who study Russia, the 19<sup>th</sup> century French aristocrat and writer Marquis Astolphe de Custine, is one of the best-known chroniclers of Russian political culture. A travel writer in the style of Alexis de Tocqueville who wrote <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3KbtvsD">Democracy in America</a></em>, de Custine traveled to Russia in 1839, and penned his travelogue <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3vJZ9Iv">Empire of the Czar</a></em>. De Custine visited Russia in expectation of finding material to support his criticism of France’s representative government, but instead became an advocate for constitutional government and a vocal critic of Russian despotism. He identified a number of 19<sup>th</sup> century Tsarist traits that can equally describe the Russia of Vladimir Putin, to include domestic repression, institutional incompetence and a culture of lies.</p>



<p>In the lead-up to the war in Ukraine, Vladimir Putin ramped up repression at home, poisoning his opponents and jailing anyone who criticized the government. In 1839, de Custine described Tsarist Russia as a prison, in which the emperor holds the key. As he commented, “under a despotism, all the laws are calculated to assist oppression; …every indiscretion of speech is equivalent to a crime of high treason [and] the only criminal is the man who goes unpunished.” De Custine concluded that, “other nations have supported oppression, the Russian nation has loved it: it loves it still.” In Russia, “despotic tyranny is permanent.”</p>



<p>While Putin’s use of lies can be attributed to his KGB background, there are also ample historical and cultural antecedents. In his book, de Custine claimed that the Tsarist court displayed a singular “dexterity in lying, a natural proneness to deceit, which is revolting.” He added that lying seemed to be part of a larger cultural instinct to not only hide the truth, but lead people astray. “Russian despotism not only pays little respect to ideas and sentiments, it will also deny facts; it will struggle against evidence, and triumph in the struggle!” wrote de Custine, who further noted that in Russia, “to lie is still to perform the part of a good citizen; to speak the truth, even in apparently unimportant matters, is to conspire.” And as we have seen in the 21<sup>st</sup> century, instinctual lying has a political cost. As de Custine outlined, “by continually endeavoring to hide truth from the eyes of others, people become at last unable to perceive it themselves.”</p>



<p>The recent invasion of Ukraine also displayed a surprising level of bureaucratic incompetence. It seems that the Russian Army suffered from a variety of problems, including poor planning, poor intelligence and an inability for mid and lower-level officers to make decisions without approval from above.</p>



<p>In Putin’s Russia, fealty to the Kremlin is valued far more than professionalism. Similar to Stalin in the lead-up to WWII, Putin’s intelligence chiefs <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/09/trump-soviet-intelligence/570085/">reinforced his preconceived notions</a> rather than challenging them. This behavior was also rampant in the 19<sup>th</sup> century Russian court that de Custine encountered.</p>



<p>According to his chronicle, the Tsarist court suffered from a total absence of independent thought brought on by fear of upsetting the Tsar. According to de Custine, “a profound flatterer in Petersburg is the same as a sublime orator in Paris.” He continued, “a Russian conceals everything,” and “a word of truth dropped in Russia is a spark that may fall on a barrel of gunpowder.” de Custine also noted a familiar similarity that Russians have shared across the centuries. Here, he said, “the greatest pleasure of the people is drunkenness; in other words, forgetfulness…I do not believe that suicide is common there: the people suffer too much to kill themselves.”</p>



<p>Like the Tsars before him, Putin has survived by a willingness to use force at home and abroad, and by maintaining an image of power. Over the past two decades, many observers have used the same phrase to describe Putin’s actions on the international stage &#8212; Putin plays a weak hand well. His bullying, threats and lies have protected him from those who might threaten his power.</p>



<p>However, like Tsar Nicholas in WWI, with his invasion of Ukraine, Putin foolishly turned over all his cards and showed his weak hand, seemingly breaking his spell of invincibility. In doing so he has allowed his enemies to better gauge their own strength and position. While it is not clear if Putin has gravely jeopardized his control at home, he has nonetheless weakened himself and Russia, and can no longer bluff that he is playing a winning hand.</p>



<p>As de Custine described 19<sup>th</sup> century Russia but could well be said of Vladimir Putin’s Kremlin, “a government that lives by mystery, and whose strength lies in dissimulation, is afraid of everything.”</p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a> because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness">The Core of Putin&#8217;s Weakness</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-core-of-putins-weakness/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy’s Impact on Europe’s Moral Imperative</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 14:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36943</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron is joining other European leaders in support of an EU Russian oil embargo according to French officials.  French Finance Minister Bruno <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative">Energy&#8217;s Impact on Europe&#8217;s Moral Imperative</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>French President Emmanuel Macron is joining other European leaders in support of an EU <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/an-eu-embargo-russian-oil-works-french-minister-2022-04-19/">Russian oil embargo</a> according to French officials.  French Finance Minister Bruno Le Maire says he hopes that the EU can “stop importing Russian oil in a matter of weeks.” </em></p>



<p><em>Just last week, foreign ministers from Ireland, Lithuania and the Netherlands said the European Union was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/russian-oil-embargo-could-be-part-next-eu-sanctions-package-ministers-say-2022-04-11/">drafting proposals</a>&nbsp;for an oil embargo on Russia on news that Russian troops were killing civilians in Ukraine.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><em>Before that, the EU approved a fifth round of sanctions that included a ban on Russian <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/european-countries-debate-how-to-cut-purchases-of-russian-oil-11649595841">coal imports</a>.  But with Russian oil making up nearly a quarter of the EU’s crude imports, a ban would come at a noteworthy cost.</em></p>



<p><em>The Cipher Brief spoke last week with expert&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule">Norm Roule</a></strong>&nbsp;to help </em><em><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective">put Europe’s energy problem into perspective</a>.&nbsp; “A hard cutoff of Russian energy would confront Europe with curtailed industrial production, blackouts, an inability to build stockpiles for next winter, and a likely recession,” said Roule.&nbsp; “Policymakers will also want to understand the impact further economic sanctions will have on emerging economies and whether India and China will cooperate. &nbsp;Actions that diplomatically isolate Russia will be easier, albeit far less impactful on Russian decision making.”</em></p>



<p><em>But reluctance over such a ban – even in light of Russia’s brutal actions in Ukraine &#8211; <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/14/world/europe/european-union-oil-embargo-russia-ukraine.html?searchResultPosition=1">remains</a>, as the prospect of expanded Western sanctions would work directly against Europe’s economic interests.</em></p>



<p><em>The Cipher Brief talked with <strong>Dr. Anna Mikulska</strong>, and <strong>Dr. Ariel Cohen</strong>, for their perspectives on Europe&#8217;s need for energy and what&#8217;s at stake.</em></p>


<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif"><strong>Dr. Ariel Cohen</strong>, Nonresident Senior Fellow, Atlantic Council Eurasia Center</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<img src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Ariel-Cohen.jpeg" alt="" width="230" class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif">Dr. Ariel Cohen is a nonresident senior fellow at the Atlantic Council Eurasia Center and a member of the Council of Foreign Relations. Dr. Cohen is also a senior fellow at the International Tax and Investment Center (ITIC) where he heads the Energy, Growth, and Security Program (EGS). Dr. Cohen is the Founding Principal of International Market Analysis Ltd, a boutique political risk advisory firm.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif"><strong>Dr. Anna Mikulska</strong>, Nonresident Fellow in Energy Studies, Center for Energy Studies</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<img src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Anna-Mikulska.jpeg" alt="" width="230" class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif">Dr. Anna Mikulska is a nonresident fellow in energy studies for the Center for Energy Studies at Rice University&#8217;s Baker Institute for Public Policy. Her research focuses on the geopolitics of natural gas within the EU, former Soviet Bloc and Russia. Mikulska is a senior fellow at University of Pennsylvania’s Kleinman Center for Energy Policy, where she teaches graduate-level seminars on energy policy and geopolitics of energy.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief</em></strong>:&nbsp; <em>Some observers believe that cutting off Russian gas could wipe out growth in Europe&#8217;s biggest economies, send energy prices to record levels, and propel inflation through the global economy.&nbsp; Given the grim outlook, what measures is Europe likely to pursue to demonstrate its disapproval of Russian military actions in Ukraine?</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Mikulska</em></strong>:&nbsp; It may depend on the extent to which Russia is willing to further push its actions and atrocities that its military might commit. &nbsp;Europe’s economy is important but may have to take a back seat at some point. &nbsp;Just look at the exit of Western companies from Russia, including energy companies such as BP and many others. The move is not predicated upon expectations of profit, rather the opposite but the moral imperative is more important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For Europe, this will also be the case and each government will put different variables into their equation. &nbsp;Natural gas is a tricky commodity, especially in the winter, as much of it serves heating people’s houses. The inability to do so could be catastrophic &#8212; think February last year in <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2022/02/15/texas-power-grid-winter-storm-2021/">Texas</a>. Europe has already cut some of its industrial activity that depended on gas and possibly more is up for cuts.&nbsp; This will impact European economic growth either way. Prices of natural gas will be high as Europe will try to fill up its storage facilities over the summer with Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG), competing with Asian buyers.</p>



<p><strong><em>Cohen:</em></strong>&nbsp; This issue is driven by the internal priorities and interests of each country. France generates about 70 percent of its electricity through nuclear.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mind slamming natural gas sanctions against Russia because it will still have its electricity from nuclear and it will have gas from other sources.&nbsp; Germany, on the other hand is vehemently against that.&nbsp; Holland is against that because the Dutch field at Groningen is depleting, and Holland is also a center for LNG trade, so it wants Russian LNG.&nbsp; Everybody is scrambling to protect their own interests.</p>



<p>The interplay between Paris, Berlin, and more minor capitals and Brussels is fascinating, but I think what&#8217;s significant, and what people forget, is that Europe was really driving the transition to renewables hard. &nbsp;In Germany, this is known as ‘energiewende’ &#8212; energy transformation.&nbsp; Now they have the Green Party in the coalition, so that was a moment to shine.&nbsp; Then, in December, probably knowing what was coming, and probably understanding that the massive investment in renewables is not paying off, the EU declared that natural gas and nuclear will be the green fuels. &nbsp;Before that they were not.</p>



<p>Germany agreed on natural gas because for them, it&#8217;s a major transition from fuel to renewables, but they still resisted nuclear.&nbsp; I think the biggest strategic mistake by Germany that drove this dependence on Russian gas was shutting down nuclear because of the Green agenda. It was a strategic mistake. Whether they&#8217;re going to roll it back or not remains to be seen. So far, I think they&#8217;re sticking to no nuclear.&nbsp; When you&#8217;re asking, what can they do, they can start boosting their nuclear energy.</p>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief</em></strong>:&nbsp; <em>Even before the public exposure of apparent atrocities committed by Russian troops, European leaders – Germany, in particular – were talking about implementing contingency plans to reduce dependence on Russian energy supplies.&nbsp; What do these measures include, and could they be expanded and accelerated?</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Mikulska:&nbsp; </em></strong>Yes, Germany would need to think about what to do if they wanted to replace their supply of gas coming from Russia, which makes up more than 50 percent of their imports. Rationing will be important as will working with other countries to balance the market. An important move was Germany’s takeover of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/german-energy-regulator-sustain-gazprom-germania-operations-2022-04-08/">Gazprom Germania GmbH</a>, the subsidiary that in 2021, was held to record-low gas storage levels. In fact, Gazprom was fulfilling some of its contractual obligations to supply gas to Europe by withdrawing that gas from its storage in Europe at the time when the EU was trying to buy more gas to fill its storage to average levels. The system was obviously broken and will need to be fixed. In Europe, this will most likely mean regulatory measures; we have already heard about mandatory 90 percent storage fill levels as of October 1st.&nbsp; The EU also is talking about mandatory gas storage fill levels.</p>



<p><strong><em>Cohen:</em></strong>&nbsp; Europe has LNG terminal capacity, but they also are now buying Floating Storage and Regasification Units (FSRU). &nbsp;That&#8217;s big bucks because each unit costs something like $250m.&nbsp; The Lithuanians have one, the Poles have one, and then they have one on the beach facilities, K-R-K in Croatia. There&#8217;s one being built in Alexandroupolis, in Greece. &nbsp;The connectivity between the European network and these FSRU facilities is another very important subject.&nbsp; Spain and Portugal have a lot of capacity, but they don&#8217;t have the pipeline into the rest of Europe. &nbsp;They can take LNG and pump it into the rest of Europe, into France and further into the network.</p>



<p>The other problem you have is the scarcity of gas. That&#8217;s a big problem. We don&#8217;t have enough LNG sloshing around and that will drive prices up, clearly. For example, the price of LNG in Europe was half of the price of LNG in Asia. Now they will even out.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The Cipher Brief hosts expert-level briefings on national security issues for <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+Members</a> that help provide context around today’s national security issues and what they mean for business.&nbsp; Upgrade your status to <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+</a> today.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief</em></strong><em>:&nbsp; &nbsp;Although the present crisis is centered in Europe, global factors are likely to come into play as the U.S., EU, and Russia prepare for shifts – and countermoves – in the energy economy.&nbsp; What role could actors outside the region – especially Middle East oil suppliers – play in the evolving situation?&nbsp; Are oil-producing states likely to favor the U.S. and its allies, or Russia?</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Mikulska</em></strong>:&nbsp; We have seen little to no moves from OPEC when it comes to oil supply and production increases beyond the levels that were set long before the Russian invasion. This can – and most likely has &#8212; roots in two factors.</p>



<p>First, there is a general expectation from oil producers that current needs for oil production will wane as recovery from COVID-19 fades, or new COVID waves are an issue, especially in Asia, and hence, if they start producing much more, they may end up with a low demand-high supply situation and we will experience a wild drop in oil prices.</p>



<p>Second, OPEC countries, including most importantly, Saudi Arabia, have been moving geopolitically toward Russia in recent years and away from the U.S. &nbsp;There has been the feeling, also in the U.S., that the <a href="https://history.state.gov/historicaldocuments/frus1977-80v18/d45">Carter Doctrine</a> is not as central to the U.S. policy given the U.S. shale revolution and its success in oil and gas production. In fact, this production made it difficult for OPEC to control global oil markets as it did before. &nbsp;It needed Russia to regain its influence. &nbsp;Therefore, OPEC is hesitant to go against Russia now by increasing production and calming crude prices, which would be seen as helping the U.S. and Europe &#8211; as well as other countries globally of course &#8211; in taming prices at the pump.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Subscriber+Members have a higher level of access to Expert Perspectives on Global Issues.&nbsp; <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade to Subscriber+ now</a>.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong><em>Cohen:&nbsp; </em></strong>Everybody is running to the Saudis and the Emiratis asking to pump more oil, and for sure, Saudis can whereas the gas is in Qatar, but the Qatar production is already spoken for, and American production is spoken for. &nbsp;&nbsp;Qatar, the U.S., and Australia are the top three producers. This is a very tight market. &nbsp;To make a long story short, it will take time, and these are very capital intensive projects. Gas is an order of magnitude more expensive than oil to drill for. And offshore is more expensive than onshore.</p>



<p>So let me pivot to Iran. Iran has 90 million barrels of oil in storage. &nbsp;The U.S. released 180 million [from the strategic reserve] and the International Energy Agency released another 60 million.&nbsp; Saudi could just start pumping up probably a million to a 1.5 million barrels a day immediately. But the Iranians have 90 million in storage. They could start releasing it. That would drive the oil prices down.</p>



<p>Iran has a lot of gas, and if they&#8217;re smart, they would just calm down and let oil companies or gas companies develop the huge gas resources. The giant gas field that the Qataris are exploiting is very successful, to the tune of over a trillion dollars in the national sovereign wealth fund. The Iranians have more than half of that field. They just didn&#8217;t get to developing it. They could if they stop being so cantankerous. &nbsp;So that&#8217;s another possibility. &nbsp;We develop Iran, both through a release of oil in storage and bring back the Iranian oil industry to address shortages and also to develop gas.</p>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief</em></strong><em>: &nbsp;If, as expected, the EU decides in the near term on limited sanctions on Russian energy supplies &#8212; affecting primarily coal and oil &#8212; what longer term steps can the EU or individual European states take to reduce dependence on Russian natural gas deliveries?&nbsp; Is there willingness in the EU to develop alternatives to existing natural gas structures and arrangements?</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Mikulska</em></strong>:&nbsp; Europe needs to develop a system that is independent of the Russian supply. &nbsp;The continent emphatically needs gas. &nbsp;Gas is great for use when renewables are not there to support the grid. &nbsp;Plus, gas is a major fuel for heating.&nbsp; There are several important ways in which Europe could and should act.</p>



<p>First, building more interconnections to make use of unused LNG capacity, particularly in the Iberian Peninsula, which has a huge amount of LNG intake capacity but is barely connected to the rest of Europe. Also, potentially better connections to Italian LNG intake, and via pipeline to the UK, could help balance the European gas market.</p>



<p>In addition, bringing more LNG terminals online particularly where Russian gas would have been used otherwise. Germany comes to mind, of course, but other locations could also be important. More LNG capacity in Central and Eastern Europe could be added too. They are not as well interconnected as the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Cohen:</em></strong>&nbsp; I’ll focus on Germany.&nbsp; When the Germans say we&#8217;ll get off Russian gas, and you look at the numbers &#8212; if they opened the Nordstream 2 pipeline, they would have had 55 percent of their gas coming from Russia. As it is now, it&#8217;s over 40 percent. How you replace that amount in billion cubic meters &#8212; that&#8217;s a lot of their gas. Russia is exporting about 200 billion, it goes up and down. Out of that, let&#8217;s say Germany is half, that&#8217;s 100 BCM, and I&#8217;m looking of the available pipelines and LNG, it is very, very difficult. I do not see how they replace it.</p>



<p>They&#8217;re already saying we&#8217;re giving up Russian coal, and Germany has capacity for coal-fired stations. There&#8217;s plenty of coal around the world, but it&#8217;s very polluting. &nbsp;</p>



<p>They could do a 180 and say, &#8220;<em>You know what, on second opinion, we decided that nuclear is not so polluting and not so bad. Here are the guidelines</em>.&#8221; That&#8217;s what the EU did. You don&#8217;t just keep, like we do, spent fuel in barrels somewhere. You bury it like the French and the Finns do, deep in the mountain somewhere, and hope it doesn&#8217;t seep into the water table. They need to revisit and tighten the controls over nuclear. Here&#8217;s where your baseline capacity may come from. They haven&#8217;t done that yet. And the second thing is that now, nuclear is very expensive. The materials are expensive. The timeline to build used to be four or five years, now it&#8217;s seven to ten years, and double the price, so I&#8217;m not sure they will buy that. They can also push more renewables.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what the limitations are.</p>



<p><em>The piece includes reporting, research and analysis by&nbsp;Ken Hughes and editing by Suzanne Kelly</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a> because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative">Energy&#8217;s Impact on Europe&#8217;s Moral Imperative</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/energys-impact-on-europes-moral-imperative/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting Europe’s Energy Problem into Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 13:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Norm Roule]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36922</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective">Putting Europe&#8217;s Energy Problem into Perspective</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective">Putting Europe&#8217;s Energy Problem into Perspective</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putting-europes-energy-problem-into-perspective/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise of the New Hacker Army but Where’s the Battle?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 14:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Initiatives Group]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech/Cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[hacker army]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36897</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle">Rise of the New Hacker Army but Where&#8217;s the Battle?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle">Rise of the New Hacker Army but Where&#8217;s the Battle?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/rise-of-the-new-hacker-army-but-wheres-the-battle/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How South Korea’s Election Could Impact U.S. National Security</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ambassador Joe DeTrani]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36874</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security">How South Korea&#8217;s Election Could Impact U.S. National Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security">How South Korea&#8217;s Election Could Impact U.S. National Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-south-koreas-election-could-impact-u-s-national-security/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did The Cold War Ever Really End?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 13:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CIA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[national security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36854</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Sonya Seunghye Lim, Former Chief of Station, CIA Sonya Seunghye Lim is a former Chief of Station with the Central Intelligence Agency where she had <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end">Did The Cold War Ever Really End?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;"><strong>Sonya Seunghye Lim</strong>, Former Chief of Station, CIA</p>
</div>
<div>
<div><img class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0;" src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sonya-Lim-200x200.jpeg" alt="" width="230"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;">Sonya Seunghye Lim is a former Chief of Station with the Central Intelligence Agency where she had a 24-year distinguished career in the Directorate of Operations, to include two assignments as Chief of Station. She also served as Chief of Operations at CIA Headquarters.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;"><strong>Christopher Turner</strong>, Former CIA Operations Officer</p>
</div>
<div>
<div><img class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0;" src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Christopher-Turner-200x200.jpeg" alt="" width="230"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;">Christopher Turner had a 25-year career in the Central Intelligence Agency’s Directorate of Operations, during which he completed several sensitive assignments in the Far East, South Asia, and Europe.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<p id="block-1ff43425-4af5-4888-b49c-bf4880949400"><strong><br>OPINION </strong>&#8212; From the optic of the United States intelligence community (USIC), the Cold War didn&#8217;t end in the 1990s with the Fall of Communism. Its outward appearance was merely altered. Beneath a thin veneer of economic and political engagement, Russia and China continued to pose threats to liberal democratic ideals and values.&nbsp; The past twenty years have seen massive Russian and Chinese operations against the US and its allies to steal our secrets and to disseminate anti-democratic propaganda.</p>



<p id="block-bd904a6a-c0a2-44fd-a391-3cd687fdb315">But outside the USIC, political rapprochement without clear-eyed calculation and economic expediencies without consideration of long-term costs were the preferred approaches. &nbsp;Such wishful thinking spawned a false sense of security&#8211;that wars could be contained and that aggressors could be talked out of their mad plans. &nbsp;From 2008’s Russo-Georgia War to Russia’s taking of Crimea in 2014, its direct entry into the Syrian conflict in 2015, and its invasion of Ukraine this year, Russian President Vladimir Putin has proved again how inaccurate and fanciful such perceptions were. &nbsp;A world emerging from the horrors of Putin’s latest large-scale predations will require decisive action and clear policy to quell its sordid aftermath—rampant spread of misinformation, persistent cyberattacks, and withering skirmishes in the realms of economy, security, and intelligence. &nbsp;</p>



<p id="block-b8e9ec8d-3247-4ba3-8fa2-7c6d0480a5d9">Since his invasion of Ukraine, the airwaves, the internet and print media have been filled with observations and analyses on Putin’s many mistakes focused on the fact that he took these missteps despite his KGB background and the vast intelligence apparatus at his beck and call. &nbsp;It’s clear that Putin chose to wage this war based on a myriad of wrong assumptions, on an inaccurate assessment of his military’s competence and readiness, and on poor, misinterpreted, or dismissed intelligence (or perhaps all three). &nbsp;Putin’s Russia as a threat to democratic ideals is no longer an abstraction that can be shelved or otherwise discounted for the sake of political expediency. &nbsp;Putin is now demonstrating that he is a menace to any semblance of world security and stability; he has no other role or purpose in the world. &nbsp;While Putin’s war has so far failed to achieve his strategic goals, it has hastened the inevitable confrontation between liberal democracy and authoritarianism and has split much of the world—though in overly simplistic terms—into two camps, good and evil. &nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The Cipher Brief hosts expert-level briefings on national security issues for </em></strong><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus"><strong><em>Subscriber+Members</em></strong></a><strong><em> that help provide context around today’s national security issues and what they mean for business.&nbsp; Upgrade your status to </em></strong><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus"><strong><em>Subscriber+</em></strong></a><strong><em> today.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p id="block-0ba43266-fcfa-42ae-9ce2-fdc2b187a06f">This split has also affected global order and prioritization. After a period of sending mixed signals, the US has re-emerged as the leader of those liberal democratic countries that stand against cruel authoritarian regimes. This development may also create closer agreement between the US and the European Union (EU) on their policies towards China. And, in coldly pragmatic terms, the US may profit from a new iteration of the Cold War as the EU dramatically reduces its energy reliance on and trade with Russia. &nbsp;On this point Germany offers a clear example. &nbsp;For the past four decades, Germany maintained a close relationship with Russia. &nbsp;The construction of the Nord Stream II pipeline, despite the limited sanctions and US prostrations at the time, illustrated Berlin’s once-favorable stance towards Russia. Putin’s invasion of Ukraine changed all of this, and Germany now finds itself on the cusp of a taking on another prominent role in the EU—charting the region’s future in security and military affairs.</p>



<p id="block-18e16602-04ed-4f55-9575-2fc1f499b3dd">With the significant reduction in Russia’s economic relations with the EU, China will likely be Putin’s sole viable option for economic and political support. &nbsp; Due to China’s established and growing confrontation with the US and the EU, both in terms of trade and Chinese expansion of influence and territory, coupled with China’s great need for energy, Russia and China appear fated to intensify their cooperation. &nbsp; Exactly how this cooperation will sort out remains uncertain, but it only bodes ill for the non-authoritarian world.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" id="block-ac2fb2b9-cadb-413d-8897-94a2defe71ea"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center" id="block-d90932f5-6217-4153-94cc-06ac69e0fec6"><strong><em>Today’s constant barrage of information makes it easy for countries to wage disinformation campaigns and your emotions are the weapon of choice.&nbsp; Learn how disinformation works and how we can fight it in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">short video</a>.&nbsp; This is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">one link</a> you can feel good about sharing.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" id="block-fea3cfdf-7200-4bd0-98ff-1e4f746faceb"/>



<p id="block-803428ea-e016-428f-808f-bcbf563e1ad8">But Russia has other, albeit smaller, de-facto supporters. As the biggest producers of fossil fuel energy, Arab nations will benefit from rising energy prices caused by late-pandemic demand and sanctions against Russia. &nbsp;Those Arab countries that have not supported the US/EU sanctions against Russia may well become safe havens for Russian oligarchs. &nbsp;It is not surprising that some of them have already begun to park their most extravagant assets in the region in attempts to avoid sequestration.</p>



<p id="block-328fc77f-208e-4356-a27e-c9951475f508">The outlook offers an abundance of gloom and doom, but we should always recall that, in great setbacks and challenges, equally great opportunities often lie. Energy dependence, economic investments, and risk aversion were some of the key obstacles to closer cooperation between the US and the EU on Russia and China in the recent past. &nbsp; We are witnessing a dangerous formation of an international order in which Russia and China solidify their resolve to confront US-led alliances and intentions. &nbsp;But we are also seeing the exploitable weaknesses in Putin’s regime. &nbsp;Survivalist instincts, shifting allegiances, and raw greed at both the individual and national levels will present opportunities to collect key intelligence on liberal democracies’ fiercest adversaries. &nbsp;We are also witnessing the enormous power of ideology, liberal values, and collective actions. &nbsp;</p>



<p id="block-5c29eea5-5012-4f2a-a22c-632238902efd">Regardless of the outcome of Putin’s war against Ukraine, in the coming months and years Russia and China will wage an even more intense espionage war against the US and its allies. &nbsp; The good news is that liberal democracies have finally been roused from the complacency in which they’d largely wallowed since the Fall of Communism. Now is the time to commit to comprehensive intelligence and security cooperation among our allies so that we may formulate coherent and clear policies to counter these existing and coming threats.</p>



<p id="block-acba078d-2641-49c5-8305-eda8bbc0ff92"><strong><em>Sharing informed opinions is important.&nbsp; Opinion pieces represent the diverse views of The Cipher Brief audience and do not represent views of The Cipher Brief.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center" id="block-be7655d1-c867-4801-8045-e3bae8219338"><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a> because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end">Did The Cold War Ever Really End?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/did-the-cold-war-ever-really-end/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cruelty of Half Measures in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 13:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Doug Wise]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[refugees]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Robert Papp]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36846</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Doug Wise, Former Deputy Director, Defense Intelligence Agency Douglas H. Wise served as Deputy Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency from August 2014 until August <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine">The Cruelty of Half Measures in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif"><strong>Doug Wise</strong>, Former Deputy Director, Defense Intelligence Agency</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<img src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Doug-Wise-bw-200x200.jpg" alt="" width="230" class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif">Douglas H. Wise served as Deputy Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency from August 2014 until August 2016. Following 20 years of active duty in the Army where he served as an infantry and special operations officer, he spent the remainder of his career at CIA.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif"><strong>Robert Papp</strong>, Former Senior Executive, CIA</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<img src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Robert-Papp.jpeg" alt="" width="230" class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif">Robert Papp retired from the Central Intelligence Agency as a senior executive with extensive service abroad and command experience. He began his career in the U.S. Navy as a cryptologic officer and Russian linguist. He has a PhD in Russian history from Columbia University an M.A. in Russian Area Studies from Georgetown University and a B.S. from the U.S. Naval Academy.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<p id="block-715e7727-46f6-438a-b2ae-6da4c15b7d2a"><strong><br>OPINION </strong>&#8212; As of this article, the slaughter continues to increase, the Russian military juggernaut stumbles forward and backward, and the negotiations stalemate. At some point in the not-too-distant future, historians and political scientists will try to answer the question, when does encouraging and incentivizing a valiant nation fighting brutal aggression become an act of geopolitical cynicism as well as a source of inspiration?</p>



<p id="block-e4ff7074-958f-4f9d-bbb4-8852ab8811f8">As the Russian invasion of Ukraine continues in “full force,” NATO continues with a set of “half measures,” and overly cautious initiatives. For this article, we define “half-measures” as the provision of military support, encouragement of Ukrainians to fight, and the economic “warfare” against the Russia &#8211; all done to respond to the invasion while avoiding direct combat with the Russian military (the authors believe the deployment of NATO forces into Ukraine should have been done before the Russian military violated Ukraine sovereignty).</p>



<p id="block-2a73edc3-b2b4-4d22-a50b-616ebaef407c">We believe those in the future will judge us harshly for being overly cautious and not intervening earlier and more decisively. It’s also likely they will harshly criticize us for exploiting the limitless courage and determination of the Ukraine people. We acknowledge the provision of NATO anti-tank weapons, surface-to-air missiles, and other equipment and intelligence support by NATO member states has made a major difference on the Ukraine battlefield. As a consequence, observers around the globe are consuming a steady diet of social media images of burned-out Russian tanks and helicopters falling to earth.</p>



<p id="block-7498f3b7-6071-4f2c-96ad-0971a952ed99">Additionally, we internalize a degree of comfort by expressing our “solidarity” and encouraging Ukrainian resistance while we remain inspired by the brave defiance of President Zelenskyy. Because we culturally champion the underdog, we harbor a fervent hope Russian forces are stalled, out of ammunition, suffering from poor morale and training, incapable of a full victory, and the tide will turn in favor of the Ukraine Army. But hope is not a plan, and we must remain receptive to the objective reality Ukraine cannot force the Russian army from Ukraine soil.</p>



<p id="block-775b6030-7cb8-431e-ad0b-794e52f06ea2">Despite the poor military advice Putin received from his armed forces leaders, matched by his own fantasies about a quick conquest of the largest country in Europe, we need to look objectively at what is happening on the ground. Comparing a current tactical map of Russian advances to Putin’s infamous “historical” map of an illegitimate Ukrainian state, suggests he is not decisively winning, unless winning to Putin is the slaughter of thousands of innocent Ukraine civilians. We also have a yearning for regime change in Russia. But is Russia really turning against him while we silently plead for the mothers of those Russian soldiers killed in action to rise up and confront the Putin regime? Or are we blinded by our own optimism because we narrowly focus on street protests, bloggers, and newsroom embarrassments in Moscow?</p>



<p id="block-1684be8c-bddb-4e75-b28a-5e0b3dc8644f">We may vilify Putin as a national leader, but doubt he is truly isolated and need to keep in mind he enjoys the support of the majority of the Russian population, and it is also important to remember parts of the world have not spoken out against him, and some are even supporting him. Unable to achieve victory on the ground, Putin’s immoral recourse (which we’ve already started to see) is to turn to indiscriminate missile and air attacks, and barbaric rocket and artillery strikes against innocent civilians. As Putin becomes more enraged with losses on the ground, he is already “culturally compelled” to use the time-tested Russian method of pounding cities into submission.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" id="block-2285e7d7-af71-4a2c-a1e6-a9d7627c61bd"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center" id="block-39935442-c21b-4e77-b63b-fcc90fa85034"><strong><em>Cipher Brief <u>Subscriber+Members</u> can access Cipher Brief Expert and former CIA Chief of the Central Eurasia Division, Rob Dannenberg’s assessment, <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalatio">With his only option being escalation, this is how Putin’s War must End</a></em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" id="block-8bf0f1b4-74a9-4f5e-a35a-2aacf714749a"/>



<p id="block-2732dcfa-3573-4914-99cc-8467c127fbc5">These tactics have been used by the Russia throughout history from the Berlin in World War II, Grozny in Chechnya, and Raqqa in Syria. Since Putin’s inner circle is personally named in sanctions, threatened with designation as war criminals, and facing the ultimate economic collapse of the Russian Federation, they are trapped. Like Putin’s childhood “cornered rat”, they have little recourse but to join with him and fight to the end because their wealth and power derives from him, and his from the state.</p>



<p id="block-3085cc3b-011d-48af-afb9-7ad21e3f7074">The wounded bear must win and do so quickly. Total war in Ukraine is a logical outcome as NATO’s half measures are unlikely to dissuade Putin from seeking total and unconditional victory. While we painfully ponder why Russia is taking this violent path, it is important to keep in mind that Putin’s “special military operation” is as much about humiliating and punishing Ukraine as it is about military accomplishment. As we watch the “irresistible Russian force meet the immovable Ukrainian object,” can we credibly assess that a decisive Ukrainian victory on the ground is achievable?</p>



<p id="block-d80c948c-2cd9-4f1a-a6bb-3a5c48693413">Ukrainians will certainly die trying, while NATO remains on the sidelines debating ever-expanding ideas about what constitutes an act of war while conveniently defining the limits of NATO’s moral obligations (in the absence of the Article V ethos of “an attack on one, is an attack on all”) to conveniently avoid doing more.</p>



<p id="block-929e5472-786f-4e29-84fa-495b918f43cd">It might be useful to note at this point the NATO bombing of Belgrade in 1999, to defend the Kosovar Albanians, was done outside the Article V obligation. Nobody, including the authors, advocates abandoning the Ukrainians to their fate or encouraging them to sue for peace under draconian terms. But who gains and who loses from the continued carnage and human suffering that NATO’s almost-but-not-quite good-enough-to-turn-tide-of victory military support is inevitably enabling?</p>



<p id="block-c299e02e-c27f-452a-a479-3bca600651fa">Soon the Ukrainian population, which has already seen the flight of some three million refugees, will have little remaining but rubble for where cities once stood. The humanitarian implications of this wanton Russian destruction on the ground are only just starting to be felt and it is unlikely the Russian occupiers will accept future humanitarian aid and assistance from the West fearing it will bring the spirit of freedom in addition to critically needed food, water, and medical care.</p>



<p id="block-07fc44b2-5ed3-4aec-a0a0-9551eddc94e5">Other losers across the globe and far from the carnage have yet to be fully defined. The dizzying levels of NATO economic warfare, as a surrogate for NATO military action, may not produce decisive results, but will remain satisfying for Western leaders. Forget for now the effects on supply chains and global markets, stock market portfolios, hedge funds, and currencies in developed economies. Forget even potential cyberattacks or the possible disabling of the internet. Consider instead the epic plight of poor nations, who even now are staggering from the price of wheat in the Middle East and beyond.</p>



<p id="block-23b09008-2d9c-45bb-99b6-6f0ecd765992">One constant in this war is its unpredictability. We have been surprised at every turn and it is very possible that in spite of NATO’s cautious actions we will find ourselves in direct military confrontation with Russian forces. Should this happen, we will regret we had not confronted the Russians some 10,000 fallen Ukrainians ago. We missed our opportunity to intervene as the Russians were massing their invasion forces, so now we are fighting “by, with, and through” Ukrainian courage while NATO stands and watches.</p>



<p id="block-ed715eef-690f-466a-ae5d-b4a94065a7f3">The historians of the future will judge us harshly for exploiting and squandering the gift every fallen Ukrainian has given us. Let us honor and applaud the courage, determination and resilience of the Ukraine people and loudly condemn the barbaric Russian aggression. Let us also not have illusions about the real impact of feelgood measures that do not change final outcomes in place of decisive NATO support. Cruelty comes in many forms.</p>



<p id="block-bed8ebd7-9792-43f5-8b88-0a07035bdfcc"><strong><em>Sharing informed opinions is important.&nbsp; Opinion pieces represent the diverse views of The Cipher Brief audience and do not represent views of The Cipher Brief.&nbsp; Have an opinion to share?&nbsp; Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com</em></strong></p>



<p id="block-fc56b572-82aa-45c3-a4a5-e4e47857bbfb"><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a> because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine">The Cruelty of Half Measures in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cruelty-of-half-measures-in-ukraine/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO’s Emergency Session Will Move Us Closer to What?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 14:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[NATO]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36824</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what">NATO&#8217;s Emergency Session Will Move Us Closer to What?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what">NATO&#8217;s Emergency Session Will Move Us Closer to What?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/natos-emergency-session-will-move-us-closer-to-what/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is NATO’s Casablanca Moment</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 13:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[NATO]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36797</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OPINION &#8212; In the 1942 Hollywood classic Casablanca, Ingrid Bergman, playing Ilsa Lund famously says, “Play it, Sam.” A little under a year later, the <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment">This is NATO&#8217;s Casablanca Moment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>OPINION</strong> &#8212; In the 1942 Hollywood classic Casablanca, Ingrid Bergman, playing Ilsa Lund famously says, “Play it, Sam.” A little under a year later, the Casablanca Conference was held at the Anfa Hotel in Casablanca. Attending were the leaders of many of the Allied powers including U.S. President Franklin Roosevelt and British Prime Minister Winston Churchill.</p>



<p>The purpose of the conference was to discuss allied war strategy, but it is most famously remembered for the declaration of “unconditional surrender,” a doctrine which reflected the unity, will, confidence and determination of the Allies. The war was far from certain to be won by the Allies.&nbsp; The battle of Stalingrad was raging as was combat in the Pacific.&nbsp; The battle of the Atlantic was far from over and most of Europe was still occupied by Nazi Germany.</p>



<p>The Casablanca Conference was nonetheless a bold meeting with a declaration that reflected the understanding those leaders had that the world was at an historic inflection point and an unequivocal message needed to be sent to the Axis powers.</p>



<p>We are at a similar inflection point in history, but do not yet have a world at war.</p>



<p>On March 24, the leaders of the NATO member states will meet in Brussels for talks on the Russian invasion of Ukraine. Biden is then scheduled to attend a European Union summit to discuss further sanctions against Russia and humanitarian aid for Ukraine. This is commendable, but misses the opportunity to send a message as decisive as the message sent in Casablanca in 1943.</p>



<p>Putin has launched a war of conquest against a smaller neutral neighbor. The images from that invasion have horrified the civilized world as has the refugee and displaced persons crisis.&nbsp; Nearly three million Ukrainians have fled the country and perhaps a larger number have been internally displaced.</p>



<p>Putin’s lackey, Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko—often referred to as Europe’s last dictator—has allowed Belarus to be used as a platform from which Putin launched the invasion and Belarus continues to be a primary support base for invasion forces.</p>



<p>The war is not going well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many observers believe an effective stalemate has been reached with Putin no longer having the military forces to achieve the conquest of the Ukraine or achieve his pre-war objectives. Conservative estimates of Russian casualties suggest numbers greater than the U.S. losses in Iraq and Afghanistan combined and Soviet losses in the 10 years of their invasion of Afghanistan. The Ukrainians have fought with skill and determination, but the grim mathematics of war are against them.</p>



<p>There will be no negotiated solution to this conflict. Negotiations are the favored solution in the West, but the reality of Putin’s evil proscribes a negotiated solution short of unconditional surrender by Putin. The few attempts at negotiating limited ceasefires thus far, to allow the evacuation of civilians from cities, have failed. Recent polling in Ukraine shows incredible resolve that they support their President and Commander-in-Chief (91%), that they believe they can defeat the Russians (70%), and that they do not support conceding either the secessionist Donbas regions or Crimea to Russia (79%).&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is likely the West will continue to supply Ukraine with effective anti-armor and anti-aircraft systems that will certainly inhibit any future Russian attempts to increase their territorial gains.&nbsp; The effectiveness of these weapons and the skill of Ukrainian defenders has forced the Russian advance on Kyiv to halt and revert to digging earthworks to protect their armored forces.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The White House is warning U.S. businesses of potential cyberattacks. Get expert insights into what this means by signing up for the <a href="http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/">Cyber Initiatives Group</a> newsletter. Different results require different thinking.&nbsp; Sign up for the <a href="https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;id=9307211312">CIG newsletter</a> today.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>So where does military stalemate leave us?&nbsp; With the conviction Putin seemingly still has of Russia’s victory and his assessment of the fecklessness of the West, the answer to the question may be the use of weapons of mass destruction, particularly chemical weapons, which Putin countenanced for use by his surrogate in Syria, Bashir Al-Assad.</p>



<p>Chemical weapons are particularly useful in urban combat environments like the ones Russian forces now face in several cities across Ukraine. As Ukrainian President Zelenskyy has said, if you want to know what the Russians intend to do, look at what they are accusing others of doing.</p>



<p>The Russians are accusing the US and Ukraine of developing and preparing to use chemical and biological weapons.&nbsp; Given the accuracy of US intelligence both before and during this now nearly month-long conflict, it may be significant that a growing number of US officials &#8211; that one presumes have access to this intelligence &#8211; are warning of Russia’s plans to use chemical weapons.&nbsp; This should be a flashing red light danger signal to the world of the risk of escalation of this conflict.</p>



<p>The use of any form of WMD in Ukraine should be grounds for intervention by a broad international coalition; NATO, Japan, Australia, New Zealand immediately come to mind and many more from across the international community.</p>



<p>A “no fly zone” and western Ukraine safe haven should be immediately declared.&nbsp; As well as a 21st century declaration of unconditional surrender.&nbsp; Vladimir Putin and the cabal of Russian leaders that brought about this war are war criminals and need to be brought to justice.&nbsp; Anything less is evasion and appeasement.</p>



<p>Thursday’s NATO meeting should be the opportunity to lay down a Casablanca Conference marker that sends a message to Putin and all his ilk lurking under their rocks around the world.&nbsp; They should be told that the free world will no longer ignore, rationalize, or appease them. Be it North Korea, Iran, Cuba, Venezuela, or even China, the message the West sends to Putin will be heard by the leaders of those countries.</p>



<p>An awakened and determined free world is a powerful force as Hitler, Mussolini, and Hirohito learned in the 20th Century.&nbsp; Putin has been relentlessly rebuilding Stalinism in Russia these past twenty or more years. Let us give him the opportunity to witness the collapse of that system for the second time in his life. The West needs a Casablanca moment and expression of determination, will, and confidence. Play it again, Uncle Sam.</p>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief hosts expert-level briefings on national security issues for <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+Members</a> that help provide context around today’s national security issues and what they mean for business.&nbsp; Upgrade your status to <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+</a> today.</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment">This is NATO&#8217;s Casablanca Moment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/this-is-natos-casablanca-moment/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deal or No Deal on Iran’s Nuclear Program?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 14:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Nuclear]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Gary Grappo]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Heather Williams]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36786</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Bottom Line:&#160; After a several-day hiatus brought about by a now-withdrawn Russian demand concerning relief from newly imposed Western sanctions, JCPOA talks appear ready to <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program">Deal or No Deal on Iran&#8217;s Nuclear Program?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><u>Bottom Line</u></strong>:&nbsp; After a several-day hiatus brought about by a now-withdrawn Russian demand concerning relief from newly imposed Western sanctions, JCPOA talks appear ready to resume in Vienna.&nbsp; <em><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/iran-nuclear-deals-final-hurdle-is-lifting-terrorism-sanctions-on-revolutionary-guards-11647864073?mod=hp_lead_pos7">The Wall Street Journal</a></em> reports that negotiations are facing a remaining hurdle that could derail discussions.&nbsp;&nbsp;At issue is the removal of terrorism sanctions placed on Iran’s Revolutionary Guard force by the US.&nbsp;&nbsp;<em>The Wall Street Journal</em> report calls this perhaps the ‘most politically sensitive’ issue with some US allies like Israel vehemently opposed to removing sanctions.&nbsp;&nbsp;Some US officials say that failure to compromise on this point could result in a breakdown of negotiations<em>.&nbsp;</em>What could this mean for a future deal and how is Russia’s role in negotiations playing out?</p>



<p><strong><u>Background</u></strong><strong>:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Iranian Foreign Minister Hossein Amir-Abdollahian said at the <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/3/15/russia-says-it-has-received-us-guarantees-over-iran-nuclear-deal">conclusion of talks</a> with his Russian counterpart, “If we reach an agreement with the U.S. on remaining issues which relate to some of Iran’s main red lines, based on my talks with Mr. Lavrov today, Russia will remain beside the Islamic Republic of Iran until reaching a good and sustainable agreement, continuing to play the constructive role it has played since the start.”<br><br></li><li>For his part, Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/wrapup-1-russia-says-written-181931083.html">said</a>, &#8220;We have received written guarantees – they are included in the very text of the agreement on reviving the JCPOA, and in these texts there is a reliable defense of all the projects provided for by the JCPOA and those activities – including the linking up of our companies and specialists.&#8221;<br><br></li><li>Meanwhile, a senior U.S. State Department official <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-russia-continue-engage-iran-nuclear-deal-state-department-official-2022-03-15/">said</a>, &#8220;We continue to engage with Russia on a return to full implementation of the JCPOA,&#8221; adding, &#8220;we would of course not sanction Russian participation in nuclear projects that are part of resuming full implementation of the JCPOA.&#8221;<br></li></ul>



<p><em>The Cipher Brief spoke with <strong>Ambassador Gary Grappo</strong>, former U.S. Ambassador to Oman and <strong>Heather Williams</strong>, former </em><em>acting national intelligence officer for Iran on the National Intelligence Council to get their take on the status of talks.</em><em></em></p>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief: </em></strong><em><strong>What were Russia’s objectives in raising sanctions relief related to Ukraine in the context of the JCPOA talks?</strong></em></p>


<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif"><strong>Ambassador Gary Grappo</strong>, Former U.S. Ambassador to Iran</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<img src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Gary-Grappo-bw-200x200.jpg" alt="" width="230" class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0"><p></p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif">It’s difficult to see through the smoke of the Ukraine invasion, what the Russian government may be thinking on other urgent foreign policy matters like the JCPOA. The Russian foreign ministry is clueless on the war and what their boss may now be seeking after the setbacks they’ve experienced. Nevertheless, their chief negotiator on the JCPOA had been playing a seemingly constructive role to date. &nbsp;So, it was odd that Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov made the statement he did after the Russians had pulled this eleventh hour stunt that ended up putting the Americans and the Iranians on the same side, shockingly. Clearly, the Russian gambit to somehow get themselves exempted from the recently imposed sanctions using the JCPOA collapsed and Lavrov needed to come up with an excuse/justification. His interpretation is wholly his own. I suspect the US team may waive comment until the renewed JCPOA is signed and sealed, if indeed that comes to pass. The Russians will find no escape from sanctions and no concessions… and they know it. Had the deal failed to go through because of the Russian ploy, they would have been blamed by all sides, including the Iranians. It was a hail-Mary maneuver that never had a prayer.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<p></p>


<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;">
<div style="background: #EBEBEB; padding: 6px; margin-bottom: -10px;">
<p style="margin: 1px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;"><strong>Heather Williams</strong>, Former Acting National Intelligence Manager for Iran, National Intelligence Council</p>
</div>
<div>
<div><img class="size-full wp-image-25285" style="padding: 0 13px 13px 0; background: white; float: left; width: 110px; margin: 0 15px 7px 0;" src="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Heather-Williams.jpeg" alt="" width="230" />
<p> </p>
<p style="color: white; background: #0A1531; padding: 9px 13px 9px 13px; font-size: 18px; font-family: ‘replica-pro’, arial, sans-serif;">I would assume that Russia has backed down from their demands about explicit, sweeping guarantees, and reinterpreted the deal’s language in a face-saving way, rather than the U.S. or the EU3 (France, Germany, UK) providing concessions to Russia regarding sanctions it faces because of its actions in Ukraine.  Nothing about Lavrov’s statements imply to me that the proposed language being worked out has necessarily changed because of Russia’s recent actions. Since it did sound like agreement on the language had been reached prior to Russia’s efforts to play spoiler, I don’t think that Iran &#8211; nor we &#8211; would be interested in revisiting that language if we can avoid it. This is a carefully balanced apple cart – no one wants to go poking it.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>


<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Read also <a href="JCPOA: If we Get an Agreement, What will it Mean?">JCPOA: If we Get an Agreement, What will it Mean?</a> With insights from former National Intelligence Manager for Iran, Norman Roule exclusively in The Cipher Brief</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief:</em> </strong> <em>How do you expect JCPOA to proceed?  Will the temporary impasse introduced by Russia hang over the continuation of talks, or will it simply be another obstacle solved on the way to an agreement?</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Ambassador Grappo:</em></strong><strong>&nbsp; </strong>No one in the U.S. administration is talking much about the state of the negotiations other than to say they are close. The Americans’ discipline is both necessary and admirable, given the sensitivity of this matter to so many interests in the U.S. and abroad. Without knowing the U.S. redlines, it’s very hard then, to know where we may be. &nbsp;My own take is that this administration does not wish to suffer the same fate as the Obama administration, i.e., negotiate an agreement that is roundly panned by the Republicans as well as many Democrats and by many of our allies in the Middle East, especially Israel, and then overturned by the next Republican administration. It will, therefore, have to address the time horizons on when various sanctions expire, missiles and Americans held by the Iranian government. I would be very surprised if these three issues did not appear in some form in a newly negotiated JCPOA.</p>



<p><strong><em>Williams:</em> </strong>At this point, it does seem like a resumption of the deal is imminent, despite Russia’s failed attempt to squeeze out self-serving advantage in these final hours of negotiation.&nbsp; I don’t foresee those diplomatic games having a lasting impact on the deal itself, but they—and the attacks in Erbil—are a reminder that the nuclear deal will be jostled by all of the other many contentious issues at play in the region.&nbsp; I consider that a reminder that the ability of the JCPOA to make meaningful advancements in limiting Iran’s nuclear program and ability to develop nuclear weapons—even if it could not also address Iran’s missile capabilities and nefarious regional influence—as a strength rather than a weakness of the nuclear deal. Attempting to solve every contentious issue at play with Iran through negotiations is an impossible task, but addressing this critical issue allows us to focus on leveraging other tools of national power on our other national security interests vis-a-vis Iran.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The Cipher Brief hosts expert-level briefings on national security issues for </em></strong><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus"><strong><em>Subscriber+Members</em></strong></a><strong><em> that help provide context around today’s national security issues and what they mean for business.&nbsp; Upgrade your status to </em></strong><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus"><strong><em>Subscriber+</em></strong></a><strong><em> today</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong><em>The Cipher Brief:  </em></strong><em><strong>There are, of course, other interests and agendas at stake related to JCPOA besides the agreement itself.  What are the impacts of domestic and regional politics, proxy and insurgent attacks, and concerns about Iran’s nuclear future on near- and long-term debate, stability, and conflict?</strong></em></p>



<p><strong><em>Ambassador Grappo</em></strong><em>:</em>&nbsp; My own very personal view is that this is an issue [the Biden] administration seems to have pursued diligently and faithfully. To return with no agreement, while disappointing to some party stalwarts, could be easily explained with little near-term domestic political fallout. (However, we should then expect tensions in the Middle East to ratchet up as the Israelis and Saudis take steps to counter the Iranian nuclear threat.) And the administration would be off the hook in terms of Republican opposition, having shown resolve on bottom lines and not “caving in,” as it were. Whereas, a new deal will have to meet some pretty high bars, of which the administration and the negotiating team must be very much aware.</p>



<p>As for Iran’s support for the various malign groups in the region, this is a <em>strategic </em>issue for the Iranians. Making progress on that would require the direct engagement of multiple parties in the region, many of whom do not speak with one another.&nbsp; But establishing some process to finally address that, or least appearing to, would be a significant achievement. But to date, we’ve heard nothing on this matter from any of the negotiators, which is to be expected, given its enormous sensitivity. The U.S. and our allies in the P5+1 (China, France, Russia, United Kingdom, United States—plus Germany) may end up making some sort of joint statement and the Iranians something different, with no clear resolution other than continued efforts, at best. I’m less hopeful on this issue than on the rest.</p>



<p><em>The piece includes research, analysis and reporting by Cipher Brief Analyst Ken Hughes</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insight, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a></em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program">Deal or No Deal on Iran&#8217;s Nuclear Program?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/deal-or-no-deal-on-irans-nuclear-program/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soviet Espionage Under the Cover of Diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 14:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Espionage]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Calder Walton]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[United Nations]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36757</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE &#8212; Immediately after Russia’s invasion of Ukraine last month, the US government expelled 13 Russian diplomats working at the United Nations. It did <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy">Soviet Espionage Under the Cover of Diplomacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE</strong> &#8212; Immediately after Russia’s invasion of Ukraine last month, the US government expelled 13 Russian diplomats working at the United Nations. It did so on the grounds they were Russian intelligence officers or operatives working under diplomatic cover. We do not know details about their alleged activities, but we do know something for certain: the Kremlin has a long history of using the United Nations (UN) for espionage.</p>



<p>During the Cold War, Soviet intelligence penetrated and subverted key parts of the UN. Occasionally these operations crashed into the public domain, when Western governments expelled Soviet ‘diplomats’. Contrary to what we might assume, such expulsions were not just grandstanding, but in fact paid off counterintelligence dividends for Western national security.</p>



<p>From its earliest days, the Soviet government viewed the UN as a platform for delivering its outward message to the world. The Soviet government was a permanent member of the UN Security Council, which granted it a right of veto, which it frequently used.</p>



<p>Between 1945 and 1983, the Soviet government cast 115 vetoes, as opposed to 38 by the US government and 20 by the British. Under the terms of the Yalta agreement reached between the Soviet government and Western powers in 1945, two of the Soviet Socialist Republics, Ukraine and Byelorussia (present day Belarus), were members of the UN in their own right. This effectively gave the Soviet Union three votes as opposed to the US government’s one.</p>



<p>These aspects of the Soviet Union’s open diplomacy at the UN are well known. Its clandestine activities there are less so. They are revealed in a British foreign office file that was declassified in September 2021, titled “<a href="https://discovery.nationalarchives.gov.uk/details/r/C17474019">Russian intelligence service operating under UN cover</a>”. The thick, orange-covered file, stamped “Secret”, carries strict instructions for its handling. Reading it throws the US government’s expulsions today into sharp relief.</p>



<p>The file reveals that in the 1970s, the Soviet Union’s intelligence services, the KGB and the GRU, thoroughly penetrated the UN in New York and Geneva. Their officers used diplomatic cover for espionage. In fact, as the file makes clear, the KGB controlled key parts of the UN’s bureaucracy. This was happening when the Soviet government was supposedly enjoying a thaw in Cold War relations with West, during the period of détente.</p>



<p>The most sensational disclosure about Soviet penetration of the UN occurred in 1978. That year, its Undersecretary General, Arkady Shevchenko, a Soviet national, defected to US authorities – the highest-ranking Soviet official ever to do so. Shevchenko soon <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breaking-Moscow-Arkady-N-Shevchenko/dp/0394520556/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1EN0MS7KCGTT2&amp;keywords=Arkady+shevchenko&amp;qid=1646944677&amp;sprefix=arkady+shevchenko%2Caps%2C126&amp;sr=8-1">publicly revealed</a> that he was a KGB officer.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Register for your own Expert-Level Briefing on <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/register/4198840714317866766">Ukraine and How Private Sector Intelligence is Defining a New World</a> with Mandiant CEO Kevin Mandia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Wednesday, March 23 from 1:30p – 2:30p ET</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>Shevchenko had been previously recruited by the CIA, which convinced him to continue— bravely— to operate as an agent in place at the UN. After his defection and extensive de-briefing, he revealed to the world that the Soviet intelligence presence at the UN went deep. The Soviet regime was cheating when it came to détente. His intelligence can be corroborated by other sources, which to this day, the Kremlin wants kept secret.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shevchenko revealed that half of the Soviet nationals working at UN headquarters in New York, and in its Office in Geneva, were either intelligence officers or were explicitly assigned intelligence-related tasks. By obtaining posts in the UN Secretariat, the Soviet government effectively obtained a rolodex of information about civil servants of member states working there. The head of personnel at the UN in Geneva, for example, was a KGB officer.</p>



<p>The Soviet government also secured for itself virtually, in perpetuity, the post of Director of the Division for Policy Coordination in the Office of Personnel Services in New York. Soviet intelligence headquarters (‘the Center”) instructed its undercover officers at the UN that their success would be measured by intelligence collected, the secrets they stole, not their ostensible work for the UN. This contravened UN rules, which required nationals seconded there to work to work for the UN, not their home governments.</p>



<p>Hijacking UN positions gave the KGB rich pickings for recruiting Western nationals as espionage agents or agents of influence. A case in point occurred the same year as Shevchenko’s defection in 1978.</p>



<p>In May that year, the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/1978/05/21/fbi-arrests-two-soviets-in-spying-case/278d3953-da11-42b9-a07f-90a9f747f9ea/">FBI arrested</a> and successfully prosecuted two Soviet citizens working in the UN Secretariat on charges of espionage. They were caught trying to steal US anti-submarine warfare secrets from an agent who they believed they had recruited within the US navy, but their source was in fact, a double-agent, secretly working for the FBI. Its special agents arrested the Soviet officials at a shopping mall in New Jersey, as they attempted to retrieve a microfilm of defense secrets that their Navy ‘agent’ had dropped in an orange juice carton. They did not have diplomatic immunity, hence their arrest, but a third Soviet citizen picked up at the scene did, allowing him to face no penalty for what he had done.</p>



<p>The nature of Soviet espionage at the UN was further revealed when a Soviet military intelligence (GRU) officer working at the Soviet UN mission in Geneva, Vladimir Rezun, defected to British intelligence in July 1978. His mission, as he later publicly revealed under the alias <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Inside-Aquarium-Making-Top-Soviet/dp/0026154900/ref=sr_1_1?crid=K53RW0GECKFB&amp;keywords=suvorov+aquarium&amp;qid=1646945353&amp;sprefix=suvarov+acquarium%2Caps%2C111&amp;sr=8-1">Viktor Suvorov</a>, was to steal scientific and technical secrets from western powers, especially the United States. His hunting ground was the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD).</p>



<p>Soviet intelligence also penetrated other UN branches, like its Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), and also the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Secret-Servant-Life-Soviet-Elite/dp/006015912X/ref=sr_1_1?crid=12WS1G84ABOJG&amp;keywords=Ilya+Dzhirkvelov&amp;qid=1646945517&amp;sprefix=ilya+dzhirkvelov%2Caps%2C132&amp;sr=8-1">World Health Organisation</a> (WHO). The UN’s Department of Public Information was, Shevchenko revealed, subverted to become a mouthpiece for Soviet propaganda.</p>



<p>What about Western governments, we might ask? Were they not doing the same, using the UN as diplomatic cover for their spies? The answer is surely yes. Documentary evidence is hard to come by, but it would be naïve to suppose otherwise. Spies spy. Get over it.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Today’s constant barrage of information makes it easy for countries to wage disinformation campaigns and your emotions are the weapon of choice.  Learn how disinformation works and how we can fight it in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">short video</a>.  This is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">one link</a> you can feel good about sharing.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>Consider for a moment, however, the scale of Soviet presence at the UN, and you get a sense of the quantitative difference between how the Cold War’s two sides used (and apparently abused) the UN.</p>



<p>The Kremlin had a phalanx of intelligence officers masquerading as diplomats there. In November 1984, the Soviets had as many as 126 diplomats accredited to the UN in New York. This compared with 59 in the US mission and just 20 in the UK mission. As the newly unveiled British foreign office file notes, the majority of these Soviet officials were “engaged in intelligence work”. In 1980, the Swiss government estimated that of the 650 or so Soviet officials residing in Switzerland, at least 200 were engaged in espionage.</p>



<p>During the Cold War, both sides traded in expulsions of diplomats suspected, or established, to be intelligence officers. We might assume that such expulsions were gimmicks, tit-for-tat shows between the world’s two superpowers and their allies. They were, but they also served a purpose. In the espionage world, sometimes even a blunt instrument, like expulsions, is necessary. By expelling Soviet intelligence officers, Western governments deprived them of their recruiting grounds and an architecture for espionage in the West.</p>



<p>In September 1971, the British government expelled 105 Soviet ‘diplomats’ from Britain in what they dubbed, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Six-Moments-Crisis-British-Foreign-ebook/dp/B00BBUQZ0W/ref=sr_1_1?crid=JR1A9OCXZY4H&amp;keywords=gill+Bennett+six+crises&amp;qid=1646945722&amp;sprefix=gill+bennett+six+crises%2Caps%2C137&amp;sr=8-1">Operation FOOT</a>, perhaps a sly reference to kicking them out. It was the largest such expulsion during the Cold War. By that year, the number of Soviet officials in London had swollen to nearly 1,000, including those accredited to the Soviet embassy, its Trade Delegation, as well as many Soviet “working wives”, a ploy the Kremlin used to circumvent British restrictions on the swelling Soviet diplomatic presence in London. There were so many Soviet officials in Britain that MI5 could not keep track.</p>



<p>Operation FOOT followed the defection of a KGB officer in Britain, Oleg Lyalin, who worked in its sabotage department (Department V). Operating under cover in the Soviet Trade Delegation, Lyalin revealed to MI5 that his mission was to prepare for sabotage operations against Britain when World War Three broke out—hot war between the Soviet Union and the West. Britain’s foreign secretary, Alec Douglas-Home, raised the issue of the huge number of Soviet intelligence officers on British soil with his Soviet counterpart, Andrei Gromyko. Absurdly, the Soviet foreign minister replied: “These figures you give cannot be true because the Soviet Union has no spies”. It was difficult for the British to know what to do with this level of Kremlin obfuscation.</p>



<p>Operation FOOT marked a watershed for British counter espionage during the Cold War. Previously classified <a href="https://www.amazon.com/The-Sword-and-Shield-audiobook/dp/B0084H9DM2/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3C0D778PWR8IX&amp;keywords=mitrokhin+archive&amp;qid=1646945669&amp;sprefix=mitrokhin+archive%2Caps%2C128&amp;sr=8-1">KGB archives</a> reveal that for the first time, Britain became a hard target for Soviet spy chiefs. One high-ranking former KGB officer, Oleg Kalugin, later claimed that FOOT dealt a blow to Soviet intelligence in Britain from which it never recovered.</p>



<p>The Kremlin’s espionage activities at the UN did not stop at the end of the Cold War. The KGB’s successor service in Russia, the SVR, continued its tradecraft. One SVR defector at the end of the 1990s, Sergei Tretyakov (known as ‘Comrade J), defected to the CIA from Russia’s UN mission in New York, where he was reportedly close to its then head, Sergei Lavrov.</p>



<p>Today, western intelligence agencies are hopefully recruiting disaffected Russian intelligence officers, working under diplomatic cover in the West, who will follow in the path of their Soviet predecessors. It is not difficult to imagine Russian foreign intelligence officers feeling despondent and disgusted by Putin’s war in Ukraine— now willing to share the secrets they know to be on the right side of history.</p>



<p>Hopefully Western case officers are busy with operations that one day we will read about in declassified files. With even better luck, the West will be able to obtain the modern-day equivalent to the KGB archivist, Vasili Mitrokhin. He was so horrified about the Soviet regime’s cruelty, that he smuggled an archive of KGB secrets (the “Mitrokhin Archive”) to the West, with the help of MI6. Today, the West needs a similar Mitrokhin to expose Putin’s darkest intelligence secrets.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Want to go a level deeper?  Become a Cipher Brief Subscriber+Member for exclusive access to expert-led briefings on national security issues.  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade your access today</a>.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><em>Sharing informed perspectives is important.&nbsp; Opinion pieces represent the diverse views of The Cipher Brief audience and do not represent views of The Cipher Brief.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief </a>because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy">Soviet Espionage Under the Cover of Diplomacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soviet-espionage-under-the-cover-of-diplomacy/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Intelligence is only as Good as what goes into it</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 13:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CIA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intelligence]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36750</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OPINION &#8212; Officers in the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)’s Directorate of Operations (DO) have a penchant for action and readiness to serve in any circumstance. <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it">US Intelligence is only as Good as what goes into it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>OPINION</strong> &#8212; Officers in the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)’s Directorate of Operations (DO) have a penchant for action and readiness to serve in any circumstance. DO officers relish challenges, finding solutions to seemingly impossible tasks, and protecting America in the process. Retired DO officers still feel this tug to mission and patriotic duty.</p>



<p>Russia’s unprovoked invasion of the sovereign nation of Ukraine has us asking what we can do to serve our nation and to support democracy in Ukraine.&nbsp; We have likened Vladimir Putin to a modern-day Adolph Hitler:&nbsp; annexing portions of a neighboring nation on a whim, and when the reaction of the rest of the world is muted or absent, the aggressor is emboldened to be even more aggressive.&nbsp; Options to counter this aggression range hugely; all must be informed by accurate information to be effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before we retired, we would often discuss how “the business” was changing with the outsized impact that technology was having on the conduct of espionage, the “second oldest profession.” The fundamentals of tradecraft that we were trained to use in the 80s and 90s, have been in existence as long as the profession of spying and were used by George Washington’s Culper Ring during the Revolutionary War and by the OSS during World War II. It is tradecraft focused on the physical world. The evolution of tradecraft in the later stages of our careers factored in the exponential growth of technology and ubiquitous technical surveillance, incorporating a focus on the digital world. The digital world included data, data processing, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), Natural Language Processing (NLP), and analysis.</p>



<p>As we engage in business in retirement and have some distance from the intelligence mission, we have come to the consensus that data actually is the most critical element of the digital equation, because the quality of output (data plus processing and analytics) is directly proportional to the quality of data used. To put it in the vernacular, “garbage in, garbage out.”</p>



<p>This means that data, of which commercial data is a huge and growing subset, is at the very cornerstone of the digital world. Commercial data or commercially sourced intelligence, CSINT, is already shaping business in the digital world. Some ask why create a new INT? And to that we respond, we do not need to create it. It is already here and is being used by governments and businesses to edge out the competition.</p>



<p>Why should we care?&nbsp; We should care because right now, we are in the equivalent of a modern arms race to derive meaning and value from CSINT, and those who win that race will achieve strategic advantage. Those who do not will fail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Back to Ukraine, CSINT has significant play in everything.&nbsp; Ukrainian military defense operations could have been informed by using CSINT to track the Russian soldiers’ mobile devices that for the last few weeks, were located in Russia and Belarus on the border of Ukraine.&nbsp; Analyzed CSINT could continue to provide insight to Ukraine and its allies to strategically plan deployment of troops and materiel.&nbsp; On the humanitarian side, CSINT can assist relief organizations in understanding areas of crisis and where to position medical, humanitarian and food supplies for maximum impact.&nbsp; More broadly, for Ukraine’s neighbors (Latvia, Estonia, Lithuania, Poland, Moldova, Romania and Hungary), CSINT could bolster analysis and assessments of Russian plans and intentions by filling gaps in the information puzzle.</p>



<p>CSINT has tremendous potential to shape intelligence tradecraft as well, either enhancing or challenging it in every form of intelligence (INT) collection:&nbsp; Human Intelligence (HUMINT), Signals Intelligence (SIGINT), Imagery Intelligence (IMINT), Measurement and Signals Intelligence (MASINT), and Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT).</p>



<p>It is important to differentiate between OSINT and CSINT because some tend to confuse the terms. OSINT refers to a broad array of information in the public domain that can be accessed by the general public. OSINT consists of information obtained from media, professional and academic records and conferences, government reports, demographics, etc.  It is free and available.  CSINT is only available to the originator, describes or represents internal commercial activities, and is only acquired through a commercial transaction.  It is not free (it is bought and sold), and this data is a valuable commodity to the data owner.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Today’s constant barrage of information makes it easy for countries to wage disinformation campaigns and your emotions are the weapon of choice.  Learn how disinformation works and how we can fight it in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">short video</a>.  This is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQrOupETzFI">one link</a> you can feel good about sharing.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>In terms of shaping intelligence tradecraft, CSINT is a critical component because it allows the data foundation of analysis and decision-making to be more accurate and more complete. In HUMINT, CSINT could provide missing details about an operational target, including location and movement information to business and banking details.&nbsp; Link and pattern analysis fueled by CSINT could provide leads to new streams of SIGINT, IMINT and MASINT collection. CSINT could provide insights to military planners as they ponder the plans and intentions of nations diametrically opposed to the ideals of liberty and freedom. More broadly, CSINT could provide previously unknown, needed, pieces of the puzzle to solve complex investigations in the supply chain, disinformation, and counter-espionage realms, thereby protecting proprietary information, critical national infrastructure, U.S. secrets and the very fabric of our precious democracy.</p>



<p>When AI and ML are leveraged to glean insights from commercial data, the output tells the story at an algorithmic level human analysis alone would not have had the capacity to achieve. And that is the power of CSINT.</p>



<p>In addition to enabling intelligence missions, CSINT can help protect U.S. critical national infrastructure, improve U.S. cyber security posture, and aid the Department of Defense in planning and executing every one of their missions. The U.S. and our allies must be proactive in the use of CSINT to enable these missions. CSINT exists whether or not we take advantage of it – failure to understand and ingest CSINT means that it will exist not as an enabler but as a challenge to tradecraft and a challenge to mission in that key insights will be missing from decision-making. The enemies of the U.S. &#8211; the enemies of democracy and democratic values &#8211; are using commercial intelligence as an enabler in any way that can bolster their strategic advantage.</p>



<p>Remember what we said about garbage?&nbsp; Do we want less than successful missions, aka “garbage out,” to be the result of a failure to understand and adopt CSINT?&nbsp;&nbsp; We think not.&nbsp; It is time to embrace CSINT.</p>



<p><em>Sharing informed opinions is important.  Opinion pieces represent the diverse views of The Cipher Brief audience and do not represent views of The Cipher Brief.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in The Cipher Brief because National Security is Everyone’s Business</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it">US Intelligence is only as Good as what goes into it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-is-only-as-good-as-what-goes-into-it/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cornered Putin Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 13:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36725</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem">The Cornered Putin Problem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem">The Cornered Putin Problem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cornered-putin-problem/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Russians Can Bring an End to Putin’s Chekist State</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 14:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mark Kelton]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36712</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state">How Russians Can Bring an End to Putin&#8217;s Chekist State</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state">How Russians Can Bring an End to Putin&#8217;s Chekist State</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-russians-can-bring-an-end-to-putins-chekist-state/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With His only Option being Escalation, this is How Putin’s War Must End</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 15:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Robert Dannenberg]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36666</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end">With His only Option being Escalation, this is How Putin&#8217;s War Must End</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end">With His only Option being Escalation, this is How Putin&#8217;s War Must End</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/with-his-only-option-being-escalation-this-is-how-putins-war-must-end/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Putin is Drawing the World into its Most Dangerous Time in History</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Nuclear]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tim Willasey-Wilsey]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36654</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE &#8212; Putin has been sucked into the conquest and occupation of a hostile Ukraine; the very circumstance he has sought to avoid over <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history">How Putin is Drawing the World into its Most Dangerous Time in History</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE</strong> &#8212; Putin has been sucked into the conquest and occupation of a hostile Ukraine; the very circumstance he has sought to avoid over the past two decades. The West too must avoid ‘mission creep’ in spite of Ukraine’s ordeal. Putin’s fate may be sealed but his departure could be one of the most dangerous periods in world history.</p>



<p>One of the many ironies of President Putin’s current campaign in Ukraine is that he has fallen foul of the very mission creep that he carefully observed in America’s wars in Afghanistan and Iraq. All his actions since the initial phase of the Chechen war of 1999-2000 have pointed to his learning from Western mistakes. Wherever possible he has employed hybrid warfare; such as using proxies and ‘frozen conflicts’ in the Donbass and Georgia, cyber attacks and disinformation, and mercenaries (the Wagner Group) in <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2022/02/08/russias-wagner-group-in-africa-influence-commercial-concessions-rights-violations-and-counterinsurgency-failure/">Africa</a>. Even when he has used conventional forces he has planned for quick and relatively light interventions with clear goals, such as annexing Crimea and saving Syria’s President Assad.</p>



<p>In planning the current Ukraine campaign, he seems to have envisaged a two-stage operation. The massing of troops along the borders of Ukraine might (he may have calculated) have had two effects. Ukrainians could have been sufficiently intimidated to sue for peace or overthrow the Zelensky government. Additionally, the West might have agreed to exclude Ukraine from both the EU and NATO in perpetuity. On the other hand, some of <a href="https://mid.ru/ru/foreign_policy/rso/nato/1790803/?lang=en">Putin’s demands</a> (such as the roll-back to a pre-1997 NATO) seemed calculated to be rejected.</p>



<p>So, invasion must always have been his preferred outcome. However, he clearly expected a very different sort of invasion to the one which transpired; maybe not a triumphant drive to Kyiv with a cheering population lining the streets (like the Anschluss in 1938) but more reminiscent of the 3-day invasion of Afghanistan in 1979 which was not greeted with flowers but at least was largely uncontested. Thus, he saw no need for heavy bombing or shelling of Kyiv prior to arriving in the city and establishing a puppet government.</p>



<p>In an ideal world the Russian troops would then have withdrawn from Ukraine, or at least from public visibility, as they did after the brief and <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/1/10/kazakh-leader-declares-attempted-coup-detat-over">successful operation</a> to shore up the Tokayev government in Kazakhstan in January. Ukraine would then have become a second Belarus ruled by a compliant government dependent on Russia’s support but at arm’s length from Moscow.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>French officials warned this week, the worst is yet to come in Ukraine after a phone call between French President Emmanuel Macron and Russian President Vladimir Putin.</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Subscriber+Members</a> can access a piece by former <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse">Ukraine and an Assessment of how a Bad Situation Could get Much Worse</a> by Cipher Brief Expert and former Chief of CIA’s Central Eurasia Division Robert Dannenberg.  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade your access today</a>.</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>The strength of the Ukrainian opposition to the invasion and the speed and unity of the Western reaction must have come as an enormous shock to Putin. And here comes the critical moment of mission creep. He could not bring himself to abandon the invasion but instead doubled-down with the sort of coercive operation which worked for him in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/12/10/world/europe/photos-chechen-war-russia.html">Chechnya in 1999</a>, but in very different and far less visible circumstances.</p>



<p>The power and might of the Russian army will surely conquer the much of Ukraine in the next few weeks but it will be brutal and ugly. The Russian army and security services will then be drawn into overseeing an occupation. Even assuming that anti-Lukashenko protests do not restart in Belarus (and anti-Putin demonstrations do not get out of control in Moscow) the subjugation of Ukraine will be a massive task. With a faltering economy at home and with body bags returning to Russia Putin will be at greater risk than at any time during his 22-year reign.</p>



<p>But the situation is replete with danger for the West too. The perils of mission creep will be considerable as popular and human right pressures grow for more active solidarity with the people of Ukraine. If British Foreign Secretary Liz Truss’s comments can prompt Putin to alert his nuclear forces how much more so would a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-60558048">‘no-fly zone’</a>. As Putin becomes more and more vulnerable we can expect more nuclear threats and we may also be reminded of his chemical and <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/usa-putin-chemical-weapons-ukraine-b2024445.html">biological warfare capabilities</a>. Even equipment and ammunition resupply for Ukrainian fighters across the Polish border could be presented by Putin as a <em>casus belli</em>.</p>



<p>A cornered and reviled Putin might also strike out at NATO in the hope of provoking a response. In this context the position of the three Baltic States is particularly exposed; especially Lithuania with its proximity to the Kaliningrad enclave and Estonia with its vulnerable town of Narva.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Read <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column/expert-view/the-facts-that-putin-cannot-change">The Facts that Putin Cannot Change</a> by Cipher Brief Expert and former Sr. Member of the British Foreign Office Nick Fishwick only in The Cipher Brief</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>It is hard not to conclude that this saga could be the end of Putin. But his final years could be protracted and dangerous. Analysts were predicting the fall of Robert Mugabe for nearly two decades and <a href="https://www.latimes.com/world/africa/la-fg-robert-mugabe-timeline-20171121-story.html">his successor</a> is little better. Those with the power to challenge Putin are no better than him; Igor Sechin of Rosneft or one of the other Siloviki (ex security personnel) or perhaps the current leadership of the FSB which stands to lose financially from the collapsing economy. Even the courageous Alexei Navalny is a long way from being a democratic leader in the Zelensky mould.</p>



<p>Finally, the most alarming aspect of this whole affair is Putin’s psychological isolation. His public humiliation of his Head of Foreign Intelligence (SVR) on television was a chilling moment, showing that his contempt is not just reserved for weak Western leaders but also for his own advisors. His departure from the world stage could be one of the most hazardous periods in world history.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Read <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column/expert-view/with-the-world-turning-against-him-putins-going-to-need-a-way-out">With the World Turning Against Him, Putin’s Going to Need a Way Out</a> from Former National Security Advisor to the Canadian Prime Minister, Richard B. Fadden only in The Cipher Brief</em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history">How Putin is Drawing the World into its Most Dangerous Time in History</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-putin-is-drawing-the-world-into-its-most-dangerous-time-in-history/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China and the Global Power Play in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 15:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Taiwan]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[New world order]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36634</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine">China and the Global Power Play in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine">China and the Global Power Play in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-and-the-global-power-play-in-ukraine/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and an Assessment of how a Bad Situation Could Get Much Worse</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 18:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36589</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse">Ukraine and an Assessment of how a Bad Situation Could Get Much Worse</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse">Ukraine and an Assessment of how a Bad Situation Could Get Much Worse</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-and-an-assessment-of-how-a-bad-situation-could-get-much-worse/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Watch’ or ‘Stand Against’ the Digital Machinery of Aggression in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 17:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Initiatives Group]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[national security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tech/Cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Christopher Ahlberg]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[cyber]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Geoff Brown]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Cipher Brief]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36582</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OPINION &#8212; The machinery of aggression moves across the land of the people of Ukraine to their capital. There should be no words to argue <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine">&#8216;Watch&#8217; or &#8216;Stand Against&#8217; the Digital Machinery of Aggression in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>OPINION</strong> &#8212; The machinery of aggression moves across the land of the people of Ukraine to their capital. There should be no words to argue with, let alone to aspire to, that shifts light from that dark reality. If the United States, the United Kingdom, Europe, and the nations of the world believe the machinery of that aggression can only move at the pace of physical geography, we are fools. If we hang our hope on that belief, then we will fail our responsibility to pursue our resolve. The machinery of that aggression will move at the speed of our digital co-dependencies.</p>



<p>The clearest example of the potential of aggression absent geography, is NotPetya. NotPetya was in 2017. NotPetya was unleashed through the indifference and irresponsibility of the very foe we all now condemn. The active indifference of this foe, through NotPetya, created outsized disruptive and destructive impacts on an expanse of our supply chains and business operations around the globe. We only expect in 2022, that we are prepared for more, but the potential impact of more is unacceptable, and if the equities we claim to serve are disrupted, it would be a terrible failure of our capabilities to work together.</p>



<p>Since before the turn of the year, experts from the cybersecurity community, government and private sector, have tracked and revealed website defacements, denial-of-service attacks, misinformation campaigns, and the lacing of Ukrainian systems with malware that was posed to cripple systems. And in the recent weeks, those consequences were realized.</p>



<p>All of this serves to disrupt. And all of this poses the very real potential to cross digital boundaries and cause harm. Beyond that, it is with high confidence that we believe that Russia will use our digital commons to counter-message, manipulate, and confuse. Russia will use the digital commons to excuse, explain away, and create pretense. And, as many <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">Cipher Brief</a> and <a href="http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/">Cyber Initiatives Group</a> members have noted, others watch.</p>



<p>We know this is coming. We prepare and react. These effects have arrived. But we are slow to act.&nbsp; To speed up, we could choose to overcome our hesitations and defend together. We could take this moment to drop our separate agendas and form the cross-expertise collaboration and calibration that this moment calls for. The point is not about information sharing. Information sharing was just the beginning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must adjust quickly to what the moment calls for. That’s why we’re sending out a call to those willing to stand together. We ask our government friends to encourage us to thwart the efforts of this foe together on behalf of the networks we serve, and without hesitation (but within the boundaries of defense).&nbsp; Right now, there exists unparalleled expertise, definitive capability, and sound judgment in our community. This can contribute substantially to complicating the digital threats that directly and indirectly catapult outwards from this Russian aggression against Ukraine. So, we call on friends of democracy and self-determination to rally together to share ideas and knowledge, for operational collaboration, in furtherance of the defense of the principles we teach in our classrooms to our children.</p>



<p>Standing with Ukraine must mean devoting any, and all to help complicate the digital aggression experienced within Ukraine’s systems today. We’re thankful that many in the cyber security community and beyond, are doing just that. Aggression will transit to us digitally as Russia presses closely against the physical boundaries of the current seizure.  So, for tomorrow, standing together means we must accelerate our willingness to operate without boundaries in the defense of any aggression we observe in the digital space.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em><strong><a href="http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com">The Cyber Initiatives Group</a>’s Public-Private Summit co-hosted by Cipher Brief CEO &amp; Publisher Suzanne Kelly and former NSA Deputy Director Rick Ledgett is happening Wednesday, May 25.  <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/register/9203051283903580684">Reserve your seat today</a>.</strong></em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>The Blueprint</strong></p>



<p>One way we can do this is by recognizing that the commercial space provides an expansive radar on what is knowable. Having great confidence in the knowable – the unclassified, vast knowable – allows for more precision in the use of specific capabilities, reserved for governments, in pursuit of the hardest to reach knowledge.</p>



<p>As argued recently in <em><a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-intelligence-game-is-changing-are-we-ready">The Cipher Brief</a></em>, there is both depth and breath, in commercially sourced intelligence. And to be distinct, commercially sourced intelligence should not be viewed as competitive to sensitive or classified intelligence. We need commercially sourced intelligence because it is the very information that we can use to make decisions from unclassified environments. That means it can be deployed and actioned against quickly. It can reach into the hands of those across the public and private sectors, and across contested borders, who need it; need it acutely as we stand against the digital threats that seem viscerally close, perhaps unlike ever before.</p>



<p>The governments galvanized in opposition to aggression can immediately, systematically, and then continually augment their holdings and analysis with intelligence from commercial providers. Not only with a potentially unique view not subject to the limits of tasked governmental resources, and to compliment sensitive and classified holdings, but also because both the questions and answers that can be applied and discovered in commercially sourced intelligence specifically allows for the immediate deployment of that intelligence to those who need to take action themselves, separately, in the defense of their own systems, services, and on behalf of the people who depend on them.</p>



<p>That streamlining of producing trusted knowledge in this exigent circumstance is one way to not just say that we stand with Ukraine, but to do something. And perhaps in this moment, as Kiev is encircled and likely infiltrated, it rings as not enough to discuss what we can do to protect our digital dependencies.</p>



<p>Acknowledging that, we also acknowledge that as intelligence and security professionals we have no option to remain with our regrets. We must mitigate what our experience tells us is likely to come. When we say we stand with Ukraine, we must start by standing together.</p>



<p>We believe the willing can re-examine the ways we develop, categorize, and deploy the knowledge needed to effectively collaborate; and we certainly believe using a common platform assists this aim. Beyond, we believe the willing must stand together in alliance to contend with the speed and consequences of the convergence of the physical world on the digital, and the digital world on the physical.</p>



<p>In doing so, with all our leadership, innovation, and energies, can we truly act together, to further help Ukraine, and to contend with the borderless digital ramifications of this history changing aggression.</p>



<p><strong><em>Cipher Brief Subscriber+ Members receive exclusive expert briefings from members of our expert network.&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade to Subscriber+ today</a>.</em></strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insight, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a></em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine">&#8216;Watch&#8217; or &#8216;Stand Against&#8217; the Digital Machinery of Aggression in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/watch-or-stand-against-the-digital-aggression-in-ukraine/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence Isn’t Just for Commanders Anymore</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 13:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Corporate Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[corporate intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Cipher Brief]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36575</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE &#8212; Intelligence is for commanders, or at least so I&#8217;ve been told. Regardless of the term you prefer—commander, principal, or policymaker—the idea expressed <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore">Intelligence Isn&#8217;t Just for Commanders Anymore</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE</strong> &#8212; Intelligence is for commanders, or at least so I&#8217;ve been told. Regardless of the term you prefer—commander, principal, or policymaker—the idea expressed by the phrase, that intelligence exists to help some &#8220;decision-maker&#8221; make better decisions, is conventional wisdom in the intelligence community. But it has probably outlived its usefulness.</p>



<p>In an age in which the speed, scale, and scope of overlapping national security issues have eclipsed the ability of any individual leader to keep track of them all, we must think seriously about broadening the intelligence audience. I think that in a period of renewed great power rivalry that takes place under globalized, digital conditions, intelligence must no longer be for commanders—it must be for entire organizations.</p>



<p>The idea that intelligence exists to support executive decision-makers is an old one, passed down through generations of intelligence officers. It originated, whether those passing it realized it or not, with the autocrats who established the first rudimentary spy agencies in the 16<sup>th</sup> and 17<sup>th</sup> centuries. Early modern dynasts viewed the gathering of information as their <a href="https://www.amazon.com/1688-Revolution-Walpole-Eighteenth-Century-Culture/dp/0300171439">private concern</a> and saw the information that was gathered as their <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/intelligence-power-in-peace-and-war/39B13810C2D49FD2894827D9BA373CCB">personal property</a>.</p>



<p>The same was true of the military commanders who aimed to further these rulers&#8217; interests at war. For one example, consider Napoleon Bonaparte, who was perhaps the ultimate personification of both autocratic ruler and general who was also a voracious personal consumer of the intelligence gathered by his infamous Black Cabinet.</p>



<p>Napoleon&#8217;s contemporaries did the same. During the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wellingtons-Headquarters-Administrative-Peninsula-1809-1814/dp/B003WL4D8Yhttps:/www.amazon.com/Wellingtons-Headquarters-Administrative-Peninsula-1809-1814/dp/B003WL4D8Y">Peninsula War</a> of 1807 – 1814, “…all intelligence came to [The Duke of] Wellington and the appraisal of it was his alone…&#8221; By the industrial revolution, the notion that intelligence existed to support centralized decision-making had long been established as doctrine. Consider how plainly it was put by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Armand_Furse">George Armand Furse</a>, a Victorian-era British Army colonel who, in his 1895 book <em>Information in War</em>, declared that all intelligence belonged to the commander alone and that “…it is only for <em>him</em> to draw proper conclusions from a thorough consideration of the total information gathered from every possible source.” This doctrine <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Frederick-Great-Prussia-David-Fraser/dp/0880642610">influence</a>d the formation of <a href="https://www.wired.com/2014/03/stunningly-complex-organization-chart-19th-century/">early</a> private sector <a href="https://www.amazon.com/End-Power-Boardrooms-Battlefields-Churches/dp/1469031205">enterprises</a> in the nineteenth century, which then themselves went on to influence the establishment of modern government <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Origins-Political-Order-Prehuman-Revolution/dp/0374533229">bureaucracies</a>—such as the first real intelligence services—in the early twentieth.</p>



<p>Today, this inheritance still weighs heavily on the intelligence community. It influences both broad organizational <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/02684527.2012.749063">values</a> and the daily <a href="https://warontherocks.com/2019/02/policy-and-you-a-guide-for-intelligence-analysts/">actions</a> of individual collectors, analysts, and managers. From determining who gets access to the sensitive fruits of the community&#8217;s secretive labor to framing how the intelligence agencies themselves are structured, staffed, and funded, the mantra that intelligence is <em>for</em> a select audience of deputies, principals, and other senior executives is so deeply ingrained that it would be difficult to root out.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Cipher Brief Subscriber+ Members receive exclusive expert briefings from members of our expert network.  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade to Subscriber+ today</a>.</em></strong> </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>That&#8217;s unfortunate because today the emphasis on providing intelligence to senior leaders—which too often comes at the expense of the broader national security enterprise—leaves America insufficiently equipped for an era of strategic competition. With few exceptions, and despite a real push to provide greater intelligence support to lower-level commands during the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, the community still expends the vast majority of its time and resources to produce high-level intelligence products intended to only ever be seen by the smallest number of people at or near the top of large bureaucratic pyramids.</p>



<p>Admittedly, it does an excellent job at this. Every day, talented and dedicated intelligence officers cater to the individual schedules and preferences of officials across the Executive Branch, providing them with on-demand, world-class intelligence support wherever they might be. Entire teams of analysts on both the front and back ends are dedicated to providing these decision-makers with customized briefing books and curated deskside presentations modeled after the President&#8217;s Daily Brief itself. These executives&#8217; questions are answered, usually on the spot—and if that isn&#8217;t possible, analytic teams supporting them will find someone who can answer them as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the vast majority of national security employees—which includes more junior military and foreign service officers, various homeland security and law enforcement officials, sundry action, program, and acquisition officers, and others—have little time or incentive to seek out even the limited intelligence support they have access to—which too often isn&#8217;t much. All of these staffers frame discussions, coordinate between agencies, generate policy options for seniors, and otherwise make important decisions themselves every day, but many amazingly lack access to the computer networks on which the best on-the-shelf intelligence products reside, and even if they did have it most of them wouldn&#8217;t know where or how to retrieve the products that already exist anyway because they&#8217;re not easy to find.</p>



<p>In simpler times, when useful information was scarcer, when the relative influence and the span of control of individual leaders was greater, and when the rate of change was slower, this way of doing things made a whole lot of sense. Hierarchies are very effective at coordinating large systems when the rate of change is slower, and centralized decision-making works quite well when decisions need to be made less frequently. In the past, these sorts of systems were pretty good at resolving internal conflicts quickly and enforcing compliance across the organization.</p>



<p>We no longer live in simpler times.</p>



<p>Today, in contrast to the past, we are inundated with useful information. Today, in contrast to the past, the influence of empowered collectives matters just as much, if not more, than the influence of any individual leader.</p>



<p>Today, in contrast to the past, the rate of change is rapid, and it shows no signs of slowing down any time soon. Our era is characterized by information overload, persistent uncertainty, and relentless technological progress—it is one in which the scope, scale, speed, and interconnectedness of strategic issues regularly exceed the decision-making prowess of anyone, no matter how brilliant they might be.</p>



<p>Ours is also an era of strategic competition with rival great powers, a competition that is more about organizational acumen and administrative capacity than it is the decision-making prowess of any single leader. In contrast to the past, the competition today is not limited to staterooms and military command centers. Indeed, it is distributed globally, across time and space, at multiple levels of organization, and every dimension of national power. It encompasses the whole of society through overlapping webs of influence that run over, under, and through international institutions, governments, political parties, and individuals. The units of maneuver in this competition are no longer just naval squadrons and army divisions, but entire offices, agencies, and departments. To win, we will need organizations that are both internally coherent and externally aligned with a vision established by national leaders. We will need organizations with honed senses that are more responsive to changes in the competitive space, both at home and abroad. We will need organizations better able to act swiftly to mitigate threats or seize opportunities.</p>



<p>These things can&#8217;t be commanded from the top down. They can only be facilitated from the bottom up. Since each person in a traditional hierarchy only works on the tasks they are assigned, those near the top are the only ones who can see the proverbial &#8216;big picture.&#8217; When these individual leaders—brilliant or not—become overloaded with work or suffer from decision fatigue, the entire system slows down.</p>



<p>By that point, what decisions do get made typically only serve to reinforce the status quo when they should instead be responsive to change. Famed political scientist James March describes this in his book, <a href="https://amzn.to/3HogPNT"><em>A Primer on Decision Making</em></a><em>.</em> When only the senior-most people in an organization are empowered to decide, you get what he calls “garbage can decisionmaking&#8221; —exactly the sort we can no longer afford.</p>



<p>Recognizing this, successful enterprises in the private sector increasingly no longer operate this way. They’ve learned that the pace of change in the digital age has eclipsed the ability of both individual leaders to keep up and of centralized decision-making processes to keep pace. They&#8217;re no longer using disparate organizational functions merely as channels through which information is sifted and refined as it gets passed up the chain, and they’re no longer waiting for that information to eventually reach an executive with enough authority to make a decision before then having to pass it all the way back down that chain before to be implemented.</p>



<p>Instead, they&#8217;ve adapted to the speed, complexity, and uncertainty of the 21st-century by reorganizing to solve problems when and where they arise. They&#8217;ve torn down the walls between silos to facilitate the freer exchange of information for broader organizational awareness, and they&#8217;ve flattened arbitrary administrative hurdles to empower those closest to the source of an issue with both the access and the authority needed to make and execute decisions on their own. They&#8217;ve encouraged their employees to take responsibility for decisions within the scope of their work by devolving authority and removing layers of mid-century managerial style. These steps alone go far toward letting individuals see the connection between their contribution to a project and its outcome, giving them a greater sense of agency and more ownership over results that hierarchical organizations just can’t easily replicate.</p>



<p>Google, for just one example, is a famously ‘<a href="https://www.inc.com/marcel-schwantes/googles-insane-approach-to-management-could-transform-your-company.html">bottom-up</a>’ style of company, where even very junior employees have a significant role in decision-making within their scope of work. Even in the military, where you might expect the mantra of commander exclusivity to be intractably retrenched, forward-thinking leaders are coming around to the idea that today unity of effort might trump unity of command. The U.S. Army, for instance, is promoting a concept called <a href="https://fas.org/irp/doddir/army/adp6_0.pdf">&#8216;mission command</a>&#8216; that anticipates the speed and uncertainty of contemporary warfare by empowering decentralized, local decision-making at the tactical edge.</p>



<p>While it&#8217;s unlikely that the national security enterprise will ever become as agile as private sector firms like Google (or even the U.S. Army), I nonetheless believe there is much to be learned from this nimbler, more collaborative way of doing things. For the intelligence community in particular, the lessons are clear.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Read The <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/corporate-intelligence-playbook-part-1">Corporate Intelligence Playbook</a> by Cipher Brief Expert and VP of Intelligence &amp; International Advisory at bp, Bradley Fernandez in The Cipher Brief</em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>In an article last year for <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/united-states/2021-03-09/declining-market-secrets"><em>Foreign Affairs</em></a>, <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/carmen-medina">Carmen Medina</a> and I called for the intelligence community to embrace not just open sources, but the concept of <em>openness</em> itself. What does that mean? For the immediate future, it would mean more production based on publicly-available information and significant investments in building convenient, user-focused applications to deliver these products frictionlessly. Eventually, it would mean the overhaul of a legacy security architecture that governs the classification of sensitive sources and methods—a long-overdue updating of these guidelines to make them better suited to the digital era, enabling the community to give access to many more people across the national security enterprise and to critical partners in the private sector and academia, as well.</p>



<p>More recently, Kathleen McInnis and I argued in <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/10/25/pentagon-office-culture-stuck-modernize-workforce/"><em>Foreign Policy</em></a> that in addition to its information technology, the national security enterprise needs to overhaul its work processes, as well. The defense and intelligence sectors are spending a lot of money building hybrid cloud systems to enable greater information-sharing, but if it doesn&#8217;t update its workflows and decision-making processes at the same time, these will be of limited utility. Because organizations are composed of individuals, national security professionals across the government should be able to access all-source intelligence swiftly, easily, and in a manner that suits their personal preferences. This would facilitate both their routine work and the crucial decisions they make daily.</p>



<p>Of course, executive leadership still matters. Few doubt that some decisions should only be made at the highest levels of an organization. But in our fast-paced, complex world, a senior leader&#8217;s role is less about making day-to-day decisions and more about setting the conditions for others to make decisions on their behalf. Their role is more about being able to effectively articulate a common vision for their organizations to target, and then to equip their followers with the resources and leeway that allows them to take aim.</p>



<p>Today, rapid, organization-wide communication is more important than stratified reviews that delay the delivery of practical insight to users. Intelligence should no longer focus on gathering information and funneling it to the top; instead, it should make organizational sensemaking its purpose. It should facilitate the frictionless flow of useful information—which is to say, intelligence—to every node within the trusted workforce.</p>



<p>In conclusion, all of this will require a reframing of what we think intelligence is and just who we think it is for. Instead of seeing intelligence as an exclusive product delivered to senior leaders—the standing-room-only briefing, the restricted-access white paper—we should start thinking of intelligence as an intangible, continuous, and much more broadly accessible, <a href="https://hbr.org/2018/10/6-ways-to-build-a-customer-centric-culture">human-focused</a> <em>service</em> that expands a given user&#8217;s mental map of the world and helps them to navigate that world more easily, in collaboration with their colleagues.</p>



<p>Intelligence is instrumental. It has no autarkic purpose of its own at all. It does not, as Sherman Kent himself <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/titles/3920.html">wrote</a>, “pursue knowledge for its own sake.” Intelligence is simply the act of helping someone who can affect a given situation understand that situation better than they did before. Intelligence is also an enterprise—that is, it is a team sport. But the game this team is playing is not a finite one with clearly-defined rules and an established roster of player positions; it is instead an infinite game in which the rules can change during the course of play, bounded only by a colleague&#8217;s—or an opponent’s—creativity. In other words, the needs of the team are apt to change just as the external world is, itself, always changing.</p>



<p>Intelligence is still for commanders, but today, it’s also for entire organizations.</p>



<p><em>The views expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official policy or position of the Department of Defense or the U.S. Government.&nbsp; </em><em></em></p>



<p><em>The Cipher Brief may earn a small commission on products purchased via links.</em><em></em></p>



<p><em><strong>The Cyber Initiatives Group’s next Public-Private Summit co-hosted by Cipher Brief CEO &amp; Publisher Suzanne Kelly and former NSA Deputy Director Rick Ledgett, is on Wednesday, May 25.&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/register/9203051283903580684">Reserve your seat today</a>.</strong></em></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insight, perspective and analysis in <a href="http://www.thecipherbrief.com/">The Cipher Brief</a></em></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore">Intelligence Isn&#8217;t Just for Commanders Anymore</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/intelligence-isnt-just-for-commanders-anymore/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could This be Putin’s Big Tango?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 03:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Putin]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36564</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango">Could This be Putin&#8217;s Big Tango?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango">Could This be Putin&#8217;s Big Tango?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/could-this-be-putins-big-tango/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Power of Intelligence ‘Auxiliaries’</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 14:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Corporate Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Open Source]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36529</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The democratization of intelligence is changing how espionage is done – and by whom. How can states best achieve their aims in an age of <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries">The Real Power of Intelligence &#8216;Auxiliaries&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The democratization of intelligence is changing how espionage is done – and by whom. How can states best achieve their aims in an age of silo-spotting, open source sleuths and other “intelligence auxiliaries”? &nbsp;</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><strong>EXPERT PERSPECTIVE</strong> &#8212; Late in the summer of 2021, researchers affiliated with the Federation of American Scientists (FAS) <a href="https://fas.org/blogs/security/2021/07/china-is-building-a-second-nuclear-missile-silo-field/">discovered evidence that China</a> was upgrading its ballistic missile silo count in what they described as “the most significant expansion of the Chinese nuclear arsenal ever.” To reach this conclusion, the analysts relied on open source intelligence (OSINT) techniques, including commercial satellite imagery and unclassified knowledge about Chinese missile technology, that has <a href="https://www.economist.com/briefing/2021/08/07/open-source-intelligence-challenges-state-monopolies-on-information">become commonplace</a> in recent years.</p>



<p>FAS’ research did not go unnoticed by the US government. In response to the findings, Admiral Charles Richard of USSTRATCOM used a press conference to rhetorically <a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/41974/strategic-command-boss-wants-more-open-source-intel-sleuthing-on-chinas-nuclear-expansion">ask the researchers</a>, “If you enjoy looking at commercial satellite imagery or stuff in China, can I suggest you keep looking?&#8221;</p>



<p>Admiral Richard’s deadpan aside, his comment raises interesting questions about the future of public-private partnerships in intelligence. What happens when sophisticated intelligence capabilities <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/reviews/review-essay/2021-06-22/spies-us">exist outside of government</a>? What intelligence functions should only be performed by states – and which should be done by non-state actors? And most pressingly, what tools can we give leaders like Admiral Richard so that they can stop “suggesting” and start working effectively with outside groups to achieve common policy objectives?</p>



<p>Since Admiral Richard’s comment, we have seen <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/875f6d2d-b09d-406c-b97c-64f987481cf8">yet</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/11/01/satellite-russia-ukraine-military-518337">more</a> examples of how the “<a href="https://www.rand.org/content/dam/rand/pubs/perspectives/PE200/PE273/RAND_PE273.pdf">democratization of intelligence</a>” is creating new opportunities for private sector and NGO groups to provide insight on important geopolitical questions. Today, as Russia marshals its forces to widen its existing invasion of Ukraine, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/russias-military-buildup-near-ukraine-is-an-open-secret-11641292202">OSINT practitioners are continually scanning</a> for new troop movements, giving policymakers ways to discuss publicly what once would have been secret intelligence. More broadly, across government and the think tank world, there has <a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/csis-technology-and-intelligence-task-force">been widespread recognition</a> of the increasing sophistication of open source intelligence capabilities. Most recently, we have also seen intelligence leaders, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/cs-speech-to-the-international-institute-for-strategic-studies">including most prominently MI6 Chief Richard Moore</a>, comment on the exciting possibilities of public-private partnerships founded in part on open source techniques.</p>



<p>But so far, we have seen few new ways of working designed to actually capture this potential. Typically, the conversation about open source centers on how government can do more – rather than on how the public sector can forge innovative partnerships. As a result, national security professionals who wish to work with a burgeoning non-state intelligence sector are often left with unclear guidance. There has been plenty of work on integrating OSINT tools into state arsenals; but less toward creating the new policies, procedures, and ways of working needed to actually leverage non-state OSINT capability.</p>



<p>This is a missed opportunity. The IC should articulate new ways of working that effectively leverage the activities of non-state “intelligence auxiliaries” to help achieve national priorities. Such auxiliaries, whether they are directly tasked, paid, or integrated into the IC’s structure or not, have proven that they can make vital contributions to important tasks in mission awareness and information operations.</p>



<p>Leveraging intelligence auxiliaries is not without risk, and should be engaged in with care and according to a transparent and understandable framework. But intelligence auxiliaries are not going away – the state’s option is not whether to engage with them, but instead how.</p>



<h1 id="intelligence-auxiliaries-in-history">Intelligence Auxiliaries in History</h1>



<p><em>Intelligence Auxiliaries are not new – non-state intelligence activity has been a part of the world’s “second oldest profession” since the beginning.</em></p>



<p>Historically, the idea that non-state actors should work on the frontlines of intelligence would hardly have seemed out of place. Private individuals in <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Intelligence-Activities-in-Ancient-Rome-Trust-in-the-Gods-But-Verify/Sheldon/p/book/9780415452717">ancient Rome</a> were prolific practitioners of intelligence. European religious orders were famous collectors of intelligence – a long-standing tradition that <a href="https://www.cbcew.org.uk/drivers-urged-to-join-intelligence-gathering-effort-against-slavery-in-hand-car-washes/">continues today</a>. Journalists have long been adjuncts, wittingly and unwittingly, to intelligence work &#8211; Napoleon was a famous consumer of British newspapers for information on troop movements, relying on them more than <a href="https://amzn.to/3sVlEZJ">secret intelligence</a>.</p>



<p>Moreover, states often collaborated with non-state intelligence gathering networks to supplement their own awareness. In the <a href="https://tarlton.law.utexas.edu/aztec-and-maya-law/aztec-commercial-and-tax-law">ancient Aztec empire</a>, intelligence networks organized by merchants were often leveraged by the state. In the age of European expansion, commercial actors regularly engaged in espionage for private as well as state gain – with European commercial actors famously stealing the techniques for processing <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/the-great-british-tea-heist-9866709/">tea leaves</a> and for making <a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/porcelain-corporate-espionage-china-missionary-dentrecolles">porcelain from China.</a> The East India Company, itself a commercial actor, routinely made use of pre-existing espionage networks to inform its policy before the handover to the Crown in 1858.</p>



<p>For most of human history, states didn’t necessarily hold better espionage technology than did non-states – but they were still able to out-perform and effectively leverage non-state intelligence actors because, by virtue of being states, they possessed certain abilities that non-states could not hope to equal. These “enduring state characteristics” helped ensure that, even when non-states had superior information, states were still able to remain the most important players in the espionage market.</p>



<ul><li><strong>States had control over the information environment.</strong> The state’s historical ability to publish, censor, or encourage the production of information shaped the intelligence-gathering environment. Historical censorship of the press during times of conflict, such as during <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/02582479908671894">Britain’s Boer War</a>, shows how states have used control over the information environment to achieve objectives related to their own or foreign actors’ espionage. Today, China’s <a href="https://www.maritime-executive.com/article/report-new-data-law-cuts-off-access-to-chinese-ais-tracking">ability to control information</a> leaving its borders is a continuation of the exercise of this power.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>States had agenda-setting ability.</strong> In times of peace or conflict, the state’s ability to guide non-state practitioners toward common outcomes was a major lever through which it exercised indirect control over non-state auxiliaries. Historically, mission-definition was an important way for states to guide the activities of private groups such as privateers, explorers, missionaries, and private trading corporations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>States had fiat power.</strong> States could simply declare activities or types of information legal or illegal, and could engage in activities that they made illegal for others without fear of punishment. This historical ability to “live above the law”, whether through law courts or <a href="https://www.esd.whs.mil/Portals/54/Documents/FOID/Reading%20Room/Other/15-F-0990_DOC_02_State_Surveillance_of_the_Chinese_Domestic_Population_A_Preliminary_Report_CSBA_200705_Final.pdf">secret police</a>, gave states powerful levers to compel the production of information.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>States had superior historical memory.</strong> One of the single most important advantages of historical intelligence bureaucracies was their ability to develop and sustain large archives. <a href="https://omnilogos.com/ancient-intelligence/">Archeological evidence</a> of intelligence archives has attested to the importance that this state advantage had even in ancient times. Though less relevant today with the development of large-scale information storage in the private sector, state advantages in collecting and classifying information still persist today.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>States had market-making ability.</strong> States could incentivize or de-incentivize the production of information through their market-making power. Not only were states the largest players in information markets – they have had the ability to set the rules by which other players engage in market activity. This gave states the ability to offer bounties or create attractive commercial partnerships for information.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Direct Contracting Ability.</strong> Finally, states could and did directly commission private groups to conduct intelligence work on their behalf. While not unique to states, this ability nonetheless is a major way that states have been able to leverage capabilities possessed by non-state actors throughout history.</li></ul>



<h1 id="the-rise-and-fall-of-information-overmatch">The Rise and Fall of Information Overmatch</h1>



<p><em>During the Cold War, states could rely on qualitatively better information than non-states. As this advantage recedes, “intelligence auxiliaries” are coming back on the scene.</em></p>



<p>The Cold War saw the technological gap between states and non-state “intelligence auxiliaries” widen. During this period of rapid advances in technology, states added a new intelligence advantage vis a vis non-states – the simple ability to reliably access and exploit information that far outclassed in quantity and type that available to non-states. As this advantage erodes in the modern day, the difference between the classified and non-classified worlds is diminishing – and with it a way of working based on information overmatch.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Access&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk">The Us is Engaging in a Strategy to Share Intelligence on Russia more broadly.&nbsp; Is it Worth the Risk?&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;This is content reserved for&nbsp;Subscriber+ Members</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus">Upgrade your access to Subscriber+ today</a></em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>Today’s premier intelligence bureaucracies were largely formed during the “long” 20<sup>th</sup> century. This was an era when states increasingly came to enjoy privileged access to intelligence based on capabilities that non-states could not match, at least not reliably. During the long 20<sup>th</sup> century, as war and intelligence-gathering became more mechanized and technological, militaries and intelligence agencies became increasingly invested in industrial development and production as a way of securing the necessary materials to win wars. With the private sector unlikely to support the cost of expensive investments in military and intelligence technology on its own, “<a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/article/95/4/765/5513164">the role of the state [became] vital because it was the state that provided the critical financial resources required to take embryonic technologies and develop them at a speed unlikely to be matched by the civilian market</a>.”</p>



<p>This sponsorship gave rise to sophisticated intelligence technologies such as computers, satellites, maritime domain awareness tools, unmanned aerial vehicles, and more. With sponsorship came control, and for most of the long 20<sup>th</sup> century states were the only entities with access to sophisticated espionage technology. Groups outside of government were largely restricted to low-grade versions of the same technology, or to classic “<a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RR1964.html">first generation</a>” OSINT sources such as media and grey literature collection. While some non-state groups had significant impact on events throughout the Cold War, top-tier intelligence activities were largely restricted to states.</p>



<p>This state monopoly on access to top-tier information began to break down at the beginning of the 21<sup>st</sup> century. As the <a href="https://www.economist.com/technology-quarterly/2019/09/12/drastic-falls-in-cost-are-powering-another-computer-revolution">price of computing continued to fall</a>, the state’s role as the principal investor in military and intelligence technology became less important. As a result, private companies increasingly took the lead in creating, and funding, technologies that transformed the practice of intelligence, such as the internet, social media, and artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>In place of the government monopoly on espionage technology, today there is a boisterous bazaar of information and data vendors. These companies sell a wide variety of social media intelligence tools, earth observation capabilities, large-scale information storage and processing, mobile phone location data, global HUMINT platforms, and sophisticated telemetry intelligence capabilities. This private market has changed the game. Today, with enough money and focus, a small group of dedicated individuals can leverage private sector capability to rival a well-funded intelligence agency. For example, the following capabilities are all within easy, legal reach for any government or non-governmental organization (so long as the budget is right):</p>



<ul><li>An <strong>on-call satellite imagery</strong> service from providers such as Planet, Maxar, IceEye, or others. Today, non-government researchers can access reams of satellite imagery on any area in the world, often at time increments of less than 24 hours for refresh. This means that together with sophisticated, openly available image recognition algorithms, a small team can scour the desert for Chinese siloes – or <a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/2021/07/27/using-open-source-intelligence-to-verify-future-agreement-with-north-korea-pub-85006">monitor North Korea’s nuclear program,</a> and study <a href="ttps://www.planet.com/pulse/planet-ksat-and-airbus-awarded-first-ever-global-contract-to-combat-deforestation/">deforestation trends</a> globally.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>A flexible HUMINT capability</strong> that can source insights from anywhere on the globe. While journalism could always have been considered “OSINT-enabled HUMINT,” today a range of social media intelligence tools or distributed online survey platforms that allow a user to query “sources” all over the globe. Finally, natural language processing platforms allow anyone to conduct a sophisticated, global information-gathering operation completely out of the box.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.rand.org/content/dam/rand/pubs/perspectives/PE200/PE273/RAND_PE273.pdf"><strong>A mature SIGINT capability,</strong></a> from private firms whose satellites <a href="https://www.militaryaerospace.com/rf-analog/article/14211741/rf-and-microwave-sigint-satellites">allow for the measurement</a> of RF and microwave signals from emitters on earth.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Finally, all of this is supported by a <strong>diverse, evolving, and multi-participant marketplace</strong> for <a href="https://www.lawfareblog.com/data-brokers-and-national-security">both data</a> and <a href="https://www.recordedfuture.com/open-source-intelligence-future/">AI/ML capabilities</a>, many of which are hungry for non-governmental researchers to show, in unclassified spaces, the power of their tools.</li></ul>



<p>This only scratches the surface of the tools available. New low and no-cost OSINT platforms are consistently replicating capabilities once held only by top-tier spy agencies – for anyone to use. From NGOs to private companies to non-state terrorist groups and hacker collectives, the increasing sophistication and scope of OSINT capabilities has meant that states no longer have reliable information overmatch vis a vis non-states.</p>



<h1 id="how-to-work-with-intelligence-auxiliaries">How to Work with Intelligence Auxiliaries</h1>



<p>During the Cold War, it simply wasn’t possible for, say, the Bacardi corporation to charter U2 overflights of Cuba to provide snapshots of ongoing missile deployments, or for a group of disaffected Soviet emigres to conduct large-scale online surveys on food availability in supermarkets. Today, <a href="https://www.aspi.org.au/report/uyghurs-sale">similar groups</a> <a href="https://cset.georgetown.edu/publication/harnessed-lightning/">routinely</a> use capabilities such as the tools highlighted above to produce impactful reporting on global issues of crime, corruption, and conflict around the world.</p>



<p>While profit is part of the equation, for many of these organizations, a dedication to mission is a key motivation. This new generation of intelligence auxiliaries combines the mission-motivation of a non-profit with the nimble structure of a startup and the technological reach of an intelligence agency. These groups rapidly collect, analyze, and disseminate research products to audiences both inside and outside of government. Because they often work almost entirely with publicly available information (PAI), such groups frequently have more flexibility than government bodies in whom they hire, how they work, what tools they use, and how they leverage their research, giving them the ability to move faster than any state actor.</p>



<p>States can leverage this energy by recognizing the existence of intelligence auxiliaries aligned with their goals, and looking at how they can enable these groups. Loosely speaking, state responses to the capability of intelligence auxiliaries can be arrayed on a spectrum control, borrowed from principles of agency law. On the “loosest” end of the spectrum, states can engage in Admiral Richard’s “opportunistic enlistment” of an intelligence auxiliary. He (presumably) was not aware of FAS’ research before it was published, learned about it in the news, and was pleased that it happened to align well with his mission priorities. He chose to amplify the research through independent, uncoordinated strategic communications. The defining feature of this model is a total absence of control and coordination.</p>



<p>On the “tightest” side of the spectrum, states can exercise a “direct control” style tasking of auxiliaries, as one might do with a traditional defense contractor. Under this model, a state actor directly contracts with an outside organization to conduct an activity on the state’s behalf, subject to conditions which the state imposes. Different degrees of control over working methods, personnel, timelines, and requirements may be imposed by the state under this model, but its defining feature is a high degree of control over methods and tools of work.</p>



<p>Between these two ends of the spectrum, however, are a variety of ways of interacting with intelligence auxiliaries. These ways of working aren’t based on information overmatch, but instead on long-term, enduring capabilities that states have had throughout history. A hypothetical spectrum of options based on these “enduring state functions” might look something like this:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Opportunistic Enlistment of Intelligence Auxiliaries.</strong> Relying on the fact that intelligence auxiliaries pursue their activities independently from the State, states can simply observe their production and choose to amplify it when convenient, with little to no coordination between the two. This looks much like the case of Admiral Richard, or of other policymakers who seek to leverage emerging news stories.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using the Information Environment as Intelligence Terrain.</strong> States have the ability to define what information is open and what isn’t – and can do so with an eye to granting intelligence auxiliaries more access to mission-important information. For instance,&nbsp; <a href="https://www.akingump.com/en/news-insights/corporate-transparency-act-establishes-new-beneficial-ownership-reporting-requirements-for-us-and-us-registered-foreign-companies.html">the US</a> has recently enacted new beneficial ownership laws, changing what information companies must provide when incorporating themselves. Information in public registers is a gold mine for intelligence auxiliaries working on anti-corruption issues; if states act to change laws with the idea that information disclosed will be used by intelligence auxiliaries for citizen OSINT policing, then they’re shaping the environment for good in a way that frees up state resources.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using Mission-Definition Power to Signal What is Important.</strong> Intelligence auxiliaries depend for funding and credibility on their ability to achieve important missions. There are many ways that policymakers can help guide intelligence auxiliaries toward important goals without revealing classified information or exercising direct control. This might take the form of an <a href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/cyber/2022/01/18/new-academic-partnership-to-provide-military-access-to-more-cyber-research-on-hard-problems/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=EBB%2001.19.2022&amp;utm_term=Editorial%20-%20Military%20-%20Early%20Bird%20Brief">expanded campaign of academic outreach</a> or of embedding select personnel within non-governmental intelligence auxiliary groups. In one example, the government could expand ongoing efforts to bring <a href="https://fcw.com/security/2022/01/nga-looks-tech-support-unclassified-workforce/360487/">commercial expertise</a> into mixed unclassified and classified spaces.&nbsp; Alternatively, states might create common information spaces virtually: instant messaging spaces could be created for trusted intelligence auxiliaries to join and share ongoing research and leads. Such groups could also serve as impromptu coordinating spaces for quick reaction OSINT monitors, as they are currently doing for Ukraine contingencies.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using Fiat Power to Empower Auxiliaries.</strong> States could simply declare activities or types of information legal or illegal depending on the identity of the actor. A simple example of this in action is how <a href="https://www.fincen.gov/section-314b">Bank Secrecy Act (BSA) Section 314(b)</a> gives financial institutions the ability to share sensitive information with one another “in order to identify and report activities that may involve terrorist activity or money laundering.” An expanded version of this law could expand 314(b)’s safe harbor to chosen intelligence auxiliaries, giving banks a way to collaborate with trusted outside experts to better combat money laundering.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using Historical Memory to Feed Private Efforts.</strong> States have significant troves of information, both classified and unclassified, that they often find difficult to truly leverage. If more of these resources are given to non-states, the burden on states to create value from data can be more widely shared. This can (but doesn’t have to) mean selective declassification. Government departments such as Commerce and CBP have significant amounts of unclassified trade and corporate data that could help identify human traffickers, proliferators, and other bad actors.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using Market-Making Ability to Create Information Marketplaces.</strong> States have significant ability to create markets for information, both as participants and as rule-setters. They can use this power to incentivize groups to work together toward state goals. States can both signal priorities and make market connections among non-state actors by hosting short term surges or “hackathons” designed to temporarily gather expertise and tooling to answer an important question. Governments could incentivize private sector tech providers to make “in kind” donations of capability for set periods of time to boost intelligence auxiliaries, with the results of a short-term surge going to support policymaker awareness or strategic communications campaigns. Hackathons often offer <a href="https://www.scielo.cl/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;pid=S0718-18762019000200104&amp;lng=e&amp;nrm=iso&amp;tlng=en">more direct control</a> than do similar “open data” initiatives, making them more attractive for sensitive missions.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Using Commissioning Power to Task Directly.</strong> Finally, states can pursue familiar, tried and true models of direct tasking. This model can be effective in certain circumstances, but often is slow and laborious to implement.</li></ul>



<p>The above are not new ways of working – in nearly every case, there are examples of government leveraging similar models to achieve important goals. But thinking of intelligence auxiliaries and the ways of working with them together as part of a single toolkit can help clarify the operational and legal issues at play. Rather than try to be overly prescriptive with how states can engage with non-state intelligence auxiliaries, policymakers should focus on creating a playbook of workable collaboration frameworks that can be relied on by intelligence professionals at different levels in government to engage with outside organizations. Without such models, commanders are likely to improvise – which may lead to good outcomes in some cases and bad ones in others.</p>



<p>These are far from the only models possible – and which model is appropriate will depend on the specifics of a given situation. Just as there is no one-size fits all approach to a given intelligence question, so there will not be an appropriate universal model for collaboration between state actors and non-state intelligence auxiliaries.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Read also Open Source Intelligence and Uncovering Secrets Hidden in Plain Sight in <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/open-source-intelligence-and-uncovering-secrets-hidden-in-plain-sight">The Cipher Brief</a></em></strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h1 id="not-whether-but-how">Not whether, but how</h1>



<p>Ultimately, the method of interacting with an intelligence auxiliary will be situation-dependent. Should it be covert or overt? Paid or unpaid? Public or private? Short-term or long-term? Policymakers will have to negotiate these questions with reference to specific facts.</p>



<p>But they should not have to negotiate them without functioning models. Admiral Richard is far from the only policymaker who has identified an outside capability that he has no tools to use. We must give intelligence officials, policymakers, and commanders flexible, clear, and transparent ways of working with intelligence auxiliaries. A failure to define the rules of engagement will not deter interaction, but instead leave it less clear and more likely to lead to uncontrollable outcomes. Without clear rules, a government actor could collaborate with an intelligence auxiliary in ways that endanger civil liberties or even lives.</p>



<p>But doing nothing is also a strategy. Policymakers do not get to negotiate the existence of intelligence auxiliaries. Intelligence technology is likely to continue to develop outside the walls of government, and private groups will continue to leverage this technology either in pursuit of a self-defined charitable mission, or for private gain. For non-authoritarian countries with strong civil societies and robust data governance regimes, the rise of intelligence auxiliaries is likely to be a significant force-multiplier vis a vis authoritarian rivals. The question for states is not whether they engage with outside intelligence capability, but how.</p>



<p><strong><em>Read additional <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/open-source-intelligence-and-uncovering-secrets-hidden-in-plain-sight">expert perspectives</a> on open source intelligence in The Cipher Brief</em></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in <a href="https://amzn.to/3sVlEZJ">The Cipher Brief</a></em></strong></p>



<p><em>The Cipher Brief may receive a small commission for <a href="https://amzn.to/3sVlEZJ">products purchased</a> via links</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries">The Real Power of Intelligence &#8216;Auxiliaries&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-real-power-of-intelligence-auxiliaries/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US is Engaging in a Strategy to Share Intelligence on Russia More Broadly.  Is it Worth the Risk?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk</link>
      <comments>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Suzanne Kelly]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CIA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Intelligence]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Cipher Brief]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.thecipherbrief.com/?p=36508</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief <span class="more">[...]</span> <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk" class="post_link inline">More <i class="fas fa-chevron-right"></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk">The US is Engaging in a Strategy to Share Intelligence on Russia More Broadly.  Is it Worth the Risk?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i>&#8220;The Cipher Brief has become the most popular outlet for former intelligence officers; no media outlet is even a close second to The Cipher Brief in terms of the number of articles published by formers.” &#8211;</i> Sept. 2018, Studies in Intelligence, Vol. 62 No.</p>
<p><strong><em>Access all of The Cipher Brief&#8217;s national-security focused expert insight by becoming a  <a href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/membership" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cipher Brief Level I</a> Member .  </em></strong>    </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk">The US is Engaging in a Strategy to Share Intelligence on Russia More Broadly.  Is it Worth the Risk?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thecipherbrief.com">The Cipher Brief</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-us-is-engaging-in-a-strategy-to-share-intelligence-on-russia-more-broadly-is-it-worth-the-risk/feed</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>