<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 23:27:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>U.S. to Partially Evacuate Iraq Embassy as Tensions With Iran Rise</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chantelle Lee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 23:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The decision comes amid heightened tensions between the U.S. and Iran as talks over a potential nuclear deal appear to have stalled. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293392"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/US-Embassy-Iraq.jpg" alt="Iraq US"/>



<p>The U.S. plans to partially evacuate its embassy in Iraq amid rising tensions between the U.S. and Iran, officials told multiple media outlets on Wednesday.</p>



<p>U.S. staffers who are deemed nonessential will be removed from the embassy in Baghdad, the State Department told <a href="https://apnews.com/article/state-department-embassy-baghdad-f892ebd6a50850ef5650f31819541bff"  target="_blank">The Associated Press</a>.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/us-embassy-iraq-preparing-ordered-evacuation-due-heightened-security-risks-2025-06-11/"  target="_blank">Reuters</a> reported that four U.S. and two Iraqi unnamed sources confirmed the news, but the sources didn&rsquo;t share with the news outlet what security risks sparked the move. In a statement to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/11/us/politics/iran-us-iraq-diplomats-middle-east.html"  target="_blank">New York <em>Times</em></a>, the State Department said it had decided to reduce its diplomatic presence in Iraq, but didn&rsquo;t specify how many officials would be removed from the country.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The AP reported that the State Department is authorizing nonessential staffers and their families to depart Bahrain and Kuwait as well.</p>



<p>The decision comes amid heightened tensions between the U.S. and Iran as the countries&#8217; negotiations over a potential nuclear deal appear to have stalled. In a <a href="https://app.magellan.ai/listen_links/NYP"  target="_blank">podcast</a> released on Wednesday, President Donald Trump said that he is growing &ldquo;less confident&rdquo; about the possibility of reaching an agreement with Iran that would limit the country&rsquo;s ability to develop nuclear weapons. </p>



<p>Trump has <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/30/trump-threatens-bomb-iran-00259786"  target="_blank">previously threatened</a> to bomb Iran if negotiations over its nuclear program fail. Iranian Defense Minister Aziz Nasirzadeh <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-threatens-us-bases-region-if-military-conflict-arises-2025-06-11/"  target="_blank">said</a> Wednesday that Iran would strike U.S. military bases in the region if talks fail and conflict with the U.S. escalates.</p>



<p>A U.K. maritime trade agency <a href="https://www.ukmto.org/recent-incidents#9aa802ba-9f3a-4fdb-82b7-7f863fb7baf3"  target="_blank">issued</a> a public advisory on Wednesday, cautioning commercial vessels in the area. The agency said that it had &ldquo;been made aware of increased tensions within the region which could lead to an escalation of military activity having a direct impact on mariners.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293392</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Know About the Northern Ireland Riots as Police Use Water Cannon Amid Petrol Bombs and Chaos</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday saw the second night of riots in Northern Ireland, with rioters using petrol bombs and torching cars.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293105"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218973412.jpg" alt="Police Respond To Second Night Of Unrest In Ballymena"/>



<p>For a second night in a row, riots rocked the town of Ballymena in Northern Ireland on Tuesday, lasting into the early hours of Wednesday morning. Protesters used petrol bombs and fireworks as they clashed with the authorities. In response, police used plastic baton rounds and a water cannon.</p>



[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]

<p>The overnight disruption in Ballymena, situated north of the capital Belfast, resulted in the injury of 17 police officers, with some requiring hospital treatment. Five people were arrested on suspicion of riotous behavior, <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-service-statement-second-night-violence-ballymena"  target="_blank">according to the Police Service of Northern Ireland</a> (PSNI).</p>



<p>Police have said that across both nights of rioting, businesses and homes have been &ldquo;attacked and damaged,&rdquo; adding that more vehicles were set alight on Tuesday evening, as tensions escalated.</p>



<p>A number of protests also took place in other towns and cities across Northern Ireland, including Belfast, Lisburn, and Newtownabbey.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the ongoing unrest in Ballymena.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What prompted the riots in Northern Ireland?</strong></h2>



<p>The disorder started on Monday, June 9, after a peaceful protest took place in the town of Ballymena <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/ballymena-protest-fireworks-petrol-bombs-and-glass-bottles-thrown-at-riot-police-as-serious-disorder-deepens-13381896"  target="_blank">over an alleged sexual assault</a> that police say occurred <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c5y26l5z379o"  target="_blank">the previous Saturday</a>.</p>



<p>Earlier on Monday, two 14-year-old boys appeared at Coleraine Magistrates&#8217; Court in relation to the assault. The boys are charged with attempted oral rape. Both deny the charges. </p>



<p>The boys appeared via videolink from a juvenile center, and confirmed their names and ages via a Romanian translator.</p>



<p>Later in the day, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c98p0696r4do"  target="_blank">hundreds of people</a>&mdash;including men, women and children&mdash;peacefully protested the ongoing case in the town centre of Ballymena, raising concerns about the safety of young women and locals.</p>



<p>Separate riots then began in the town on Monday night, as <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-dealing-disorder-ballymena-appeal-calm"  target="_blank">police reported</a> a number of &ldquo;missiles&rdquo; thrown at officers and properties nearby being damaged.</p>



<p>The authorities have referred to the escalated riots as &#8220;<a href="https://x.com/Diarmuid_9/status/1932426877089509630"  target="_blank">racially-motivated</a>&#8221; attacks that are targeting minority ethnic communities.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-dealing-disorder-ballymena-appeal-calm"  target="_blank">Chief Superintendent Sue Steen</a> issued a plea to the public on Monday night, saying: &ldquo;We are urging everyone to remain calm and to act responsibly. Violence and disorder will only place people at greater risk.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219014444.jpg" alt="Ballymena Protest" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How long are the riots expected to last?</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/someone-is-going-to-get-killed-appeal-issued-after-six-arrested-on-second-night-of-mindless-violence/a1432369102.html"  target="_blank">Speaking to the BBC&rsquo;s <em>Nolan Show</em></a> on Wednesday morning, assistant chief constable Ryan Henderson said that more disorder is expected.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We are absolutely prepared that we may see more of this in the coming days,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Given that we have seen it now for two nights and the severity has maintained over both nights, we are certainly preparing that we may face similar tonight.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Henderson <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0k3le25r8ro"  target="_blank">urged the public</a> to stay at home on Wednesday evening.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Sky News correspondent Connor Gillies, who is in Ballymena, <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/ballymena-protest-fireworks-petrol-bombs-and-glass-bottles-thrown-at-riot-police-as-serious-disorder-deepens-13381896"  target="_blank">said that some families</a> are &ldquo;barricading themselves&rdquo; in their attics amid the escalating violence. &#8220;The talk here in this town is that it could go on for weeks yet,&#8221; he said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How have police responded?</strong></h2>



<p>In response to the first night of rioting, Henderson said <a href="https://x.com/Diarmuid_9/status/1932426877089509630"  target="_blank">during a press conference</a>: &ldquo;This violence was clearly racially-motivated and targeted at our minority ethnic community and the police. It was racist thuggery purely and simply, and any attempt to justify or explain it as anything else is misplaced.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0k3le25r8ro"  target="_blank">The BBC has reported</a> that some households have put up signs signifying the ethnicity or nationality of its residents, seemingly in an effort to remain out of harm&#8217;s way. One photo showed a sign above a door reading &ldquo;Filipino lives here.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-service-statement-second-night-violence-ballymena"  target="_blank">In a statement</a> released on Wednesday in response to the second night of chaos, chief constable Jon Boutcher called the riots &ldquo;mindless violence&rdquo; and that it was &#8220;deeply concerning and utterly unacceptable.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;These criminal acts not only endanger lives but also risk undermining the ongoing criminal justice process led by the [police] in support of a victim who deserves truth, justice, and protection,&rdquo; Boutcher said. &ldquo;Ironically, and frustratingly, this violence threatens to derail the very pursuit of justice it claims to challenge. Let me be clear: This behaviour must stop. I appeal to everyone involved to cease all further acts of criminality and disorder immediately.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The chief constable also thanked the police officers tasked with handling and responding to the riots, adding that he believes the PSNI is &ldquo;critically underfunded.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Despite operating under immense financial pressure&mdash;far greater than that faced by other public services in Northern Ireland or police forces across the UK and in the Republic of Ireland&mdash;our officers continue to display unwavering professionalism, courage, and resolve,&rdquo; said Boutcher.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218973427.jpg" alt="Ballymena Protest" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What have politicians said about the riots?&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>British Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZU7LWldJjqc"  target="_blank">addressed the riots</a> during Prime Minister&rsquo;s Questions in the House of Commons on Wednesday.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I utterly condemn the violence that we&rsquo;ve seen overnight in Ballymena and in other parts of Northern Ireland,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;It is absolutely vital that PSNI are given the time they need to investigate the incidents concerned rather than face mindless attacks as they seek to bring peace and order to keep people safe.&rdquo;</p>



<p>On Tuesday, a Downing Street spokeperson for the Prime Minister had said: &ldquo;The reports of sexual assault in the area are extremely distressing, but there is no justification for attacks on police officers while they continue to protect local communities.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Irish T&aacute;naiste [Deputy Prime Minister] Simon Harris has also condemned the rioting. &#8220;The scenes of violence over the last two nights in Ballymena are deeply disturbing. The strong collective calls for the violence and disorder to end immediately must be heeded. There can be no justification for attacks such as these on people&rsquo;s homes or on the police,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/SimonHarrisTD/status/1932802628737491347"  target="_blank">he said</a>. </p>



<p>Michelle O&rsquo;Neill, Northern Ireland&rsquo;s First Minister, has called for an immediate end to &ldquo;the racist and sectarian attacks on families across the North and the rioting in Ballymena.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/moneillsf/status/1932735595475882157/photo/1"  target="_blank">Speaking out via social media</a> on Wednesday morning, she said: &ldquo;No one, now or ever, should feel the need to place a sticker on their door to identify their ethnicity just to avoid being targeted.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Leader of the Northern Irish Unionist Ulster Party <a href="https://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/someone-is-going-to-get-killed-appeal-issued-after-six-arrested-on-second-night-of-mindless-violence/a1432369102.html"  target="_blank">Mike Nesbitt, who also serves as Health Minister, said</a>: &ldquo;There is no justification for this mayhem, and my thoughts are with those who have lost their homes and the greater number who are feeling intimidated and unwelcome. I understand there are community concerns regarding an alleged serious sexual assault. There are legitimate ways to express those concerns. Street violence is not one of them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Sinn F&eacute;in MP (Member of Parliament) John Finucane has condemned the attacks.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The racist attacks on a number of homes near the Ballysillan area last night were abhorrent, and my thoughts are with those families affected. Sickening behaviour such as this has no place in our society,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/johnfinucane/status/1932710366095560723"  target="_blank">Finucane said in a statement</a> shared via social media on Wednesday morning. &ldquo;I will be contacting the families affected to ensure they receive the support they need in the time ahead. Racism, wherever it occurs, must be stamped out and faced down through strong leadership in our communities.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Northern Ireland&rsquo;s Justice Minister Naomi Long <a href="https://www.justice-ni.gov.uk/news/justice-minister-condemns-disorder-ballymena"  target="_blank">has also expressed her concerns</a> over the &ldquo;disturbing scenes&rdquo; from Ballymena.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;There is absolutely no place in our society for such disorder and there can be no justification for it,&rdquo; Long said. &ldquo;Attacking homes and police officers serves no purpose other than to damage communities and raise tensions. Those involved will be pursued and held accountable for their actions.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The World Is Looking to Europe to &#8216;Resist,&#8217; Says French Foreign Minister</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vivienne Walt / Nice, France]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jean-Noël Barrot speaks to TIME about ocean conservation, Trump, and the future of multilateralism.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292963"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/jean-noel-barrot-french-foreign-minister-oceans-climate-trump-ukraine-gaza-europe-future.jpg" alt="France's Minister for Europe and Foreign Affairs Jean-Noel Barrot addresses the audience during a plenary session on the second day of the United Nations Ocean Conference in Nice, France, on June 10, 2025. "/>



<p>When French President Emmanuel Macron appointed Jean-No&euml;l Barrot last September as his new Minister for Europe and Foreign Affairs&mdash;the fourth during eight years in power&mdash;some feared the 42-year-old economist might be totally eclipsed by the country&rsquo;s kinetic leader. Indeed, Macron has zipped furiously across Europe, the Middle East, and Asia all year, negotiating deals on climate, trade, military assistance, and peace, some of it in an effort to fill an aching vacuum left by Washington. For all that, Barrot, who spent a few years teaching at MIT, has emerged as a fervent voice for his boss&rsquo;s agenda, attempting to give the world a global-minded alternative to an increasingly inward-looking U.S. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>This week, that contrast is on stark display in the sun-baked Provence city of Nice, where thousands are gathered for the U.N.&#8217;s Oceans Conference. The hope is that after five days of talks and speeches, nations will agree to international controls on fishing, deep-sea mining, wildlife conservation, and other issues, in order to stanch the rapid degradation of oceans, crucial to reining in global warming. Delegations of top government officials, presidents, and prime ministers from about 170 countries are among the crowds. Absent: The U.S.</p>



<p>At the end of the hectic opening day on Monday, Barrot sat down with TIME to reflect on the impact of a deeply changed global order, and what can be done.</p>



<p><em>This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>



<p><strong>TIME:</strong> <strong>The U.S. administration is not represented here. Did they decline the invitation, or did they never say whether they were coming?</strong></p>



<p>Barrot: Everyone was invited. This is a U.N. conference, so any U.N. member country is invited to come. But I cannot help but notice that many U.S. organizations are present. We have U.S. scientists. We have the Mayor of New Orleans, the Mayor of New York, the Mayor of Los Angeles.</p>



<p><strong>This is a really crucial global summit. Are you saying it doesn&rsquo;t matter whether the U.S. takes itself out of the whole process? Because of course, it is not just the oceans.</strong></p>



<p>One thing is true: Europe will never give up on multilateralism, on cooperation. We believe it is in the interest of mankind, but it&#8217;s also in our own interests.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing many countries around the world, in Africa, in Latin America, in Southeast Asia, that are looking at France and Europe to resist. They&#8217;re looking at us and expecting us to resist the temptation by some to go back to confrontation, fears of coercion. And it is our intention to build coalitions whenever traditional multilateral forums are not effective, to show that there is only one way to solve the global issues we&#8217;re facing, the consequences of which are going to affect our daily lives, [which] is by multilateral means.</p>



<p><strong>That feels a bit like you&#8217;re climbing uphill. You&#8217;ve got to put together a coalition, and build this multilateralism, without a key player involved</strong>.</p>



<p>No. What I&#8217;m saying is that we will defend multilateralism in all areas. We&#8217;re celebrating the 80th anniversary of the U.N. this year. They built those that came before us. They built a number of multilateral forums for trade, for security, for environment. We&#8217;re going to defend and support these. But at any point in time when they will not be able to deliver results, because some will oppose them from within, then we will find other ways for multilateral forums and cooperation to exist.</p>



<p>The key message is that everyone, every country in the world, is better off with an effective multilateralism. It is not because some countries in the world would like to give up on multilateralism, that we will give up. We will not.</p>



<p><strong>This goes beyond oceans.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I&rsquo;m thinking of international trade, of security, of the security architecture coming out of the Second World War, starting with the U.N. Charter that basically says that there is never any pretext for violence and brute force, except for self defense, and except when the Security Council prescribes it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing these basic principles&mdash;that you don&#8217;t touch my borders and I will not touch yours&mdash;being violated.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>You mean Ukraine?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, and other places in the world. We are seeing the Non-Proliferation Treaty being questioned by some countries that are basically close to acquiring nuclear weapons and creating massive instability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I could mention other global goods, such as health, with the World Health Organization.</p>



<p><strong>So the whole architecture we&#8217;ve relied on for 80 years.</strong></p>



<p>It is weakened. It is going to have to be something new. That is why we&#8217;re pleading in favor of reform of the Security Council at the U.N., to allow India, Brazil, Germany, Japan, and two African countries to become permanent members. [Since 1945 only the U.S., Britain, France, China, and Russia have been permanent members of the Security Council, holding veto power on votes at the U.N.]</p>



<p>If we want international law and multilateral principles to be stronger, we need the institutions to be more representative and legitimate.</p>



<p><strong>People have been calling for this for a long time, and it&rsquo;s never happened. Do you see an opportunity now, given what terrible shape multilateralism is in?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I think history is accelerating. And for all those who believe in this legacy that came out of the ruins of the Second World War, and that feel responsible for transferring &nbsp;to the next generation the global architecture that does not prevent all countries from having anything bad happen, that has prevented so many of these things over the past decades&mdash;if we want this to survive, it&#8217;s time to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>There are two wars that seem to have no end date. How do you see this ending in Ukraine and in Gaza?</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>So in Gaza, we are calling for an immediate ceasefire. Liberation of hostages held by Hamas and unhindered access of humanitarian help to Gaza.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But then, the only alternative to a permanent state of war is a political solution resting on two states living side by side with security guarantees. This is what we&#8217;re working on in the perspective of the conference that will be taking place in a few days [a U.N. conference in New York on June 18], removing all the obstacles on the path towards such a political solution, because we believe it to be in the interests of the Israeli people, of the Palestinian people&mdash;and therefore, in our interests as well, as Europeans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For Ukraine, we need Vladimir Putin to cease fire and to agree to enter into peace negotiations that will comply with the principles of the U.N. Charter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since he doesn&#8217;t seem to be sending any signal that he&#8217;s willing to do that, we&#8217;re going to build up significant pressure, by coordinating with the efforts <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/07/lindsey-graham-russia-sanctions-bill-trade-embargo-00393297"  target="_blank">led by the U.S. senators</a> to adopt in the next few days a new package of sanctions, targeted to force Putin, allowing for peace negotiation to start.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>And military security guarantees from Europe too?</strong></p>



<p>We need a ceasefire for discussions to start, and then, of course, those discussions will have [to] come to the question of territories and security guarantees.</p>



<p><strong>You think you could go ahead without the U.S., or you think that the U.S. will finally come on board?</strong></p>



<p>The most important point is for Ukraine to be able to deter any further aggression. This starts with strengthening their own army. A strong army is in itself a powerful deterrent. There are various possible formulas and scenarios that I don&#8217;t want to present here, some of which indeed include some form of contribution by the U.S.</p>



<p><strong>Getting back to the oceans: President Macron told the conference the </strong><a href="https://time.com/7292295/whats-at-stake-un-global-ocean-conference/" ><strong>oceans &lsquo;are not for sale.&rsquo;</strong></a><strong> Everyone, myself included, understood that to refer to President Trump&rsquo;s executive order allowing deep-sea mining.</strong></p>



<p>On this, there&#8217;s no surprise. We&#8217;ve brought together a coalition of more than 30 countries that request a moratorium, or at the very least to apply a precautionary principle to the exploitation of deep seas, and that supports international efforts by the International Seabed Authority to draft a mining code. So it&#8217;s no surprise [that] when we&#8217;ve seen recent decisions allowing exploitation of the seabed that we would voice our opposition. We&#8217;re saying it today and we&#8217;ll say it in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>But what do you do if the U.S. simply goes ahead and effectively violates international law?</strong> <strong>What&#8217;s your recourse?</strong></p>



<p>Our mission here in Nice is to highlight the risks of indulging in such seabed exploitation without first taking the time to explore its resources and draft legislation that is going to preserve the resources of the ocean and allow for economic activity with and from the ocean. That&#8217;s the only way to make such sort of ocean-based economic activity acceptable and sustainable.</p>



<p><strong>Do you have international law to enforce that?</strong> <strong>I mean, at the moment, the enforcement mechanism is a little bit lacking.</strong></p>



<p>No. The International Seabed Authority is in the process of drafting a mining code. We support this effort. As far as the high seas is concerned, there is absolutely no regulation. This <a href="https://www.un.org/bbnjagreement/en"  target="_blank">Treaty on the High Seas</a> [a U.N.-negotiated document which several countries are ratifying in Nice this week] is going to initiate the process. It is going to end up with regulation of 50% of the planet [the oceans] that is subject to absolutely no law, nor any regulation.</p>



<p>That adds to various announcements regarding marine protected areas, decarbonization of transportation, the creation of an international organization for the science of the ocean, and the creation of a global coalition of cities and regions. The world is basically taking its destiny in its hands and acting for the ocean.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>But not the U.S.?</strong></p>



<p>Everywhere I&rsquo;m walking in Nice I am seeing the presence of U.S. scientists, U.S. mayors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We still have some work to do to keep raising awareness, so that everyone around the world understands that there is only one ocean, and that our future is pretty much &mdash; very much &mdash; connected to it.</p>



<p>If we don&#8217;t act with resolution, the ocean that is our friend and ally can also become an adversary, especially for countries that have coastlines that are exposed to the rising sea levels.</p>



<p>This is the biggest ever conference organized on the ocean. We had 4,000 people in 2017 in New York [the first U.N. Oceans Conference], 7,000 in Lisbon in 2022, and over 100,000 people in Nice.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>President Macron is going to Greenland this weekend. Why?</strong></p>



<p>Greenland is European territory. He will be there with the Prime Minister of Denmark. We&#8217;ve been saying repeatedly that European borders are not negotiable. So it&#8217;s a way to reaffirm this principle, but also to strengthen our cooperation with Greenland. We intend to enhance those links, from scientific cooperation to economic cooperation.</p>



<p><strong>Is it a message to the U.S. president too?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s more of a message to Greenland. And the testament to our friendship as well.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292963</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the U.K. and Allies Sanctioned Israeli Ministers Ben-Gvir and Smotrich—and What Comes Next</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 20:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.K. and allies sanctioned Israeli ministers for inciting violence and expanding settlements in the occupied West Bank.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292990"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2155281904.jpg" alt="Israeli Cabinet Members At Odds Over Proposed Ceasefire Deal"/>



<p>The U.K. and several allies <a href="https://x.com/FCDOGovUK/status/1932440082046189723"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">have imposed sanctions</a> on Israeli ministers Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich, accusing the two far-right politicians of inciting violence against Palestinians in the occupied West Bank.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/global-affairs/news/2025/06/canada-imposes-fourth-round-of-sanctions-on-facilitators-of-extremist-settler-violence-against-civilians-in-west-bank.html"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.foreignminister.gov.au/minister/penny-wong/media-release/joint-statement-foreign-ministers-australia-canada-new-zealand-norway-and-united-kingdom-measures-targeting-itamar-ben-gvir-and-bezalel-smotrich"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Australia</a>, New Zealand, and Norway joined the U.K. in imposing a travel ban on Ben-Gvir&mdash;Israel&rsquo;s national security minister and a West Bank settler&mdash;and Finance Minister Smotrich. The five governments also froze any assets either may have in their countries.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich have incited extremist violence and serious abuses of Palestinian human rights. These actions are not acceptable,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/DavidLammy/status/1932450814595117306"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a> British Foreign Secretary David Lammy. &ldquo;This is why we have taken action now &ndash; to hold those responsible to account.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The British government&nbsp;<a href="https://news.sky.com/video/foreign-secretary-david-lammy-confirms-sanctions-on-israeli-ministers-over-inciting-violence-13381736"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">reaffirmed</a>&nbsp;its support for a two-state solution and described the ongoing violence against Palestinians in the West Bank as &ldquo;completely unacceptable.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The sanctions come as the U.K. and other European nations increase pressure on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu&rsquo;s government to lift the blockade on aid into Gaza, where humanitarian experts warn that famine is imminent.</p>



<p>&#8220;Britain has already tried once to prevent us from settling the cradle of our homeland, and we cannot do it again,&rdquo; responded Smotrich, referring to a 1939 British document limiting Jewish migration. &ldquo;We are determined God willing to continue building,&#8221; Smotrich added, speaking at the inauguration of a new settlement in the Hebron Hills.</p>



<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar condemned the sanctions as &ldquo;outrageous,&rdquo; adding that the government would convene a special meeting to determine its response to what he called an &ldquo;unacceptable decision.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the sanctions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the sanctions mean for Ben-Gvir and Smotrich</strong></h2>



<p>The British Foreign Office <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-and-partners-unite-to-sanction-ministers-inciting-west-bank-violence"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a> the sanctions imposed on Ben-Gvir and Smotrich were effective immediately due to their &ldquo;repeated incitement of violence against Palestinian civilians.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Israeli cabinet ministers are now subject to a U.K. travel ban, will have any assets in the country frozen, and are barred from directing, managing or promoting a British company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Foreign Office called on the Israeli government to crack down on settler violence against Palestinians in the West Bank, and emphasized that &ldquo;measures today cannot be seen in isolation from events in Gaza, where Israel must uphold international humanitarian law.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In May, the British government announced it was <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/20/uk-suspends-trade-talks-with-israel-repellant-extremism"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">suspending negotiations</a> with Israel on a prospective trade agreement.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2216570861.jpg" alt="ISRAEL-PALESTINIAN-CONFLICT-JERUSALEM DAY" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What led to the sanctions?</strong></h2>



<p>On May 19, Prime Minister Keir Starmer joined Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau and French President Emmanuel Macron <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-statement-from-the-leaders-of-the-united-kingdom-france-and-canada-on-the-situation-in-gaza-and-the-west-bank"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">in signing a joint statement</a> condemning both Israel&rsquo;s blockade of humanitarian aid into Gaza and the expansion of settlements in the West Bank.</p>



<p>An estimated&nbsp;<a href="https://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/jewish-settlements-population-1970-present"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">529,455 Jewish settlers</a>&nbsp;currently live in&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7289555/israel-expansion-settlements-west-bank/?utm_source=chatgpt.com"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">settlements</a>&nbsp;in the West Bank, excluding those living in East Jerusalem. The United Nations considers these settlements&nbsp;<a href="https://www.un.org/unispal/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/The-Status-of-Jerusalem-Engish-199708.pdf"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">illegal under international law</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Violence against Palestinians in the West Bank has escalated since the October 7, 2023, Hamas terror attack on Israel, during which militants killed approximately 1,200 people and took around 250 others hostage.</p>



<p>Between Jan. 1, 2024, and April 30, 2025, at least 616 Palestinians, including 115 children, had been killed by settlers or the Israeli military according to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ochaopt.org/content/west-bank-monthly-snapshot-casualties-property-damage-and-displacement-april-2025"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">U.N. Office for Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</a></p>



<p>In the same period, OCHA recorded 1,936 incidents of violence toward Palestinians, with 41,272 being displaced in the West Bank.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who are Ben-Gvir and Smotrich?</strong></h2>



<p>Cabinet members Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich lead far-right parties that had been regarded as outside the mainstream of Israeli politics until Benjamin Netanyahu invited them into a <a href="https://main.knesset.gov.il/en/mk/government/pages/governments.aspx?govid=37"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">ruling coalition</a>&mdash;which they now hold the power to disband. </p>



<p>Smotrich&rsquo;s Religious Zionism party holds 14 seats in the 120-seat Knesset while Ben-Gvir&rsquo;s Otzma Yehudit party holds six.</p>



<p>The two ministers are known for their far-right political views and strong support for Israeli settlement expansion in the West Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Smotrich, born in the occupied Golan Heights in 1980, has repeatedly called for Israeli settlers to return to Gaza.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On May 30, Smotrich&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7289555/israel-expansion-settlements-west-bank/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced plans to establish 22 new settlements</a>&nbsp;in the West Bank&mdash;a move widely regarded as illegal under international law.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/bezalelsm/status/1927960845625000276"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">He called the expansion</a>&nbsp;a &ldquo;historic decision,&rdquo; saying, &ldquo;We have succeeded in creating a profound strategic change, returning the State of Israel to a path of construction, Zionism, and vision.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2023-01-16/ty-article/.premium/israels-far-right-finance-minister-im-a-fascist-homophobe-but-i-wont-stone-gays/00000185-b921-de59-a98f-ff7f47c70000"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Self-described</a>&nbsp;as a &ldquo;fascist homophobe,&rdquo; Smotrich has previously advocated for government&nbsp;<a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2016-05-06/ty-article/smotrich-if-israel-took-revenge-on-palestinians-thered-be-no-jewish-attacks/0000017f-f686-d318-afff-f7e752e20000"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">reprisal attacks on Palestinians</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/lawmaker-backs-segregated-jewish-arab-maternity-wards/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">supported segregated maternity wards</a>&nbsp;for Jewish and Arab mothers.</p>



<p>Itamar Ben-Gvir, Israel&rsquo;s national security minister, has a long history of far-right activism.</p>



<p>A former disciple of the extremist Rabbi Meir Kahane, Ben-Gvir was known in his youth for his&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/02/27/itamar-ben-gvir-israels-minister-of-chaos"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">affiliation with Kach</a>, a Jewish supremacist group outlawed in both Israel and the United States as a terrorist organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By his early 30s, he had been convicted of incitement to racism and supporting a terrorist organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though he has since rebranded himself as a mainstream political figure, Ben-Gvir continues to advocate for hardline policies against Palestinians and is a vocal proponent of expanding Israeli settlements in the West Bank.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mahrang Baloch Writes From Prison: &#8216;Speaking Up for Justice Is Not a Crime&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mahrang Baloch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 17:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIME 100 Next]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pakistan arrested Mahrang Baloch for her human rights work in Balochistan.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292408"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Mahrang-Baloch.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-PAKISTAN-POLITICS-UNREST-RIGHTS-BALOCH-PROTEST"/>



<p>It has been more than two and a half months since I was <a href="https://time.com/7271141/pakistan-jails-mahrang-baloch-human-rights-activist/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thrown into prison</a>&mdash;Hudda Prison, in Quetta, Pakistan, the same place father was caged nearly two decades ago, also for promoting the rights of the people of Balochistan.</p>



<p>Since my arrest, Pakistan&#8217;s state secuity agencies have deployed every tactic to break me. I have been offered a deal: stay silent, avoid political activity, and you can be home. I refused. The state has failed to produce a single piece of evidence linking me to any act of violence or criminality. The only &#8220;proof&#8221; they cite is a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15y08Sg9jMs"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">press conference</a> I gave a few days before my March 22 arrest.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>I spoke to reporters after armed militants had <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy0d5y9ew24o"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">hijacked a train </a>and held 300 passengers hostage for hours. The attack occurred in the Balochistan, the largest province in Pakistan, and was carried out by Baloch separatists who have been fighting with the state for decades. At the press conference, I spoke not to defend the hijackers&mdash;our movement, the Baloch Yakjehti [Unity] Committee, has always renounced violence. Indeed, my intention was to draw a distinction between those who confront the state with arms and those who confront it with words.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s a crucial distinction, one the state prefers to blur. In Pakistan, &ldquo;terrorist&rdquo; is a label pinned on anyone who advocates for Baloch rights. Those who speak up run the <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2025/03/pakistan-systematic-attacks-and-relentless-crackdown-on-baloch-activists-must-end/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">risk of arrest</a> by military and intelligence agencies. After their arrest, they might never be seen again. If they are, it is often as a body, produced after a violent incident like the train attack.<br><br>This was why I asked reporters:  Who were the more than two dozen &ldquo;unidentified&rdquo; bodies brought to Quetta&#8217;s Civil Hospital after the hijacking? And why were 13 of them buried overnight without being named? The attackers, the Baloch Liberation Army, had released pictures and details of the 12 militants it said were killed. The identities of the rest were a mystery, but we had our suspicions. In Balochistan it is common practice, after violent episodes, for the forcibly disappeared persons to be put to death, and their bodies produced as those of militants.</p>



<p>I demanded DNA testing of those who had been buried in the dead of night. Families of the disappeared feared, with good reason, that their loved ones were among them.<br><br><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7271141/pakistan-jails-mahrang-baloch-human-rights-activist/" ><em>Pakistan Jails Baloch Human Rights Activist</em></a></p>



<p>So I am in jail for insisting on the distinction between peaceful activism and violence.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Mahrang-Baloch2.jpg" alt="PAKISTAN-UNREST-BALOCHISTAN-RIGHTS" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>My work had already drawn unwelcome international attention. In May 2024, Pakistani officials were outraged after I visited Norway at the invitation of <a href="https://wexfo.no/2025/04/29/why-norway-must-speak-up-for-dr-mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank">PEN Norway,</a> the Norwegian branch of PEN International and the World Expression Forum. I was even harassed on Norwegian soil by individuals linked to Pakistan&#8217;s embassy in Oslo, whose intervention was ended by the Norwegian domestic security agency, PST. When I returned to Pakistan, I was immediately charged with sedition, and treated as if I had returned from an ISIS camp in Syria or Iraq rather than one of the most peace-loving countries in the world.</p>



<p>In October, the government&#8217;s smear campaigns amplified with my inclusion on the <a href="https://time.com/7023541/mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TIME100 Next Emerging Leaders</a>. I was called &ldquo;Malala 2&rdquo; and a Western puppet. Surveillance around me intensified, and I was placed on the Fourth Schedule, an anti-terror watch list typically reserved for hardened militants, and which restricts the movement and activities of the listed. <a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I was barred</a> from travelling abroad.</p>



<p>I am learning the price of peaceful activism.</p>



<p>For decades, Pakistan has kept the rest of the country, and the world, in the dark about Balochistan. It remains an information black hole. Among those the military and intelligence agencies have <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2011/mar/29/balochistan-pakistans-secret-dirty-war"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">forcibly disappeared, killed, or forced into exile</a> are journalists who dare to write about these atrocities. According to the Balochistan Union of Journalists, more than 40 have been killed since 2000. Foreign media are <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/declan-walsh-expelled"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">denied </a>access to the region.</p>



<p>From this darkness, a woman leading a grassroots movement for Baloch rights was unacceptable. The hostility of the state intensified with the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/resources/idt-4f79d09b-655a-42f8-82b4-9b2ecebab611"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">BBC&#8217;s 100 Women list</a>, and a nomination for the Nobel Peace Prize. But if international pressure has prevented my being killed, I face psychological warfare, threats, and the constant spectre of danger.</p>



<p>I write this the day my sister told me that the Islamic State of Khorasan (ISIS-K) released a 100-page Urdu-language booklet accusing me of being a Western agent. Their &#8220;evidence&#8221;?  The TIME <a href="https://time.com/collections/time100-next-gala-2024/7276600/time100-next-gala-toasts-2024/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">honor</a> and Norway trip. Other BYC leaders are in jail with me: Sabghat Ullah Shah Jee, Beebarg Zehri (a disabled man), Gulzadi, and Beebow. I tell them: We are not the first to be imprisoned for demanding peace, justice, and rights. From Nelson Mandela to <a href="https://narges.foundation/two-months-of-detention-the-narges-foundation-calls-for-the-immediate-release-of-dr-mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Narges Mohammadi</a>, we walk the same path. We draw strength from their courage, intellect, and defiance.</p>



<p>Our movement is rooted in peace. We speak against enforced disappearances, extrajudicial killings, forced displacement, and the systematic denial of basic rights to the Baloch. We are the rightful owners of the <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/why-chinese-investment-is-stoking-anger-in-pakistans-balochistan-province/a-54188705"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Saindak Copper-Gold Project</a> (worth billions of dollars, but the profits are not shared with the local population), the Reko Diq mine (<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/pakistans-reko-diq-mine-generate-74-billion-free-cash-flow-over-37-years-barrick-2025-01-20/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">estimated </a>to hold copper and gold reserves worth over $60 billion, but the benefits are not reaching the Baloch people), and Gwadar &mdash; the gateway to the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor. Yet, 70% of Balochistan&#8217;s population lives below the poverty line.<br><a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/" ><br></a><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/" ><em>Pakistan Bars Activist From Traveling to </em>TIME<em> Event Honoring Her</em></a><br><br>The state is offended and brands us terrorists and violent. But we are not violent. The state is armed, powerful, and ruthless. It uses violence to silence those who ask for justice. The practices once reserved for the Baloch, considered lesser citizens, are now expanding to other parts of Pakistan. <a href="https://time.com/6693147/pakistan-election-results-imran-khan-pti-military/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Former Prime Minister Imran Khan</a> and his party are now under the military&#8217;s wrath. He is jailed. Is Imran Khan also a terrorist? Are members of his PTI party now &#8220;agents of hostile agencies&#8221;?</p>



<p>If the Pakistan Army and its intelligence agencies are as competent as they claim to be, why have they failed to present a single piece of credible proof? Why have they not held a fair, transparent trial?</p>



<p>Because this isn&#8217;t about the law; it&#8217;s about fear, their fear of our truth.</p>



<p>This prison is more than bricks and bars. It carries the <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250417-mahrang-baloch-a-child-of-the-resistance-for-pakistan-s-ethnic-minority"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">memory of my father</a>. As a child, I visited him here. I didn&#8217;t grow up playing with toys. I grew up holding posters of my father, who was detained and then disappeared. When I turned eighteen, I received his lifeless, tortured, bullet-riddled body. This is not just my story. It&#8217;s the story of every child in Balochistan. Childhood here is shaped by grief, fear, and posters of the disappeared.</p>



<p>When our generation came of age, those of us raised in the shadows of state violence, we vowed: No child after us should suffer the same fate. We are fully aware of the power imbalance between us and a nuclear-armed state. It controls the media. It runs smear campaigns. It weaponizes the judiciary. It deploys overwhelming force. It controls the parliament. It operates proxy groups and armed militias.</p>



<p>Our confinement is part of a war of narratives.</p>



<p>Speaking up for justice is not a crime.</p>



<p>Raising our voices against state violence is not treason.</p>



<p>Demanding rights is not terrorism.</p>



<p>It is humanity.</p>



<p>And one day, we believe, this struggle will succeed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292408</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Austria Has Some of the Most Relaxed Gun Ownership Laws in Europe</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Solcyré Burga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Austria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Austria ranks 12th in the world for gun ownership.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292837"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218904840.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-AUSTRIA-SHOOTING-SCHOOL"/>



<p>A <a href="https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/" >school shooting in Graz, Austria</a> left at least nine people dead and 12 injured Tuesday, prompting renewed attention to the country&rsquo;s relatively permissive gun laws. </p>



<p>The attack marks Austria&rsquo;s deadliest mass shooting in its postwar history and the first major incident of its kind since 2020.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932402453317894165"  target="_blank">Authorities said</a> the suspected gunman, who was found dead at the scene, used two firearms that were legally registered under a valid license. Local media <a href="https://kurier.at/chronik/steiermark/graz-dreierschuetzengasse-schule-amoklauf-toter/403048807"  target="_blank">has</a> <a href="https://www.krone.at/3808844"  target="_blank">reported</a> that the suspect was a former student, aged 22. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Austrian Chancellor Christian Stocker gave his condolences to the families of the victims, calling the shooting a national tragedy and a &ldquo;dark day in [the] history of our country&rdquo; in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g00Xp9WEazg"  target="_blank">a press briefing</a> Tuesday. The identities of the victims have not yet been released.</p>



<p>The government has declared a three-day period of national mourning. A nationwide minute of silence is scheduled for 10 a.m. local time Wednesday.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gun ownership rates</h2>



<p>Austria ranks among the highest in Europe for civilian gun ownership, with approximately 30 guns per 100 residents, <a href="https://www.smallarmssurvey.org/sites/default/files/resources/SAS-BP-Civilian-Firearms-Numbers.pdf"  target="_blank">according to the 2017 Small Arms Survey</a>, a Geneva research group. While countries such as Cyprus, Finland, and Iceland report slightly higher rates, Austria remains an outlier in the continent.  </p>



<p>At a global level, Austria ranks <a href="https://www.smallarmssurvey.org/sites/default/files/resources/SAS-BP-Civilian-Firearms-Numbers.pdf"  target="_blank">12th in the world</a> for gun ownership, though significantly lagging behind the country with the highest rate: the United States. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">History of mass shootings in Austria</h2>



<p>The country has recorded two public mass shootings in the period between 2000 and 2022, <a href="https://rockinst.org/blog/public-mass-shootings-around-the-world-prevalence-context-and-prevention/"  target="_blank">according to research by the Rockefeller Institute of Government</a>. The most recent incident occurred in <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-54798508"  target="_blank">November 2020</a>, when a gunman killed four people and wounded 23 others. Last year, authorities said they thwarted a planned attack targeting a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna. </p>



<p>By contrast, there were more than 500 mass shootings recorded in the U.S. in 2024, <a href="https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/"  target="_blank">according to the Gun Violence Archive</a>, which defines such incidents as those involving four or more people shot, either injured or killed, excluding the perpetrator. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7278187/forgotten-half-of-americas-gun-crisis/" ><em>My Dad&rsquo;s Death and the Forgotten Half of America&rsquo;s Gun Crisis</em></a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who is allowed to possess and carry a firearm in Austria?</h2>



<p>Austria has some of the most liberal firearm regulations in Europe. Residents aged 18 or older are permitted to own a firearm, with some exceptions allowing 16-year-olds to acquire guns for hunting purposes. All firearms must be registered within six weeks of acquisition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To possess and carry handguns, repeating shotguns, or semi-automatic firearms&mdash;provided they are not classified as war material or prohibited weapons&mdash;individuals must obtain an official permit. </p>



<p><a href="https://www.ris.bka.gv.at/GeltendeFassung.wxe?Abfrage=Bundesnormen&amp;Gesetzesnummer=10006016"  target="_blank">Federal law</a> prohibits people from possessing weapons or ammunition if they could endanger the &ldquo;life, health or freedom&rdquo; of individuals or their property. Those considered legally &ldquo;unreliable&rdquo; &mdash;including individuals with a history of alcoholism, addiction, or mental illness&mdash;are barred from owning and carrying firearms. The same applies to those who have been convicted of a criminal act involving the use or threat of violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Authorities have an obligation to conduct an &#8220;assessment of reliability.&rdquo; Federal law says that individuals who do not have a hunting license must &ldquo;provide an expert opinion stating whether they have a tendency to handle weapons carelessly or use them recklessly, particularly when under psychological stress.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gun owners are required to carry their permit documents when carrying or transporting firearms.</p>



<p>The Austrian government <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC1971203/"  target="_blank">tightened its firearm regulations</a> in 1997, in line with a European Council directive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Visitors from other European Union member states in possession of a firearm must bring a European firearms pass and a permit related to the specific weapon they are carrying, <a href="https://www.bmf.gv.at/en/topics/customs/travellers/prohibitions-and-restrictions-on-imports/carrying-weapons.html"  target="_blank">according to Austria&rsquo;s Federal Ministry</a>. The country also has an existing ban on the import of weapons such as pump-action shotguns.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292837</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>At Least 10 Dead After School Shooting in Austria, Police Say</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 12:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mayor of Graz says presumed gunman among the dead as local media report 28 people are being treated for injuries. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292668"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218892094.jpg" alt="AUSTRIA-SHOOTING-SCHOOL"/>



<p>At least 10 people are dead <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/ced27g4e6xwo"  target="_blank">following a mass shooting</a> at the BORG Dreiersch&uuml;tzengasse high school in Graz, Austria, according to <a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932402453317894165"  target="_blank">state police</a>.</p>



<p>Among the dead were <a href="https://www.polizei.gv.at/stmk/presse/aussendungen/presse.aspx?prid=546232672F564F326D57773D&amp;pro=0"  target="_blank">eight students</a>, one adult, and the suspected gunman in the deadliest mass shooting in Austria&rsquo;s postwar history. Twelve others were injured. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Austrian Chancellor Christian Stocker called the shooting a national tragedy and a &ldquo;dark day in [the] history of our country&rdquo; in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g00Xp9WEazg"  target="_blank">a press briefing</a> Tuesday.</p>



<p>Police said the gunman, believed to be 21 years old, is thought to have acted alone. The identities of the victims have not yet been released.</p>



<p>Austrian Interior Minister Gerhard Karner <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/what-we-know-so-far-about-school-shooting-in-austria-13381583?dcmp=snt-sf-twitter"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> that the suspect was a former student at the school who did not graduate. <a href="https://www.polizei.gv.at/stmk/presse/aussendungen/presse.aspx?prid=546232672F564F326D57773D&amp;pro=0"  target="_blank">Authorities also said</a> the firearms used in the attack were legally obtained and owned.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/" >Why Austria Has Some of the Most Relaxed Gun Ownership Laws in Europe</a></em></p>



<p>The suspected gunman reportedly carried a pistol and a shotgun, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/one-person-killed-attack-austrian-school-media-report-2025-06-10/"  target="_blank">opening fire in two classrooms</a> before taking his own life in a bathroom at the school.</p>



<p>Special forces were among those sent to the school after police received a phone call at 10 a.m. local time in Austria&rsquo;s second largest city. </p>



<p>Police <a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932401810628882663"  target="_blank">said</a> that students from the high school would be taken to the local ASK&Ouml; Stadium, where they can then be picked up by parents and relatives.</p>



<p>The government has declared a three-day period of national mourning. A nationwide minute of silence is scheduled for 10 a.m. local time Wednesday.</p>



<p>Tuesday&rsquo;s incident is the first significant mass shooting in Austria since November 2020, when a 20-year-old gunman <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-54798508"  target="_blank">killed four people</a> and injured 23 others. Islamic State later claimed responsibility for the attack. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292668</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Searching for Devils at CECOT</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291798/inside-cecot-photo-essay/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291798/inside-cecot-photo-essay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Holsinger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El Salvador]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exclusive photos inside the notorious prison in El Salvador]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291798"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291798/inside-cecot-photo-essay/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-10.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>To grasp why El Salvador built the Terrorism Confinement Center&mdash;the prison known as&nbsp;CECOT&mdash;you need to know about the killings that plagued the country before it existed. For more than a year, I have walked crime scenes, interviewed victims, and heard President Nayib Bukele himself describe the vicious murders perpetrated by the nation&rsquo;s gangs. In May, local investigators led me to one of the killing fields, and into a world of macabre rituals. At Mount St. Bartolo, an old farmer showed me a &ldquo;killing tree,&rdquo; its trunk scarred by machetes. &ldquo;Farmers don&rsquo;t strike trees,&rdquo; explained one of my guides, a man named Carlos. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s where a torso hung.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The ancient Amate tree leaned over a canyon like a broken metronome. In its limbs were rusty spikes where gangs once pinned human bodies in the shape of an inverted cross. As Carlos talked, I had to concentrate on the nails, counting them one by one, to keep myself from vomiting.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those nails follow me every time I enter CECOT. Built specifically to house the gang members that terrorized this country, the prison is spartan as a space station, grim as a gulag. Bukele has said no prisoner will leave the place alive, and that they will lead lives devoid of comfort. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-02.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-08.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-05.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-07.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>Module 8 is different. It holds the 238 Venezuelan men the United States deported on March 15 under an emergency order that branded them Tren de Aragua gangsters. Trump Administration officials insisted all were hardened criminals, which subsequent reporting has revealed to be untrue. </p>



<p>I have visited Module 8 three times. Each time I braced for the eerie, enforced silence that envelops CECOT. But this unit is different. The Venezuelans chant &ldquo;Liberty!&rdquo; and &ldquo;Venezuela!&rdquo; They proclaim their innocence, so loudly you can hear them from outside. They climbed the bars and waved white shirts like flags of surrender. Some pleaded for phones to call home. A few screamed curses. No guard approached to stop them. But the guards did not allow visitors to approach them either. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-01.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>Module 8 is unsettling not because it is cruel but because it is almost merciful in comparison to the rest of CECOT, and to the larger prison system of El Salvador. The detainees here have sleep pads, sheets, and pillows. They eat from an enhanced menu which sometimes includes hamburgers. They have some access to writing instruments; I saw a scrap of white sheet with a cross drawn on it. The rest of El Salvador&rsquo;s prisoners live in a world of steel and silence. </p>



<p>I have asked Salvadoran officials why they make exceptions for the foreigners. No one has offered an answer. Maybe it&rsquo;s because they know these inmates will one day be let out. Maybe it&rsquo;s because they believe these are not the same demons.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/7269604/el-salvador-photos-venezuelan-detainees/" >What the Venezuelans Deported to El Salvador Experienced. </a></em></p>



<p>During a tour of Module 8 on May 9, I searched the faces for Andry, the &ldquo;barber&rdquo; whose image ignited outrage on social media in the wake of <a href="https://time.com/7269604/el-salvador-photos-venezuelan-detainees/" >my previous reporting</a> for TIME. I thought about shouting his name, but we were forbidden to speak with the Venezuelan inmates. Their uniform crew cuts made it difficult to differentiate faces. Their fearful eyes left me afraid. I departed with only the echo of anonymous men, arms reaching through bars, begging for someone to take their number, to tell someone they were there, believing someone might come. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-09.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>I review my photographs and wince to think about what they mean. In every frame I see questions:&nbsp;<em>Who are the devils today, and who gets to decide?</em>&nbsp;El Salvador answered by pouring 236,000 square meters of concrete and steel onto the side of a volcano, to build a warehouse for the men they saw as devils. The U.S. answered by chartering three planes, exorcising their perceived foreign demons. On one side of&nbsp;CECOT, there is austere silence. On the other side, chaotic pleas. I think of the old rusting nails on a tree that once held human flesh.</p>



<p>The nails tell a story. But I&rsquo;m not sure it&rsquo;s the story of Module 8. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cecot-el-salvador-detainees-philip-holsinger-12.jpg" alt="Primary image"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291798/inside-cecot-photo-essay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291798</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greta Thunberg Deported After Aid Ship Bound for Gaza Is Intercepted by Israel</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292250/freedom-flotilla-greta-thunberg-gaza-ship-intercepted/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292250/freedom-flotilla-greta-thunberg-gaza-ship-intercepted/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 15:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swedish activist deported after Israeli military intercepts humanitarian aid ship Madleen en route to Gaza.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292250"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292250/freedom-flotilla-greta-thunberg-gaza-ship-intercepted/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/freedom-flotilla-greta-thunberg-june1.jpg" alt="'Freedom Flotilla' And Greta Thunberg Prepare To Depart Italy For Gaza"/>



<p><a href="https://time.com/person-of-the-year-2019-greta-thunberg/" >Greta Thunberg</a> has been deported from Israel after the humanitarian aid ship she was aboard was intercepted by the Israeli military and towed to the port city of Ashdod.</p>



<p>The Swedish climate activist was among <a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/2025/06/01/a-month-after-conscience-attack-freedom-flotilla-ship-madleen-sets-sail-for-gaza/"  target="_blank">a 12-person crew</a> on board the Madleen, a vessel organized by the Freedom Flotilla Coalition (FFC), which was carrying aid including rice, flour, and baby formula to Gaza. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Thunberg had joined the mission to draw attention to the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, saying: &ldquo;Every single one of us has a moral obligation to do everything we can to fight for a free Palestine.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s Foreign Ministry <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMFA/status/1932337642886021543"  target="_blank">confirmed Tuesday</a> that Thunberg had boarded a flight to Sweden, via France. The remaining crew members are also being deported, the ministry said, with some refusing to sign documents and expected to face a judicial process before being sent to their home countries.</p>



<p>The Madleen was <a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/2025/06/09/israeli-military-attacks-madleen-in-international-waters-weeks-after-bombing-of-conscience/"  target="_blank">intercepted in international waters</a> shortly after 3 a.m. local time on Monday, June 9, according to FFC, a group that describes itself as a <a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/who-we-are/"  target="_blank">&ldquo;grassroots solidarity movement&rdquo; </a>working to end Israel&rsquo;s blockade of Gaza. </p>



<p>The organization <a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/2025/06/09/israeli-military-attacks-madleen-in-international-waters-weeks-after-bombing-of-conscience/"  target="_blank">said the seizure</a> of the vessel violates international law and defies the International Court of Justice&rsquo;s binding orders requiring unimpeded humanitarian access to Gaza.</p>



<p>Footage <a href="https://x.com/GazaFFlotilla/status/1931872075653980567"  target="_blank">released</a> by the FFC appeared to show Israeli personnel intercepting the boat. In the video, the crew have their hands raised, and a person is heard saying &ldquo;everyone, phones need to go, in the water.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Israel has dismissed the vessel as a &ldquo;selfie yacht&rdquo; and said the &ldquo;tiny amount&rdquo; of aid aboard would be distributed in Gaza. The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) said it had acted in accordance with international law to enforce the naval blockade on Gaza. </p>



<p>&ldquo;The vessel Madleen attempted to breach the naval blockade lawfully imposed for security reasons,&rdquo; the IDF said in a statement to TIME, adding that the flotilla had &ldquo;repeatedly refused&rdquo; offers to offload the aid for distribution through official channels.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/IsraelMFA/status/1932151038699508006"  target="_blank">In a post on X</a>, the government confirmed the ship&#8217;s crew <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMFA/status/1932066660984254888"  target="_blank">would be returned safely</a> to their home countries and reiterated that 1,200 aid trucks have entered Gaza over the last weeks. It also pointed to the U.S. and Israel-backed Gaza Humanitarian Foundation (GHF), which it said had distributed 11 million meals in the territory since it began operations on May 26.</p>



<p>The GHF has faced sharp criticism from <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2025/05/1163071"  target="_blank">the United Nations</a> and other aid organizations, which have accused it of &ldquo;weaponizing aid&rdquo;. Concerns over its operations have intensified following multiple fatal shootings of <a href="https://time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/" >Palestinians</a> near distribution hubs. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/" ><em>How Closures at Food Distribution Hubs Are Impacting Gazans</em></a></p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what we know about the ship and the status of its crew.</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=jZn8udus vertical]</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why was the Madleen heading to Gaza?</strong></h2>



<p>The ship, named after Gaza&rsquo;s <a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/2025/06/01/a-month-after-conscience-attack-freedom-flotilla-ship-madleen-sets-sail-for-gaza/"  target="_blank">first and only fisherwoman</a> according to FFC, was launched from Sicily, Italy on June 1.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ship was carrying aid to Gaza, estimated to not be much more than a truck&#8217;s-worth, but FFC <a href="https://x.com/GazaFFlotilla/status/1927858617052487810"  target="_blank">said that the mission</a> was to raise awareness of the humanitarian situation in Gaza. </p>



<p>This campaign comes a month after another FFC ship, named &ldquo;Conscience&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/GazaFFlotilla/status/1918131538794864916"  target="_blank">was struck by drones </a>and set on fire as a result of the attack while sailing in international waters.</p>



<p>Before the Israel-Hamas war, <a href="https://www.unicef.org/mena/documents/gaza-strip-humanitarian-impact-15-years-blockade-june-2022"  target="_blank">Israel still maintained control</a> over what goods entered Gaza, as well as water and electricity supplies in the strip. This began after Hamas gained control over the strip in 2007. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who was onboard the Madleen?</strong></h2>



<p>The 12-person crew included: </p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://time.com/person-of-the-year-2019-greta-thunberg/" ></a><a href="https://time.com/person-of-the-year-2019-greta-thunberg/" >Greta Thunberg</a>, Swedish climate activist. </li>



<li><a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/meps/en/256912/RIMA_HASSAN/home"  target="_blank">Rima Hassan</a>, a French Member of the European Parliament.</li>



<li><a href="https://freedomflotilla.org/2024/08/17/thiago-avila-brazil/"  target="_blank">Thiago Avila</a>, who leads FFC Brazil and is on the organization&#8217;s Steering Committee.</li>



<li>Baptiste Andr&eacute;, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/omarfaiad/"  target="_blank">Omar Faiad</a>, Pascal Maurieras, <a href="https://x.com/yanmdi?lang=en"  target="_blank">Yanis Mhamdi</a>, and Reva Viard, all French nationals. Mhamdi is a journalist for Blast; Faiad is a journalist with Al Jazeera.</li>



<li><a href="https://refugeworldwide.com/artists/yasmin-acar"  target="_blank">Yasemin Acar</a>, an activist from Germany.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.instagram.com/suayb_ordu/"  target="_blank">&#350;uayb Ordu</a>, an activist from Turkey.</li>



<li><a href="https://x.com/MacroPsychoKine/status/1931884186270375984"  target="_blank">Sergio Toribio</a>, an activist from Spain.</li>



<li><a href="https://x.com/ProtectPal/status/1930331991389679978"  target="_blank">Marco Van Rennes</a>, an activist from the Netherlands.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What has Israel said about the ship and its interception?</strong></h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMFA/status/1931877539871338775"  target="_blank">statement posted Monday,</a> the Israeli Foreign Ministry confirmed that it had intercepted the &ldquo;selfie yacht&rdquo; and that the &ldquo;celebrities&rdquo; on board would be returned to their home countries.</p>



<p>The Ministry <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMFA/status/1931885257604645074"  target="_blank">also published a video</a> of the crew being handed water and sandwiches, saying they were safe and unharmed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Defense Minister Israel Katz said he had instructed the IDF to show the crew a video of events on October 7 2023, when Hamas militants killed more than 1,200 people and took another 250 hostage.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What international reaction has there been?</strong></h2>



<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/clyg5x15n3zt?post=asset%3Ae2a53c75-4c43-49ea-be1b-fcf347982b93#post"  target="_blank">has said</a> that France has offered to assist in facilitating the &ldquo;swift return&rdquo; of the French nationals onboard the ship.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/clyg5x15n3zt?post=asset%3A39aefbf9-5191-426e-be1c-f6a5a9501fb5#post"  target="_blank">In a press briefing Monday</a>, a spokesperson for British Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer said that the U.K. government urged the situation to be resolved &ldquo;safely with restraint, in line with international humanitarian law&rdquo;.</p>



<p>Special Rapporteur to the United Nations, <a href="https://x.com/FranceskAlbs/status/1931884302880346302"  target="_blank">Francesca Albanese said</a>: &ldquo;As the Madleen was reportedly intercepted and seized by Israeli forces in international waters, the UK government must urgently seek full clarification and secure the immediate release of the vessel &amp; its crew.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In a post on social media, Albanese continued: &ldquo;The Madleen must be allowed to continue its lawful humanitarian mission to Gaza.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/amnesty/status/1932048637665685742"  target="_blank">Amnesty International</a> said that Israel&rsquo;s interception of the ship ignores its &#8220;legal obligations towards civilians in the occupied Gaza Strip.&rdquo; </p>



<p>&ldquo;As the occupying power Israel has an international obligation to ensure civilians in Gaza have sufficient and safe access to food, medicine, and other supplies indispensable to their survival,&rdquo; the <a href="https://x.com/amnesty/status/1932048637665685742"  target="_blank">human rights organization said</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292250/freedom-flotilla-greta-thunberg-gaza-ship-intercepted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Latest U.S.-China Talks Yield Unspecified ‘Framework’: A Timeline of the Trade War So Far</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are all the tariffs, counter-tariffs, dealmaking, and deal-breaking between the world’s two biggest economies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292207"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/us-china-trade-war-counter-tariffs.jpg" alt="concept photo for China-USA trade war conflict"/>



<p>After months of turmoil since U.S. President Donald Trump reignited his trade war with China upon his return to the White House, representatives from the world&rsquo;s two biggest economies said they&rsquo;ve made progress toward a renewed truce as they work to resolve their differences, which may bring some calm to global markets and supply chains.</p>



<p>Following two days of &ldquo;in depth and candid&rdquo; talks in London, the two sides have &ldquo;agreed in principle&rdquo; to a framework for &ldquo;implementing the consensus&rdquo; between Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping during their <a href="https://time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation" >much-anticipated</a> direct<a href="https://time.com/7291416/trump-and-xi-have-first-call-in-months/" > call</a> on June 5 as well as previous talks between their delegations in Geneva, <a href="https://x.com/ChineseEmbinUS/status/1932636893457358923"  target="_blank">said</a> Li Chenggang, China international trade representative with the Ministry of Commerce, in London on Tuesday, June 10.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;The two largest economies in the world have reached a handshake for a framework,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2025-06-11/us-china-agree-on-framework-to-implement-geneva-deal-video"  target="_blank">said</a> U.S. Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to start to implement that framework upon the approval of President Trump, and the Chinese will get their President Xi&rsquo;s approval, and that&rsquo;s the process.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Lutnick recognized that the two countries have &ldquo;lots of complex issues&rdquo; but said they &ldquo;pounded through all of them.&rdquo; He called the framework agreement &ldquo;the first step&rdquo; toward building a trade relationship that is &ldquo;beneficial to both&rdquo; sides: &ldquo;First we had to get sort of the negativity out, and now we can go forward to try to do positive trade.&rdquo;</p>



<p>While it&rsquo;s not yet clear where things could go next, it may be valuable to take stock of how we got here.</p>



<p>Through tariffs and counter-tariffs, dealmaking and deal-breaking, here&rsquo;s a timeline of the U.S. and China&rsquo;s tumultuous trade relations since the start of Trump&rsquo;s second term.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">February 1</h3>



<p>Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/imposing-duties-to-address-the-synthetic-opioid-supply-chain-in-the-peoples-republic-of-china/"  target="_blank">signed</a> an executive order increasing tariffs on imported goods from China by 10%, to take effect on Feb. 4. The order aimed to curb the import of fentanyl into the country. Tariffs of 25% were imposed on Canada and Mexico for similar reasons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The order also ended the <a href="https://time.com/6695469/temu-shein-de-minimis/" ><em>de minimis </em>exemption</a> for Chinese goods, whereby small items valued at $800 or less and shipped directly to U.S. consumers were exempted from customs declarations and duties. The Trump Administration argued that the rule contributed to the entry of fentanyl and illegal drugs into the U.S.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">February 4</h3>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Finance <a href="https://www.mof.gov.cn/zhengwuxinxi/caizhengxinwen/202502/t20250204_3955222.htm"  target="_blank">announced</a> it would impose, effective Feb. 10, a 15% tariff on coal and liquefied natural gas as well as a 10% tariff on crude oil, agricultural machinery, large-displacement cars, and pickup trucks.</p>



<p>The same day, China&rsquo;s Commerce Ministry <a href="https://www.mofcom.gov.cn/zwgk/zcfb/art/2025/art_e623090907fc4e1092f0a4db72f57b95.html"  target="_blank">announced</a> export controls on a number of rare-earth minerals, including bismuth, indium, molybdenum, tungsten, and tellurium items that can be used in various industries like electronics or munitions manufacturing, saying there was a need &ldquo;to safeguard national security and interests and fulfill international obligations such as non-proliferation.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">February 5</h3>



<p>In an amendment to his previous order, Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/amendment-to-duties-addressing-the-synthetic-opioid-supply-chain-in-the-peoples-republic-of-china/"  target="_blank">said</a> that eligible packages will have <em>de minimis</em> exemptions until &ldquo;adequate systems are in place to fully and expediently process and collect tariff revenue.&rdquo;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">February 10</h3>



<p>Trump issued a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/adjusting-imports-of-steel-into-the-united-states/"  target="_blank">proclamation</a> announcing <em>ad valorem</em> tariffs on steel imports. Aluminum imports are also increased from 10% to 25%. In the proclamation, Trump said exports of steel from China have increased, &ldquo;displacing production in other countries and forcing them to export greater volumes of steel articles and derivative steel articles to the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">February 27</h3>



<p>Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/america-first-investment-policy/"  target="_blank">signed</a> a memorandum directing the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) to restrict investors with links to China from investing in U.S. technology, critical infrastructure, healthcare, agriculture, energy, raw materials, and other strategic sectors.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">March 3</h3>



<p>Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/further-amendment-to-duties-addressing-the-synthetic-opioid-supply-chain-in-the-peoples-republic-of-china/"  target="_blank">raised</a> tariffs on Chinese goods to 20%.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">March 4</h3>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Finance <a href="https://gss.mof.gov.cn/gzdt/zhengcefabu/202503/t20250304_3959228.htm"  target="_blank">responded</a> with a 15% tariff on chicken, wheat, corn and cotton, and a 10% tariff on sorghum, soybeans, pork, beef, aquatic products, fruits, vegetables, and dairy products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Commerce <a href="https://www.mofcom.gov.cn/syxwfb/art/2025/art_77034b7776ad43dda542bd6af0c77e0d.html"  target="_blank">also</a> sued the U.S. over the March 3 tariffs through the World Trade Organization&rsquo;s dispute settlement mechanism.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7272434/trump-trade-war-us-tariffs-china-yiwu-market/" ><em>Viewing Trump&rsquo;s Trade War From the World&rsquo;s Shopping Mall in China</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">April 2</h3>



<p>Trump unveiled his &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7274195/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-world-responses-china-eu-countries-leaders-countermeasures/" >Liberation Day</a>&rdquo; universal tariffs, which included an additional 34% tariff on Chinese goods on top of the existing 20% tariff rate, bringing the total tariff on Chinese goods to 54%.</p>



<p>He also signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/04/further-amendment-to-duties-addressing-the-synthetic-opioid-supply-chain-in-the-peoples-republic-of-china-as-applied-to-low-value-imports/"  target="_blank">executive order</a> once again ending the <em>de minimis</em> exemption for packages from mainland China and Hong Kong, saying the previously absent &ldquo;adequate systems&rdquo; to process and collect tariff revenue for affected parcels were &ldquo;now in place.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">April 4</h3>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Finance <a href="https://gss.mof.gov.cn/gzdt/zhengcefabu/202504/t20250404_3961451.htm"  target="_blank">retaliated</a> with a 34% tariff on all imports from the U.S, starting April 10.</p>



<p>On the same day, China&rsquo;s Ministry of Commerce <a href="https://aqygzj.mofcom.gov.cn/flzc/gzjgfxwj/art/2025/art_f3a1432ba20248eca12ff7b91bc73fda.html"  target="_blank">announced</a> that it would require companies to apply for a license before exporting seven types of rare earths: samarium, gadolinium, terbium, dysprosium, lutetium, scandium and yttrium.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7277920/china-manufacturing-us-trump-factory-workers-ai-videos-social-media/" ><em>Why China Laughs at the Idea of Americans Taking Their Manufacturing Jobs</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">April 8</h3>



<p>Following up on an <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114297331052690348"  target="_blank">earlier threat</a> to escalate tit-for-tat tariffs, Trump issued an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/04/amendment-to-recipricol-tariffs-and-updated-duties-as-applied-to-low-value-imports-from-the-peoples-republic-of-china/"  target="_blank">executive order</a> effectively raising the tariffs on imported goods from China to 104%.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">April 9</h3>



<p>China again <a href="https://gss.mof.gov.cn/gzdt/zhengcefabu/202504/t20250409_3961684.htm"  target="_blank">hiked</a> its tariffs on U.S. imports from 34% to 84%.</p>



<p>Hours later, Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114309144289505174"  target="_blank">responded</a> to China&rsquo;s latest hike on Truth Social, saying: &ldquo;Based on the lack of respect that China has shown to the World&rsquo;s Markets, I am hereby raising the Tariff charged to China by the United States of America to 125%, effective immediately.&rdquo; This <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/04/modifying-reciprocal-tariff-rates-to-reflect-trading-partner-retaliation-and-alignment/"  target="_blank">brought</a> the total tariff rate on China&rsquo;s exports to the U.S. to 145%.</p>



<p>In the same post, Trump also announced a 90-day reduction of his universal tariffs on other countries to 10%.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7276293/trump-tariffs-reversal-world-leaders-countries-responses-uncertainty-trade-war/" ><em>&lsquo;Nothing Is Certain but Uncertainty&rsquo;: How the World Is Reacting to Trump&rsquo;s Tariff Reversal</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">April 11</h3>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Finance <a href="https://gss.mof.gov.cn/gzdt/zhengcefabu/202504/t20250411_3961823.htm"  target="_blank">adjusted</a> its tariff rate against U.S. exports to 125% but said: &ldquo;If the U.S. continues to impose tariffs on Chinese goods exported to the U.S., China will ignore it.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump, in an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/04/clarification-of-exceptions-under-executive-order-14257-of-april-2-2025-as-amended/"  target="_blank">executive order</a>, said the U.S. was removing reciprocal tariffs on a range of electronics products and parts, including from China. Electronics from China, however, remained subject to the 20% tariff on Chinese goods.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">May 12</h3>



<p>Chinese and U.S. officials, in a <a href="https://time.com/7284765/us-china-trade-war-pause/" >meeting in Geneva</a>, came to an agreement to temporarily reduce reciprocal tariffs by 115% starting May 14. The effective tariff rate on Chinese imports was reduced to 30%, while the Chinese tariff rate on American goods was reduced to 10%. The deal also included a 90-day pause on other trade barriers and <a href="https://time.com/7285316/us-china-trump-tariff-rates-de-minimis-low-value-imports/" >another amendment to the <em>de minimis</em> rules</a> for low-value shipments from China.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7286933/trump-trade-war-us-china-tariff-pause-businesses-costs-uncertainty/" ><em>How Trump&rsquo;s Tariff Unpredictability Hurts Businesses and Consumers&mdash;and Could Help China</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">May 28</h3>



<p>The U.S. Court of International Trade in New York <a href="https://time.com/7289394/trump-tariffs-uscit-court-international-trade-ruling-appeal-reactions-explainer/" >ruled</a> that Trump did not have the authority to impose sweeping tariffs, including some imposed on China. The Trump Administration swiftly appealed the ruling.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">May 30</h3>



<p>Trump accused China of reneging on the deal made in Geneva, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114596705340367716"  target="_blank">posting</a> on Truth Social: &ldquo;I made a FAST DEAL with China in order to save them from what I thought was going to be a very bad situation, and I didn&rsquo;t want to see that happen. Because of this deal, everything quickly stabilized and China got back to business as usual. Everybody was happy! That is the good news!!! The bad news is that China, perhaps not surprisingly to some, HAS TOTALLY VIOLATED ITS AGREEMENT WITH US. So much for being Mr. NICE GUY!&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump Administration officials <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/scott-bessent-treasury-secretary-face-the-nation-06-01-2025/"  target="_blank">would later reveal</a> that China did not ease its restrictions on rare earth exports as was supposedly a part of the deal.</p>



<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7275818/rare-earth-china-tariffs-metals-minerals/" ><em>How Rare Earths Are Playing a Pivotal Role in the U.S.-China Trade War</em></a></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">June 2</h3>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Commerce <a href="https://www.mofcom.gov.cn/xwfb/xwfyrth/art/2025/art_6b2d4a2b91644a8ca0284867769a9713.html"  target="_blank">reacted</a> to accusations that it went back on its word. &ldquo;After the Geneva economic and trade talks, the United States has successively introduced a number of discriminatory restrictive measures against China, including issuing export control guidelines for AI chips, stopping the sale of chip design software (EDA) to China, and announcing the revocation of Chinese student visas,&rdquo; a spokesperson said. &ldquo;These practices seriously violate the consensus reached by the two heads of state on January 17, seriously undermine the existing consensus of the Geneva economic and trade talks, and seriously damage China&#8217;s legitimate rights and interests.&rdquo;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">June 5</h3>



<p>Trump and Xi held their first phone call in months. According <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114631295762726849"  target="_blank">to Trump</a>, the call lasted for around 90 minutes, where they discussed &ldquo;some of the intricacies of our recently made, and agreed to, Trade Deal.&rdquo;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">June 6</h3>



<p>Trump<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114637838750311907"  target="_blank"> announced</a> on Truth Social that Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick, and United States Trade Representative Jamieson Greer will represent the U.S. in trade talks in London beginning June 9. &ldquo;The meeting should go very well,&rdquo; Trump posted.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">June 10</h3>



<p>U.S. and Chinese negotiators announced that they reached a framework to implement a trade truce. Details of the deal have not been disclosed, though U.S. negotiators said they &ldquo;absolutely expect&rdquo; that issues surrounding critical minerals and magnets will be resolved.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">June 11</h2>



<p>Trump on Wednesday, June 11, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114664632971715644"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social: &ldquo;OUR DEAL WITH CHINA IS DONE, SUBJECT TO FINAL APPROVAL WITH PRESIDENT XI AND ME. FULL MAGNETS, AND ANY NECESSARY RARE EARTHS, WILL BE SUPPLIED, UP FRONT, BY CHINA. LIKEWISE, WE WILL PROVIDE TO CHINA WHAT WAS AGREED TO, INCLUDING CHINESE STUDENTS USING OUR COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES (WHICH HAS ALWAYS BEEN GOOD WITH ME!). WE ARE GETTING A TOTAL OF 55% TARIFFS, CHINA IS GETTING 10%. RELATIONSHIP IS EXCELLENT! THANK YOU FOR YOUR ATTENTION TO THIS MATTER!&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/7289945/us-china-trump-rubio-international-student-visa-restrictions-trade-negotiations/" >How Trump&rsquo;s Crackdown on International Students Could Escalate Trade Tensions With China</a></em></p>



<p>He <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114664867178522750"  target="_blank">added</a>: &ldquo;President XI and I are going to work closely together to open up China to American Trade. This would be a great WIN for both countries!!!&rdquo;</p>



<p>JL MAG Rare-Earth, a Chinese rare earths magnet producer, announced the same day that it had received export licenses for rare earths products to the U.S., Europe, and Southeast Asia, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/jl-mag-rare-earth-says-it-obtained-export-licenses-rare-earth-products-us-europe-2025-06-11/"  target="_blank">Reuters reported</a>. The company shared the news soon after U.S. and Chinese negotiators reached the framework agreement, though the company didn&rsquo;t reveal when the licenses were granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292207</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
