<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 20:04:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>European Leaders Seek Diplomacy in Talks With Iran as Trump Weighs Strike</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 18:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European ministers met with an Iranian delegation in Geneva in hopes of reaching an agreement over the conflict between Israel and Iran.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296249"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/abbas-araghchi-un-speech-june20.jpg" alt="Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi News Conference"/>



<p>Officials from Europe met with their Iranian counterparts on Friday in hopes of reaching a diplomatic solution to the <a href="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" >ongoing conflict between Iran and Israel</a>, even as attacks continued.</p>



<p>U.K. <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4ve5mo001g3b6ncvzid95c"  target="_blank">Foreign Secretary David Lammy</a> said ahead of the meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, that a &ldquo;window now exists&rdquo; to end the crisis.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>After the talks concluded with no apparent breakthrough, Lammy <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/20/world/israel-iran-trump"  target="_blank">said</a> European ministers were &ldquo;keen to continue ongoing discussions and negotiations with Iran,&rdquo; and urged the country to continue talks with the U.S.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is a perilous moment,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;and it is hugely important that we don&rsquo;t see regional escalation of this conflict.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Lammy, French Foreign Minister Jean-No&euml;l Barrot, German Foreign Minister Johann Wadephul, and High Representative of the European Union Kaja Kallas said in a joint <a href="https://www.eeas.europa.eu/eeas/statement-ministers-foreign-affairs-france-germany-and-united-kingdom-together-high-representative-0_en"  target="_blank">statement</a> that they had &ldquo;reiterated their longstanding concerns&rdquo; about Iran&#8217;s nuclear program to their Iranian counterpart and &ldquo;discussed avenues towards a negotiated solution.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The good result today is that we leave the room with the impression that the Iranian side is ready to further discuss all the important questions,&rdquo; Wadephul <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250620-europe-powers-urge-iran-to-keep-up-diplomacy-despite-israeli-strikes"  target="_blank">said</a>. He stressed that the U.S. taking part in negotiations &ldquo;is of great importance.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2025/6/20/live-iran-israel-continue-missile-fire-irans-fm-to-meet-eu-counterparts"  target="_blank">told reporters</a> after the talks that &ldquo;Iran is ready to consider diplomacy once again&mdash;once the aggression is stopped and the aggressor is held accountable for the crimes committed.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Added uncertainty was cast on the possibility of reaching an agreement on Friday when Iran launched a fresh barrage of missile strikes on targets in <a href="https://mdauk.org/mda-on-highest-level-of-alert-june-2025/"  target="_blank">the south of Israel</a>, and on the <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4tecad000r3b6nlmk588i8"  target="_blank">northern city of Haifa</a>.</p>



<p>The attacks came after the Israel Defense Forces <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1935946673454268771"  target="_blank">said that it struck</a> a number of military targets in Iran overnight, including facilities used for missile manufacturing. The Israeli military says it has now destroyed around <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc50rnyk001g3b6ok4msle8a"  target="_blank">half of Iran&rsquo;s missile launchers</a>, as well as killing <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >a number of military personnel</a> since last week.</p>



<p>President Donald Trump has also been weighing whether to launch a military strike on Iran. He is <a href="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" >expected to make a decision</a> within two weeks, Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt said on Thursday, reading a statement from Trump in which the President said &ldquo;there&rsquo;s a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not take place with Iran in the near future.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S. and Iran have been engaged in protracted talks over a possible nuclear deal for the past two months, but a scheduled round of negotiations was cancelled after Israeli strikes began. &ldquo;There is no room for negotiations with the U.S. until Israeli aggression stops,&rdquo; Araghchi <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2025/06/20/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-nuclear-talks-live-updates/84283929007/"  target="_blank">reportedly said</a> while speaking on Iranian state TV earlier on Friday. </p>



<p>Before negotiations in Geneva began, French President Emmanuel Macron said while talking to reporters in Paris that &ldquo;Iran must show that it is willing to join the platform for negotiations we are putting on the table.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/c994v4gm9jmt?post=asset%3A2acb7df0-7d65-48c4-b9e4-9d4810afc294#post"  target="_blank">Macron outlined</a> particular focus points of the discussions, which included working towards zero uranium enrichment in Iran, the oversight of Iranian ballistic missiles, Iranian funding of proxy groups in the Middle East, and the release of foreign nationals in Iranian prisons.</p>



<p>As negotiations took place, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4tmjm900003b6o4kycyba9"  target="_blank">a spokesperson for Iran&rsquo;s Presidency</a> said: &ldquo;Iran believes in civilian dialogue &hellip; Directly or indirectly is not important.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The spokesperson, Majid Farahani, added: &ldquo;President Trump can easily stop the war by only one telephone [call] to [the] Israelis.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Macron and Trump exchanged barbs earlier in the week after Trump departed the G7 summit early as the conflict between Iran and Israel mounted.</p>



<p>Trump called the French President &ldquo;publicity seeking&rdquo; after Macron <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/world/europe/trump-macron-israel-iran-ukraine.html"  target="_blank">told press</a> that the U.S. had assured &ldquo;they will find a cease-fire, and since they can pressure Israel, things may change.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;President Emmanuel Macron, of France, mistakenly said that I left the G7 Summit, in Canada, to go back to D.C. to work on a &lsquo;cease fire&rsquo; between Israel and Iran,&rdquo; Trump said in a post on Truth Social. &ldquo;Wrong! He has no idea why I am now on my way to Washington, but it certainly has nothing to do with a Cease Fire. Much bigger than that.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s latest stance on direct U.S. involvement comes after <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >some uncertainty earlier this week</a>, during which the President said: &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&rdquo; when asked if he was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Iranian Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935303824325108208"  target="_blank">warned</a> on Wednesday that &ldquo;the harm the US will suffer will definitely be irreparable if they enter this conflict militarily.&rdquo;</p>



<p>European officials began talks with Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi at around 4 p.m. local time (11 a.m. ET) on Friday. Before talks began, Araghchi addressed the United Nations Security Council, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/c994v4gm9jmt?post=asset%3A748632d5-7c1b-417e-abf2-ba850e2c8108#post"  target="_blank">calling</a> last week&rsquo;s initial attack from Israel as &#8220;an outrageous act of aggression&#8221; and a &#8220;stark violation of the U.N. charter&#8221; in his remarks.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s Ambassador to the U.N. Daniel Meron <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-slams-un-rights-council-giving-floor-iran-ahead-nuclear-talks-2025-06-20/"  target="_blank">criticized the body</a> for allowing Araghchi the floor at the meeting, saying in a letter addressed to council president Jurg Lauber, &#8220;Affording the Iranian foreign minister the floor before this body continues to undermine the council&#8217;s credibility and constitutes a blatant betrayal of the many victims of this regime worldwide.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israeli foreign minister Gideon Sa&rsquo;ar was dismissive of the talks in Geneva in an interview on Friday. &ldquo;All diplomatic efforts until now were not successful,&rdquo; he <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/israel-rejects-diplomacy-iran-europeans-tehran-geneva-gideon-saar-middle-east-donald-trump-eu/"  target="_blank">said</a>. &ldquo;They usually use these talks in order to deceive, in order to waste time.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296249</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TIME Is Looking for the World’s Top Universities</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296211/worlds-top-universities-search/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296211/worlds-top-universities-search/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TIME Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 16:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the first time, TIME will publish a ranking of the World&#8217;s Top Universities, in partnership with Statista, a leading international provider of market and consumer data and rankings. This new list will recognize the world&#8217;s leading higher education institutions based on academic performance, student outcomes, and the institutional learning environment. As part of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296211"></div></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/international-students-trump.jpg" alt="Cornell University As Ivy League Prices Push $90,000 A Year"/>



<p>For the first time, TIME will publish a ranking of the World&rsquo;s Top Universities, in partnership with Statista, a leading international provider of market and consumer data and rankings. This new list will recognize the world&rsquo;s leading higher education institutions based on academic performance, student outcomes, and the institutional learning environment.</p>



<p>As part of the research phase, TIME and Statista are now accepting data submissions. While submitting data ensures that eligible institutions will be considered for inclusion, it does not guarantee a place on the final list. Additionally, the final ranking will not be limited to institutions that submit data.</p>



<p>The deadline for submissions is July 18, 2025.</p>



<p>To apply, click <a href="http://research.statista.com/?i_survey=19__d187dd15f96404fcf1c354e0acdace92"  target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



<p>More information visit:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statista.com/page/worlds-top-universities"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">https://www.statista.com/page/worlds-top-universities</a>. Winners will be announced on TIME.com in early 2026.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296211/worlds-top-universities-search/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Man Who Wants to Save NATO</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295448/rutte-nato-secretary-general-interview/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295448/rutte-nato-secretary-general-interview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Rasmi/Brussels]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magazine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Secretary-General Mark Rutte is getting allies to spend trillions more on defense—and keep Donald Trump on side.  ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295448"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295448/rutte-nato-secretary-general-interview/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/rutte-nato-interview-003.jpg" alt="NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte speaks to the press at NATO headquarters ahead of a meeting of the defense ministers of the 32 NATO countries, in Brussels, Belgium."/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 20, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the U.S. and Iran, a profile of the man who wants to save NATO, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>53b7290a-77fc-4225-b6d9-d816006c0d94</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>2774c911-50f2-4fc1-bc73-9a8d0f4d6e6d</code></p></div>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte keeps a variety of mementos in his office. There is a sprawling photograph of the North Sea from the vantage point of his hometown in the Netherlands, a kanji gift from Japan&rsquo;s Minister of Defense, and a framed floral embroidery that reads &ldquo;In Unity is Strength&rdquo; in Cyrillic with the stitched flags of NATO, Ukraine, and the E.U. But the room&rsquo;s largest ornamental feature is the blue-and-white map of the world that looms above his conference desk. &ldquo;In the past, I was responsible for this,&rdquo; the <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2023/07/10/europe/rutte-netherlands-resignation-government-collapse-intl"  target="_blank">former Dutch Prime Minister</a> says, pointing to his tiny home country in the northwestern corner of Europe. He extends his arms out to encircle the entire Western defense alliance that is home to 1 billion people. &ldquo;And now &#8230;&rdquo; he says, with a wry laugh.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s a glimpse of the storms roiling beneath the optimism of the preternaturally cheerful Rutte. We are in the steel and glass NATO HQ on the outskirts of Brussels, <a href="https://apnews.com/general-news-bb033955958f49ca9de58858b4fdc5b0"  target="_blank">completed eight years ago</a> at a cost of $1.3 billion, its interlocking buildings meant to evoke fingers clasped together in unity. But on this balmy May afternoon, five weeks before a critical summit with the mercurial <a href="https://time.com/7200212/person-of-the-year-2024-donald-trump/" >U.S. President Donald Trump</a> and dozens of other leaders, the question of unity hangs over the alliance. &ldquo;It is really a pivotal moment,&rdquo; Rutte says, after we sit down in his office, some six short months after he became Secretary-General in October. </p>



<p>&ldquo;Pivotal&rdquo; may be an understatement. Trump has repeatedly said, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/mar/07/donald-trump-nato-alliance-us-security-support"  target="_blank">most recently in March</a>, that he&rsquo;s &ldquo;not going to defend&rdquo; NATO allies that don&rsquo;t spend enough on their militaries, a <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2017/05/trump-declines-to-affirm-natos-article-5/528129/"  target="_blank">threat</a> to the mutual defense commitment at the heart of the alliance. Europeans, awakened to the danger of American inconstancy, are scrambling to spend <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/03/06/nato-5-percent-defense-spending-trump-russia-ukraine/"  target="_blank">trillions more</a> on defense in coming years. All the while, Russia&rsquo;s assault on Ukraine grows deadlier by the month, and <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/freezing-ukraine-war-would-allow-russia-threaten-nato-latvian-intelligence-warns-donald-trump-peace-talks/"  target="_blank">intelligence</a> from the <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/international/article/2025/03/07/what-baltic-intelligence-agencies-say-about-the-risks-of-peace-talks-with-russia_6738924_4.html"  target="_blank">Baltic states</a>, <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/russia-war-threat-europe-within-5-years-danish-intelligence-ddis-warns/"  target="_blank">Denmark</a>, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-has-plans-test-natos-resolve-german-intelligence-chief-warns-2025-06-09/"  target="_blank">Germany</a> suggests Moscow could rebuild its armed forces and attack NATO members Estonia, Latvia, or Lithuania within a few years.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/rutte-nato-interview-004.jpg" alt="Rutte, center, and Zelensky, right, visited a military hospital in Odesa, Ukraine, on April 15" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Rutte, 58, brings an idiosyncratic mix of experience and personality to the job of saving the alliance. An amateur concert pianist and part-time high school social-studies teacher, the center-right politician was the longest-serving Dutch Prime Minister in history. In that role, he developed a talent for working with people from across the political spectrum in the Netherlands, Europe, and the U.S. He even gained a reputation as something of a Trump whisperer. </p>



<p>Rutte has used those skills while shuttling between European capitals and Washington, D.C., to push for a new <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/donald-trump-5-percent-defense-spending-target-far-fetched-nato/"  target="_blank">defense-spending target of 5% of GDP</a> for NATO members. The goal, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/nato-capability-targets-plans-defense-spending-trump-b123977c8f3c1bce277fb1b9957b1b78"  target="_blank">set by</a> the Trump Administration, is a stretch: about a quarter of the allies last year failed to reach the current target of 2%.</p>



<p>Lurking behind the numbers are hard questions about what European and Canadian allies are capable of on the battlefield. For decades, NATO has depended on the U.S. for mobile land forces, air defense, long-range weapons systems, and the biggest security shield of all&mdash;the nuclear &ldquo;umbrella&rdquo; over the continent. &ldquo;[NATO] doesn&rsquo;t work without the nuclear umbrella and all the strategic leadership and strategic force capabilities that the U.S. brings,&rdquo; says General Gordon B. Davis Jr. (ret.), a senior fellow at the Center for European Policy Analysis and former top NATO official.</p>



<p>The position of Secretary-General is mainly a diplomatic one, with no direct military authority. But Rutte, a workaholic bachelor with no photos of loved ones in his office, seems to be <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/crljpwnr220o"  target="_blank">marshaling member states</a> to meet the moment. His most immediate task is ensuring allies rally around the spending push during the June 24&ndash;25 NATO summit in his hometown of the Hague, and in that he is optimistic. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m really pretty confident that it will be a splash,&rdquo; Rutte says. &ldquo;I see Europeans stepping up.&rdquo;</p>



<p>And after that? In its first half century, NATO preserved democracy in postwar Europe, helped defeat the Soviet Union, and served as a synonym for &ldquo;the West.&rdquo; Once Rutte finishes sorting out the books, there awaits the challenge of making sure the alliance remains united and durable for the years to come.</p>



<hr/>



<p><strong>Rutte has trained</strong> his eyes on the spending target ever since Trump <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/23/can-trump-get-nato-allies-to-spend-more-on-defense.html"  target="_blank">first floated it in January</a>. He is keeping up the push in the weeks before the summit. Two days after his TIME interview, Rutte strolls up to a black Mercedes, arm extended, to greet Czech President Petr Pavel as he steps out of the vehicle, brown leather bag in hand. &ldquo;Welcome back,&rdquo; Rutte smiles, guiding the stoic Pavel, a retired army general and former chairman of the NATO Military Committee, toward the headquarters building. The two men sit down for a closed-door meeting, and afterward, Pavel is direct about his nation&rsquo;s spending commitment. &ldquo;If the discussion in the Hague leads us to a general agreement that we need to spend up to 5%, Czech Republic is ready to support it,&rdquo; he says at the closing press conference. </p>



<p>Others are less forthcoming. A couple of hours after Pavel&rsquo;s positive comments, Rutte greets a beaming Dutch Prime Minister Dick Schoof elsewhere in the building with a hug and launches into talks. At the press conference that caps his visit, Schoof is evasive when asked if the Dutch will agree to the 5% goal. &ldquo;We will discuss intensively in the Cabinet and the parliament probably as well on what we are going to do.&rdquo; The Netherlands <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-13/dutch-cabinet-approves-nato-s-5-defense-spending-target"  target="_blank">agreed to the target</a> on June 13.</p>



<p>Getting Europe to pay up may be the most important step in preventing the transactional Trump from undermining the alliance, but managing him requires its own skills. Rutte has repeatedly said that the Trump Administration is &ldquo;<a href="https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2024/11/07/ruttes-message-to-trump-north-korean-troops-in-ukraine-war-threaten-the-us-too"  target="_blank">absolutely right</a>&rdquo; in making more demands of the alliance, and that tone has played well in Washington.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s great to be with a friend of mine,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mfo3TQ34bHU"  target="_blank">said</a> at their last meeting in the Oval Office in March. &ldquo;Every report I&rsquo;ve gotten is &lsquo;What a great job he did,&rsquo; and I&rsquo;m not at all surprised.&rdquo; Rutte&rsquo;s approach also seems to be yielding tangible results. Trump had reportedly threatened to skip the NATO summit, but the White House <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250603-trump-to-attend-nato-summit-in-the-hague"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> on June 3 that he will attend. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/rutte-nato-interview-002.jpg" alt="Rutte, known as a Trump whisperer, at the White House on March 13" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The spending push is not just about addressing Trump&rsquo;s complaints that the allies aren&rsquo;t paying their fair share for defense. &ldquo;This is about practical stuff,&rdquo; Rutte says. &ldquo;We know that on the Canadian and European side we lack air-defense systems, we lack long-range missiles, we lack logistics systems, maneuverable land formations.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Increased European capability would free America up to focus more on China. &ldquo;The [U.S.] defense budget is continually under pressure. We have real readiness issues after many years of deployment,&rdquo; says Rachel Ellehuus, a former adviser to the U.S. NATO mission. &ldquo;The U.S. is facing its own pressures and really needs allies to step up.&rdquo;</p>



<p>No matter how quickly they do, few think America&rsquo;s NATO allies could stand up to a direct Russian threat without the U.S. Which means all of Rutte&rsquo;s efforts on the budget and capabilities fronts would be for naught if Trump simply decided not to come to the defense of alliance members, should the worst come to pass.</p>



<p>There&rsquo;s reason to worry it might. Russian sabotage against U.S. and European targets tripled from 2023 to 2024, according to a <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/russias-shadow-war-against-west"  target="_blank">Center for Strategic and International Studies report</a>. The head of Germany&rsquo;s intelligence has even warned that sabotage could trigger Article 5, NATO&rsquo;s mutual-defense clause. So could a Russian attempt to seize land in former Soviet republics where Russian-speaking minorities are numerous.</p>



<p>All of which adds urgency to the cheery Netherlander holding the reins.</p>



<hr/>



<p><strong>War and tragedy</strong> have loomed over Rutte&rsquo;s life. His father Izaak, a trader who spent much of his life in Indonesia, then a Dutch colony, survived the Tjideng Japanese labor camp. His wife Petronella did not, and Izaak married her sister Mieke. They would live in the country until the 1950s.</p>



<p>Rutte was born in the Hague in 1967, the youngest of seven children from his father&rsquo;s two marriages; some siblings are decades older. One brother died from AIDS in the 1980s, an event he <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/world/europe/article/hollands-mr-no-mark-rutte-sees-off-eu-but-risks-putting-eurosceptics-in-saddle-fj5n6wn23"  target="_blank">once said</a> &ldquo;drastically&rdquo; changed his worldview. &ldquo;I realized that I will only live once. There is no dress rehearsal, there is only one performance,&rdquo; Rutte said. &ldquo;That is where my enormous drive comes from.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Rutte showed an early interest in politics. He joined the youth branch of the center-right People&rsquo;s Party for Freedom and Democracy (VVD) at 16. Although his ambition was to be a concert pianist, he chose to pursue a degree in Dutch history at Leiden University instead. Rutte calls the piano his &ldquo;great hobby&rdquo; but is careful not to play past 9 p.m. because of neighbors living on six sides. &ldquo;Then you get calls, &lsquo;Our children are trying to sleep. And by the way, it was not as good as you thought,&rsquo;&rdquo; he laughs.</p>



<p>Rutte rose up the VVD&rsquo;s ranks, becoming national chairman of its youth branch while a student at Leiden. He graduated in 1992 and held a series of human-resources jobs at Unilever before taking office as a member of parliament in 2003. Rutte won the VVD leadership position in 2006, and in the 2010 elections led the party to become the largest in parliament for the first time ever.</p>



<p>Soon after, he became Prime Minister, proving himself to be a master coalition builder. Rutte&rsquo;s first government was a coalition with the more right-leaning Christian Democrats (CDA) but was <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/20101008-rightist-pro-business-vvd-party-form-minority-government-wilders-rutte-pvv-netherlands-dutch"  target="_blank">propped up</a> by the far-right Party for Freedom (PVV), led by the anti-Muslim firebrand Geert Wilders. His second, third, and final Cabinets included a mix of social democrats, centrists, and conservatives. He is &ldquo;a very capable politician who is able to bring people together even when they have very different views,&rdquo; says Simon Otjes, a senior assistant professor at Leiden University.</p>



<p>Rutte has also been dogged by scandal. His third Cabinet <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/15/world/europe/dutch-government-resignation-rutte-netherlands.html"  target="_blank">resigned in January 2021</a> following a parliamentary report that found that as many as 10,000 families were forced to repay thousands of euros after they had been wrongly accused of welfare fraud. Another <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-politics-exxon-mobil-corp-netherlands-mark-rutte-86e87976aa8dbcca1c12cd351391b6fd"  target="_blank">parliamentary report in February 2023</a> found the Dutch government had for years ignored the risks of drilling gas in Groningen, which had caused man-made earthquakes that damaged homes and affected thousands of lives. Rutte apologized for both scandals. Throughout various controversies, Rutte had a habit of stating he had &ldquo;<a href="https://www.euractiv.com/section/politics/news/mark-rutte-becomes-netherlands-longest-serving-prime-minister/"  target="_blank">no active memory</a>&rdquo; of thornier details. &ldquo;He had a more flexible relationship with the truth,&rdquo; Otjes says. </p>



<p>The end came in July 2023 when he <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/dutch-pm-mark-rutte-resigns-after-collapse-of-coalition-government-12917179"  target="_blank">resigned over a migration fight</a>. But even as his political career waned, the next February he <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/feb/22/us-and-uk-endorse-dutch-pm-mark-rutte-as-next-nato-chief"  target="_blank">secured a critical endorsement</a> from the U.S. for the top NATO job. The Biden Administration considered other candidates, including the more hawkish Kaja Kallas, then Prime Minister of Estonia. But &ldquo;President Biden had liked him,&rdquo; recalls Sean Savett, the former White House National Security Council spokesperson, and Biden and his advisers concluded that Kallas was &ldquo;less likely to be able to win over support from some of the Western European allies.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/rutte-nato-interview-001.jpg" alt="Rutte is reflected into a glass booth while speaking during a media conference prior to a meeting of the Ukraine Defense Contact Group at the NATO headquarters in Brussels, on June 4, 2025." alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Those who know Rutte well expected the job would be a big lifestyle shift for him. He had spent years going to the same hairdresser, visiting the same caf&eacute;s, and eating the same meals at the same restaurants in the Hague. &ldquo;He sometimes drives his closest friends crazy, because of all these habits,&rdquo; says Sierk Nawijn, a special adviser to NATO who has worked with Rutte for a decade.</p>



<p>Rutte has also kept the same modest apartment in the Hague that he bought with his best friend in his youth. He later shared it with that friend&rsquo;s mother for 20 years until she passed away in 2012 while Rutte was Prime Minister. Rutte still gets back to the Hague whenever work permits&mdash;perhaps in part because of the routines that help keep him grounded. Those include teaching a high school social-studies class on Fridays at the Johan de Witt group of schools. &ldquo;I love doing it,&rdquo; Rutte says. &ldquo;It gives you so much energy.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The downing of MH17 over Ukraine&rsquo;s Donbas region, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/mh17-malaysia-airlines-anniversary-russia-ukraine-australia-netherlands-020574037fc9349c377f04e9581e03a0"  target="_blank">by</a> <a href="https://apnews.com/article/mh17-compensation-icao-council-russia-ukraine-war-d4d7e81d05b48cd7795bebde24047500"  target="_blank">Russian-backed forces</a> in July 2014, may have provided the most formative experience to the future NATO Secretary-General. The attack claimed 298 lives, 196 of them Dutch. Rutte says that &ldquo;all illusions&rdquo; he may have had about Vladimir Putin were &ldquo;gone&rdquo; after it took six nights of calls for the Russian President to agree to help families retrieve the remains of loved ones. &ldquo;And then after that he never, ever, ever was able to accept that the Russians probably made a mistake,&rdquo; a still visibly shaken Rutte says. &ldquo;It has to do with basic decency.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p><strong>The tragedy of Ukraine</strong> has stayed with Rutte ever since. He became one of the most frequent wartime visitors to the country and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/nato-chief-rutte-visits-ukraine-first-trip-new-role-2024-10-03/"  target="_blank">made his first trip as Secretary-General</a> there on Oct. 3, just two days after taking up the NATO post, meeting Volodymyr Zelensky in Kyiv. In April he <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/natos-rutte-visits-odesa-says-support-ukraine-unwavering-2025-04-15/"  target="_blank">visited Odesa</a>, a city the Ukrainian President has avoided taking world leaders to since last March when a Russian ballistic missile struck within hundreds of meters of <a href="https://time.com/6970097/mitsotakis-interview-greece-economy/" >Greek Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis</a>. When asked why he was willing to take the risk of traveling there, he says it was &ldquo;just to make the point that it is not only Kyiv which is under threat.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Rutte now helps coordinate outside security assistance to Ukraine, a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/nato-takes-over-coordination-military-aid-kyiv-us-source-says-2024-12-17/"  target="_blank">new responsibility</a> given to NATO by the Biden Administration in an attempt to Trump-proof aid. European and Canadian NATO allies have so far this year given more than the estimated $20 billion the U.S. provided in 2024. A German military officer involved in providing support to Ukraine <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/europe-can-sustain-ukraines-war-effort-without-us-german-general-says-2025-06-06/"  target="_blank">told Reuters</a> that, if necessary, Europe can sustain Ukrainian resistance alone.</p>



<p>But the war in Ukraine has also underscored the limits of Rutte&rsquo;s power. Almost a year ago, NATO members <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c29d03574zdo"  target="_blank">agreed to an &ldquo;irreversible path&rdquo;</a> for Ukraine to join the alliance. Rutte finds himself in the middle. On the one hand, he says the deal with Kyiv is &ldquo;still standing,&rdquo; but he adds, to the disappointment of Ukrainian officials, that it &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t mean that membership is part of a peace deal.&rdquo; </p>



<p>That&rsquo;s another delicate issue. Rutte has publicly backed the peace talks that grew out of Trump&rsquo;s view of himself as a dealmaker, and have at times raised alarm among others in NATO. The &ldquo;Trump Administration&rsquo;s approach has been to put pressure on the victim, Ukraine, rather than on the aggressor, Russia,&rdquo; the U.S. Ambassador to Ukraine Bridget Brink <a href="https://eu.freep.com/story/opinion/contributors/2025/05/16/trump-ukraine-policy-russia-ambassador-resign/83648993007/"  target="_blank">said in April</a> before resigning. Rutte says that the U.S. President is &ldquo;doing exactly what he needs to do. I really commend him for that. Because he broke the deadlock and is constantly engaging with Ukraine and Russia.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/rutte-nato-interview-005.jpg" alt="NATO-Meeting-5-June-2025" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Rutte brushed off current concerns that Trump is abandoning his cease-fire efforts at the press conference with Schoof. An agreement must ensure that Putin never again tries to &ldquo;capture one square kilometer, square mile of Ukraine. That is crucial.&rdquo; But the conflict has only escalated, with Russia&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/06/09/russia-attacks-ukraine-with-nearly-500-drones-and-missiles-in-latest-record-strike"  target="_blank">launching</a> some of its <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/17/russia-drone-missile-strikes-kyiv-ukraine"  target="_blank">most extensive</a> strikes in a war that has claimed <a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/03/06/how-do-ukrainian-soldier-fatalities-compare-with-russias"  target="_blank">hundreds of thousands of casualties</a>, and Ukraine&rsquo;s carrying out the audacious <a href="https://www.economist.com/podcasts/2025/06/14/inside-operation-spiderweb"  target="_blank">Operation Spiderweb</a> drone attack, which damaged or destroyed strategic aircraft inside Russia. The prospect of a cease-fire looks more elusive than ever.</p>



<p>NATO, of course, was created to deter an attack by Russia, when it was doing business as the Soviet Union. And the U.S. was a key architect of the alliance, and the world order Trump is intent on dismantling. So there are easier jobs than the one Rutte holds. And even critics give Rutte high marks for handling Trump and rallying European allies to boost spending and military readiness. The abbreviated NATO summit&mdash;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-04/nato-preparing-brief-summit-to-assuage-trump-on-defense-spending"  target="_blank">reportedly scaled back</a> to keep Trump happy&mdash;should be a point of celebration for both men, assuming the funding boost is agreed to as hoped. But the next challenge will be executing those plans. &ldquo;He&rsquo;s got big, big work to do,&rdquo; General Davis says, and &ldquo;there are surprises to come.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It helps that he&rsquo;s upbeat. Back at Rutte&rsquo;s office, as our interview begins to wind down, the Secretary-General repeats a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/natos-new-military-realism-defense-gdp-percent-target-8e3f5532"  target="_blank">familiar line</a> about the alliance&rsquo;s ability to outpace Moscow&mdash;if it chooses to. &ldquo;The Russian economy is only 5% of the NATO economy. They are $2 trillion. NATO is $50 trillion. And they produce four times as much ammunition as the whole of NATO.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Three-quarters of a century after its founding, Rutte is confident that NATO can fend off any threat from Moscow. &ldquo;I am pretty much convinced that we are safe for now,&rdquo; he says. But Russia is reconstituting its armed forces, and Rutte warns of the risk of being complacent. &ldquo;If we do not invest much more, plus get the defense industrial production going,&rdquo; he says, &ldquo;the Russians might try something.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Optimism, after all, will get you only so far. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295448/rutte-nato-secretary-general-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295448</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘If Middle East Is Unstable, World Will Not Be at Peace’: How China Views the Israel-Iran War</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here’s what to know about China’s approach to—and stakes in—the Israel-Iran war.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296139"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/china-iran.jpg" alt="Iran and China two flags together realations textile cloth fabric texture"/>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s friends don&rsquo;t like the war decimating Tehran, but they&rsquo;re not ready to join the fight against Israel and potentially the U.S.</p>



<p>Instead, <a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" >Russia</a> and now China have urged deescalation, emphasizing the dangerous consequences the escalating conflict could have on the whole world.</p>



<p>&ldquo;If the Middle East is unstable, the world will not be at peace,&rdquo; Chinese President Xi Jinping said Thursday. &ldquo;If the conflict escalates further, not only will the conflicting parties suffer greater losses, but regional countries will also suffer greatly.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;The warring parties, especially Israel, should cease fire as soon as possible to prevent a cycle of escalation and resolutely avoid the spillover of the war,&rdquo; Xi added.</p>



<p>Xi&rsquo;s comments came in a call with Russian President Vladimir Putin, in which both leaders called for a ceasefire, according to a <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/zyxw/202506/t20250619_11653446.shtml"  target="_blank">readout</a> by China&rsquo;s foreign ministry. Earlier this week, Russia <a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" >warned</a> that Israel&rsquo;s attacks have brought the world &ldquo;millimeters&rdquo; from nuclear calamity, and Putin urged Trump against attacking Iran, as the President is <a href="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" >mulling</a> direct U.S. military engagement in the war that has already killed hundreds in Iran and dozens in Israel.</p>



<p>Kremlin aide Yuri Ushakov <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/russias-putin-chinas-xi-condemn-israel-over-its-iran-strikes-phone-call-kremlin-2025-06-19/"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters that Putin and Xi &ldquo;strongly condemn Israel&rsquo;s actions, which violate the U.N. Charter and other norms of international law.&rdquo; Ushakov <a href="https://tass.com/politics/1976285"  target="_blank">added</a> that Xi expressed support for Putin&rsquo;s suggestion to mediate the conflict, an offer Trump <a href="https://www.barrons.com/news/trump-tells-putin-to-end-ukraine-war-before-mediating-iran-israel-d14475c0"  target="_blank">said</a> he has rejected.</p>



<p>China, like Russia, has also positioned itself as a potential peacebroker, though experts say it&rsquo;s unlikely Israel would accept Beijing as a neutral conciliator, given its past criticisms of Israel and ties with Iran.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about how China has responded so far to the conflict and what it may see is at stake.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rhetorical but not material support</h2>



<p>&ldquo;Iran doesn&rsquo;t need communiqu&eacute;s or declarations, but concrete help, like anti-aircraft systems or fighter jets,&rdquo; Andrea Ghiselli, a Chinese foreign policy expert at the University of Exeter, <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/middle-east/20250619-outbreak-of-israel-iran-war-leaves-china-s-mideast-diplomacy-at-an-impasse"  target="_blank">told France 24</a>. But communiqu&eacute;s and declarations are all China is likely to offer, experts tell TIME.</p>



<p>William Figueroa, an assistant professor of international relations at the University of Groningen, tells TIME that China&rsquo;s lack of military support should not come as a surprise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China has historically followed a policy of non-interference, focusing more on domestic issues while aiming to avoid entanglement in protracted foreign conflicts. Earlier this year, China similarly <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3309356/china-urges-restraint-india-pakistan-tensions-escalate-military-strikes"  target="_blank">called on</a> both <a href="https://time.com/7283325/india-pakistan-attacks-kashmir/" >India and Pakistan</a>, the latter being an &ldquo;<a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3311200/china-offers-support-ironclad-friend-pakistan-urges-dialogue-india"  target="_blank">ironclad friend</a>&rdquo; of China, to show restraint. And while it has been accused of providing &ldquo;<a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/united-states-accuse-china-help-russia-war-kurt-campbell/"  target="_blank">very substantial</a>&rdquo; support to Russia in <a href="https://time.com/7287693/trump-discovers-the-war-in-ukraine-may-be-too-complicated/" >its war against Ukraine</a>, China has maintained that it doesn&rsquo;t provide weapons or troops to its neighbor. (<a href="https://www.economist.com/china/2025/06/19/china-has-become-the-most-important-enabler-of-russias-war-machine"  target="_blank">Reports</a> suggest, however, that its material support has included lethal systems.)</p>



<p>White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt <a href="https://transcripts.cnn.com/show/cnc/date/2025-06-19/segment/08"  target="_blank">said</a> Thursday that the White House doesn&rsquo;t see &ldquo;any signs&rdquo; of China providing military support to Iran &ldquo;at this moment in time.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Instead, China has offered words. Beijing has been &ldquo;harshly critical&rdquo; of Israel, says Figueroa. In separate calls with his <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/mfa_eng/wjbzhd/202506/t20250615_11648771.html"  target="_blank">Iranian</a> and <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/mfa_eng/wjbzhd/202506/t20250615_11648766.html"  target="_blank">Israeli</a> counterparts over the past weekend, after <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >Israel launched an attack on Friday against Iran</a>, Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi stressed that China &ldquo;explicitly condemns Israel&rsquo;s violation of Iran&rsquo;s sovereignty, security and territorial integrity.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It has also publicly advised the U.S. against greater involvement in the conflict.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The heating up of the Middle East region serves no one&rsquo;s interests,&rdquo; Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson Guo Jiakun <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/mfa_eng/xw/fyrbt/202506/t20250617_11651839.html"  target="_blank">said</a> on Tuesday. &ldquo;To fan up the flames, use threats and exert pressure does not help deescalate the situation and will only aggravate tensions and enlarge the conflict.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The international community, especially influential major countries, should uphold a fair position and a responsible attitude to create the necessary conditions for promoting a ceasefire and returning to dialogue and negotiation so as to prevent the regional situation from sliding into the abyss and triggering a greater disaster,&rdquo; a Chinese state-media editorial <a href="https://global.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202506/19/WS68541388a310a04af22c7529.html"  target="_blank">declared</a> on Thursday.</p>



<p>China&rsquo;s diplomatic response reflects its priority to &ldquo;lower the temperature,&rdquo; says Figueroa, particularly in tensions with the U.S.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Diplomatic limitations</h2>



<p>China has sought to deepen its investments and influence in the Middle East over the years, which has raised the expectations of its regional diplomacy to &ldquo;sky high&rdquo; levels, says Figueroa. But while Beijing touted brokering a <a href="https://time.com/6262985/china-saudi-arabia-iran-ukraine-peace-talks/" >historic truce between Saudi Arabia and Iran in 2023</a>, the task before it now is much taller.</p>



<p>Wang, the Chinese foreign minister, said China is &ldquo;ready to play a constructive role&rdquo; in resolving the conflict, according to foreign ministry readouts of his calls with both Iran and Israel, but unlike with Saudi Arabia and Iran, Figueroa says, Israel has expressed no interest in negotiating a resolution. And even if Israel was interested in coming to the table, China is unlikely to be seen as a neutral arbiter given its ties with Iran, criticisms of Israel <a href="https://time.com/6325352/china-israel-hamas-war/" >including over Gaza</a>, and ongoing global power competition with the U.S., Israel&rsquo;s biggest ally.</p>



<p>China has developed strong economic ties with Iran over the years, becoming Iran&rsquo;s largest trading partner and export market, especially for oil&mdash;a critical lifeline for Iran as the U.S. has placed severe economic sanctions on the country. Iran joined BRICS, the intergovernmental group China has viewed as an alternative collective of emerging powers to the Western-oriented G7, in 2024; <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-07-04/iran-joins-sco-the-china-founded-regional-security-grouping"  target="_blank">joined</a> the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, a Beijing-backed security group, in 2023; and the two countries <a href="https://thediplomat.com/2021/12/the-china-iran-strategic-partnership-40-years-in-the-making/"  target="_blank">signed</a> a 25-year cooperative agreement in 2021.</p>



<p>While China has also maintained an economic relationship with Israel&mdash;China is Israel&rsquo;s second-biggest trading partner and the two countries have had an &ldquo;innovative comprehensive partnership&rdquo; since 2017&mdash;Figueroa says it&rsquo;s &ldquo;not close enough to have a serious influence over Israel&rsquo;s actions.&rdquo;</p>



<p>When asked about the possibility of China acting as a mediator, Israel&rsquo;s Ambassador to Beijing Eli Belotserkovsky <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3315025/israel-ready-keep-talking-china-despite-criticism-iran-strikes-ambassador-says?module=perpetual_scroll_0&amp;pgtype=article"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>South China Morning Post</em> on Wednesday, &ldquo;at this stage, we are concentrating on the military campaign. This is our main concern at the moment, and we need to see how things will develop.&rdquo; Still, he added that Israel would &ldquo;continue talking to China as [part of] an ongoing process.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Failure to help bring peace to the Middle East could seriously dampen China&rsquo;s recent efforts to portray itself as an effective global peacebroker, especially after Ukraine already rejected a peace plan Beijing had proposed in 2023. And if Iran&rsquo;s regime falls, Marc Lanteigne, an associate professor of political science at the Arctic University of Norway, told France 24, the China-mediated truce with Saudi Arabia would also risk &ldquo;going up in smoke.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It is hard to predict how the conflict itself might impact [China&rsquo;s diplomatic] efforts,&rdquo; Figueroa says. &ldquo;A wider conflict would undoubtedly complicate Chinese diplomatic efforts, which largely rest on their ability to provide economic development.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Economic concerns</h2>



<p>While the Iran-China trade balance is largely skewed in China&rsquo;s favor&mdash;<a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/china-headaches-iran-deal"  target="_blank">around a third of Iranian trade is with China, but less than 1% of Chinese trade is with Iran</a>&mdash;China is heavily dependent on the Middle East&rsquo;s oil.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China is by far the largest importer of Iranian oil,&rdquo; according to a <a href="https://www.state.gov/sanctioning-entities-purchasing-and-transporting-iranian-oil-to-further-impose-maximum-pressure-on-iran/"  target="_blank">statement</a> in March by the U.S. State Department, which added: &ldquo;The Iranian regime uses the revenue it generates from these sales to finance attacks on U.S. allies, support terrorism around the world, and pursue other destabilizing actions.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Sara Haghdoosti, executive director of public education and advocacy coalition Win Without War, tells TIME that China &ldquo;has a vested interest in seeing the conflict end before Israel strikes more of Iran&rsquo;s oil infrastructure.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But China is less dependent on Iran itself than on access to the region&rsquo;s reserves. &ldquo;The Islamic Republic is a replaceable energy partner,&rdquo; according to a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-19/xi-shows-no-sign-of-rescuing-iran-as-trump-ramps-up-pressure"  target="_blank">Bloomberg analysis</a>.</p>



<p>For global oil markets too, changes to Iran&rsquo;s supply alone are unlikely to cause significant price disruptions. &ldquo;Even in the unlikely event that all Iranian exports are lost, they could be replaced by spare capacity from OPEC+ producers,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.fitchratings.com/research/sovereigns/israel-iran-conflict-raises-regional-security-risk-16-06-2025"  target="_blank">assessed</a> credit agency Fitch Ratings earlier this week.</p>



<p>Around 20% of the world&rsquo;s oil trade, however, passes through the Strait of Hormuz, which Iran has <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-19/what-is-the-strait-of-hormuz-and-could-iran-block-it"  target="_blank">threatened to close</a> in retaliation if the U.S. joins the war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;If the United States officially and operationally enters the war in support of the Zionists, it is the legitimate right of Iran in view of pressuring the U.S. and Western countries to disrupt their oil trade&rsquo;s ease of transit,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.mehrnews.com/news/6504770/%D8%A7%DA%AF%D8%B1-%D8%A2%D9%85%D8%B1%DB%8C%DA%A9%D8%A7-%D9%88%D8%A7%D8%B1%D8%AF-%D8%AC%D9%86%DA%AF-%D8%A8%D8%A7-%D8%A7%DB%8C%D8%B1%D8%A7%D9%86-%D8%B4%D9%88%D8%AF-%D8%A8%D8%B3%D8%AA%D9%86-%D8%AA%D9%86%DA%AF%D9%87-%D9%87%D8%B1%D9%85%D8%B2-%D8%AD%D9%82-%D9%85%D8%B4%D8%B1%D9%88%D8%B9-%D9%85%D8%A7%D8%B3%D8%AA"  target="_blank">said</a> Iranian lawmaker Ali Yazdikhah on Thursday, according to state-sponsored Iranian news agency Mehr News.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Doing so would also impact China, for which <a href="https://www.energypolicy.columbia.edu/publications/chinas-oil-demand-imports-and-supply-security/"  target="_blank">more than 40%</a> of crude oil imports come from the Middle East.</p>



<p>The conflict&rsquo;s &ldquo;greatest impact on China could be on energy imports and supply chain security,&rdquo; Sun Degang, director of the Center for Middle Eastern Studies at Fudan University, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3314822/could-china-help-broker-ceasefire-between-iran-and-israel?module=spotlight&amp;pgtype=homepage"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>South China Morning Post</em>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;While Beijing will continue to condemn the conflict, it will also seek to balance ties with Israel and the Gulf states and promote stable energy flows,&rdquo; according to Bloomberg&rsquo;s analysts, especially as surging commodity prices would exacerbate domestic economic growth challenges already hampered by the <a href="https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/" >trade war with the U.S.</a> and an <a href="https://time.com/6320739/china-evergrande-soccer-real-estate-crisis/" >ongoing real estate crisis</a>.</p>



<p>In response to a question about the potential interruption of Iranian oil supplies to China, Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson Guo Jiakun <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/lxjzh/202506/t20250617_11651839.html"  target="_blank">reiterated</a> on Tuesday the need to &ldquo;ease tensions as soon as possible&rdquo; in order to &ldquo;prevent the region from spiraling into greater turmoil.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A contained conflict could be good for China</h2>



<p>&ldquo;If a wider conflict breaks out,&rdquo; Figueroa says, &ldquo;the impact on China&rsquo;s economic projects and investments in the region would be significant.&rdquo; Foreign policy analyst Wesley Alexander Hill <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/wesleyhill/2025/06/18/china-loses-big-in-israel-iran-conflict/"  target="_blank">noted</a> in a Forbes op-ed that an escalated conflict could force China into a bind between taking &ldquo;decisive action&rdquo; to defend Iran, which might alienate Saudi Arabia, or doing nothing militarily and letting Israeli and potentially U.S. attacks &ldquo;continue to degrade Iranian export capacity,&rdquo; which would leave other regional partners with a &ldquo;dim view [of] what Chinese commitment under pressure looks like.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Still, some analysts have suggested that China&mdash;as well as Russia&mdash;may be content for now to sit back and let things play out, with their higher priorities clearly elsewhere.</p>



<p>According to Bloomberg Economics analyst Alex Kokcharov, a contained conflict in the Middle East could &ldquo;distract Washington from strategic competition with China.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Added Bloomberg&rsquo;s bureau chief in China, Allen Wan, in a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-06-20/xi-keeps-iran-at-arm-s-length-as-middle-east-conflict-deepens"  target="_blank">newsletter</a> Friday: &ldquo;Should the U.S. once again get tangled up in a war in the Middle East, that&rsquo;d probably suit China just fine. Beijing and the [People&rsquo;s Liberation Army] would appreciate the chance to squeeze Taiwan tighter.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;At very least, both powers [Russia and China] are content to watch the U.S. further squander goodwill with gulf Arab partners by backing another destabilizing conflict in the region,&rdquo; Haghdoosti, the Win Without War executive director, tells TIME. And they, she adds, are likely &ldquo;shedding no tears that the U.S. military is currently burning through stocks of difficult-to-replenish missile defense interceptors to shield Israel.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296139</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Did Iran Try to Kill Trump? What to Know</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296125/iran-assassination-plot-trump-kill-khamenei-us-israel-carlson-cruz/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296125/iran-assassination-plot-trump-kill-khamenei-us-israel-carlson-cruz/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iranian officials have denied trying, but multiple alleged conspirators linked to Tehran have been charged over attempted plots against the U.S. President.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296125"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296125/iran-assassination-plot-trump-kill-khamenei-us-israel-carlson-cruz/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/donald-trump-iran-kill-factcheck-explainer.jpg" alt="New Flag Poles Installed On White House Grounds"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 20, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the U.S. and Iran, a profile of the man who wants to save NATO, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>53b7290a-77fc-4225-b6d9-d816006c0d94</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>2774c911-50f2-4fc1-bc73-9a8d0f4d6e6d</code></p></div>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>One thing is clear: Israel openly wants to kill Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader. Ayatollah Ali Khamenei &ldquo;<a href="https://www.channelnewsasia.com/world/israel-iran-khamenei-no-longer-exist-missile-strikes-netanyahu-us-trump-5192491"  target="_blank">can no longer be allowed to exist</a>,&rdquo; Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said Thursday, just days after U.S. President Donald Trump publicly announced that the U.S. knows Khamenei&rsquo;s location but is holding off on killing him &ldquo;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">for now</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Another isn&rsquo;t so much, depending on who you ask.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve never heard that before,&rdquo; former Fox News host <a href="https://time.com/7295566/trump-tucker-carlson-feud-israel-iran-conflict/" >Tucker Carlson</a> responded quizzically after Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas) <a href="https://youtu.be/smemFVe0l5E?t=4793&amp;feature=shared"  target="_blank">asserted</a> that Iran has tried&mdash;and is trying&mdash;to kill Trump. &ldquo;We should attack Iran immediately if that&rsquo;s true,&rdquo; Carlson, one of the flagbearers of the anti-war wing within the <a href="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" >factious MAGA right</a>, facetiously continued.</p>



<p>Cruz argued that he doesn&rsquo;t think the U.S. military attacking Iran or killing Khamenei would necessarily be the most appropriate response to the threat against the U.S. President, but he insisted that &ldquo;nobody disputes&rdquo; Iran is indeed trying to assassinate Trump. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s an objective fact,&rdquo; Cruz <a href="https://x.com/tedcruz/status/1935762246459679165"  target="_blank">posted on X</a> after the interview.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="time-embed time-embed__twitter" data-provider="twitter" data-url="https://twitter.com/tedcruz/status/1935390891390419353" ><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The Iranian regime has been trying to murder President Trump and other American officials for years. It is one of the most basic facts about the threat they pose to the national security of the United States. And yet, there are people who don&#39;t want to act against the Ayatollah -&hellip; <a href="https://t.co/MR1pGqV05E"  target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/MR1pGqV05E</a></p>&mdash; Ted Cruz (@tedcruz) <a href="https://twitter.com/tedcruz/status/1935390891390419353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"  target="_blank">June 18, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>A <a href="https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/" >U.S. attack on Iran</a>, including potentially targeting Khamenei, <a href="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" >may yet be in the cards</a>, despite Trump&rsquo;s political campaigns <a href="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" >against military interventions</a> aimed at &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7296013/trump-strike-iran-war-regime-change/" >regime change</a>.&rdquo; But it&rsquo;s unlikely to be in retaliation to an Iranian assassination plot&mdash;unless such a plot is successful.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Trump said he had ordered the annihilation of the state of Iran if it assassinates him.</p>



<p>&ldquo;That would be a terrible thing for them to do,&rdquo; he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xi4xYFK9qmU"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters in February. &ldquo;Not because of me. If they did that, they would be obliterated. That would be the end. I&rsquo;ve left instructions: if they do it, they get obliterated. There won&rsquo;t be anything left.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" ><em>As Trump Considers Striking Iran, Russia Warns World Is &lsquo;Millimeters&rsquo; Away From Nuclear Catastrophe</em></a></p>



<p>Iran is <a href="https://ctc.westpoint.edu/trends-in-iranian-external-assassination-surveillance-and-abduction-plots/"  target="_blank">known to conduct assassination plots overseas</a>, usually <a href="https://time.com/7270415/iran-assassins-new-york-trial-conviction-guilty-verdict-masih-alinejad/" >targeting Iranian dissidents</a> and not always successful. Iranian officials have also been <a href="https://www.iranintl.com/en/202407173988"  target="_blank">vowing</a> to kill Trump for years after he ordered the <a href="https://time.com/5758250/qasem-soleimani-iran-retaliation/" >assassination</a> of Gen. Qasem Soleimani, who led the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps&rsquo; Quds Force, in January 2020.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Still, as the U.S. has even charged would-be assassins, Iran has denied ever targeting Trump.</p>



<p>Politico <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/07/16/iran-plot-assassinate-trump-00168830"  target="_blank">reported</a> last July that the U.S. intelligence community had collected increasing evidence suggesting Iran was actively working on plots to kill Trump. Neither of the attempts that summer on Trump&rsquo;s life in <a href="https://time.com/6998302/trump-rally-shooting-2/" >Butler, Pa.</a>, or <a href="https://time.com/7021475/trump-golf-club-shooter-assassination-attempt-reactions-investigation/" >West Palm Beach, Fla.</a>, have been linked to Iran, though the <a href="https://time.com/7021494/ryan-wesley-routh-trump-golf-course-shooter-politics-iran-ukraine/" >shooter in the latter</a> expressed support for Iran in public writings. But around the same time, a 46-year-old Pakistani national named <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/06/pakistani-murder-for-hire-trump-00172945"  target="_blank">Asif Merchant</a> was arrested in Texas and charged with seeking to kill high-ranking U.S. politicians or officials&mdash;potentially including Trump&mdash;allegedly under the instructions of Iran.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7013497/donald-trump-iran-assassination-plot/" ><em>Iran, Trump, and the Third Assassination Plot</em></a></p>



<p>&ldquo;We have not received any reports on this matter from the U.S. Government,&rdquo; a spokesperson for Iran&rsquo;s United Nations Mission <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/08/06/politics/iran-trump-assassination-charges/index.html"  target="_blank">told</a> CNN at the time. &ldquo;However, it is evident that the modus operandi in question contradicts the Iranian Government&rsquo;s policy of legally prosecuting the murderer of General Soleimani.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In September, Trump&rsquo;s campaign <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-briefed-alleged-assassination-threats-by-iran-his-campaign-says-2024-09-25/"  target="_blank">said</a> he had been briefed on &ldquo;real and specific threats from Iran to assassinate him.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Big threats on my life by Iran,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/113196325135640926"  target="_blank">posted</a> on social media. &ldquo;The entire U.S. Military is watching and waiting. Moves were already made by Iran that didn&rsquo;t work out, but they will try again.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Biden Administration sent a warning through Switzerland in September that an assassination attempt against Trump would be seen as an act of war, to which Iran responded in October&mdash;again via Swiss diplomats&mdash;that it would not try to kill Trump, U.S. officials <a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/iran-told-u-s-it-wasnt-trying-to-kill-trump-c2d8267d"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>Wall Street Journal</em>.</p>



<p>In November 2024, after Trump was elected, the Justice Department <a href="https://www.justice.gov/archives/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-murder-hire-and-related-charges-against-irgc-asset-and-two"  target="_blank">announced</a> charges against a 51-year-old Afghan national named Farhad Shakeri, who was allegedly tasked by Iranian officials to assemble a plan to surveil and assassinate Trump.</p>



<p>&ldquo;A new scenario is fabricated,&rdquo; Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1855277524839731593?lang=en"  target="_blank">posted</a> on X. &ldquo;The American people have made their decision. And Iran respects their right to elect the President of their choice. The path forward is also a choice. It begins with respect.&rdquo; Iranian foreign ministry spokesperson Esmaeil Baghaei <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/iran-trump-assassination-plot-1.7379508"  target="_blank">claimed</a> the allegations were part of a &ldquo;repulsive&rdquo; plot by Israel to sabotage U.S.-Iran relations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/investigations/iran-never-plotted-kill-president-elect-donald-trump-irans-president-t-rcna187644"  target="_blank">told</a> NBC in January that Iran &ldquo;never attempted&rdquo; to kill Trump, &ldquo;and we never will.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is another one of those schemes that Israel and other countries are designing to promote Iranophobia,&rdquo; Pezeshkian said. &ldquo;Iran has never attempted to nor does it plan to assassinate anyone. At least as far as I know.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</a>, who derailed <a href="https://time.com/7287313/iran-israel-strike-report-nuclear-us-trump-history-context-explainer/" >U.S.-Iran nuclear negotiations</a> by <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >launching strikes last week against Iran</a> and is <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/14/israel-iran-war-us-nuclear-program-trump"  target="_blank">reportedly</a> trying to sway Trump to authorize more direct U.S. military <a href="https://time.com/7294500/israel-attack-iran-us-involvement-trump-netanyahu-khamenei/" >involvement in the conflict</a>, claimed in a <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/netanyahu-reveals-iran-marked-trump-enemy-number-one-assassination-plot"  target="_blank">Fox News interview</a> on Sunday that Iran actively worked to assassinate Trump because he&rsquo;s &ldquo;forceful&rdquo; and &ldquo;decisive.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;They want to kill him,&rdquo; Netanyahu insisted. &ldquo;He&rsquo;s enemy number one.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296125/iran-assassination-plot-trump-kill-khamenei-us-israel-carlson-cruz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296125</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump to Decide &#8216;Within Two Weeks&#8217; Whether to Take Action on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Simmone Shah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt told reporters the President will see through negotiations before deciding whether to strike.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296098"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran.jpg" alt="IRAN-ISRAEL-CONFLICT-STRIKE"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 20, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the U.S. and Iran, a profile of the man who wants to save NATO, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>53b7290a-77fc-4225-b6d9-d816006c0d94</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>2774c911-50f2-4fc1-bc73-9a8d0f4d6e6d</code></p></div>



[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]

<p>President Donald Trump will make a decision within two weeks on whether to strike on Iran, Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt told reporters during a press briefing on Thursday. </p>



<p>Reading a statement from Trump, Leavitt said, &ldquo;Based on the fact that there&rsquo;s a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not take place with Iran in the near future, I will make my decision whether or not to go within the next two weeks.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The President&rsquo;s deadline comes amid escalating strikes between Iran and Israel&mdash;and as the U.S. considers direct military action against Iran. On Wednesday, <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >when asked</a> if the U.S. was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities, Trump told reporters, &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The United States government maintains this fact that Iran has never been closer to obtaining a nuclear weapon,&rdquo; Leavitt went on to say. She noted that the President continues to be briefed by his National Security Council and remains in &ldquo;constant communication&rdquo; with the Israeli government and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>



<p>The attacks between the two countries began last Friday, when Israel launched what it called &ldquo;preemptive air strikes&rdquo; targeting more than a dozen sites in Iran. The <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/day-six-of-israeli-strikes-on-iran-an-overview-of-the-events/"  target="_blank">Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA) says</a> that since Israel&rsquo;s initial missile attack on Iran, 639 people have been killed there and a further 1,329 injured&mdash;the organization says that 263 of those killed were civilians and 154 military personnel. <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">In Israel</a>, 24 people have been killed so far by Iranian strikes, with 838 injured.</p>



<p>On Thursday, an <a href="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" >Iranian missile strike</a> damaged a hospital in southern Israel, as part of a barrage of strikes Israel said injured 271 people.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" >Trump&rsquo;s base is divided</a> as he weighs his options, especially given that he campaigned on a <a href="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" >pledge of no new wars</a>.</p>



<p>The two-week timeline opens the door for negotiations, but does not negate the possibility of U.S. involvement. &ldquo;The president has made it clear he always wants to pursue diplomacy,&rdquo; Leavitt said. &ldquo;But believe me the president is unafraid to use strength if necessary.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296098</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israeli Hospital Damaged by Iranian Airstrike as Missile Exchange Continues</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The strike on the hospital in the southern city of Beersheba has left over 70 injured according to Israel's Health Ministry.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296012"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/nurse-soroka-hospital-israel-june19.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-ISRAEL-IRAN-CONFLICT"/>



<p>Seventy-one people have been &#8220;slightly injured&#8221; after an Iranian missile strike damaged a hospital in Southern Israel, according to the country&rsquo;s <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMOH/status/1935649625060368823"  target="_blank">health ministry</a>.</p>



<p>The strike on Soroka Medical Center, in the city of Beersheba, was part of a wider barrage from Iran, <a href="https://x.com/ariel_oseran/status/1935567014674018647"  target="_blank">hitting neighborhoods in Tel Aviv</a>, including Holon and Ramat Gan. Israel&rsquo;s <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMOH/status/1935649625060368823"  target="_blank">health ministry</a> has said that a total of 271 people were injured in the strikes, including those at Soroka, with four in serious condition.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said that Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, &ldquo;can no longer be allowed to exist,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/jun/19/israel-iran-conflict-live-hospital-in-southern-israel-hit-in-iran-missile-strike-say-israeli-officials?CMP=share_btn_url&amp;page=with%3Ablock-6853e39e8f08a4f72f5f14a1#block-6853e39e8f08a4f72f5f14a1"  target="_blank">speaking to reporters</a> at the site of missile strikes in Holon.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Khamenei openly declares that he wants Israel destroyed&mdash;he personally gives the order to fire on hospitals. He considers the destruction of the state of Israel to be a goal,&rdquo; Katz said before threatening the Ayatollah.</p>



<p><a href="https://en.irna.ir/news/85866868/"  target="_blank">Iranian state media</a> has said that the strike in southern Israel targeted a military command and intelligence center near the hospital, and that the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-iran-war-latest-06-19-2025-14b868f4514a7c337d5b9859de130bf0"  target="_blank">blast from the strike</a> caused damage to the medical center, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-iran-war-latest-06-19-2025-14b868f4514a7c337d5b9859de130bf0"  target="_blank">The Associated Press reported</a>.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Israel has launched a series of its own missile attacks on Iran, targeting a nuclear reactor in Arak, nuclear facilities in Natanz, and ballistic missile sites, according to the <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1935583119320469744"  target="_blank">Israel Defense Forces</a>.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/day-six-of-israeli-strikes-on-iran-an-overview-of-the-events/"  target="_blank">Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA) says</a> that since Israel&rsquo;s initial missile attack on Iran, 639 people have been killed there and a further 1,329 injured.</p>



<p>HRANA reported on Thursday that 263 of these deaths have been confirmed as civilians and 154 as military personnel.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">In Israel</a>, 24 people have been killed so far by Iranian strikes, with 838 injured.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Israel reacts to Iranian strike damaging hospital</strong></h2>



<p>Israeli government officials have responded to Thursday&rsquo;s strike on the hospital, with <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1935581234001809807"  target="_blank">Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying</a>, &ldquo;We will exact the full price from the tyrants in Tehran.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before his comments threatening Khamenei on Thursday morning, Katz said: &ldquo;The cowardly Iranian dictator sits in the depths of the fortified bunker and fires aimed shots at hospitals and residential buildings in Israel. These are war crimes of the most serious kind&mdash; and Khamenei will be held accountable for his crimes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Prime Minister and I have instructed the IDF to increase the intensity of attacks against strategic targets in Iran and against government targets in Tehran in order to remove threats to the State of Israel and undermine the ayatollahs&#8217; regime,&rdquo; Katz continued in <a href="https://x.com/Israel_katz/status/1935588198505173249"  target="_blank">a statement on social media</a>.</p>



<p>While visiting the damaged hospital in Beersheba, <a href="https://x.com/SkyNews/status/1935665849538424850"  target="_blank">Itimar Ben-Gvir</a>, Israel&rsquo;s Security Minister said: &ldquo;The regime of the ayatollahs needs to be annihilated.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is an historic moment, we have the opportunity to defeat the Iranian nukes, the Nazis, the ayatollahs, anyone who hates the state of Israel,&rdquo; he added.</p>



<p>Ben-Gvir has recently been in the spotlight after <a href="https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/" >he was sanctioned</a> by the British, Canadian, Australian, Norwegian and New Zealand governments for inciting violence against Palestinians in the West Bank. Israel&rsquo;s Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich also faces the same sanctions, including a travel ban and the freezing of all assets in those countries.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The question of U.S. involvement in the conflict continues</strong></h2>



<p>On Thursday,&nbsp; while visiting the Soroka Medical Center, Netanyahu was asked about potential U.S. involvement in the conflict with Iran. He said: &ldquo;President Trump will do what&#8217;s best for America. I trust his judgment, he is a tremendous friend, a tremendous world leader, a tremendous friend of Israel.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Donald Trump has been considering direct U.S. military action against Iran in recent days. On Wednesday, he told reporters, &ldquo; I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble,&rdquo; <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >when asked</a> if the U.S. was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Iranian leader Khamenei issued a grave warning to the U.S. earlier on Wednesday, saying, &ldquo;The Americans should know that any U.S. military intervention will undoubtedly be accompanied by irreparable damage,&rdquo; during a public address.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" >Russia has also warned</a> about the consequences should President Trump decide to take action against Iran. Kremlin spokesperson <a href="https://tass.com/politics/1976159"  target="_blank">Dmitry Peskov</a> told Russian state media U.S. intervention would mar &ldquo;an expansion in the conflict&#8217;s geography. We are hearing from Tehran that this could lead to another dangerous escalation.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exclusive: Iranian Nobel Laureate Narges Mohammadi Calls for Israel-Iran Ceasefire</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman and Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The renowned rights advocate called on other Nobel Peace Prize winners to amplify the call for an end to the Israel-Iran war.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295994"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/narges-mohammadi.jpg" alt="Narges-Mohammadi-Iranian-Human-Rights-Activist"/>



<p>Iranian Nobel Peace Prize laureate <a href="https://time.com/6965015/narges-mohammadi-2024/" >Narges Mohammadi</a> has long fought for freedom and human rights, even at the expense of her own. With her country now at <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >war with Israel</a>, Mohammadi called on her fellow activists to band together and call for a ceasefire.</p>



<p>In an exclusive message to TIME from Iran, Mohammadi said that the outbreak of war, which began in the early morning of <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >June 13</a>, has forced millions of Iranians to leave their homes and caused damages to &ldquo;critical national infrastructure,&rdquo; compounding an economic crisis its citizens already bore the brunt of. Mohammadi herself has <a href="https://x.com/nargesfnd/status/1935140081116807410"  target="_blank">left Tehran</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;The scale of destruction already resembles that of a months-long conflict,&rdquo; Mohammadi writes.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" ><em>A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</em></a></p>



<p>Mohammadi was <a href="https://time.com/6321287/narges-mohammadi-nobel-peace-prize/" >awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2023</a> for her women&rsquo;s rights advocacy in Iran. She is known for helping imprisoned activists, leading a campaign against the death penalty, and openly criticizing the Iranian regime&rsquo;s use of torture and sexualized violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has been arrested several times for her work, and sentenced to more than 36 years. Mohammadi was in prison when she became the Nobel Prize recipient in 2023, but she was furloughed in December 2024 for <a href="https://time.com/7159230/imprisoned-nobel-laureate-narges-mohammadi-fights-for-life-iran/" >medical reasons</a>.</p>



<p>Mohammadi called on other Nobel laureates &ldquo;to use all your individual, collective, and institutional capacities to amplify the call of &lsquo;No to War&rsquo; and support our urgent plea for a ceasefire and an end to this war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Earlier, Mohammadi told the BBC that she could possibly return to prison for speaking publicly against the war, but she said she&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/live/cx23e4jz2g0t?post=asset%3Aaffaf574-f769-4ec2-804e-e9c1af795eac#post"  target="_blank">not worried</a>.&rdquo; Mohammadi, alongside fellow Nobel laureate Shirin Ehbadi and other prominent Iranian voices, <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/opinion/article/2025/06/16/israel-iran-this-conflict-poses-a-grave-threat-to-the-very-foundations-of-human-civilization_6742387_23.html"  target="_blank">wrote an op-ed</a> earlier this week demanding a halt to Iran&rsquo;s uranium enrichment program and an end to the attacks.</p>



<p>Israel launched an attack on Iran saying it intends to stop the country from achieving the capability of producing a nuclear weapon. Hundreds are believed to have been killed in the strikes on Iran, which has retaliated by firing missiles into Israel, killing at least 24.</p>



<p>Read Mohammadi&rsquo;s full statement below.</p>



<hr/>



<p><em>To the Nobel Peace Prize Laureates, Human Rights Orgs, people of the world peace lovers,</em></p>



<p><em>I urge you to take action to stop the war between Israel and the Islamic Republic of Iran.</em></p>



<p><em>Six days have passed since the beginning of this horrific war. The violence is accelerating at a devastating pace, and the scale of destruction already resembles that of a months-long conflict.</em></p>



<p><em>The growing fear that Israel may attack the Islamic Republic&rsquo;s nuclear facilities adds terrifying uncertainty to the war. Millions of Iranian citizens have fled their homes. Amid crushing economic hardship and soaring inflation, they are unable to afford basic daily expenses and have sought refuge in other cities.</em></p>



<p><em>The targeting of critical national infrastructure, the rising number of casualties, and the threat to evacuate the capital, Tehran, are deeply alarming.</em></p>



<p><em>I call on you&mdash;Nobel Peace Prize laureates&mdash;to use all your individual, collective, and institutional capacities to amplify the call of &ldquo;No to War&rdquo; and support our urgent plea for a ceasefire and an end to this war.</em></p>



<p><em>Let us rise together to form a united, global front for the right to peace. The scope of war expands by the day. Its fire will not remain confined to the lands directly involved&mdash;it will cross borders and engulf the entire world.</em></p>



<p><em>War casts a dark shadow over humanity&rsquo;s future&mdash;a darkness that cannot easily be erased from the eyes of humankind.</em></p>



<p><em>Let us stand together&mdash;loudly, clearly&mdash;for peace and for an end to war.</em></p>



<p><em>I demand an immediate halt to the war and the declaration of a ceasefire.</em></p>



<p><em>&mdash; Narges Mohammadi</em></p>



<p><em>18th June 2025</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Iran’s Nuclear Program Goes From Here</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The incentive to bury its nuclear program even deeper is stronger than ever.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295632"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/fate-of-iran-nuclear-01.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>Deep beneath the Zagros Mountains in central Iran, in a labyrinth of fortified tunnels outside the city of Natanz, centrifuges spun at speeds too fast for the eye to track. The cascade of machines, arranged in long halls and shielded by concrete and steel, have been central to Iran&rsquo;s most sensitive nuclear work, and, until recently, largely immune to airstrikes. But this month Israeli warplanes penetrated Iranian airspace and struck multiple nuclear sites, including underground facilities thought to be untouchable.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>While the full extent of the damage remains murky, satellite imagery and initial damage assessments by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) indicate that the strikes on Iran&rsquo;s Natanz nuclear facility were particularly effective, knocking out the electricity to the underground area.</p>



<p>The Israeli strikes also blew up the uneasy nuclear status quo that existed in the Middle East for years while raising a daunting question: What happens if Iran decides that the only true deterrent is to build a bomb?</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>For over a decade, Tehran has operated just below the threshold of nuclear breakout capability. But this spring it abandoned that restraint. The IAEA reported in May that Iran had accumulated roughly 120 kg of uranium enriched to 60%&mdash;&shy;dangerously close to weapons-grade levels of 90%&mdash;and enough to build 22 nuclear bombs within five months if further enriched. At the same time, Iran began building a third enrichment hall on top of the two already in use. U.S. officials saw it as a provocation; Israel viewed it as a casus belli.</p>



<p>The military strikes Israel launched on June 13 were swift, surgical, and calibrated. Israeli officials described them as a pre-emptive operation to cripple Iran&rsquo;s ability to build a nuclear weapon by targeting its main enrichment sites, nuclear scientists, and military officials.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/fate-of-iran-nuclear-02.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>But while the strikes appear to have disrupted Iran&rsquo;s enrichment operations, it retains scientific expertise and stockpiled material, and now possesses a stronger incentive to bury its program even deeper. &ldquo;If Iran survives the conflict, they could decide that a nuclear weapon is the only way to have deterrence,&rdquo; says Alex Vatanka, a senior fellow at the Middle East Institute.</p>



<p>Iran could attempt a dash for a nuclear weapon at one of its remaining sites. One, at Fordo, is buried so deeply in mountains near the city of Qom that only the U.S.&rsquo;s most powerful bunker-busting bomb&mdash;the 30,000-lb. GBU-57&mdash;is believed capable of reaching it.</p>



<p>The threat underscores the collapse of diplomatic efforts to constrain Iran&rsquo;s program. &ldquo;Trying to get to a deal now is infinitely harder than it used to be,&rdquo; says Richard Nephew, who worked on Iran sanctions in the Obama Administration. Others are more hopeful about the outcome of the war. Says Matt Kroenig of the Atlantic Council: &ldquo;We were on the verge of Iran becoming a nuclear power and it looks like now we&rsquo;ve set that threat into the future.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295632</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Campaigned on Staying Out of Wars. Now He&#8217;s Changing His Tune on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's a hair-trigger situation and the stakes for America are high]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295729"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-troops-middle-east-03.jpg" alt="Trump troops"/>



<p>When President Donald Trump ducked out early from a meeting with G-7 nations in the Canadian mountain resort of Kananaskis on June 16, he said he needed to get back to Washington as strikes escalated between Israel and Iran. He didn&rsquo;t like relying on phone calls, he told reporters on Air Force One, and he wanted to be a &ldquo;little bit, I think, more well versed.&rdquo; For the normally freewheeling Trump, it was a sign of the gravity of the moment, a rare acknowledgement that he didn&rsquo;t have enough information to handle a hair-trigger situation.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The stakes for America are high. Backed into a corner by Israel&rsquo;s surprisingly effective attack, Tehran could decide to turn its proxy terrorist forces against the U.S. in the region and beyond. The strategic rapprochement between Israel and Arab states hangs in the balance as conflict threatens to spread. More broadly, the outcome of the war could decide whether the U.S. commits another generation of troops to the Middle East, once again diverting American might from countering China&rsquo;s expansion in the Pacific.</p>



<p>At the same time, an Israeli defeat of Iran could open a <a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >new era</a> of Arab-Israeli cooperation, defang Tehran&rsquo;s regional militias, and deliver a blow to China, which had sought to bolster &shy;Tehran as a regional counterweight to the U.S. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve got this axis with Beijing at the core,&rdquo; argues Matthew Pottinger, former Deputy National Security Adviser during Trump&rsquo;s first term.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>The U.S. could tip the balance either way, but Trump is constrained in how he manages the conflict. It&rsquo;s been four years since the disastrous U.S. pullout from Afghanistan. Trump campaigned on not getting the U.S. into more wars, and some of the fiercest opposition to further entanglement is coming from his own MAGA base.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-troops-middle-east-02.jpg" alt="Afghanistan troops" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Trump has already beefed up the U.S. military presence around Israel and Iran, ordering another guided-missile destroyer to the waters off Israel and directing the U.S.S. <em>Nimitz</em> aircraft carrier and its strike group to change course in the Pacific and motor toward the Arabian Sea.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</a></em></p>



<p>Iran sits at one of the world&rsquo;s most important strategic crossroads. Nearly one-third of the world&rsquo;s crude-oil production passes through the Strait of Hormuz&mdash;and within 30 miles of Iran&rsquo;s coastline. Tanker ships have been warned to sail closer to the coast of Oman, on the western side of the strait. Amid the massive military mobilization, maritime alerts are warning shipping vessels that &ldquo;electronic interference&rdquo; could jam their navigation equipment.</p>



<p>For Trump, a direct Iranian attack on the U.S. would trigger a military response. Iran ordered an assassination attempt against Trump and tried to kill an Iranian-American journalist living in Brooklyn. &ldquo;The fact that they have been open in these threats tells me they don&rsquo;t believe they are facing credible retaliatory risk from the United States,&rdquo; Pottinger says. &ldquo;The Israeli strikes might inject some reality into their calculus. But Iranians have been known to miscalculate on many occasions.&rdquo;</p>



<p>After his return to Washington, Trump issued noticeably more hostile rhetoric. He called for Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;unconditional &shy;surrender&rdquo; and chastised its leaders for not taking talks more seriously. &ldquo;Why didn&rsquo;t you negotiate with me two weeks ago? You could have done fine. You would have had a country,&rdquo; he said. Now all bets are off for Iran, and the U.S.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295729</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
