<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Breaking: Israel Strikes Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a developing story. Here’s what we know so far.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293795"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/iran-israel-strikes.jpg" alt="APTOPIX Iran Mideast Wars"/>



<p>Israel conducted a &ldquo;preemptive&rdquo; strike early Friday on Iran, without involvement from the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Explosions in the capital Tehran were captured in images and videos.</p>



<p>An Israeli military official told <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-says-it-strikes-iran-amid-nuclear-tensions-2025-06-13/"  target="_blank">Reuters</a> that Israel was targeting &ldquo;dozens&rdquo; of nuclear and military targets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said in a <a href="https://x.com/efenigson/status/1933320590833619376/photo/1"  target="_blank">statement</a> that a retaliatory attack on Israel and its civilian population &ldquo;is expected in the immediate timeframe.&rdquo;</p>



<p>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio said in a <a href="https://x.com/yashar/status/1933326064668881089"  target="_blank">statement</a>: &ldquo;Tonight, Israel took unilateral action against Iran. We are not involved in strikes against Iran and our top priority is protecting American forces in the region. Israel advised us that they believe this action was necessary for its self-defense. President Trump and the Administration have taken all necessary steps to protect our forces and remain in close contact with our regional partners. Let me be clear: Iran should not target U.S. interests or personnel.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The attack comes a day after the U.S. began <a href="https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/" >evacuating embassy personnel</a> across the Middle East amid rising regional tensions as negotiations between the U.S. and Iran over the latter&rsquo;s nuclear program have appeared to stall.</p>



<p><em><strong>This is a developing story and will be updated.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Mongolia’s New Prime Minister Means for Its Democracy</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s either a triumph for people power or a worrying lurch towards authoritarianism, depending on whom you ask.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293415"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Gombojav-Zandanshatar-Mongolia-PM.jpg" alt="Hungary Mongolia"/>



<p>It&rsquo;s either a triumph for people power or a worrying lurch towards authoritarianism, depending on whom you ask, but Mongolia has a new Prime Minister: Zandanshatar Gombojav, a Russian-educated former banker who previously served as Foreign Minister, Chief of the Cabinet Secretariat, and speaker of the State Great Khural parliament.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I will work forward, not backward,&rdquo; Zandanshatar told the State Great Khural, whose lawmakers overwhelmingly approved his elevation to the premiership by 108 out of the 117 members present. &ldquo;By respecting unity, we will overcome this difficult economic situation.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>They&rsquo;re economic woes that contributed to the downfall of outgoing <a href="https://time.com/7209066/mongolia-prime-minister-oyun-erdene-luvsannamsrai-uranium-france-putin-trump/" >Prime Minister Luvsannamsrain Oyun-Erdene</a>, who belongs to the same Mongolian People&rsquo;s Party (MPP) but <a href="https://time.com/7290686/mongolia-prime-minister-oyun-erdene-luvsannamsrain-resigns-protests-corruption-son/" >quit</a> after failing to receive sufficient backing in a June 3 confidence vote he called to quell popular protests demanding his ouster.</p>



<p>For several weeks, thousands of predominantly young demonstrators have thronged central Ulaanbaatar&rsquo;s Sukhbaatar Square in outrage at the lavish displays of wealth that Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s son and fianc&eacute;e posted on social media, including helicopter rides, an expensive engagement ring, a luxury car, and designer handbags.</p>



<p>The crowds called for Oyun-Erdene to disclose his personal finances, but he declined saying that they had already been provided to the nation&rsquo;s Anti-Corruption Agency, as required by law. However, public trust in that body and the wider judiciary is scant following a slew of high-profile <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2023/1/25/after-anti-corruption-protests-mongolia-rethinks-coal-sales"  target="_blank">graft scandals</a> coupled with a conspicuous lack of prosecutions or accountability.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Oyun-Erdene was the one who was talking about morals, transparency, and corruption,&rdquo; protest leader Unumunkh Jargalsaikhan, 27, tells TIME. &ldquo;But Mongolia is actually degrading when it comes to the economy and freedoms. The corruption scandal was just the spark.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Unumunkh blames rising living costs and torpid wages for driving public anger, especially among young people. Mongolia is facing an economic crunch with government spending <a href="https://www.fitchratings.com/research/sovereigns/mongolias-next-government-may-face-rising-fiscal-risk-09-06-2025"  target="_blank">rising</a> 20% year-on-year for the first four months of 2025 but goods exports falling by 13% over the same period, owed not least to a 39% decline in coal exports. Still, Oyun-Erdene was dismissive of the protesters and in a statement instead blamed &ldquo;a web of interests, tangled like a spider&rsquo;s web&rdquo; for toppling him.</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s supporters say his ouster had three drivers: Firstly, and with a dash of irony, his relentless pursuit of official graft, including a <a href="https://www.parliament.mn/en/nn/74900/"  target="_blank">draft law</a> his cabinet just submitted that would compel all public officials to justify their income.</p>



<p>Secondly, last year&rsquo;s updated Minerals Law, which puts 34% of the equity of &ldquo;strategic&rdquo; mines&mdash;defined as producing over 5% of GDP&mdash;into a Sovereign Wealth Fund. Today, nine of Mongolia&rsquo;s 16 strategic deposits are privately owned by influential industrialist families. &ldquo;Those private companies are very unhappy and completely opposed to 34% belonging to the state,&rdquo; says Jargalsaikhan Dambadarjaa, a Mongolian broadcaster and political commentator.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6976412/nuclear-power-mongolia-uranium-climate-change/" ><em>The Promise of Nuclear Energy Brings the West to Mongolia</em></a></p>



<p>The third alleged driver is more contentious: that Mongolian President Ukhnaagiin Khurelsukh deviously undermined Oyun-Erdene in order to change the constitution to boost presidential powers and extend term limits from the single, six-year stint currently permitted.</p>



<p>True, incoming Prime Minister Zandanshatar&rsquo;s most recent posting was as chief-of-staff to Khurelsukh, who chose to give a midnight speech to the State Great Khural on the eve of Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s no-confidence vote that urged lawmakers to represent their constituents rather than a single political leader. Despite the MPP having enough lawmakers to reach the 64-vote threshold required to save Oyun-Erdene, his own party deserted him, with the secret ballot totaling just 44 votes for, 38 against.</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s camp paints Khurelsukh as an aspiring autocrat intent on aligning Mongolia with authoritarian neighbors China and Russia, noting how he hosted Vladimir Putin in Ulaanbaatar in September, flouting an International Criminal Court arrest warrant, and also <a href="https://president.mn/en/2025/05/10/president-khurelsukh-attends-the-victory-day-parade/"  target="_blank">attended</a> Moscow&rsquo;s Victory Day Parade in May. A doctored <a href="https://x.com/HansGutbrod/status/1929465880821325841"  target="_blank">photo</a> depicting Khurelsukh as having commissioned a giant golden statue of himself in the manner resembling a Central Asian despot is doing the rounds on social media.</p>



<p>However, this narrative has some problems. Gladhanding Putin is a political necessity for landlocked Mongolia, whose 3.5 million population relies on Moscow for 90% of imported gas and petroleum and is completely beholden to Russia for security. &ldquo;Turning up in September was Putin showing the rest of the world his middle finger,&rdquo; says Prof. Julian Dierkes, a Mongolia expert at the University of Mannheim in Germany. &ldquo;There was no option for Mongolia to say no.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, Khurelsukh has proven an internationalist, first <a href="https://blogs.ubc.ca/mongolia/2021/khurelksukh-un-general-assembly-security-council/"  target="_blank">addressing</a> the U.N. General Assembly soon after his inauguration in 2021 and returning every year since. (His predecessor, Khaltmaagiin Battulga, rarely showed up.) While not outright condemning Russia&rsquo;s aggression in Ukraine, Khurelsukh&rsquo;s latest UNGA address in September did pointedly <a href="https://gadebate.un.org/sites/default/files/gastatements/79/mn_en.pdf"  target="_blank">voice opposition to</a> &ldquo;using force against the territorial integrity and political independence of any state.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Khurelsukh has also repeatedly <a href="https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/06/01/mongolian-president-i-will-not-support-constitutional-amendments"  target="_blank">gone on record</a> to oppose amending the constitution, which was just updated in 2019 to strengthen the legislative branch. &ldquo;Honestly, there isn&rsquo;t a lot of worry about the President trying to stay in power,&rdquo; says Bolor Lkhaajav, a Mongolian political analyst and commentator. Dierkes agrees: &ldquo;I call baloney on the &lsquo;evil President thesis.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s also a thesis that completely ignores the concerns of the Sukhbaatar Square protesters while presuming that things in Mongolia were otherwise rosy and improving under Oyun-Erdene. However, Mongolia&rsquo;s score on the Transparency International Corruption Perceptions Index had fallen from 35 out of 100 when he came to power in 2021 to just 33 last year. Meanwhile, human-rights groups have <a href="https://monitor.civicus.org/explore/mongolia-press-freedom-at-risk-with-arrest-and-prosecution-of-journalists-while-protesters-detained/"  target="_blank">condemned</a> the prosecution of peaceful protesters and prominent journalists under his watch. Mongolia&rsquo;s press freedom ranking <a href="https://rsf.org/en/country/mongolia"  target="_blank">dropped</a> to 109 out of 180 countries last year, down from 88 in 2023, according to Reporters Without Borders.</p>



<p>&ldquo;On corruption, he&rsquo;s taken rhetorical actions,&rdquo; Dierkes says of Oyun-Erdene. &ldquo;And on democracy promotion, he&rsquo;s taken negative actions. He is no democracy warrior.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, while Zandanshatar is clearly close to the President, he is by no means a lacky, being a highly educated career politician&mdash;a former visiting scholar at Stanford&mdash;with his own power base. Still, what Zandanshatar&rsquo;s rise to the premiership means for Mongolia going forward is a big question.</p>



<p>A married father-of-four, Zandanshatar, 55, developed a reputation as a thoughtful, steady speaker of parliament. Following his posting at Stanford, he returned enthused about <a href="https://deliberation.stanford.edu/what-deliberative-pollingr"  target="_blank">deliberative polling</a>, which was subsequently employed to <a href="https://cddrl.fsi.stanford.edu/news/deliberative-polling-fosters-peace-and-instigates-positive-change-among-people-mongolia"  target="_blank">gauge public opinion</a> prior to the 2019 constitutional amendment. Zandanshatar does, however, have a democratic deficit given he&rsquo;s one of the few senior MPP figures not to have won a seat in the 2024 election, though he had been elected three times previously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although choosing a non-lawmaker as Prime Minister is not unprecedented, Dierkes fears this may serve as a &ldquo;legitimacy achilles heel&rdquo; should the winds turn against him. Jargalsaikhan also notes Zandanshatar was one of the proponents of Mongolia&rsquo;s 2006 &ldquo;windfall tax&rdquo; on copper and gold mining profits. (The 68% levy&mdash;the world&rsquo;s highest&mdash;was repealed in 2009 after decimating investor confidence.)</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene had earmarked 14 new mega projects to boost economic growth, including a major expansion of renewable energy and cross-border railway connections with China, which receives 90% of Mongolian exports. He also promised to diversify the country&rsquo;s economy, which is heavily dependent on a mining industry that accounts for a quarter of GDP. But policy continuity is key to attracting the foreign investment necessary to realize these goals.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Until investment laws are consistent here, investors are going to be wary,&rdquo; says Steve Potter, an honorary member and former chairman of the American Chamber of Commerce in Ulaanbaatar. &ldquo;Constant changes in rules and regulations have long been a problem. Consequently, foreign investment has been very lackluster.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Investor uncertainty isn&rsquo;t the only worry. Having lasted in power four-and-a-half years, Oyun-Erdene was the longest-serving of Mongolia&rsquo;s 18 Prime Ministers since its 1990 democratic revolution. The revolving door of governments and leaders has augmented the idea that parliamentarian democracy is flawed or inherently unsuited to Mongolian society, while rendering a centralized political system more appealing for some&mdash;an idea that is being amplified by shadowy actors on social media and galvanized by Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s tone deaf response to protesters&rsquo; demands.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The protests were organic, but instead of showing his financial papers the Prime Minister&rsquo;s response was so political,&rdquo; says Bolor. &ldquo;His reaction showed just how disconnected he was from the people, who only care about how his policies are impacting their daily lives, such as air pollution, unemployment, and corruption.&rdquo;</p>



<p>So while Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s demise was likely rooted in factional bickering rather than a nefarious power grab, the debacle contains a stark warning that Mongolia&rsquo;s political class needs to start pulling in the same direction for cherished freedoms to be secured. &ldquo;Democracy itself is very fragile,&rdquo; says Jargalsaikhan. &ldquo;But it&rsquo;s so important and can only be protected by a thriving parliamentarian system. And we must not lose democracy in Mongolia.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293415</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Know About Crash of Air India Flight to London and Its Sole Survivor</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The plane crashed just moments after takeoff, with 242 people on board. Here's what we know so far.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293469"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-025.jpg" alt="Air India plane crash in Ahmedabad"/>



<p>A passenger plane heading to London, England, carrying 242 people, crashed shortly after takeoff from Ahmedabad, India, on Thursday. One person survived the crash and was being treated in a hospital, Air India <a href="https://x.com/airindia/status/1933240865591370052?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> early Friday local time. All 241 other people who were onboard have died.</p>



<p>The aircraft was carrying 169 Indian nationals, 53 British, seven Portuguese, and one Canadian. The airline described the sole survivor as a British national of Indian origin.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>At Ahmedabad&rsquo;s Civil Hospital, Dr. Dhaval Gameti said he had examined the survivor, whom he identified as Vishwashkumar Ramesh, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/india-plane-crash-cad8dad5cd0e92795b03d357404af5f8"  target="_blank">according to The Associated Press</a>. &ldquo;He was disoriented, with multiple injuries all over his body. But he seems to be out of danger,&rdquo; Gameti is quoted as saying. </p>



<p>Ramesh&#8217;s brother, Nayan Ramesh, confirmed to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/12/world/india-plane-crash-ahmedabad/f8817dc8-ce2b-5be5-93b4-a8b66feb1043?smid=url-share"  target="_blank">the New York <em>Times</em></a> that he was the sole survivor of the crash. He told the outlet Vishwashkumar Ramesh had been on vacation with another one of his brothers, who was also on the plane, describing the family as &ldquo;completely devastated and just in shock.&rdquo;</p>



<p>His cousin, Ajay Valgi, told reporters on Thursday that Vishwashkumar Ramesh was &ldquo;fine,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/ahmedabad-india-plane-crash-06-12-25#cmbts4w950000356styzrz3pl"  target="_blank">CNN reported</a>.</p>



<p>TIME has been unable to independently verify reports relating to Ramesh being the lone survivor.</p>



<p>Sambit Patra, a lawmaker from Modi&rsquo;s ruling Bharatiya Janata Party, said Gujarat&rsquo;s former chief minister, Vijay Rupani, is reportedly among the dead.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-024.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-INDIA-AVIATION-CRASH" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Footage shows the Air India Boeing 787-8 plane flying low above a residential area before crashing, resulting in a ball of flames emerging from the impact site.</p>



<p>Local media reported that the plane crashed into local medical college accommodation, south-west of Ahmedabad&rsquo;s airport. At least <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/5-dead-at-medical-students-hostel-in-ahmedabad-where-air-india-plane-crashed-8650656?pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll"  target="_blank">five people at the accommodation</a> building are believed to have been killed in the crash, as well as many others reported injured and or missing.</p>



<p>Police <a href="https://apnews.com/live/air-india-plane-crash-ai171-ahmedabad-london#00000197-641c-dc65-a7f7-ee1f7b430000"  target="_blank">initially said it appeared</a> there were no survivors from the flight. But the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/12/world/india-plane-crash-ahmedabad/fe3a4932-5482-5972-9297-6cdbdc91ae8e?smid=url-share"  target="_blank">Ahmedabad police commissioner, G.S. Malik,</a> later said there could be survivors, as rescue teams continued working. Over 200 bodies have been recovered from the site.</p>



<p>Air India CEO <a href="https://youtu.be/ZkBI-XtkHm8"  target="_blank">Campbell Wilson said in a video statement</a> that &#8220;the injured passengers have been taken by local authorities to the nearest hospitals.&#8221;</p>



<p>Indian Home Minister Amit Shah <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OnPN5dUr_o8"  target="_blank">told reporters</a> Thursday that he had met with the crash&#8217;s survivor in the hospital.</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=KnabC35z vertical]</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How did the crash in Ahmedabad unfold?</strong></h2>



<p>The plane took off from Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel International Airport at <a href="https://x.com/airindia/status/1933100970399166759"  target="_blank">1:38 p.m local time</a>. Initial indications that it had crashed came when Air India announced the aircraft had been &ldquo;involved in an accident.&rdquo;</p>



<p>FlightRadar, which displays live updates for flights worldwide, <a href="https://www.flightradar24.com/data/flights/ai171#3ac3097f"  target="_blank">shows that the path of the plane</a> ended shortly after takeoff. The signal with the aircraft <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/c8d1r3m8z92t?post=asset%3Ad3b3e213-8c28-4de4-a439-87f4c31bf9dd#post"  target="_blank">was reportedly lost at around 625 ft</a>.</p>



<p>A large ball of flames could be seen rising from the crash site, followed by <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/india-plane-crash-gatwick-latest-ahmedabad-airport-live-sky-news-13382494?postid=9717003#liveblog-body"  target="_blank">clouds of dark smoke </a>as emergency services rushed to the scene. Images of the crash site show extensive damage to buildings in the vicinity, with charred rubble and parts of the plane scattered across the landscape. The rear of the aircraft could be seen partially intact on top of a nearby building.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-026.jpg" alt="All 242 people aboard crashed Air India plane believed dead: Report" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What are the details of the flight?</strong></h2>



<p>There were 242 people onboard the Air India plane, including 12 crew.</p>



<p>The flight was scheduled to land at London&rsquo;s Gatwick Airport at approximately 6:25 p.m. local time on Thursday evening, <a href="https://x.com/Gatwick_Airport/status/1933126034112553357"  target="_blank">according to the airport.</a></p>



<p>Aviation expert <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/india-plane-crash-gatwick-latest-ahmedabad-airport-live-sky-news-13382494?postid=9717222#liveblog-body"  target="_blank">Julian Bray has said</a> that the pilot made a mayday call before the crash, indicating that the crew was aware of a problem with the aircraft.</p>



<p>Local news outlet <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/plane-crashes-near-airport-in-ahmedabad-more-details-awaited-8649161?pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll"  target="_blank">NDTV is reporting</a> that pilot Sumeet Sabharwal had 8,200 hours of flight experience, and co-pilot Clive Kundar had 1,100 hours, citing the Directorate General of Civil Aviation.</p>



<p>Boeing, the plane&#8217;s manufacturer, said <a href="https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=131554"  target="_blank">in a statement</a> that it was in contact with Air India regarding the flight and was ready to support the airline.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Our deepest condolences go out to the loved ones of the passengers and crew on board Air India Flight 171, as well as everyone affected in Ahmedabad. I have spoken with Air India Chairman N. Chandrasekaran to offer our full support, and a Boeing team stands ready to support the investigation led by India&rsquo;s Aircraft Accident Investigation Bureau,&rdquo; <a href="https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=131555"  target="_blank">Boeing President and CEO Kelly Ortberg said</a>.</p>



<p>It is the first ever Boeing 787-8 plane to crash, according to the <a href="https://asn.flightsafety.org/"  target="_blank">Aviation Safety Network</a> database. </p>



<p>However, generally speaking, Boeing has a history of high-profile crashes. This latest incident comes a month after the aircraft company<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/jun/12/air-india-first-crash-of-boeing-787-model-comes-weeks-after-1bn-dollar-737-max-payout"  target="_blank"> agreed to pay $1.1bn</a> in a deal with the U.S. Department of Justice to avoid prosecution over two crashes in 2018 and 2019 that together killed 346 people.</p>



<p>Air India said the plane was 12 years old.</p>



<p>Just hours after the most recent crash, as of around 4 p.m. local time, Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel International Airport has reopened and is operational once again, according to <a href="https://x.com/MoCA_GoI/status/1933126693817823349"  target="_blank">India&rsquo;s civil aviation ministry.</a></p>



<p>Tata Group, the parent company of Air India, said that it is &ldquo;deeply anguished&rdquo; by the crash. The company said it will be providing &#8377;1 crore, equivalent to over $116,000, to the families of those who have died in the crash.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We remain steadfast in standing with the affected families and communities during this unimaginable time,&rdquo; the Tata Group relayed <a href="https://x.com/TataCompanies/status/1933159585772367969"  target="_blank">in a statement</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-022.jpg" alt="APTOPIX India Plane Crash" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How are lawmakers and world leaders reacting?</strong></h2>



<p>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi called the crash a &ldquo;tragedy&rdquo; and said he is &ldquo;stunned and saddened.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It is heartbreaking beyond words. In this sad hour, my thoughts are with everyone affected by it. [I] have been in touch with Ministers and authorities who are working to assist those affected,&rdquo; he said <a href="https://x.com/narendramodi/status/1933110947553681853"  target="_blank">in a statement via social media</a>.</p>



<p>British Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer has also offered his condolences, <a href="https://x.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1933108640002588855"  target="_blank">calling the situation &ldquo;devastating</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I am being kept updated as the situation develops, and my thoughts are with the passengers and their families at this deeply distressing time,&rdquo; Starmer said.</p>



<p>Starmer <a href="https://x.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1933213493966074069"  target="_blank">said later Thursday</a> that the U.K. has dispatched an investigation team in response to the crash.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, former British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said that he and his wife are &ldquo;deeply shocked and distressed&rdquo; by the incident. &ldquo;There is a unique bond between our two nations and our thoughts and prayers go out to the British and Indian families who have lost loved ones today,&rdquo;<a href="https://x.com/RishiSunak/status/1933149418053583037"  target="_blank"> he said</a>.</p>



<p>King Charles III has <a href="https://x.com/RoyalFamily/status/1933137934699430271"  target="_blank">offered his &ldquo;deepest possible sympathies</a>&rdquo; in an official statement. &ldquo;My wife and I have been desperately shocked by the terrible events in Ahmedabad this morning. Our special prayers and deepest possible sympathies are with the families and friends of all those affected,&rdquo; His Majesty said. &ldquo;I would like to pay a particular tribute to the heroic efforts of the emergency services and all those providing help and support at this most heartbreaking and traumatic time.&rdquo; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-021.jpg" alt="India Plane Crash" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>India&rsquo;s Civil Aviation Minister <a href="https://x.com/RamMNK/status/1933096368203317279"  target="_blank">Ram Mohan Naidu Kinjarapu said he is</a> &ldquo;deeply shocked and saddened&rdquo; by the incident, adding that &ldquo;all aviation and emergency response agencies have been directed to take rapid and coordinated action.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Speaking to reporters on Thursday, U.S. President Donald Trump said &ldquo;the plane crash is terrible. I&rsquo;ve already told them, anything we can do &hellip; It&rsquo;s a big country, a strong country. I let them know that anything we can do, we&rsquo;ll be over there immediately.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S.&#8217;s National Transportation Board said in a <a href="https://x.com/NTSB_Newsroom/status/1933147382331445483"  target="_blank">post</a> on X that it would lead a team of U.S. investigators traveling to India to assist in the investigation into the crash.</p>



<p>The country&#8217;s Secretary of Transportation Sean Duffy said his department was &ldquo;prepared to assist India with anything it needs to investigate this tragedy.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Canadian Prime Minister <a href="https://x.com/MarkJCarney/status/1933138048469844421"  target="_blank">Mark Carney relayed that he was &ldquo;devastated&rdquo;</a> to learn of the incident. &ldquo;My thoughts are with the loved ones of everyone on board. Canada&rsquo;s transportation officials are in close contact with counterparts and I am receiving regular updates as the response to this tragedy unfolds,&rdquo; he said. </p>



<p>Portuguese Prime Minister Lu&iacute;s Montenegro <a href="https://x.com/imprensagov"  target="_blank">also reacted to Thursday&rsquo;s crash</a>. &ldquo;It was with deep dismay that I learned of the tragic plane crash in India, in which seven citizens with Portuguese nationality were travelling,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;On behalf of myself and the Government, I would like to express my condolences and deep solidarity with the families of the victims.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293469</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fears of Israeli Strike on Iran Rise as U.S. Evacuates Embassy Staff From Middle East: What We Know So Far</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chantelle Lee and Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 23:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is an attack imminent? Why are tensions in the region climbing? Here’s everything we know so far.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293392"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/US-embassy-baghdad-iraq.jpg" alt="IRAQ-US-POLITICS-DIPLOMACY"/>



<p>Fears of a potential <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/11/us/politics/iran-us-iraq-diplomats-middle-east.html"  target="_blank">Israeli strike on Iran</a> are mounting amid rising tensions in the Middle East that are prompting the U.S. to move some of its non-military personnel out of the region.</p>



<p>Asked on Thursday about reports of a possible Israeli strike on Iran, President Donald Trump told reporters, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t want to say it&rsquo;s imminent, but it looks like something that could well happen.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The growing concerns of a strike, which could threaten to spark a regional conflict, come amid heightened tensions between the U.S. and Iran as the countries&#8217; negotiations over a potential nuclear deal appear to have stalled. In a <a href="https://app.magellan.ai/listen_links/NYP"  target="_blank">podcast</a> released on Wednesday, Trump said that he is growing &ldquo;less confident&rdquo; about the possibility of reaching an agreement with Iran that would limit the country&rsquo;s ability to develop nuclear weapons.</p>



<p>On Thursday, however, Trump described a deal with Iran as being &ldquo;fairly close&rdquo; and warned that an Israeli strike on the country could &ldquo;blow it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;As long as I think there will be an agreement, I don&rsquo;t want them going in,&rdquo; he told reporters.</p>



<p>Trump has previously <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/30/trump-threatens-bomb-iran-00259786"  target="_blank">threatened to &ldquo;bomb&rdquo;</a> Iran if negotiations over its nuclear program fail, and Iranian Defense Minister Aziz Nasirzadeh said Wednesday that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-threatens-us-bases-region-if-military-conflict-arises-2025-06-11/"  target="_blank">Iran would strike</a> U.S. military bases in the region if talks fail and conflict with the U.S. escalates. Last month, Israel also <a href="https://time.com/7287313/iran-israel-strike-report-nuclear-us-trump-history-context-explainer/" >reportedly began preparing</a> potential strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Daniel Shapiro, former U.S. Ambassador to Israel during the Obama Administration and former Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for the Middle East during the Biden Administration, told the <a href="https://www.jpost.com/middle-east/article-857404"  target="_blank"><em>Jerusalem Post</em></a> on Wednesday that &ldquo;the Trump Administration appears to be taking some preparations for potential military action, possibly by Israel, against Iran. It does not necessarily mean anything is imminent, as it takes time to move U.S. personnel from their posts. There is also still time for progress in upcoming nuclear talks. But it shows it is possible, and the United States wants to reduce risk. That can be useful leverage in the talks.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S. is planning to remove nonessential embassy staff from Iraq, as well as some of its other non-military personnel in the region, amid the rising tensions, Trump said Wednesday evening.</p>



<p>&ldquo;They are being moved out because it could be a dangerous place, and we&rsquo;ll see what happens,&rdquo; the President <a href="https://x.com/BarakRavid/status/1932934631537717716"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters at the Kennedy Center in Washington, D.C. &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve given notice to move out.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In a statement, the <a href="https://x.com/RobertShermanTV/status/1932876198331494540"  target="_blank">State Department</a> said: &ldquo;President Trump is committed to keeping Americans safe, both at home and abroad. In keeping with that commitment, we are constantly assessing the appropriate personnel posture at all our embassies. Based on our latest analysis, we decided to reduce our Mission in Iraq.&rdquo; U.S. staffers who are deemed nonessential will be removed from the embassy in Baghdad, the State Department told the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/state-department-embassy-baghdad-f892ebd6a50850ef5650f31819541bff"  target="_blank">Associated Press</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>American and Iraqi sources confirmed the news to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/us-embassy-iraq-preparing-ordered-evacuation-due-heightened-security-risks-2025-06-11/"  target="_blank">Reuters</a>, but the sources didn&rsquo;t share with the news outlet what security risks sparked the move or how many officials would be removed from the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Citing an unnamed government official, state-run <a href="https://ina.iq/ar/236111-.html"  target="_blank">Iraqi News Agency</a> reported that the evacuations of non-essential U.S. government employees from Baghdad were &ldquo;procedures related to the U.S. diplomatic presence in a number of Middle Eastern countries and do not only concern Iraq.&rdquo; The Iraqi official also said that from their side, they have &ldquo;not recorded any security indicator that requires this evacuation.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The AP reported that the State Department is authorizing nonessential staffers and their families to depart Bahrain and Kuwait as well.</p>



<p>A statement from the <a href="https://x.com/JenGriffinFNC/status/1932876338626519103"  target="_blank">U.S. Central Command</a>&mdash;which oversees U.S. military activity in the Middle East&mdash;said that Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth authorized the &ldquo;voluntary departure&rdquo; of military dependents across the region as the command is &ldquo;monitoring the developing tension&rdquo; and working with the State Department and allies to &ldquo;maintain a constant state of readiness.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The safety and security of our service members and their families remains our highest priority,&rdquo; the statement said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No troops in the Middle East have been ordered to evacuate, U.S. defense officials told <a href="https://x.com/Liz_Friden/status/1932887348120858744"  target="_blank">Fox News</a>.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://x.com/John_Hudson/status/1932911410431852684"  target="_blank"><em>Washington Post</em></a> reported that all the departures from Iraq came after all embassies in striking distance of Iran, including some in Europe and North Africa, were ordered to convene emergency action committees and send cables back to Washington about the measures they are taking to mitigate risks.</p>



<p>When asked what could dial down tension in the region, Trump said Wednesday at the Kennedy Center: &ldquo;They can&rsquo;t have a nuclear weapon, we&rsquo;re not going to allow that,&rdquo; in apparent reference to Iran.</p>



<p>Trump on Thursday told reporters that he &ldquo;would love to avoid a conflict,&rdquo; but that Iran is &ldquo;going to have to be willing to give us some things that they&rsquo;re not willing to give us right now.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/JenniferJJacobs/status/1932955683084792259"  target="_blank">CBS</a> reported Wednesday that U.S. officials learned Israel is &ldquo;fully ready&rdquo; to launch an operation in Iran and that Iran could respond with attacks on U.S. sites in Iraq. <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/world/middle-east/israel-considering-military-strike-iran-sources-say-rcna212528"  target="_blank">NBC</a> reported that Israel is considering military action against Iran and that it would be without U.S. support.</p>



<p>Oman&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Badr al-Busaidi <a href="https://x.com/badralbusaidi/status/1933045263267995878"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> on X that the next round of nuclear negotiations between Iran and the U.S. are scheduled for Sunday, in Oman&rsquo;s capital Muscat, amid <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/next-us-iran-talks-said-likely-to-be-postponed-source-says-date-was-never-confirmed/"  target="_blank">concerns</a> of a postponement.</p>



<p>A U.K. maritime trade agency <a href="https://www.ukmto.org/recent-incidents#9aa802ba-9f3a-4fdb-82b7-7f863fb7baf3"  target="_blank">issued</a> a public advisory on Wednesday, cautioning commercial vessels in the area. The agency said that it had &ldquo;been made aware of increased tensions within the region which could lead to an escalation of military activity having a direct impact on mariners.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/Iran_UN/status/1932856661594587161"  target="_blank">Iran&rsquo;s mission to the United Nations</a> posted on X Wednesday that &ldquo;threats of &lsquo;overwhelming force&rsquo; won&rsquo;t change facts: Iran is not seeking a nuclear weapon, and U.S. militarism only fuels instability.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293392</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Know About the Northern Ireland Riots as Petrol Bomb-Filled Chaos Spills Into Third Night</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the third night in a row, riots rocked the town of Ballymena in Northern Ireland, with protesters throwing petrol bombs and fireworks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293105"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219108922.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-BRITAIN-NIRELAND-UNREST-RACISM"/>



<p>For the third night in a row, riots rocked the town of Ballymena in Northern Ireland on Wednesday, lasting into the early hours of Thursday morning. Protesters used petrol bombs and fireworks as they clashed with the authorities. In response, police deployed plastic baton rounds and a water cannon.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-statement-following-third-consecutive-night-disorder"  target="_blank">Police Service of Northern Ireland (PSNI) confirmed</a> that an additional nine officers were injured on Wednesday during the unrest. Overall, several arrests have been made and dozens of police officers injured.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-service-statement-second-night-violence-ballymena"  target="_blank">Police said that</a> across the first two nights of rioting, businesses and homes had been &ldquo;attacked and damaged.&rdquo; As tensions escalated, tires and bins were set alight on Wednesday evening.</p>



<p>In a statement addressing Wednesday&rsquo;s violence, PSNI reported that officers responded to an arson attack at a leisure center in the nearby town of Larne.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Shockingly, people were inside the building at the time of this fire&mdash;thankfully no injuries were reported&mdash;and we could have been looking at a completely different situation,&rdquo; police said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Communities Minister Gordon Lyons of the Democratic Unionist Party (DUP) is facing resignation calls after<a href="https://www.facebook.com/lyonsmla/posts/1107244267882587?ref=embed_post"  target="_blank"> a social media post</a> about the location of migrant families who fled the riots near their homes in Ballymena and sought shelter at the leisure center.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cn056gwdjyxo"  target="_blank">Lyons has defended his post</a> from Wednesday evening, telling BBC&rsquo;s <em>Good Morning Ulster</em>: &#8220;I will very strongly hit back at any notion that I had revealed the use of this facility to the public when the protest was already planned, when everybody knew what was happening.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219085401.jpg" alt="Police Respond To Third Night Of Unrest In Ballymena" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>A number of protests have also taken place in other towns and cities across Northern Ireland, including Belfast, Lisburn, and Newtownabbey.</p>



<p>In the town of Coleraine, <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-statement-following-third-consecutive-night-disorder"  target="_blank">police reported</a> that trash cans were set alight on railway tracks at the local train station.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the ongoing unrest in Ballymena.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What prompted the riots in Northern Ireland?</strong></h2>



<p>The disorder started on Monday, June 9, after a peaceful protest took place in the town of Ballymena <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/ballymena-protest-fireworks-petrol-bombs-and-glass-bottles-thrown-at-riot-police-as-serious-disorder-deepens-13381896"  target="_blank">over an alleged sexual assault</a> that police say occurred <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c5y26l5z379o"  target="_blank">the previous Saturday</a>.</p>



<p>Earlier on Monday, two 14-year-old boys appeared at Coleraine Magistrates&#8217; Court in relation to the assault. The boys are charged with attempted oral rape. Both deny the charges.</p>



<p>The boys appeared via videolink from a juvenile center, and confirmed their names and ages via a Romanian translator.</p>



<p>Later in the day, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c98p0696r4do"  target="_blank">hundreds of people</a>&mdash;including men, women and children&mdash;peacefully protested the ongoing case in the town centre of Ballymena, raising concerns about the safety of young women and locals.</p>



<p>Separate riots then began in the town on Monday night, as <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-dealing-disorder-ballymena-appeal-calm"  target="_blank">police reported</a> a number of &ldquo;missiles&rdquo; thrown at officers and properties nearby being damaged.</p>



<p>The authorities have referred to the escalated riots as &#8220;<a href="https://x.com/Diarmuid_9/status/1932426877089509630"  target="_blank">racially-motivated</a>&#8221; attacks that are targeting minority ethnic communities.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-dealing-disorder-ballymena-appeal-calm"  target="_blank">Chief Superintendent Sue Steen</a> issued a plea to the public on Monday night, saying: &ldquo;We are urging everyone to remain calm and to act responsibly. Violence and disorder will only place people at greater risk.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Police announced on Tuesday, June 10, that a third person had been arrested in connection with the sexual assault. <a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/third-arrest-police-relation-ballymena-serious-sexual-assault"  target="_blank">PSNI said</a> that the suspect was a 28-year-old man who had been &ldquo;unconditionally released from police custody&rdquo; after questioning.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219104286.jpg" alt="Ballymena Protest" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How long are the riots expected to last?</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/someone-is-going-to-get-killed-appeal-issued-after-six-arrested-on-second-night-of-mindless-violence/a1432369102.html"  target="_blank">Speaking to the BBC&rsquo;s <em>Nolan Show</em></a> on Wednesday, assistant chief constable Ryan Henderson said that he expected the violence to continue &ldquo;in the coming days&rdquo; and urged the public<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0k3le25r8ro"  target="_blank"> to stay home</a> on Wednesday evening.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Sky News correspondent Connor Gillies, who has been in Ballymena, <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/ballymena-protest-fireworks-petrol-bombs-and-glass-bottles-thrown-at-riot-police-as-serious-disorder-deepens-13381896"  target="_blank">said on Wednesday that some families</a> had been &ldquo;barricading themselves&rdquo; in their attics amid the escalating violence. &#8220;The talk here in this town is that it could go on for weeks yet,&#8221; he said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How have police responded?</strong></h2>



<p>In response to the first night of rioting, constable Henderson said <a href="https://x.com/Diarmuid_9/status/1932426877089509630"  target="_blank">during a press conference</a>: &ldquo;This violence was clearly racially-motivated and targeted at our minority ethnic community and the police. It was racist thuggery purely and simply, and any attempt to justify or explain it as anything else is misplaced.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0k3le25r8ro"  target="_blank">The BBC has reported</a> that some households have put up signs signifying the ethnicity or nationality of its residents, seemingly in an effort to remain out of harm&#8217;s way. One photo showed a sign above a door reading &ldquo;Filipino lives here.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-statement-following-third-consecutive-night-disorder"  target="_blank">Henderson appealed</a> for &ldquo;calm voices and cool heads&rdquo; on Thursday after another night of disruption, which once again spread to protests in Belfast, Lisburn, and Antrim. Most of the protests in Belfast, as well as those in Lisburn and Antrim, &ldquo;passed without incident,&rdquo; according to the authorities.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This criminal behaviour has no place on the streets of Northern Ireland and is completely unacceptable. What we witnessed last night has caused fear and huge disruption within our communities, including to our local transport network and community services,&rdquo; Henderson said.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.psni.police.uk/latest-news/police-service-statement-second-night-violence-ballymena"  target="_blank">In a statement</a> released on Wednesday in response to the second night of chaos, chief constable Jon Boutcher called the riots &ldquo;mindless violence&rdquo; and that it was &#8220;deeply concerning and utterly unacceptable.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;These criminal acts not only endanger lives but also risk undermining the ongoing criminal justice process led by the [police] in support of a victim who deserves truth, justice, and protection,&rdquo; Boutcher said. &ldquo;Ironically, and frustratingly, this violence threatens to derail the very pursuit of justice it claims to challenge. Let me be clear: This behaviour must stop. I appeal to everyone involved to cease all further acts of criminality and disorder immediately.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The chief constable also thanked the police officers tasked with handling and responding to the riots, adding that he believes the PSNI is &ldquo;critically underfunded.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Despite operating under immense financial pressure&mdash;far greater than that faced by other public services in Northern Ireland or police forces across the UK and in the Republic of Ireland&mdash;our officers continue to display unwavering professionalism, courage, and resolve,&rdquo; said Boutcher.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219014444.jpg" alt="Ballymena Protest" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What have politicians said about the riots?&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>British Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZU7LWldJjqc"  target="_blank">addressed the riots</a> during Prime Minister&rsquo;s Questions in the House of Commons on Wednesday.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I utterly condemn the violence that we&rsquo;ve seen overnight in Ballymena and in other parts of Northern Ireland,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;It is absolutely vital that PSNI are given the time they need to investigate the incidents concerned rather than face mindless attacks as they seek to bring peace and order to keep people safe.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Northern Ireland Secretary Hilary Benn said: &ldquo;This is not what Northern Ireland is about, this is not what we want the rest of the world to see,&rdquo; on BBC&rsquo;s <em>Good Morning Ulster</em> on Thursday. &ldquo;Whatever views people hold, there is no justification for trying to burn people out of their homes, that is what is going on, and that is what needs to stop because it is shocking and damaging.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Irish T&aacute;naiste [Deputy Prime Minister] Simon Harris has also condemned the rioting. &#8220;The scenes of violence over the last two nights in Ballymena are deeply disturbing. The strong collective calls for the violence and disorder to end immediately must be heeded. There can be no justification for attacks such as these on people&rsquo;s homes or on the police,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/SimonHarrisTD/status/1932802628737491347"  target="_blank">he said</a> on Wednesday.</p>



<p>Michelle O&rsquo;Neill, Northern Ireland&rsquo;s First Minister, has called for an immediate end to &ldquo;the racist and sectarian attacks on families across the North and the rioting in Ballymena.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/moneillsf/status/1932735595475882157/photo/1"  target="_blank">Speaking out via social media</a> on Wednesday morning, she said: &ldquo;No one, now or ever, should feel the need to place a sticker on their door to identify their ethnicity just to avoid being targeted.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218973427.jpg" alt="Ballymena Protest" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Leader of the Northern Irish Unionist Ulster Party <a href="https://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/someone-is-going-to-get-killed-appeal-issued-after-six-arrested-on-second-night-of-mindless-violence/a1432369102.html"  target="_blank">Mike Nesbitt, who also serves as Health Minister, said</a>: &ldquo;There is no justification for this mayhem, and my thoughts are with those who have lost their homes and the greater number who are feeling intimidated and unwelcome. I understand there are community concerns regarding an alleged serious sexual assault. There are legitimate ways to express those concerns. Street violence is not one of them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Sinn F&eacute;in MP (Member of Parliament) John Finucane has condemned the attacks.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The racist attacks on a number of homes near the Ballysillan area last night were abhorrent, and my thoughts are with those families affected. Sickening behaviour such as this has no place in our society,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/johnfinucane/status/1932710366095560723"  target="_blank">Finucane said in a statement</a> shared via social media on Wednesday morning. &ldquo;I will be contacting the families affected to ensure they receive the support they need in the time ahead. Racism, wherever it occurs, must be stamped out and faced down through strong leadership in our communities.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Northern Ireland&rsquo;s Justice Minister Naomi Long has expressed her concerns over the riots. &ldquo;The violence we have witnessed in recent days in Ballymena and other parts of Northern Ireland is appalling, and I urgently appeal for calm throughout our society,&rdquo;<a href="https://x.com/naomi_long/status/1932760824604426643"  target="_blank"> she said</a>. &ldquo;Those responsible do not reflect our communities, and my thoughts are with everyone who has been affected.&rdquo; </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293105/northern-ireland-riots-ballymena-petrol-bombs-police-racist-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The World Is Looking to Europe to &#8216;Resist,&#8217; Says French Foreign Minister</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vivienne Walt / Nice, France]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jean-Noël Barrot speaks to TIME about ocean conservation, Trump, and the future of multilateralism.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292963"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/jean-noel-barrot-french-foreign-minister-oceans-climate-trump-ukraine-gaza-europe-future.jpg" alt="France's Minister for Europe and Foreign Affairs Jean-Noel Barrot addresses the audience during a plenary session on the second day of the United Nations Ocean Conference in Nice, France, on June 10, 2025. "/>



<p>When French President Emmanuel Macron appointed Jean-No&euml;l Barrot last September as his new Minister for Europe and Foreign Affairs&mdash;the fourth during eight years in power&mdash;some feared the 42-year-old economist might be totally eclipsed by the country&rsquo;s kinetic leader. Indeed, Macron has zipped furiously across Europe, the Middle East, and Asia all year, negotiating deals on climate, trade, military assistance, and peace, some of it in an effort to fill an aching vacuum left by Washington. For all that, Barrot, who spent a few years teaching at MIT, has emerged as a fervent voice for his boss&rsquo;s agenda, attempting to give the world a global-minded alternative to an increasingly inward-looking U.S. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>This week, that contrast is on stark display in the sun-baked Provence city of Nice, where thousands are gathered for the U.N.&#8217;s Oceans Conference. The hope is that after five days of talks and speeches, nations will agree to international controls on fishing, deep-sea mining, wildlife conservation, and other issues, in order to stanch the rapid degradation of oceans, crucial to reining in global warming. Delegations of top government officials, presidents, and prime ministers from about 170 countries are among the crowds. Absent: The U.S.</p>



<p>At the end of the hectic opening day on Monday, Barrot sat down with TIME to reflect on the impact of a deeply changed global order, and what can be done.</p>



<p><em>This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>



<p><strong>TIME:</strong> <strong>The U.S. administration is not represented here. Did they decline the invitation, or did they never say whether they were coming?</strong></p>



<p>Barrot: Everyone was invited. This is a U.N. conference, so any U.N. member country is invited to come. But I cannot help but notice that many U.S. organizations are present. We have U.S. scientists. We have the Mayor of New Orleans, the Mayor of New York, the Mayor of Los Angeles.</p>



<p><strong>This is a really crucial global summit. Are you saying it doesn&rsquo;t matter whether the U.S. takes itself out of the whole process? Because of course, it is not just the oceans.</strong></p>



<p>One thing is true: Europe will never give up on multilateralism, on cooperation. We believe it is in the interest of mankind, but it&#8217;s also in our own interests.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing many countries around the world, in Africa, in Latin America, in Southeast Asia, that are looking at France and Europe to resist. They&#8217;re looking at us and expecting us to resist the temptation by some to go back to confrontation, fears of coercion. And it is our intention to build coalitions whenever traditional multilateral forums are not effective, to show that there is only one way to solve the global issues we&#8217;re facing, the consequences of which are going to affect our daily lives, [which] is by multilateral means.</p>



<p><strong>That feels a bit like you&#8217;re climbing uphill. You&#8217;ve got to put together a coalition, and build this multilateralism, without a key player involved</strong>.</p>



<p>No. What I&#8217;m saying is that we will defend multilateralism in all areas. We&#8217;re celebrating the 80th anniversary of the U.N. this year. They built those that came before us. They built a number of multilateral forums for trade, for security, for environment. We&#8217;re going to defend and support these. But at any point in time when they will not be able to deliver results, because some will oppose them from within, then we will find other ways for multilateral forums and cooperation to exist.</p>



<p>The key message is that everyone, every country in the world, is better off with an effective multilateralism. It is not because some countries in the world would like to give up on multilateralism, that we will give up. We will not.</p>



<p><strong>This goes beyond oceans.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I&rsquo;m thinking of international trade, of security, of the security architecture coming out of the Second World War, starting with the U.N. Charter that basically says that there is never any pretext for violence and brute force, except for self defense, and except when the Security Council prescribes it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing these basic principles&mdash;that you don&#8217;t touch my borders and I will not touch yours&mdash;being violated.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>You mean Ukraine?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, and other places in the world. We are seeing the Non-Proliferation Treaty being questioned by some countries that are basically close to acquiring nuclear weapons and creating massive instability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I could mention other global goods, such as health, with the World Health Organization.</p>



<p><strong>So the whole architecture we&#8217;ve relied on for 80 years.</strong></p>



<p>It is weakened. It is going to have to be something new. That is why we&#8217;re pleading in favor of reform of the Security Council at the U.N., to allow India, Brazil, Germany, Japan, and two African countries to become permanent members. [Since 1945 only the U.S., Britain, France, China, and Russia have been permanent members of the Security Council, holding veto power on votes at the U.N.]</p>



<p>If we want international law and multilateral principles to be stronger, we need the institutions to be more representative and legitimate.</p>



<p><strong>People have been calling for this for a long time, and it&rsquo;s never happened. Do you see an opportunity now, given what terrible shape multilateralism is in?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I think history is accelerating. And for all those who believe in this legacy that came out of the ruins of the Second World War, and that feel responsible for transferring &nbsp;to the next generation the global architecture that does not prevent all countries from having anything bad happen, that has prevented so many of these things over the past decades&mdash;if we want this to survive, it&#8217;s time to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>There are two wars that seem to have no end date. How do you see this ending in Ukraine and in Gaza?</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>So in Gaza, we are calling for an immediate ceasefire. Liberation of hostages held by Hamas and unhindered access of humanitarian help to Gaza.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But then, the only alternative to a permanent state of war is a political solution resting on two states living side by side with security guarantees. This is what we&#8217;re working on in the perspective of the conference that will be taking place in a few days [a U.N. conference in New York on June 18], removing all the obstacles on the path towards such a political solution, because we believe it to be in the interests of the Israeli people, of the Palestinian people&mdash;and therefore, in our interests as well, as Europeans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For Ukraine, we need Vladimir Putin to cease fire and to agree to enter into peace negotiations that will comply with the principles of the U.N. Charter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since he doesn&#8217;t seem to be sending any signal that he&#8217;s willing to do that, we&#8217;re going to build up significant pressure, by coordinating with the efforts <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/07/lindsey-graham-russia-sanctions-bill-trade-embargo-00393297"  target="_blank">led by the U.S. senators</a> to adopt in the next few days a new package of sanctions, targeted to force Putin, allowing for peace negotiation to start.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>And military security guarantees from Europe too?</strong></p>



<p>We need a ceasefire for discussions to start, and then, of course, those discussions will have [to] come to the question of territories and security guarantees.</p>



<p><strong>You think you could go ahead without the U.S., or you think that the U.S. will finally come on board?</strong></p>



<p>The most important point is for Ukraine to be able to deter any further aggression. This starts with strengthening their own army. A strong army is in itself a powerful deterrent. There are various possible formulas and scenarios that I don&#8217;t want to present here, some of which indeed include some form of contribution by the U.S.</p>



<p><strong>Getting back to the oceans: President Macron told the conference the </strong><a href="https://time.com/7292295/whats-at-stake-un-global-ocean-conference/" ><strong>oceans &lsquo;are not for sale.&rsquo;</strong></a><strong> Everyone, myself included, understood that to refer to President Trump&rsquo;s executive order allowing deep-sea mining.</strong></p>



<p>On this, there&#8217;s no surprise. We&#8217;ve brought together a coalition of more than 30 countries that request a moratorium, or at the very least to apply a precautionary principle to the exploitation of deep seas, and that supports international efforts by the International Seabed Authority to draft a mining code. So it&#8217;s no surprise [that] when we&#8217;ve seen recent decisions allowing exploitation of the seabed that we would voice our opposition. We&#8217;re saying it today and we&#8217;ll say it in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>But what do you do if the U.S. simply goes ahead and effectively violates international law?</strong> <strong>What&#8217;s your recourse?</strong></p>



<p>Our mission here in Nice is to highlight the risks of indulging in such seabed exploitation without first taking the time to explore its resources and draft legislation that is going to preserve the resources of the ocean and allow for economic activity with and from the ocean. That&#8217;s the only way to make such sort of ocean-based economic activity acceptable and sustainable.</p>



<p><strong>Do you have international law to enforce that?</strong> <strong>I mean, at the moment, the enforcement mechanism is a little bit lacking.</strong></p>



<p>No. The International Seabed Authority is in the process of drafting a mining code. We support this effort. As far as the high seas is concerned, there is absolutely no regulation. This <a href="https://www.un.org/bbnjagreement/en"  target="_blank">Treaty on the High Seas</a> [a U.N.-negotiated document which several countries are ratifying in Nice this week] is going to initiate the process. It is going to end up with regulation of 50% of the planet [the oceans] that is subject to absolutely no law, nor any regulation.</p>



<p>That adds to various announcements regarding marine protected areas, decarbonization of transportation, the creation of an international organization for the science of the ocean, and the creation of a global coalition of cities and regions. The world is basically taking its destiny in its hands and acting for the ocean.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>But not the U.S.?</strong></p>



<p>Everywhere I&rsquo;m walking in Nice I am seeing the presence of U.S. scientists, U.S. mayors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We still have some work to do to keep raising awareness, so that everyone around the world understands that there is only one ocean, and that our future is pretty much &mdash; very much &mdash; connected to it.</p>



<p>If we don&#8217;t act with resolution, the ocean that is our friend and ally can also become an adversary, especially for countries that have coastlines that are exposed to the rising sea levels.</p>



<p>This is the biggest ever conference organized on the ocean. We had 4,000 people in 2017 in New York [the first U.N. Oceans Conference], 7,000 in Lisbon in 2022, and over 100,000 people in Nice.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>President Macron is going to Greenland this weekend. Why?</strong></p>



<p>Greenland is European territory. He will be there with the Prime Minister of Denmark. We&#8217;ve been saying repeatedly that European borders are not negotiable. So it&#8217;s a way to reaffirm this principle, but also to strengthen our cooperation with Greenland. We intend to enhance those links, from scientific cooperation to economic cooperation.</p>



<p><strong>Is it a message to the U.S. president too?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s more of a message to Greenland. And the testament to our friendship as well.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292963/jean-noel-barrot-interview-france-oceans-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292963</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the U.K. and Allies Sanctioned Israeli Ministers Ben-Gvir and Smotrich—and What Comes Next</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 20:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.K. and allies sanctioned Israeli ministers for inciting violence and expanding settlements in the occupied West Bank.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292990"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2155281904.jpg" alt="Israeli Cabinet Members At Odds Over Proposed Ceasefire Deal"/>



<p>The U.K. and several allies <a href="https://x.com/FCDOGovUK/status/1932440082046189723"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">have imposed sanctions</a> on Israeli ministers Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich, accusing the two far-right politicians of inciting violence against Palestinians in the occupied West Bank.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/global-affairs/news/2025/06/canada-imposes-fourth-round-of-sanctions-on-facilitators-of-extremist-settler-violence-against-civilians-in-west-bank.html"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Canada</a>, <a href="https://www.foreignminister.gov.au/minister/penny-wong/media-release/joint-statement-foreign-ministers-australia-canada-new-zealand-norway-and-united-kingdom-measures-targeting-itamar-ben-gvir-and-bezalel-smotrich"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Australia</a>, New Zealand, and Norway joined the U.K. in imposing a travel ban on Ben-Gvir&mdash;Israel&rsquo;s national security minister and a West Bank settler&mdash;and Finance Minister Smotrich. The five governments also froze any assets either may have in their countries.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich have incited extremist violence and serious abuses of Palestinian human rights. These actions are not acceptable,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/DavidLammy/status/1932450814595117306"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a> British Foreign Secretary David Lammy. &ldquo;This is why we have taken action now &ndash; to hold those responsible to account.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The British government&nbsp;<a href="https://news.sky.com/video/foreign-secretary-david-lammy-confirms-sanctions-on-israeli-ministers-over-inciting-violence-13381736"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">reaffirmed</a>&nbsp;its support for a two-state solution and described the ongoing violence against Palestinians in the West Bank as &ldquo;completely unacceptable.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The sanctions come as the U.K. and other European nations increase pressure on Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu&rsquo;s government to lift the blockade on aid into Gaza, where humanitarian experts warn that famine is imminent.</p>



<p>&#8220;Britain has already tried once to prevent us from settling the cradle of our homeland, and we cannot do it again,&rdquo; responded Smotrich, referring to a 1939 British document limiting Jewish migration. &ldquo;We are determined God willing to continue building,&#8221; Smotrich added, speaking at the inauguration of a new settlement in the Hebron Hills.</p>



<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar condemned the sanctions as &ldquo;outrageous,&rdquo; adding that the government would convene a special meeting to determine its response to what he called an &ldquo;unacceptable decision.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the sanctions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the sanctions mean for Ben-Gvir and Smotrich</strong></h2>



<p>The British Foreign Office <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-and-partners-unite-to-sanction-ministers-inciting-west-bank-violence"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a> the sanctions imposed on Ben-Gvir and Smotrich were effective immediately due to their &ldquo;repeated incitement of violence against Palestinian civilians.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Israeli cabinet ministers are now subject to a U.K. travel ban, will have any assets in the country frozen, and are barred from directing, managing or promoting a British company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Foreign Office called on the Israeli government to crack down on settler violence against Palestinians in the West Bank, and emphasized that &ldquo;measures today cannot be seen in isolation from events in Gaza, where Israel must uphold international humanitarian law.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In May, the British government announced it was <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/20/uk-suspends-trade-talks-with-israel-repellant-extremism"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">suspending negotiations</a> with Israel on a prospective trade agreement.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2216570861.jpg" alt="ISRAEL-PALESTINIAN-CONFLICT-JERUSALEM DAY" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What led to the sanctions?</strong></h2>



<p>On May 19, Prime Minister Keir Starmer joined Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau and French President Emmanuel Macron <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/joint-statement-from-the-leaders-of-the-united-kingdom-france-and-canada-on-the-situation-in-gaza-and-the-west-bank"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">in signing a joint statement</a> condemning both Israel&rsquo;s blockade of humanitarian aid into Gaza and the expansion of settlements in the West Bank.</p>



<p>An estimated&nbsp;<a href="https://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/jewish-settlements-population-1970-present"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">529,455 Jewish settlers</a>&nbsp;currently live in&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7289555/israel-expansion-settlements-west-bank/?utm_source=chatgpt.com"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">settlements</a>&nbsp;in the West Bank, excluding those living in East Jerusalem. The United Nations considers these settlements&nbsp;<a href="https://www.un.org/unispal/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/The-Status-of-Jerusalem-Engish-199708.pdf"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">illegal under international law</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Violence against Palestinians in the West Bank has escalated since the October 7, 2023, Hamas terror attack on Israel, during which militants killed approximately 1,200 people and took around 250 others hostage.</p>



<p>Between Jan. 1, 2024, and April 30, 2025, at least 616 Palestinians, including 115 children, had been killed by settlers or the Israeli military according to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ochaopt.org/content/west-bank-monthly-snapshot-casualties-property-damage-and-displacement-april-2025"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">U.N. Office for Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</a></p>



<p>In the same period, OCHA recorded 1,936 incidents of violence toward Palestinians, with 41,272 being displaced in the West Bank.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who are Ben-Gvir and Smotrich?</strong></h2>



<p>Cabinet members Itamar Ben-Gvir and Bezalel Smotrich lead far-right parties that had been regarded as outside the mainstream of Israeli politics until Benjamin Netanyahu invited them into a <a href="https://main.knesset.gov.il/en/mk/government/pages/governments.aspx?govid=37"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">ruling coalition</a>&mdash;which they now hold the power to disband. </p>



<p>Smotrich&rsquo;s Religious Zionism party holds 14 seats in the 120-seat Knesset while Ben-Gvir&rsquo;s Otzma Yehudit party holds six.</p>



<p>The two ministers are known for their far-right political views and strong support for Israeli settlement expansion in the West Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Smotrich, born in the occupied Golan Heights in 1980, has repeatedly called for Israeli settlers to return to Gaza.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On May 30, Smotrich&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7289555/israel-expansion-settlements-west-bank/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced plans to establish 22 new settlements</a>&nbsp;in the West Bank&mdash;a move widely regarded as illegal under international law.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/bezalelsm/status/1927960845625000276"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">He called the expansion</a>&nbsp;a &ldquo;historic decision,&rdquo; saying, &ldquo;We have succeeded in creating a profound strategic change, returning the State of Israel to a path of construction, Zionism, and vision.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2023-01-16/ty-article/.premium/israels-far-right-finance-minister-im-a-fascist-homophobe-but-i-wont-stone-gays/00000185-b921-de59-a98f-ff7f47c70000"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Self-described</a>&nbsp;as a &ldquo;fascist homophobe,&rdquo; Smotrich has previously advocated for government&nbsp;<a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2016-05-06/ty-article/smotrich-if-israel-took-revenge-on-palestinians-thered-be-no-jewish-attacks/0000017f-f686-d318-afff-f7e752e20000"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">reprisal attacks on Palestinians</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/lawmaker-backs-segregated-jewish-arab-maternity-wards/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">supported segregated maternity wards</a>&nbsp;for Jewish and Arab mothers.</p>



<p>Itamar Ben-Gvir, Israel&rsquo;s national security minister, has a long history of far-right activism.</p>



<p>A former disciple of the extremist Rabbi Meir Kahane, Ben-Gvir was known in his youth for his&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/02/27/itamar-ben-gvir-israels-minister-of-chaos"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">affiliation with Kach</a>, a Jewish supremacist group outlawed in both Israel and the United States as a terrorist organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By his early 30s, he had been convicted of incitement to racism and supporting a terrorist organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though he has since rebranded himself as a mainstream political figure, Ben-Gvir continues to advocate for hardline policies against Palestinians and is a vocal proponent of expanding Israeli settlements in the West Bank.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292990</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mahrang Baloch Writes From Prison: &#8216;Speaking Up for Justice Is Not a Crime&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mahrang Baloch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 17:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIME 100 Next]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pakistan arrested Mahrang Baloch for her human rights work in Balochistan.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292408"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Mahrang-Baloch.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-PAKISTAN-POLITICS-UNREST-RIGHTS-BALOCH-PROTEST"/>



<p>It has been more than two and a half months since I was <a href="https://time.com/7271141/pakistan-jails-mahrang-baloch-human-rights-activist/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thrown into prison</a>&mdash;Hudda Prison, in Quetta, Pakistan, the same place father was caged nearly two decades ago, also for promoting the rights of the people of Balochistan.</p>



<p>Since my arrest, Pakistan&#8217;s state secuity agencies have deployed every tactic to break me. I have been offered a deal: stay silent, avoid political activity, and you can be home. I refused. The state has failed to produce a single piece of evidence linking me to any act of violence or criminality. The only &#8220;proof&#8221; they cite is a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15y08Sg9jMs"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">press conference</a> I gave a few days before my March 22 arrest.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>I spoke to reporters after armed militants had <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy0d5y9ew24o"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">hijacked a train </a>and held 300 passengers hostage for hours. The attack occurred in the Balochistan, the largest province in Pakistan, and was carried out by Baloch separatists who have been fighting with the state for decades. At the press conference, I spoke not to defend the hijackers&mdash;our movement, the Baloch Yakjehti [Unity] Committee, has always renounced violence. Indeed, my intention was to draw a distinction between those who confront the state with arms and those who confront it with words.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s a crucial distinction, one the state prefers to blur. In Pakistan, &ldquo;terrorist&rdquo; is a label pinned on anyone who advocates for Baloch rights. Those who speak up run the <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2025/03/pakistan-systematic-attacks-and-relentless-crackdown-on-baloch-activists-must-end/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">risk of arrest</a> by military and intelligence agencies. After their arrest, they might never be seen again. If they are, it is often as a body, produced after a violent incident like the train attack.<br><br>This was why I asked reporters:  Who were the more than two dozen &ldquo;unidentified&rdquo; bodies brought to Quetta&#8217;s Civil Hospital after the hijacking? And why were 13 of them buried overnight without being named? The attackers, the Baloch Liberation Army, had released pictures and details of the 12 militants it said were killed. The identities of the rest were a mystery, but we had our suspicions. In Balochistan it is common practice, after violent episodes, for the forcibly disappeared persons to be put to death, and their bodies produced as those of militants.</p>



<p>I demanded DNA testing of those who had been buried in the dead of night. Families of the disappeared feared, with good reason, that their loved ones were among them.<br><br><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7271141/pakistan-jails-mahrang-baloch-human-rights-activist/" ><em>Pakistan Jails Baloch Human Rights Activist</em></a></p>



<p>So I am in jail for insisting on the distinction between peaceful activism and violence.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Mahrang-Baloch2.jpg" alt="PAKISTAN-UNREST-BALOCHISTAN-RIGHTS" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>My work had already drawn unwelcome international attention. In May 2024, Pakistani officials were outraged after I visited Norway at the invitation of <a href="https://wexfo.no/2025/04/29/why-norway-must-speak-up-for-dr-mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank">PEN Norway,</a> the Norwegian branch of PEN International and the World Expression Forum. I was even harassed on Norwegian soil by individuals linked to Pakistan&#8217;s embassy in Oslo, whose intervention was ended by the Norwegian domestic security agency, PST. When I returned to Pakistan, I was immediately charged with sedition, and treated as if I had returned from an ISIS camp in Syria or Iraq rather than one of the most peace-loving countries in the world.</p>



<p>In October, the government&#8217;s smear campaigns amplified with my inclusion on the <a href="https://time.com/7023541/mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TIME100 Next Emerging Leaders</a>. I was called &ldquo;Malala 2&rdquo; and a Western puppet. Surveillance around me intensified, and I was placed on the Fourth Schedule, an anti-terror watch list typically reserved for hardened militants, and which restricts the movement and activities of the listed. <a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I was barred</a> from travelling abroad.</p>



<p>I am learning the price of peaceful activism.</p>



<p>For decades, Pakistan has kept the rest of the country, and the world, in the dark about Balochistan. It remains an information black hole. Among those the military and intelligence agencies have <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2011/mar/29/balochistan-pakistans-secret-dirty-war"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">forcibly disappeared, killed, or forced into exile</a> are journalists who dare to write about these atrocities. According to the Balochistan Union of Journalists, more than 40 have been killed since 2000. Foreign media are <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/declan-walsh-expelled"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">denied </a>access to the region.</p>



<p>From this darkness, a woman leading a grassroots movement for Baloch rights was unacceptable. The hostility of the state intensified with the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/resources/idt-4f79d09b-655a-42f8-82b4-9b2ecebab611"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">BBC&#8217;s 100 Women list</a>, and a nomination for the Nobel Peace Prize. But if international pressure has prevented my being killed, I face psychological warfare, threats, and the constant spectre of danger.</p>



<p>I write this the day my sister told me that the Islamic State of Khorasan (ISIS-K) released a 100-page Urdu-language booklet accusing me of being a Western agent. Their &#8220;evidence&#8221;?  The TIME <a href="https://time.com/collections/time100-next-gala-2024/7276600/time100-next-gala-toasts-2024/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">honor</a> and Norway trip. Other BYC leaders are in jail with me: Sabghat Ullah Shah Jee, Beebarg Zehri (a disabled man), Gulzadi, and Beebow. I tell them: We are not the first to be imprisoned for demanding peace, justice, and rights. From Nelson Mandela to <a href="https://narges.foundation/two-months-of-detention-the-narges-foundation-calls-for-the-immediate-release-of-dr-mahrang-baloch/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Narges Mohammadi</a>, we walk the same path. We draw strength from their courage, intellect, and defiance.</p>



<p>Our movement is rooted in peace. We speak against enforced disappearances, extrajudicial killings, forced displacement, and the systematic denial of basic rights to the Baloch. We are the rightful owners of the <a href="https://www.dw.com/en/why-chinese-investment-is-stoking-anger-in-pakistans-balochistan-province/a-54188705"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Saindak Copper-Gold Project</a> (worth billions of dollars, but the profits are not shared with the local population), the Reko Diq mine (<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/pakistans-reko-diq-mine-generate-74-billion-free-cash-flow-over-37-years-barrick-2025-01-20/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">estimated </a>to hold copper and gold reserves worth over $60 billion, but the benefits are not reaching the Baloch people), and Gwadar &mdash; the gateway to the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor. Yet, 70% of Balochistan&#8217;s population lives below the poverty line.<br><a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/" ><br></a><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7071983/mahrang-baloch-pakistan-prevented-from-traveling/" ><em>Pakistan Bars Activist From Traveling to </em>TIME<em> Event Honoring Her</em></a><br><br>The state is offended and brands us terrorists and violent. But we are not violent. The state is armed, powerful, and ruthless. It uses violence to silence those who ask for justice. The practices once reserved for the Baloch, considered lesser citizens, are now expanding to other parts of Pakistan. <a href="https://time.com/6693147/pakistan-election-results-imran-khan-pti-military/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Former Prime Minister Imran Khan</a> and his party are now under the military&#8217;s wrath. He is jailed. Is Imran Khan also a terrorist? Are members of his PTI party now &#8220;agents of hostile agencies&#8221;?</p>



<p>If the Pakistan Army and its intelligence agencies are as competent as they claim to be, why have they failed to present a single piece of credible proof? Why have they not held a fair, transparent trial?</p>



<p>Because this isn&#8217;t about the law; it&#8217;s about fear, their fear of our truth.</p>



<p>This prison is more than bricks and bars. It carries the <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250417-mahrang-baloch-a-child-of-the-resistance-for-pakistan-s-ethnic-minority"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">memory of my father</a>. As a child, I visited him here. I didn&#8217;t grow up playing with toys. I grew up holding posters of my father, who was detained and then disappeared. When I turned eighteen, I received his lifeless, tortured, bullet-riddled body. This is not just my story. It&#8217;s the story of every child in Balochistan. Childhood here is shaped by grief, fear, and posters of the disappeared.</p>



<p>When our generation came of age, those of us raised in the shadows of state violence, we vowed: No child after us should suffer the same fate. We are fully aware of the power imbalance between us and a nuclear-armed state. It controls the media. It runs smear campaigns. It weaponizes the judiciary. It deploys overwhelming force. It controls the parliament. It operates proxy groups and armed militias.</p>



<p>Our confinement is part of a war of narratives.</p>



<p>Speaking up for justice is not a crime.</p>



<p>Raising our voices against state violence is not treason.</p>



<p>Demanding rights is not terrorism.</p>



<p>It is humanity.</p>



<p>And one day, we believe, this struggle will succeed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292408/mahrang-baloch-arrest-balochistan-pakistan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292408</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Austria Has Some of the Most Relaxed Gun Ownership Laws in Europe</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Solcyré Burga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Austria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Austria ranks 12th in the world for gun ownership.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292837"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218904840.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-AUSTRIA-SHOOTING-SCHOOL"/>



<p>A <a href="https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/" >school shooting in Graz, Austria</a> left at least nine people dead and 12 injured Tuesday, prompting renewed attention to the country&rsquo;s relatively permissive gun laws. </p>



<p>The attack marks Austria&rsquo;s deadliest mass shooting in its postwar history and the first major incident of its kind since 2020.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932402453317894165"  target="_blank">Authorities said</a> the suspected gunman, who was found dead at the scene, used two firearms that were legally registered under a valid license. Local media <a href="https://kurier.at/chronik/steiermark/graz-dreierschuetzengasse-schule-amoklauf-toter/403048807"  target="_blank">has</a> <a href="https://www.krone.at/3808844"  target="_blank">reported</a> that the suspect was a former student, aged 22. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Austrian Chancellor Christian Stocker gave his condolences to the families of the victims, calling the shooting a national tragedy and a &ldquo;dark day in [the] history of our country&rdquo; in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g00Xp9WEazg"  target="_blank">a press briefing</a> Tuesday. The identities of the victims have not yet been released.</p>



<p>The government has declared a three-day period of national mourning. A nationwide minute of silence is scheduled for 10 a.m. local time Wednesday.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gun ownership rates</h2>



<p>Austria ranks among the highest in Europe for civilian gun ownership, with approximately 30 guns per 100 residents, <a href="https://www.smallarmssurvey.org/sites/default/files/resources/SAS-BP-Civilian-Firearms-Numbers.pdf"  target="_blank">according to the 2017 Small Arms Survey</a>, a Geneva research group. While countries such as Cyprus, Finland, and Iceland report slightly higher rates, Austria remains an outlier in the continent.  </p>



<p>At a global level, Austria ranks <a href="https://www.smallarmssurvey.org/sites/default/files/resources/SAS-BP-Civilian-Firearms-Numbers.pdf"  target="_blank">12th in the world</a> for gun ownership, though significantly lagging behind the country with the highest rate: the United States. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">History of mass shootings in Austria</h2>



<p>The country has recorded two public mass shootings in the period between 2000 and 2022, <a href="https://rockinst.org/blog/public-mass-shootings-around-the-world-prevalence-context-and-prevention/"  target="_blank">according to research by the Rockefeller Institute of Government</a>. The most recent incident occurred in <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-54798508"  target="_blank">November 2020</a>, when a gunman killed four people and wounded 23 others. Last year, authorities said they thwarted a planned attack targeting a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna. </p>



<p>By contrast, there were more than 500 mass shootings recorded in the U.S. in 2024, <a href="https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/"  target="_blank">according to the Gun Violence Archive</a>, which defines such incidents as those involving four or more people shot, either injured or killed, excluding the perpetrator. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7278187/forgotten-half-of-americas-gun-crisis/" ><em>My Dad&rsquo;s Death and the Forgotten Half of America&rsquo;s Gun Crisis</em></a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who is allowed to possess and carry a firearm in Austria?</h2>



<p>Austria has some of the most liberal firearm regulations in Europe. Residents aged 18 or older are permitted to own a firearm, with some exceptions allowing 16-year-olds to acquire guns for hunting purposes. All firearms must be registered within six weeks of acquisition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To possess and carry handguns, repeating shotguns, or semi-automatic firearms&mdash;provided they are not classified as war material or prohibited weapons&mdash;individuals must obtain an official permit. </p>



<p><a href="https://www.ris.bka.gv.at/GeltendeFassung.wxe?Abfrage=Bundesnormen&amp;Gesetzesnummer=10006016"  target="_blank">Federal law</a> prohibits people from possessing weapons or ammunition if they could endanger the &ldquo;life, health or freedom&rdquo; of individuals or their property. Those considered legally &ldquo;unreliable&rdquo; &mdash;including individuals with a history of alcoholism, addiction, or mental illness&mdash;are barred from owning and carrying firearms. The same applies to those who have been convicted of a criminal act involving the use or threat of violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Authorities have an obligation to conduct an &#8220;assessment of reliability.&rdquo; Federal law says that individuals who do not have a hunting license must &ldquo;provide an expert opinion stating whether they have a tendency to handle weapons carelessly or use them recklessly, particularly when under psychological stress.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gun owners are required to carry their permit documents when carrying or transporting firearms.</p>



<p>The Austrian government <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC1971203/"  target="_blank">tightened its firearm regulations</a> in 1997, in line with a European Council directive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Visitors from other European Union member states in possession of a firearm must bring a European firearms pass and a permit related to the specific weapon they are carrying, <a href="https://www.bmf.gv.at/en/topics/customs/travellers/prohibitions-and-restrictions-on-imports/carrying-weapons.html"  target="_blank">according to Austria&rsquo;s Federal Ministry</a>. The country also has an existing ban on the import of weapons such as pump-action shotguns.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292837</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>At Least 10 Dead After School Shooting in Austria, Police Say</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 12:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7292668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mayor of Graz says presumed gunman among the dead as local media report 28 people are being treated for injuries. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7292668"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218892094.jpg" alt="AUSTRIA-SHOOTING-SCHOOL"/>



<p>At least 10 people are dead <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/ced27g4e6xwo"  target="_blank">following a mass shooting</a> at the BORG Dreiersch&uuml;tzengasse high school in Graz, Austria, according to <a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932402453317894165"  target="_blank">state police</a>.</p>



<p>Among the dead were <a href="https://www.polizei.gv.at/stmk/presse/aussendungen/presse.aspx?prid=546232672F564F326D57773D&amp;pro=0"  target="_blank">eight students</a>, one adult, and the suspected gunman in the deadliest mass shooting in Austria&rsquo;s postwar history. Twelve others were injured. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Austrian Chancellor Christian Stocker called the shooting a national tragedy and a &ldquo;dark day in [the] history of our country&rdquo; in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g00Xp9WEazg"  target="_blank">a press briefing</a> Tuesday.</p>



<p>Police said the gunman, believed to be 21 years old, is thought to have acted alone. The identities of the victims have not yet been released.</p>



<p>Austrian Interior Minister Gerhard Karner <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/what-we-know-so-far-about-school-shooting-in-austria-13381583?dcmp=snt-sf-twitter"  target="_blank">confirmed</a> that the suspect was a former student at the school who did not graduate. <a href="https://www.polizei.gv.at/stmk/presse/aussendungen/presse.aspx?prid=546232672F564F326D57773D&amp;pro=0"  target="_blank">Authorities also said</a> the firearms used in the attack were legally obtained and owned.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7292837/austria-shooting-gun-ownership-laws/" >Why Austria Has Some of the Most Relaxed Gun Ownership Laws in Europe</a></em></p>



<p>The suspected gunman reportedly carried a pistol and a shotgun, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/one-person-killed-attack-austrian-school-media-report-2025-06-10/"  target="_blank">opening fire in two classrooms</a> before taking his own life in a bathroom at the school.</p>



<p>Special forces were among those sent to the school after police received a phone call at 10 a.m. local time in Austria&rsquo;s second largest city. </p>



<p>Police <a href="https://x.com/PolizeiStmk/status/1932401810628882663"  target="_blank">said</a> that students from the high school would be taken to the local ASK&Ouml; Stadium, where they can then be picked up by parents and relatives.</p>



<p>The government has declared a three-day period of national mourning. A nationwide minute of silence is scheduled for 10 a.m. local time Wednesday.</p>



<p>Tuesday&rsquo;s incident is the first significant mass shooting in Austria since November 2020, when a 20-year-old gunman <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-54798508"  target="_blank">killed four people</a> and injured 23 others. Islamic State later claimed responsibility for the attack. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7292668/austria-graz-school-shooting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7292668</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
