<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:39:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Trump Veers From Victory Lap to Expletive-Laced Rant as Ceasefire Proves Fragile</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The profanity exposed Trump’s increasing irritation with Israel in particular]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297315"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221176644.jpg" alt="US President Donald Trump departs White House for NATO Summit"/>



<p>In 12 hours, President Trump veered from crowing about a huge foreign policy <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >victory</a> to swearing in <a href="https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/" >frustration</a> on the South Lawn. The ceasefire between Iran and Israel he had proudly announced the evening before&mdash;going so far as to tell a reporter it might last &#8220;<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-expects-israel-iran-ceasefire-last-forever-rcna214660"  target="_blank">forever</a>&#8220;&mdash;was already wavering.</p>



[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]

<p>The President had been posting on social media up until 1 a.m., alternating between praising himself for landing a peace deal and writing all caps messages demanding Israel and Iran adhere to it. But in the morning, Israel and Iran accused each other of violating the shaky agreement. By the time he came across reporters gathered to see him depart the White House to attend the <a href="https://time.com/7295448/rutte-nato-secretary-general-interview/" >NATO Summit</a> in The Hague, he was visibly angry. &ldquo;I&#8217;m not happy with Iran, but I&#8217;m really not happy with Israel,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;We basically have two countries that have been fighting so long and so hard that they don&rsquo;t know what the f&#8211;k they&rsquo;re doing.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The profanity exposed Trump&rsquo;s increasing irritation with Israel hesitating to back down from the fight when he wanted them to silence their guns, says Timothy Naftali, a Presidential historian at Columbia School of International and Public Affairs. &ldquo;Swearing at the Iranians is not a surprise, but swearing at the Israelis is very interesting,&rdquo; Naftali says. &ldquo;Most Presidents, because of the power of the office, work through their team and choose their words carefully because they know they carry enormous weight&mdash;this President is unfiltered.&rdquo;</p>



<p>That lack of filter has led to Trump sending mixed signals in the previous few days, including suggesting <a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >regime change in Iran</a> might be a good idea and then backing away from it. On Tuesday, he told reporters on Air Force One that pushing to topple the Islamic government in Iran would bring &ldquo;chaos.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It was a dizzying turn of events&mdash;both in the Middle East and for the White House, as Trump appears to be losing patience with the main players in a hair-trigger war that had already led to him launching a <a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >rare B-2 bombing raid</a> against Iranian nuclear sites. His statements to reporters and online Tuesday morning suggested he is interested in focusing his, and the country&rsquo;s, attention on other matters. </p>



<p>The fragile ceasefire appeared to come about quickly late Monday,<strong> </strong>after Iran retaliated to the U.S. airstrike with a dangerous but largely symbolic volley of ballistic missiles targeting major U.S. base in Qatar. Trump announced a ceasefire Monday evening, even as Iran and Israel appeared to still be deciding just what exactly that would look like.</p>



<p>Trump told reporters Tuesday morning he &ldquo;didn&rsquo;t like&rdquo; that Israel &ldquo;unloaded&rdquo; on Iran after the deal was made and hours before the formal ceasefire went into effect. In addition, he said Iran fired a rocket that missed its target after the negotiated time limit and Israel responded by launching planes for a bombing run<strong>.</strong> &ldquo;These guys got to calm down. Ridiculous,&rdquo; Trump said.</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s brash communication style at this sensitive moment is &ldquo;a double-edged sword&rdquo; says Lauren Wright, a political scientist at Princeton University. &ldquo;The public appreciates the directness and the transparency,&rdquo; Wright says. &ldquo;Of course, when you&rsquo;re talking about people&rsquo;s lives being at stake, including American service members, when you&rsquo;re talking about bombing campaigns, there&rsquo;s nothing more serious that a President could talk about.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But the public and other world leaders have come to expect brazen statements from Trump. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s very few things he could say that would be damaging to his reputation. They have come to know how he speaks, and it applies to the most serious of foreign policy issues and it applies to the most casual of topics and conversations,&rdquo; Wright says.</p>



<p>In another sign that Trump is trying to keep Iran on board with a peace deal, Trump announced Tuesday morning that he was lifting some sanctions on Chinese companies that buy oil from Iran. &ldquo;China can now continue to purchase Oil from Iran. Hopefully, they will be purchasing plenty from the U.S., also,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social. In April, the Trump administration sanctioned a Chinese oil refinery accused of processing Iranian oil. At the time, the Trump administration said the money Iran earned from the oil sales was being used to fund terrorist proxy groups in the Middle East.</p>



<p>Trump signaled on social media Tuesday that he wants to spend more of his time and effort on other priorities, such as pressuring Congress to pass a <a href="https://time.com/7296762/big-beautiful-bill-byrd-rule/" >&ldquo;Big, Beautiful Bill&rdquo;</a> that would extend his 2017 tax cuts and beef up immigration enforcement, and negotiating with Russian President Vladimir Putin to end the war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Aboard Air Force One as he flew over the Atlantic for the NATO Summit in The Hague, Trump seemed eager to declare his work done in negotiating peace between Israel and Iran. &ldquo;Now that we have made PEACE abroad, we must finish the job here at home by passing &lsquo;THE GREAT, BIG, BEAUTIFUL BILL,&rsquo; and getting the Bill to my desk, ASAP,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social. &ldquo;NO ONE GOES ON VACATION UNTIL IT&rsquo;S DONE,&rdquo; Trump wrote, insisting that representatives and senators not leave Washington for summer recess until the bill is passed. As much as Trump wants to move on from the conflict in the Middle East, whether the war winds down will largely depend on the leaders in Israel and Iran, and events outside of his control.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297315</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Down the Environmental Risks From Strikes on Iran&#8217;s Nuclear Enrichment Sites</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297135/environmental-risks-bombing-iran-nuclear-enrichment-sites/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297135/environmental-risks-bombing-iran-nuclear-enrichment-sites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Kluger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 13:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. attack on Iran's nuclear enrichment sites poses minimum radiation danger.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297135"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297135/environmental-risks-bombing-iran-nuclear-enrichment-sites/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220642625.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-US-IRAN-ISRAEL-CONFLICT-TRUMP"/>



<p>There is all manner of geopolitical and military fallout likely to come from the U.S. bombing of Iranian nuclear enrichment sites on June 21. What worries a lot of people more, however, is the literal fallout&mdash;the radioactive contamination that could be released when massive, bunker-buster munitions are dropped on facilities said to contain more than <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/statements/iaea-director-general-grossis-statement-to-unsc-on-situation-in-iran-20-june-2025"  target="_blank">400</a> kg (880 lbs.) of enriched uranium. Demolishing the sites, so the thinking goes, could have the same effect as detonating a so-called dirty bomb&mdash;a piece of non-fissile ordnance that spreads dangerous radioactive material across a large footprint of land and expanse of sky.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>But that fear is unfounded, say experts. &ldquo;The attack on the enrichment sites in Iran doesn&#8217;t pose the same hazard as an accident with a functioning nuclear reactor,&rdquo; says Simon Middleburgh, professor of Nuclear Engineering at the Nuclear Futures Institute at Bangor University, U.K. Any contamination is likely to be local, Middleburgh explains, because enrichment doesn&rsquo;t involve fission, which is what presents the real peril when handling radioactive materials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that&rsquo;s not to say there is no danger at all. While radioactive poisoning may be held in check, chemical poisoning&mdash;toxic exposure to gasses produced during nuclear enrichment&mdash;is another matter.</p>



<p>&ldquo;No increase in off-site radiation levels was reported,&rdquo; said Rafael Mariono Grossi, director general of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/statements/iaea-director-generals-introductory-statement-to-the-board-of-governors-23-june-2025"  target="_blank">in a June 23 statement</a> about the state of the attack sites. &ldquo;[T]he main concern is chemical toxicity.&rdquo; However much contamination has been released, Grossi added, the U.S. and Israel must choose any future targets carefully, especially taking pains to steer wide of Iran&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/world/nuclear-watchdog-warns-of-serious-catastrophe-if-israel-targets-iran-s-bushehr-reactor/ar-AA1H89rS"  target="_blank">Bushehr Nuclear Power Plant</a>, the Middle East&rsquo;s first civilian nuclear reactor. </p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/7296218/israel-iran-climate-change/" >What Conflict in the Middle East Means for Climate Change</a></em></p>



<p>&ldquo;I want to make it absolutely and completely clear,&rdquo; Grossi warned, &ldquo;[in] case of an attack on [the plant], a direct hit could result in a very high release of radioactivity to the environment.&rdquo; Damage to the power grid serving the reactor could also cause its core to melt down, leading to a release of high amounts of radiation that would necessitate evacuation or protective sheltering&mdash;measures that the IAEA said would have to be taken over distances of hundreds of miles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what else you&mdash;and the Iranian people in the nuclear crosshairs&mdash;need to know.</p>



<p>For all the mortal mischief a nuclear weapons facility could whip up, there is very little radiation risk associated with the job of enriching uranium-235 up to the level of 90% purity needed to produce a bomb. By itself, the enriched U-235 isotope is something of &ldquo;a damp squib,&rdquo; says Paddy Regan, a nuclear physics professor at the U.K.&rsquo;s University of Surrey. &ldquo;Uranium itself is not particularly radioactive.&rdquo; Iran&rsquo;s 400 kg of U-235, he says, &ldquo;would be much more dangerous if it fell on you.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s partly due to U-235&rsquo;s long half-life, which measures 700 million years&mdash;the time it takes half of the material to decay away. At the sites of the U.S. attack, Regan says, &ldquo;the bombing will do much more damage to the people in the locality than the poisoning.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Adds James Smith, professor of environmental science at the University of Portsmouth, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve worked for a long time at Chernobyl and there&rsquo;s lots of uranium from the nuclear fuel in the environment there. There&rsquo;s something like six tons of it dispersed as small fuel particles. But it&rsquo;s not the uranium we worry about.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Far more dangerous than U-235 are the elemental products given off when nuclear fuel goes through fission&mdash;especially iodine, strontium, and cesium. &ldquo;These are the things that uranium splits into when it&rsquo;s working in a reactor or a bomb,&rdquo; says Smith. &ldquo;Those fission products are much more densely radioactive than uranium.&rdquo;</p>



<p>An enrichment plant&mdash;which does not produce fission&mdash;poses other dangers beyond U-235&rsquo;s relatively low radiation load. Those more-worrisome materials are the toxic gasses that are generated as a byproduct of the enrichment process. &ldquo;When uranium is mined it&rsquo;s milled into a substance called yellow cake,&rdquo; says Jeffrey Lewis, professor and director of the East Asia Nonproliferation Project at Middlebury Institute of International Studies in Monterey, Calif. &ldquo;This is kind of a powder. You want to enrich that material in a centrifuge, and to do that you have to transform it into a gas.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Actually, it&rsquo;s transformed into multiple gasses, including uranium hexafluoride, uranyl fluoride, and hydrogen fluoride&mdash;all of which are highly corrosive and toxic when inhaled or ingested. The IAEA warns that these byproducts have likely been dispersed throughout the damaged Iranian facilities and may have escaped into the outdoor environment as well. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>The best guess the IAEA has advanced at the moment is that if the gasses have indeed escaped, they have remained local, but the group cannot say so for sure. &ldquo;When a bomb hits a site you can get a plume of dust and gas and debris,&rdquo; says Smith. That could be carried on the wind well beyond the initial point of bunker-buster impact.</p>



<p>The fog of war makes it difficult to ascertain exactly how badly the targeted sites have been hit and just how much radiation or chemical toxicity may have spread. The IAEA <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/statements/iaea-director-general-grossis-statement-to-unsc-on-situation-in-iran-20-june-2025"  target="_blank">relies in part</a> on Iran itself to report these measures; after Israel bombed the enrichment plants but before U.S. planes dropped their much heavier ordnance, the Iranians claimed there was no increase in off-site radiation levels. It&rsquo;s uncertain, however, how much of that was true and how much was just all-is-well spin.</p>



<p>For now, the IAEA plans to maintain a presence in Iran and resume inspection of the enrichment sites, as required by the nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty (NPT), of which Iran is a signatory &ldquo;as soon as safety and security conditions allow,&rdquo; according to the June 23 statement. Even before the American strikes, however, Iran <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/17/what-is-the-npt-and-why-has-iran-threatened-to-pull-out-of-the-treaty#:~:text=Israel%2DIran%20conflict-,What%20is%20the%20NPT%2C%20and%20why%20has%20Iran%20threatened%20to,escalating%20military%20conflict%20with%20Israel."  target="_blank">was threatening to withdraw</a> from the NPT, and now, battered on one side by what it considers aggression by the Israelis and on the other by the Americans, Tehran may be ill-inclined to play the good global citizen.</p>



<p>The Trump Administration, meantime, is keeping its military options open, signalling that the weekend strike <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/21/trump-iran-attack-analysis"  target="_blank">was a one-off</a>, while at the same time retaining the option of future attacks. &ldquo;Iran, the bully of the Middle East, must now make peace,&rdquo; <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-warned-iran-retaliate-us/story?id=123128251"  target="_blank">President Donald Trump said</a> in his Saturday night address, after the bombings. &ldquo;If they do not, future attacks would be far greater and a lot easier.&rdquo;</p>



<p>At present, the damage to the targeted sites seems relatively contained. Whether conditions will remain that way is impossible to say. If the truce announced late on June 23 holds, the differences among the parties could be settled without further military action. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297135/environmental-risks-bombing-iran-nuclear-enrichment-sites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How TIME and Statista Determined the World&#8217;s Most Sustainable Companies of 2025</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296709/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025-methodology/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296709/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025-methodology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TIME Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 12:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Statista and TIME have joined forces to identify the World&#8217;s Most Sustainable Companies of 2025, aiming to highlight corporate responsibility and promote sustainable practices. In an era marked by significant environmental challenges and social inequalities, it is crucial to recognize and reward companies prioritizing sustainability. By featuring these leading entities, the ranking sets a benchmark&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296709"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296709/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025-methodology/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Most-Sustainable-Companies-2025.jpg" alt=""/>



<p><a href="https://r.statista.com/en/"  target="_blank">Statista</a> and TIME have joined forces to identify the <a href="https://time.com/collection/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025/" >World&rsquo;s Most Sustainable Companies of 2025</a>, aiming to highlight corporate responsibility and promote sustainable practices. In an era marked by significant environmental challenges and social inequalities, it is crucial to recognize and reward companies prioritizing sustainability. By featuring these leading entities, the ranking sets a benchmark for other businesses, fostering transparency and accountability and encouraging the integration of sustainability into core corporate strategies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Methodology</h2>

[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]



<p>The ranking process began with a comprehensive selection from over 5,000 of the world&#8217;s largest and most influential companies, considering factors such as revenue, market capitalization, and public prominence. The process involved a rigorous 4-step methodology to identify the top 500 companies, evaluated on more than 20 key data points.</p>



<p><strong>Exclusion of Non-Sustainable Businesses:</strong> The first step excluded companies involved in non-sustainable industries like fossil fuels or deforestation. Additionally, companies appearing on negative lists related to sustainability issues, such as those identified as carbon majors or associated with environmental catastrophes, were automatically disqualified. These include: Forest 500 Report (based on 2023 data), Carbon Majors (based on 2023 data), PERI Top 100 Polluter Indexes: Air, Water, Greenhouse, Toxic Greenhouse, Suppliers, Coal (based on 2022 data.)</p>



<p>This step also considered significant scandals or controversies related to sustainability.</p>



<p><strong>Commitment &amp; Ratings:</strong> The second step involved assessing companies based on external sustainability ratings and commitments from reputable organizations. Key criteria included CDP ratings, adherence to the UN Global Compact, alignment with the Science Based Targets initiative (near-term and long-term), inclusion in the S&amp;P Global Sustainability Yearbook, participation in the UNFCCC Race to Zero campaign, and MSCI ESG &amp; SRI evaluations.</p>



<p><strong>Reporting &amp; Transparency:</strong> The third step evaluated the availability and quality of sustainability reports. This included verifying whether companies published an ESG report for 2023, ensuring these reports had undergone external assurance, and assessing compliance with international reporting standards such as GRI, SASB, and TCFD (now part of the IFRS/ISSB standards).</p>



<p><strong>Environmental &amp; Social Stewardship:</strong> The final step involved researching various environmental and social Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) from companies&#8217; Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) reports. Environmental metrics included emission intensity, emission intensity reduction, energy intensity, renewable energy ratio, waste intensity and the proportion of recycled waste.</p>



<p>Social metrics covered aspects like gender diversity on the board of directors and in leadership, gender pay gap, work safety, and employee turnover.</p>



<p>An overall sustainability score was calculated, with a maximum achievable score of 100. The top 500 companies with the highest scores were awarded the title of World&rsquo;s Most Sustainable Companies 2025. These companies are spread across more than 30 countries, with the United States, Japan, and France hosting the highest numbers.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://time.com/collection/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025/" >See the full list here.</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296709/worlds-most-sustainable-companies-2025-methodology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296709</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shaky Israel-Iran Cease-Fire Appears to Hold After Trump Publicly Rebukes Both Countries</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 11:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["We have two countries that have been fighting for so long, they don't know what the f-ck they're doing," Trump said.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297123"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219823149.jpg" alt="President Trump Holds Bill-Signing Ceremony At The White House"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 24, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on Iran, Trump, immigration, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>b55c1aa3-900c-4a9f-8d1a-dfe63efccd9c</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>a9194dab-f0b9-461b-b3c2-df9a06f21fc2</code></p></div>



<p>President Donald <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114739003459183372"  target="_blank">Trump has said</a> it was his &#8220;great honor to destroy all [Iranian] nuclear facilities and capability&#8221; and &#8220;stop the war&#8221; between Israel and Iran. He also said that both countries &#8220;wanted to stop the war equally.&#8221; His statement, shared via social media, came hours after he publicly intervened as the shaky cease-fire threatened to break down entirely when Israel accused Iran of violating the preliminary terms of the deal and vowed retaliation. Iran denied firing further missiles.<br><br>Trump issued a stern, public warning to Israel early Tuesday morning, instructing the country not to bomb Iran as the cease-fire he announced just hours before <a href="https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/" >hung in the balance.</a> </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&#8220;ISRAEL. DO NOT DROP THOSE BOMBS. IF YOU DO IT IS A MAJOR VIOLATION. BRING YOUR PILOTS HOME,&#8221; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114737953503348541"  target="_blank">Trump posted</a> on his social media platform, Truth Social.</p>



<p>Trump, who has since travelled to The Hague in the Netherlands to attend a NATO Summit, further aired his frustrations when talking to reporters outside the White House. He claimed both countries had violated the cease-fire, and said he didn&#8217;t like the fact that &#8220;Israel unloaded right after we made the deal.&#8221;</p>



<p>Taking aim at Israel and Iran, Trump said: &#8220;We have two countries that have been fighting for so long and so hard, that they don&#8217;t know what the f-ck they&#8217;re doing.&#8221;</p>



<p>In a follow-up post online, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114738104789842114"  target="_blank">Trump announced a reprieve in the tensions</a>, saying: &#8220;Israel is not going to attack Iran. All planes will turn around and head home, while doing a friendly &#8216;plane wave&#8217; to Iran. Nobody will be hurt, the cease-fire is in effect.&#8221;</p>



<p>Doubling down on his previous statements, whereby he said that <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >U.S. strikes had &#8220;obliterated&#8221;</a> three key Iranian nuclear sites over the weekend, Trump added: &#8220;Iran will never rebuild their nuclear facilities!&#8221;</p>



<p>Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu shared a call early Tuesday. Upon confirming a conversation had taken place, <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/pmo-statement-24-jun-2025"  target="_blank">Netanyahu&rsquo;s office said</a> that Israeli forces had destroyed a radar installation near Tehran in response to Iranian missile launches. They announced an intention to stand down from further military action.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Pursuant to the conversation between President Trump and Prime Minister Netanyahu, Israel has refrained from additional attacks,&rdquo; the office confirmed.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >What Is the Strait of Hormuz and What Impact Could It Have on International Trade If Iran Closes It?</a></em></p>



<p>Prior to this, Israel&#8217;s Defense Minister Israel Katz maintained that a violation had taken place, and said he had instructed the Israel Defense Forces to &#8220;respond forcefully.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;I have instructed the IDF, in coordination with the Prime Minister, to respond forcefully to the violation of the cease-fire by Iran through intense strikes against regime targets in the heart of Tehran,&#8221; <a href="https://x.com/Israel_katz/status/1937446603880906753"  target="_blank">he said</a>. &#8220;The Iranian regime has severely violated the cease-fire declared by the President of the United States and launched missiles toward Israel, and in accordance with the government&#8217;s policy as determined&mdash;we will respond forcefully to any violation.&#8221;</p>



<p>Amid the back-and-forth discourse, Iranian state media claimed that the cease-fire had been &#8220;imposed&#8221; due to Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;steadfast defense and crushing retaliatory strikes against the Israeli regime&rdquo; that &ldquo;forced the enemy to feel remorse, confess defeat and, approve the unilateral cessation of the onslaught against Iran.&rdquo; </p>



<p>As tensions simmered down, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/cn7ze4vmk2pt?post=asset%3Aec6ed1e7-4ca7-4b63-9812-0b6af5c55534#post"  target="_blank">Trump told reporters</a> on Air Force One that he does not want to push through a regime change in Iran, after all, seemingly backtracking after he shared his keenness to &#8220;Make Iran Great Again&#8221;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114729009239087163"  target="_blank"> in a social media post</a> on Sunday.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I&#8217;d like to see everything calm down as quickly as possible&hellip; Regime change takes chaos, and ideally we don&#8217;t want to see so much chaos,&rdquo; Trump said.</p>



<p>The cease-fire was announced late Monday, after Iran had launched missiles at <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >U.S. military targets at the Al Udeid airbase</a> in Qatar. The strikes were intercepted by the U.S., and no casualties were reported. The military action was retaliatory, a direct response to the U.S. strikes on nuclear facilities over the weekend, which marked a significant turn in the conflict with the U.S. becoming an active participant in the Israel-Iran combat.</p>



<p>The conflict&mdash;which started when Israel targeted nuclear and military sites on June 13, amid growing concerns over Iran&#8217;s nuclear capabilities&mdash;has resulted in significant losses on both sides. <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">Israel has reported</a> 24 deaths and over 1,361 injuries. The Human Rights Activists News Agency <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/the-eleventh-day-of-israeli-strikes-key-developments/"  target="_blank">has reported</a> 974 deaths and 3,458 injuries in Iran. Trump had been vocal in his encouragement of a cease-fire to end the &#8220;death and destruction.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/" >Even Iranians Beaten and Imprisoned by an Unforgiving Regime Condemn Foreign Interference. Here&rsquo;s Why</a></em></p>



<p>Meanwhile, after the threat of cease-fire violations abated, Trump returned to social media on Tuesday to share a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114738606142462442"  target="_blank">message</a> sent to him by NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte, who praised the U.S. for its intervention in the Middle East.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Congratulations and thank you for your decisive action in Iran, that was truly extraordinary, and something no one else dared to do. It makes us all safe,&#8221; Rutte said. &ldquo;You are flying into another big success in The Hague this evening. It was not easy but we&rsquo;ve got them all signed onto 5%!&rdquo;</p>



<p>The 5% GDP defense spending target is expected to be announced by all NATO members at the summit. The United Kingdom <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c07dk90d94vo"  target="_blank">has already confirmed</a> its commitment to reach the spending target by 2035.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ceasefire Appears to Collapse as Israel Accuses Iran of Missile Strike and Orders Retaliation</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israel ordered fresh strikes on Iran, as Iran denied violating the truce brokered by Trump just hours earlier.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297098"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/beersheva.jpg" alt="Iran And Israel Continue Trading Missile Barrages After US Intervention"/>



<p>Within a few hours of publicly agreeing to a ceasefire <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >brokered by U.S. President Donald Trump</a>, Israel has launched new strikes at Iran, which it accused of breaking the peace deal.</p>



<p>The resumption of hostilities threatens to extend the conflict that Trump dubbed the &ldquo;12 Day War.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz <a href="https://x.com/Israel_katz/status/1937446603880906753"  target="_blank">said</a> on Tuesday he ordered the Israeli Defense Forces to &ldquo;respond forcefully to Iran&rsquo;s violation of the ceasefire with intense strikes against regime targets in the heart of Tehran.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The IDF <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1937414143637639295"  target="_blank">said</a> it sounded sirens in northern Israel &ldquo;due to missile fire from Iran&rdquo; around 3:30 a.m. ET. <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/israel-hits-iranian-government-targets-day-after-u-s-strikes-on-iranian-nuclear-sites"  target="_blank">Israel</a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-iran-war-nuclear-trump-bomber-news-06-23-2025-9e78510c88ccc5e262341f41550609c5"  target="_blank">Iran</a> earlier launched strikes at each other shortly before acknowledging the beginning of a ceasefire, but an Israeli official <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-iran-trump-ceasefire-attacks-continue-f1e60190722cc3410b69f21717872ffa"  target="_blank">told</a> the Associated Press that two more missiles were detected and intercepted hours after the start of the ceasefire.</p>



<p>The Israeli Embassy in London <a href="https://x.com/IsraelinUK/status/1937438855885377711"  target="_blank">published a photo</a> purporting to show a rocket fired at Israel by Iran during the ceasefire, adding: &ldquo;Iran continues to show its true nature as a terror state and a regional threat.&rdquo;</p>



<p>According to Iranian state media, Iran&rsquo;s armed forces <a href="https://x.com/PressTV/status/1937451916486934990"  target="_blank">denied</a> Israel&rsquo;s claims that it fired fresh missiles at Israel after the ceasefire began and <a href="https://x.com/PressTV/status/1937451916486934990"  target="_blank">leveled</a> accusations against Israel of its own ceasefire violations, alleging three strikes across Iran earlier in the morning after the ceasefire had begun.</p>



<p>Iranian state media claimed, citing unnamed sources, that Israel&rsquo;s allegation of a ceasefire violation was &ldquo;<a href="https://www.presstv.ir/Detail/2025/06/24/750090/israeli-war-minister-claim-fresh-iranian-missile-strikes-not-true"  target="_blank">pretext</a>&rdquo; to engage in further aggression. The report also reiterated Iranian threats that any breaches of the ceasefire by Israel or the U.S. would be met with &ldquo;stronger retaliation.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;In light of the severe violation of the ceasefire carried out by the Iranian regime, we will respond with force,&rdquo; Israel&rsquo;s Chief of General Staff Eyal Zamir <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1937427038090006827"  target="_blank">said</a>.</p>



<p>Hardline Israeli politicians seemed to celebrate the ceasefire&rsquo;s collapse. &ldquo;Tehran trembles,&rdquo; Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich, a member of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu&rsquo;s security cabinet, <a href="https://x.com/bezalelsm/status/1937413850153852972"  target="_blank">posted</a> on X. National Security Minister Itamar Ben-Gvir <a href="https://x.com/itamarbengvir/status/1937423363070136700"  target="_blank">posted</a> a pair of emojis: &#128165;&#129292;&#127995;.</p>



<p>Israel had <a href="https://x.com/Israel/status/1937407329311265151"  target="_blank">said that it agreed</a> to the ceasefire because it had already &ldquo;achieved all of the objectives&rdquo; of its military operation that <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >began on June 13</a> and has killed hundreds of Iranians, including <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >top generals and nuclear scientists</a>. The earlier statement noted, however, that &ldquo;Israel will respond forcefully to any violation of the ceasefire.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump, who touted the truce on Monday night and warned &ldquo;please do not violate it,&rdquo; was furious on Tuesday morning with the latest developments, reportedly telling reporters that he was &ldquo;not happy&rdquo; with Iran and &ldquo;really unhappy&rdquo; with Israel.</p>



<p>&ldquo;They don&rsquo;t know what the f-ck they&rsquo;re doing,&rdquo; he said, according to the White House press pool. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m gonna see if I can stop it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114737953503348541"  target="_blank">post</a> on Truth Social, Trump <a href="https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/" >warned</a> Israel: &ldquo;DO NOT DROP THOSE BOMBS. IF YOU DO IT IS A MAJOR VIOLATION. BRING YOUR PILOTS HOME, NOW!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297098</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Brokers Ceasefire to End ‘12 Day War’ Between Israel and Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 23:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Please do not violate it,” Trump warned.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297049"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-israel-iran-ceasefire.jpg" alt="US-IRAN-ISRAEL-CONFLICT-TRUMP"/>



<p>Donald Trump shocked the world on Saturday night when he authorized strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities, seemingly bringing the U.S. into another Middle East war that seemed to be escalating.</p>



<p>Then he shocked the world again on Monday evening around 6 p.m. ET when he announced that Israel and Iran agreed to a &ldquo;complete and total ceasefire,&rdquo; set to take effect &ldquo;approximately 6 hours from now.&rdquo; The announcement even caught some of the President&rsquo;s own top officials by surprise, the <em>New York Times</em> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/23/world/middleeast/trump-ceasefire-israel-iran.html"  target="_blank">reported</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;On the assumption that everything works as it should, which it will, I would like to congratulate both Countries, Israel and Iran, on having the Stamina, Courage, and Intelligence to end, what should be called, &lsquo;THE 12 DAY WAR,&rsquo;&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114734934153569653"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social. &ldquo;This is a War that could have gone on for years, and destroyed the entire Middle East, but it didn&rsquo;t, and never will!&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t believe they will ever be shooting at each other again,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://x.com/Yamiche/status/1937291104992330039"  target="_blank">told NBC</a> after announcing the ceasefire.</p>



<p>The deal, however, wasn&rsquo;t immediately publicly confirmed by either the Iranian or Israeli governments, and the missiles kept flying.</p>



<p>Iranian state media <a href="https://x.com/yashar/status/1937307656819236888"  target="_blank">called</a> reports of a ceasefire agreement a &ldquo;fabrication&rdquo; at around 4 a.m. local time in Tehran (8:30 p.m. ET) and said Iran would &ldquo;within a few hours, demonstrate the falsehood of this claim to the Zionist regime through direct and on-the-ground action.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Around the same time, however, Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister<strong> </strong>Abbas Araghchi signaled that Iran would be open to pausing hostilities if Israel did so first.</p>



<p>&ldquo;As Iran has repeatedly made clear: Israel launched war on Iran, not the other way around,&rdquo; Araghchi <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1937311435882922420"  target="_blank">posted</a> on X. &ldquo;As of now, there is NO &lsquo;agreement&rsquo; on any ceasefire or cessation of military operations. However, provided that the Israeli regime stops its illegal aggression against the Iranian people no later than 4 am Tehran time, we have no intention to continue our response afterwards. The final decision on the cessation of our military operations will be made later.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The military operations of our powerful Armed Forces to punish Israel for its aggression continued until the very last minute, at 4am. Together with all Iranians, I thank our brave Armed Forces who remain ready to defend our dear country until their last drop of blood, and who responded to any attack by the enemy until the very last minute,&rdquo; he <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1937315583525036108"  target="_blank">added</a>.</p>



<p>But Iran&rsquo;s military operations, according to Israel, continued after that deadline as well as the midnight ET one. Trump&rsquo;s timeline left some in confusion, as he suggested Iran would &ldquo;start the ceasefire&rdquo; at approximately midnight ET, then Israel would &ldquo;start the ceasefire&rdquo; about 12 hours later, and &ldquo;upon the 24th hour&rdquo; the war would come to &ldquo;an official end.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/israel-iran-missiles-ceasefire.jpg" alt="Iran launches missile strike on Israel" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The Israeli Defense Forces <a href="https://x.com/idfonline/status/1937331898197725467"  target="_blank">reported</a> several <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog-june-24-2025/"  target="_blank">waves of missile strikes</a> on Israel even as Trump continued to <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump"  target="_blank">boast</a> on social media about his peacebrokering. At least four people were killed and a dozen injured, Israel&rsquo;s Magen David Adom national emergency services <a href="https://x.com/Mdais/status/1937374439949099342"  target="_blank">said</a>.</p>



<p>Iranian state media <a href="https://x.com/PTVBreaking1/status/1937364869990240337"  target="_blank">said</a> shortly after the last missile alert, at around 12:19 a.m. ET, that the ceasefire would now begin.</p>



<p>&ldquo;THE CEASEFIRE IS NOW IN EFFECT. PLEASE DO NOT VIOLATE IT,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114736609585800487"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social just after 1 a.m. ET.</p>



<p>Israeli political analyst Akiva Eldar told <a href="https://aje.io/7jaly7?update=3796289"  target="_blank">Al Jazeera</a> that the latest missile strikes from Iran followed a pattern where &ldquo;every side will do its most to be portrayed as having total victory or at least face-saving.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Until the last minute, they will try to improve the balance of power or the balance of damage and say, &lsquo;Look, the last pictures, the last images, the last footage [we] are getting from the enemy is showing that we are doing good,&rsquo;&rdquo; Eldar said. Still, the reports of a ceasefire, whenever it may be implemented, he said, may be &ldquo;the beginning of the light at the end of the tunnel.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How the ceasefire came together</h2>



<p>After the U.S. <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >bombed three key Iranian nuclear sites over the weekend</a>, the world <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >braced</a> for Iran&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >retaliation</a>. But on Monday, Iran responded with a largely <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >symbolic and bloodless strike</a> on a U.S. military base in Qatar.</p>



<p>Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114734424268466099"  target="_blank">thanked</a> Iran for giving &ldquo;early notice&rdquo; before launching its missiles, a majority of which were intercepted and which resulted in no casualties, in a post on Truth Social, adding: &ldquo;Perhaps Iran can now proceed to Peace and Harmony in the Region, and I will enthusiastically encourage Israel to do the same.&rdquo;</p>



<p>When Trump announced the ceasefire on social media, Vice President J.D. Vance was talking to Fox News and <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1937308216527831285"  target="_blank">said</a> that Trump &ldquo;has been working the phones constantly&rdquo; to secure a deal between Israel and Iran.</p>



<p>Last week, Trump had denied reports that he was working toward a ceasefire, instead demanding Iran&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/" >&ldquo;unconditional surrender.&rdquo;</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>After the U.S. strikes on Saturday, Trump warned Iran against further escalation and even <a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >floated the controversial idea of pursuing &ldquo;regime change,&rdquo;</a> but Israeli media <a href="https://www.ynet.co.il/news/article/rkvevsbvge"  target="_blank">reported</a> that Israeli officials were now open to ending their military campaign should Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei choose to do the same.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/iran-regime-change.jpg" alt="Anti-War Protestors Rally In Cities Across The Country After U.S. Strikes On Iran" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>In his own retelling, Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/114735940283355339"  target="_blank">posted</a>: &ldquo;Israel &amp; Iran came to me, almost simultaneously, and said, &lsquo;PEACE!&rsquo; I knew the time was NOW. The World, and the Middle East, are the real WINNERS! Both Nations will see tremendous LOVE, PEACE, AND PROSPERITY in their futures. They have so much to gain, and yet, so much to lose if they stray from the road of RIGHTEOUSNESS &amp; TRUTH. The future for Israel &amp; Iran is UNLIMITED, &amp; filled with great PROMISE. GOD BLESS YOU BOTH!&rdquo;</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/23/trump-iran-israel-ceasefire"  target="_blank">Axios</a>, Qatar acted as an intermediary between Iran and the U.S. passing a message from Iran that it did not plan further attacks on the U.S. following its restrained retaliation and a message back from the U.S. that it did not plan to respond to Iran&rsquo;s symbolic retaliation and was ready to resume negotiations.</p>



<p>A senior White House official <a href="https://apnews.com/live/iran-israel-war-updates-6-23-2025#00000197-9f9e-db03-a79f-bfffa8650000"  target="_blank">told</a> the Associated Press that Trump communicated directly with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to secure the ceasefire.</p>



<p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/qatari-prime-minister-secured-irans-agreement-us-ceasefire-proposal-after-call-2025-06-23/"  target="_blank">reported</a> that Qatar secured Iran&rsquo;s agreement to a ceasefire proposal, with Fox News <a href="https://x.com/TreyYingst/status/1937286632614264989"  target="_blank">reporting</a> that Trump and Vance coordinated directly with Qatar&rsquo;s Emir and Prime Minister.</p>



<p>Iranian state media <a href="https://x.com/Shayan86/status/1937345783344562415"  target="_blank">described</a> the agreement as &ldquo;the imposition of a ceasefire on the Zionist enemy,&rdquo; while the Israeli government put out a <a href="https://www.gov.il/he/pages/spoke-message-gov240625"  target="_blank">statement</a> calling the war &ldquo;a great success&rdquo; and saying that it had agreed to Trump&rsquo;s proposal because all the objectives of its military operation against Iran that <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >began on June 13</a> had been achieved. Still, the statement warned: &ldquo;Israel will respond forcefully to any violation of the ceasefire.&rdquo;</p>



<p><em>&mdash;Chantelle Lee contributed reporting.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where the U.S. Could Face More Retaliation From Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 21:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After its attack in Qatar, analysts warn Iran may not be done retaliating.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297022"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221062591.jpg" alt="Israel-Iranian-Ballistic-Missile-June-23"/>



<p>American military and diplomatic outposts across the globe are on high alert after a U.S. bombing raid on Saturday struck three of Iran&rsquo;s most sensitive nuclear facilities, prompting <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >vows of retaliation</a> from Tehran and raising fears of a widening regional war. </p>



<p>Already on Monday, Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >fired</a> 14 ballistic missiles at the Al Udeid Air Base in Qatar, one of the largest U.S. installations in the Middle East and a critical hub for U.S. air operations across the region. The missiles, a mix of short- and medium-range weapons, were intercepted by Qatari defenses and no casualties were reported.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>President Donald Trump dismissed Tehran&rsquo;s attack as a &ldquo;very weak response,&rdquo; saying the U.S. had been warned by Iran in advance. &ldquo;Most importantly, they&rsquo;ve gotten it all out of their &lsquo;system,&rsquo; and there will, hopefully, be no further HATE,&rdquo; he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114734424268466099"  target="_blank">posted on Truth Social</a>. Trump also suggested that Iran might now &ldquo;proceed to Peace and Harmony&rdquo; and said he would encourage Israel to do the same.</p>



<p>But even as both Tehran and Washington signal interest in avoiding an all-out war, fears remain that the conflict is far from over. Analysts warn that Iran, armed with a deep arsenal and a regional web of proxy forces, is still weighing its next moves&mdash;ones that could target global energy supplies, U.S. military installations, or even escalate its <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >nuclear program</a>.</p>



<p>Iran has threatened to choke off the vital <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >Strait of Hormuz</a>, through which nearly a quarter of the world&rsquo;s oil supply flows, and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security has <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/ntas/advisory/national-terrorism-advisory-system-bulletin-june-22-2025"  target="_blank">warned</a> of the potential for Iranian-backed cyber attacks and terrorism on American soil.</p>



<p>The rapid escalation marks a dangerous new phase in the widening conflict. The State Department has issued a series of warnings in recent days urging Americans abroad to exercise &ldquo;increased caution&rdquo; and ordering the departure of nonessential staff from diplomatic missions in Iraq and Lebanon. In Qatar, where the missiles were fired, embassy officials advised American citizens to shelter in place.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s a look at how Iran could retaliate after the U.S. strikes on its nuclear program.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Targeting the Strait of Hormuz</h2>



<p>While there have been no major disruptions to the global oil supply so far, many fear that Iran could retaliate in part by disrupting shipping in the <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >Strait of Hormuz</a>, a narrow maritime corridor between Iran and Oman through which nearly 20% of the world&rsquo;s traded oil passes.</p>



<p>The strait is a vital artery for global energy markets&mdash;and a vulnerability that Iran has long threatened to exploit. The Iranian Parliament on Sunday approved a measure to close the Strait of Hormuz, a move that would likely send global oil prices skyrocketing, shaking energy markets, and putting pressure on Washington from allies and consumers alike.</p>



<p>&ldquo;EVERYONE, KEEP OIL PRICES DOWN. I&rsquo;M WATCHING! YOU&rsquo;RE PLAYING RIGHT INTO THE HANDS OF THE ENEMY. DON&rsquo;T DO IT!,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/114732938285152785"  target="_blank">posted</a> Monday on Truth Social.</p>



<p>Secretary of State Marco Rubio on Sunday urged China to intervene to prevent Iran from closing the Strait of Hormuz, which can handle the world&rsquo;s largest crude oil tankers.</p>



<p>Very few alternatives exist if the strait is closed, making it a critical choke point for oil shipments. Around 20 million barrels flowed through the strait in 2024.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attacks on U.S. military bases</h2>



<p>In addition to the strike on Al Udeid, Iran has indicated it could target other U.S. military installations across the region&mdash;many of them far closer than Israel and potentially more vulnerable to rapid missile or drone attacks.</p>



<p>Abbas Araghchi, the Iranian foreign minister, <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1936638107169722536"  target="_blank">posted on X</a> that Iran had a legitimate right to respond to U.S. attacks on its nuclear facilities and warned that &ldquo;Iran reserves all options to defend its sovereignty, interest, and people.&rdquo; Trump previously <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114724683855260695"  target="_blank">warned</a> that Iranian retaliation against U.S. assets &#8220;will be met with even greater force than what was unleashed&rdquo; in Saturday&rsquo;s strikes.</p>



<p>The United States maintains tens of thousands of troops across the Middle East, including at permanent bases in Kuwait, Bahrain, Iraq, and the United Arab Emirates. While these bases are outfitted with sophisticated air defense systems, Iran&rsquo;s expanding arsenal of drones and short-range ballistic missiles could pose a threat.</p>



<p>Just before the explosions at Al Udeid, Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian framed Monday&rsquo;s missile strike as a calibrated response: &ldquo;We neither initiated the war nor wanted it,&rdquo; he <a href="https://x.com/drpezeshkian/status/1937179974609367299"  target="_blank">wrote on X</a> in Persian. &ldquo;But we will not leave the aggression against the great Iran unanswered.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In addition to potentially striking American military bases across the Middle East, Iran may also consider striking oil infrastructure in Gulf states allied with the United States.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Qatar-missile-attacks.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">American vessels in the Red sea</h2>



<p>Another way Iran may retaliate is by calling on its regional partners to target U.S. naval and commercial vessels in the Red Sea, a major artery for global trade and energy shipments.</p>



<p>The Houthis, who are backed by Iran and control large parts of Yemen&rsquo;s western coastline, have already shown their ability to strike vessels transiting the Bab el-Mandeb Strait, the narrow chokepoint connecting the Red Sea to the Arabian Sea. Earlier this year, the Houthis launched dozens of missile and drone attacks against American ships and commercial tankers, prompting shipping routes to be temporarily shut down.</p>



<p>The Trump Administration reached a ceasefire with the Houthis in May, but the Houthis said at the time they would resume attacks in the Red Sea if the U.S. entered the war.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Asymmetric attacks&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The U.S. intelligence community is also worried about the potential for asymmetric retaliation from Iran, which could involve cyberattacks on American infrastructure, terrorist plots against U.S. or allied targets overseas, or covert operations carried out through proxy groups.</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security on Sunday issued a <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/ntas/advisory/national-terrorism-advisory-system-bulletin-june-22-2025"  target="_blank">bulletin warning</a> of a &ldquo;heightened threat environment&rdquo; within the U.S. linked to Iranian actors. The warning said that Iranian-backed hackers &ldquo;routinely target poorly secured U.S. networks and Internet-connected devices for disruptive cyber attacks&rdquo; and that &ldquo;low-level cyber attacks&rdquo; are likely as a response to the American bombing.</p>



<p>DHS is also monitoring for signs of potential terrorist attacks orchestrated by Iranian operatives or their partners abroad. Iran has a long history of sponsoring or supporting bombings and assassinations far from its borders, and had plotted to assassinate Trump after he ordered the <a href="https://time.com/5758250/qasem-soleimani-iran-retaliation/" >assassination</a> of Gen. Qasem Soleimani, who led the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps&rsquo; Quds Force.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran also has a long-standing commitment to target U.S. Government officials it views as responsible for the death of an Iranian military commander killed in January 2020,&rdquo; the DHS bulletin warning reads. &ldquo;The likelihood of violent extremists in the Homeland independently mobilizing to violence in response to the conflict would likely increase if Iranian leadership issued a religious ruling calling for retaliatory violence against targets in the Homeland. Multiple recent Homeland terrorist attacks have been motivated by anti-Semitic or anti-Israel sentiment, and the ongoing Israel-Iran conflict could contribute to US-based individuals plotting additional attacks.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&mdash;<em>Brian Bennett contributed reporting</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is the Strait of Hormuz and What Impact Could It Have on International Trade If Iran Closes It?</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The closing of the Strait of Hormuz is something that would be extremely dangerous and not good for anybody.” ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296861"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221005993.jpg" alt="UAE-IRAN-ISRAEL-US-MARITIME-TANSPORT-CONFLICT"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 24, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on Iran, Trump, immigration, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>b55c1aa3-900c-4a9f-8d1a-dfe63efccd9c</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>a9194dab-f0b9-461b-b3c2-df9a06f21fc2</code></p></div>



<p>Iran threatened to close the Strait of Hormuz, in what would serve as <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >another act of retaliation</a>, after the U.S. launched <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >strikes on three key Iranian nuclear facilities</a> over the weekend. While there was a brief reprieve in the tension after President Donald Trump announced a cease-fire between Israel and Iran on Monday, the conflict has erupted again, with both sides accusing each other of <a href="https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/" >breaking the preliminary cease-fire terms</a>. Now, concerns over the Strait of Hormuz are once again at an all-time high.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Iran controls the Northern side of the Strait of Hormuz, a passage which sees significant global trade pass through daily. If it so wished, Iran could block vessels from journeying through, or disrupt trade by seizing and attacking shipping containers and oil or gas tankers in the area. With <a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=65504"  target="_blank">roughly 20 million barrels of oil</a> passing through the Strait daily, making up about a fifth of global consumption, any interruption could be catastrophic.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the Strait of Hormuz, its grave importance, and what stands to happen if the passage is disrupted amid the <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >ongoing Israel-Iran conflict</a>, of which the <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >U.S. is now an active participant</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>The Strait is narrow, stretching roughly 31 miles at its widest point. Iran is on its north bank opposite Oman and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</p>



<p>Most oil exports from Kuwait, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Qatar, and the UAE pass through, as well as Iran&rsquo;s own exports. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/qatar-met-with-energy-majors-discuss-risks-israel-iran-war-sources-say-2025-06-20/"  target="_blank">Around 20% of global liquid natural gas</a> exports also flow through the passage, mostly originating from Qatar. </p>



<p>The passage has long been <a href="https://time.com/5632388/strait-of-hormuz-iran-tanker/" >an area of tension and geopolitical significance</a>.</p>



<p>In 2019, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/jun/13/oil-tankers-blasts-reports-gulf-of-oman-us-navy"  target="_blank">two ships were struck</a>, one flying <a href="https://www.vesselfinder.com/vessels/details/9745902"  target="_blank">a Marshall Islands flag</a> and the other <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-48627014"  target="_blank">from Panama</a>,  whilst passing through. The U.S. blamed Iran for the attacks, which Tehran denied. A month prior, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-48245204"  target="_blank">four other tankers</a>&mdash;two from Saudi Arabia, the others from the UAE and Norway&mdash;were struck by suspected underwater mines, which the U.S. accused Iran of planting.</p>



<p>Noam Raydan, a senior fellow at the Washington Institute and an expert on energy and maritime risks, says that some countries, such as Iraq, rely on the Strait for nearly all of its energy exports, whereas other exporters have fairly reliable alternatives to fall back on, should disruption occur.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<em><a href="https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/" > Even Iranians Beaten and Imprisoned by an Unforgiving Regime Condemn Foreign Interference. Here&rsquo;s Why</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What has Iran said about closing the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>The Iranian Parliament on Sunday <a href="https://www.presstv.ir/Detail/2025/06/22/750031/iranian-parliament-moves-close-strait-hormuz-after-us-aggression-lawmaker"  target="_blank">voted in favour of closing </a>the Strait of Hormuz. The decision of whether to carry out that action now lies with Iran&#8217;s Supreme National Security Council and the Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Just verbal threats from Iran are causing concerns in the global market. So imagine how the impact will be if they <em>really</em> acted on their threats,&rdquo; says Raydan.</p>



<p>However, the maritime expert believes that a complete closure of the passage is unlikely as it would cause just as much harm to Iran themselves.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Strait of Hormuz is very important to Iranian allies such as China, because <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c78n6p09pzno#:~:text=In%202022%2C%20around%2082%25%20of,exports%20to%20the%20global%20market."  target="_blank">most of Iran&#8217;s oil</a> goes to China. Closing the Strait would also turn relations between Iran and the GCC [Gulf Cooperation Council] countries sour,&rdquo; Raydan says, adding that Iranian relations with GCC countries such as Saudi Arabia and the UAE are currently stable and also not worth risking.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran can cause disruptions and keep the oil markets jittery by only carrying out individual maritime attacks,&rdquo; Raydan argues, saying isolated assaults are far more likely than a closing of the entire passage.</p>



<p>She warns, however, that should Iranian energy infrastructure be targeted in further attacks, the Iranian response could be more severe, but &#8220;for right now, we should [instead] consider the maritime arena&hellip; there&#8217;s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iran-oil-doomsday-hormuz-may-be-more-fear-than-reality-bousso-2025-06-22/#:~:text=Moreover%2C%20while%20Hormuz%20has%20never,and%20even%20U.S.%20navy%20ships."  target="_blank">a track history of Iran</a> using that to retaliate.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Iran took part in the so-called Tanker War during the 1980s amid active conflict with Iraq, which saw oil tankers targeted by the Iranian military. The U.S. became involved and protected the tankers, in particular those flying U.S. flags, which it is bound to protect under maritime law.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Strait-of-Hormuz.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Has Iran threatened to close the Strait of Hormuz before&mdash;and did it follow through on its threat?</strong></h2>



<p>Iran previously threatened to block the strait in 2011, when Iran&rsquo;s then-Vice President Mohammad Reza Rahimi declared that oil would not pass through the waters if Western sanctions against Iran were widened. The sanctions were issued as a result of concerns over <a href="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" >Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities</a>&mdash;the very topic at the forefront of the current conflict.</p>



<p>In this instance, Iran did not follow through on its threat.</p>



<p>As <a href="https://nation.time.com/2011/12/28/can-iran-close-the-strait-of-hormuz/" >TIME noted in 2011</a>: International maritime law guarantees unimpeded transit through straits, and any deliberate military disruption can be considered an act of war.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What would be the impact on global trade if Iran closes the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>Oil exporters and importers would stand to be vastly impacted by a closure. And the economic ripple effect would surely be felt far and wide.</p>



<p>According to Deutsche Bank, the cost of a barrel of oil could surge <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/business/oil-prices-iran-israel.html"  target="_blank">to around $120</a>, should Iran block the passage or cause disruption to its shipping lanes. The cost of a barrel currently stands <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/commodities/oil-price"  target="_blank">at around $75</a>.</p>



<p>John Konrad, author and founder of maritime news site gCaptain, says that barriers on new tanker constructions and any disruption to production chains could have a &ldquo;massive&rdquo; economic and social impact.</p>



<p>&ldquo;If you have a slowdown in natural gas, you could have a slowdown in fertilizer,&rdquo; he says, adding that this could lead to &ldquo;food shortages and unrest&rdquo; in a worst-case scenario. The &ldquo;ton mile cost&rdquo; of shipping oil and natural gas will largely increase if Iran were to block trade through the Strait of Hormuz, Konrad argues, even if importers find alternative sources.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The main thing about disruptions and shipping is the ton mile. How many miles does it take to move a ton of oil, and what is that cost?&rdquo; Kondrad notes. &ldquo;The United States is a lot further away from Europe, and much further away from the massive energy consumption in China and Japan and Korea than the Middle East. So what makes the Middle East [so powerful] is not only the abundance of oil, but its central location between Europe and Asia.&rdquo;</p>



<p>European consumers would also feel the impact of any disruption in Hormuz, specifically North-West Europe, when it comes to the prices of gas, oil, and jet fuel.</p>



<p>&ldquo;U.S. refineries might intervene and substitute any gap, but still, disruptions would be felt. Prices will be higher,&rdquo; Raydan says, adding that there would also be logistical issues, similar to those felt when <a href="https://time.com/6553141/red-sea-houthi-attacks-consumer-prices-cost/" >Houthi strikes disrupted trade in the Red Sea</a> following the start of the Israel-Hamas war.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296218/israel-iran-climate-change/" >What Conflict in the Middle East Means for Climate Change</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How have lawmakers from the U.S., U.K., China, and beyond responded?</strong></h2>



<p>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio warned against action in the Strait of Hormuz from Iran in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=APD5gNeIJjY"  target="_blank">an interview with Fox News</a> on Sunday. </p>



<p>&ldquo;I would encourage the Chinese government in Beijing to call him [Khamenei] about that because they [China] heavily depend on the Strait of Hormuz for oil,&rdquo; Rubio said when asked if he expected Iran to close the Strait and disrupt global oil supplies.</p>



<p>Rubio emphasized the U.S. viewpoint that any measures taken to disrupt supply chains in the Persian Gulf would be &ldquo;another terrible mistake.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s economic suicide it they do it and we retain options to deal with that. It would be a massive escalation that would merit a response,&rdquo; he warned.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/" >China has also expressed</a> deep concern over the escalating conflict, and the potential for disruption in trade.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Persian Gulf and nearby waters are [an] important route for international trade in goods and energy. Keeping the region safe and stable serves the common interests of the international community,&rdquo; said Guo Jiakun, the spokesperson for China&rsquo;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs, <a href="https://www.mfa.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/202506/t20250623_11655211.html"  target="_blank">during a press conference on Monday</a>. &#8220;China calls on the international community to step up effort to promote de-escalation of the conflict, and prevent the regional turmoil from having a greater impact on global economic growth.&#8221;</p>



<p>Jiakun went on to emphasize that &#8220;China stands ready to step up communication with Iran and other relevant parties to continue playing a constructive role for a de-escalation.&#8221;</p>



<p>U.K Foreign Minister David Lammy also spoke out on Monday, expressing concerns over the news from the Iranian parliament.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It would be a mistake to blockade the Strait of Hormuz, I think he [Khamenei] gets that and understands that,&rdquo; a hopeful Lammy told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ilThNAQrboI"  target="_blank">the BBC</a>.</p>



<p>In agreement, Kaja Kallas, the European Union representative for foreign affairs and security policy, told reporters on Monday:<strong> </strong>&ldquo;The closing of the Strait of Hormuz is something that would be extremely dangerous and not good for anybody.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Even Iranians Beaten and Imprisoned by an Unforgiving Regime Condemn Foreign Interference. Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Arrest and imprisonment has not changed our views," says one defiant Iranian.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296872"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-88775335-1.jpg" alt="Cell At Evin Prison"/>



<p>What began as a war on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program has developed into something far more imperial. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not politically correct to use the term, &lsquo;Regime Change,&rsquo;&rdquo; President Donald Trump <a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >posted</a> on Truth Social on Sunday. &ldquo;But if the current Iranian Regime is unable to MAKE IRAN GREAT AGAIN, why wouldn&rsquo;t there be a Regime change??? MIGA!!!&rdquo;</p>



<p>On Monday, Israel did its part, launching airstrikes not on military or nuclear sites, but on what Defense Minister Israel Katz <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/katz-idf-striking-with-unprecedented-force-regime-targets-in-tehran/"  target="_blank">called</a> &ldquo;government repression bodies in the heart of Tehran.&rdquo; Among the targets was the <a href="https://x.com/JasonMBrodsky/status/1937096800231367099"  target="_blank">entrance to Evin Prison</a>, notorious for holding political prisoners. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Yet the war is finding no visible support among Iranians once imprisoned there&mdash;the activists who have risked their lives opposing the regime Washington and Tel Aviv want to change.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is exactly what the hardline groups supporting the system wanted,&rdquo; explains twice-jailed Isa Saharkhiz, referring to Israel&rsquo;s military assault. &ldquo;And now, after the U.S. attacks, they are shouting slogans about <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >closing the Hormuz Strait</a>.&rdquo; </p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </a></em></p>



<p>Saharakhiz placed his name among more than 500 activists and groups that on Sunday condemned the assault on Iran, and voiced &ldquo;serious opposition to any foreign interference.&rdquo; The <a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >statement</a>&mdash;by advocates of a democratic Iran that answers to its people&mdash;was posted in Persian on Telegram, the messaging platform on which Saharkhiz also chatted with TIME.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The civil society has been urging Iran&#8217;s ruling system to continue talks with the U.S. and to reach a peaceful agreement and even establish diplomatic relations between Tehran and Washington, and expand political, economic, and trade relations between Iran and the U.S.,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;But the Israeli attack last week, which was against international law and regulations, helped to disrupt the talks and to begin a terrible war.&rdquo; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2213788011.jpg" alt="Imam Reza Birthday Anniversary In Tehran-Iran" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>That moderate approach was championed by Iran&rsquo;s now-vanquished reformist movement, which surged almost three decades ago with the 1997 election of a gentle librarian and cleric named <a href="https://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1905910_1905908_1905894,00.html" >Mohammad Khatami</a> as Iran&rsquo;s President. Saharkhiz had worked with him earlier, and took a prominent place in his Ministry of Culture, and later among the private newspapers that thrived in the fleeting years that greater personal freedoms seemed within reach. The reformists included activists who overran the U.S. Embassy, supporters of the 1979 revolution that brought theocracy to power who had since found its religious rule heavy-handed and intrusive.</p>



<p>But Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamanei, saw the movement as a challenge to the unelected, authoritarian clerics that held ultimate power. The reformists&rsquo; last gasp came in 2009, when hundreds of thousands took to the streets saying the Presidential election had been stolen from the reformist candidate. In the crackdown that answered it, Saharkhiz was among the hundreds of politicians, activists, professors, and journalists facing arrest.</p>



<p>He did not come easily. After eluding arrest, officials kidnapped his daughter and threatened to assault her if Saharkhiz did not surrender. When he relented, he was beaten so badly he was hospitalized for weeks. In 2024, in a lawsuit filed by his son, a U.S. District court ruled <a href="https://www.iranintl.com/en/202406047698"  target="_blank">Iran should pay $5 million</a> for Saharkhiz&rsquo;s torture during imprisonment.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>Aren&rsquo;t his feelings about the war complicated by his feelings about the regime it targets?</p>



<p>&ldquo;No, not at all,&rdquo; Saharkhiz replied. &ldquo;This is the view that me and many of my friends have had throughout the last two or three decades, and would propagate in the newspapers and magazines that we published, all of which were banned. Arrest and imprisonment has not changed our views.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I remember,&rdquo; he went on, &ldquo;that back during the presidency of Khatami, when reformists had a majority in the 6th parliament, I wrote an article and proposed that a meeting be arranged between Joe Biden, who was at that time the <a href="https://time.com/archive/7030497/joe-biden/" >head of the U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations</a>, and his counterpart in the Iranian parliament, as representatives of the two nations. If I&#8217;m not mistaken, Biden had proposed travelling to Tehran at that time.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The meeting did not happen, though Biden was Vice President when then-President Barack Obama negotiated a pact that effectively <a href="https://time.com/magazine/us/4101160/november-16th-2015-vol-186-no-20-u-s/" >sidelined Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program</a> until Trump <a href="https://time.com/5269746/donald-trump-iran-nuclear-deal-macron/" >withdrew</a> from it in 2018. The withdrawal emboldened Iranian hardliners who in April alone carried out at least <a href="https://deathpenaltyinfo.org/iran-sees-75-increase-in-executions-during-first-four-months-of-2025-over-2024"  target="_blank">110 executions,</a> and have crowded Evin Prison with political prisoners&mdash;some of whom were reportedly injured by Israel&rsquo;s strike on the facility.</p>



<p>A week earlier, as the airstrikes began, several prisoners, including women&rsquo;s rights advocate <a href="https://time.com/7288811/iran-womens-rights-evin-prison-reza-khandan/" >Reza Khandan</a>, wrote a <a href="https://rfkhumanrights.org/our-voices/translation-of-letter-from-reza-khandan-to-iranian-judiciary/"  target="_blank">letter</a> to judicial officials requesting freedom from the prison during the Israeli assault, noting that their ward &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t even have a single fire extinguisher.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296872</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Fires Missiles at U.S. Base in Qatar; No U.S. Casualties Reported</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thousands of U.S. service members are stationed at Al-Udeid Air Base]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296830"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Al-Udeid-Air-Base-US-IRan.jpg" alt="WCup Qatar US Air Base"/>



<p>Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >retaliated</a> against the U.S. on Monday, launching missiles at a U.S. base in Qatar, according to a U.S. defense official and a statement from the Qatar foreign ministry. The missiles targeted Al Udeid Air Base outside Doha and were intercepted by air defenses before they could strike the base, the Qatari government said. &#8220;At this time, there are no reports of U.S. casualties&#8221; from the barrage of short-range and medium-range ballistic missiles, the U.S. defense official said.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Thousands of U.S. service members are stationed at Al Udeid Air Base, the forward headquarters for U.S. Central Command and an important American military outpost on the Persian Gulf.  Iranian officials had <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >promised</a> to strike back after an American bombing raid on Saturday hit three nuclear program sites inside Iran.</p>



<p>President Donald Trump called the volley of 14 missiles &ldquo;a very weak response&rdquo; from Iran. Of the 14 missiles Iran launched toward the U.S. base, Trump said, 13 were knocked down and one headed in a &ldquo;nonthreatening&rdquo; direction. Trump declared that Iran has gotten it &ldquo;all out of their &lsquo;system&rsquo;&rdquo; with the Qatar attack, and thanked Iran for giving the U.S. &ldquo;early notice.&rdquo; Trump signaled that he wanted to bring an end to the tit-for-tat attacks. &ldquo;Perhaps Iran can now proceed to Peace and Harmony in the Region, and I will enthusiastically encourage Israel to do the same,&rdquo; Trump wrote. </p>



<p>It&rsquo;s unclear if Iran&rsquo;s leaders will decide to <a href="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" >retaliate further</a> against the U.S. The Iranian missile attack comes after the State Department on Monday told U.S. citizens living in Qatar to shelter in place. On Sunday, the State Department had warned all American travelers worldwide to exercise &#8220;increased <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >caution</a>.&#8221; The U.S. embassy in Baghdad ordered additional personnel to leave Iraq over the weekend and issued a security alert warning Americans in Iraq of an &#8220;increased potential for foreign terrorist organization-inspired violence or attacks against U.S. businesses and locations frequented by U.S. citizens.&#8221; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Qatar-missile-attacks.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The Pentagon dismissed early reports that U.S. forces on Al Asad Air Base in western Iraq were also targeted by Iranian missiles. &ldquo;We are not aware of any additional attacks against U.S. forces in the region today,&rdquo; said a U.S. defense official late in the afternoon on Monday.</p>



<p>Authorities inside the U.S. are <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >on alert</a> for cyber attacks and potential violence in the wake of the U.S. strikes on Iran. A Department of Homeland Security advisory issued an advisory on Sunday that the &ldquo;ongoing Iran conflict is causing a heightened threat environment in the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Ahead of the attack on Qatar on Monday, Iran&rsquo;s mission to the United Nations posted on X that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was &ldquo;dragging the United States into yet another costly war&rdquo; and the U.S. had &ldquo;recklessly chosen to sacrifice its own security merely to safeguard Netanyahu.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" > <em>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime</em></a></p>



<p>In an <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >address to Americans</a> after the air strike on Iran on Saturday, Trump threatened to hit more targets in Iran if the country&rsquo;s leaders refused to &ldquo;make peace.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296830</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
