<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:52:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Trump Issues Blistering Response After Iran&#8217;s Supreme Leader Threatens U.S., as All Sides Claim Victory in Conflict</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298477/trump-iran-threat-khamenei-nuclear-bombs-sanctions/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298477/trump-iran-threat-khamenei-nuclear-bombs-sanctions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 14:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["A burned out, blown up country with no future, a decimated military, a horrible economy, and death all around them."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298477"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298477/trump-iran-threat-khamenei-nuclear-bombs-sanctions/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221346823.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-NETHERLANDS-NATO-SUMMIT-DEFENCE-DIPLOMACY"/>



<p>President Donald Trump issued blistering remarks in response to Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader claiming victory over Israel and, by extension, the U.S. In a loaded public message, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei had also <a href="https://time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/" >threatened to attack more U.S. Military bases</a>, further splintering the Middle Eastern country&rsquo;s relationship with the U.S.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Look, you&rsquo;re a man of great faith. A man who&rsquo;s highly respected in his country. You have to tell the truth. You got beat to hell,&rdquo; Trump said as he addressed the Iranian Supreme Leader during <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;v=pd4wwn30pbQ"  target="_blank">a White House press conference</a> on Friday. Trump was asked by a reporter if the U.S. would consider bombing Iran again, if intelligence reports were to conclude that Iran could enrich uranium to a level that concerns him. &#8220;Sure, without question, absolutely,&#8221; he replied.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Trump issued an even stronger response on his social media platform, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114756430889057942"  target="_blank">Truth Social</a>, later in the day, and doubled down on his stance once more when he reposted his message early Saturday morning.</p>



<p>In the lengthy post, Trump accused Khamenei of publicly sharing a &ldquo;lie&rdquo; by claiming Iran achieved a victory over Israel. He reaffirmed his much debated viewpoint that the <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >U.S. strikes &ldquo;obliterated&rdquo; the three key nuclear facilities</a> it targeted on Saturday, June 21. Trump also seemingly made reference to previous reports that stated the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/ckg7gl4zegyo"  target="_blank">White House turned down a plan</a> by Israel to try and kill Khamenei. </p>



<p>&ldquo;His country was decimated, his three evil nuclear sites were obliterated, and I knew exactly where he was sheltered, and would not let Israel, or the U.S. Armed Forces&#8230; terminate his life. I saved him from a very ugly and ignominious death,&rdquo; Trump said, lamenting that Khamenei would not &ldquo;thank&rdquo; him for this. &ldquo;During the last few days, I was working on the possible removal of sanctions, and other things, which would have given a much better chance to Iran at a full, fast, and complete recovery. The sanctions are biting! But no, instead I get hit with a statement of anger, hatred, and disgust, and immediately dropped all work on sanction relief.&rdquo; </p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/IF12452"  target="_blank">Congress</a>, the U.S. sanctions on Iran &ldquo;are arguably the most extensive and comprehensive set of sanctions that the United States maintains on any country.&rdquo; They block Iranian government assets in the U.S., ban nearly all U.S. trade with Iran, and prohibit foreign assistance and arms sales.</p>



<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </a></em></p>



<p>Trump concluded his charged social media message by saying &ldquo;Iran has to get back into the world order flow&rdquo; or else things &ldquo;will only get worse for them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;They are always so angry, hostile, and unhappy, and look at what it has gotten them. A burned out, blown up country with no future, a decimated military, a horrible economy, and death all around them. They have no hope, and it will only get worse! I wish the leadership of Iran would realize that you often get more with honey than you do with vinegar. Peace!&#8221;</p>



<p>Khamenei broke his silence on Thursday, publicly speaking out&mdash;via a pre-recorded televised address and various social media comments&mdash; for the first time since Trump announced the (admittedly fragile) cease-fire between Israel and Iran.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/" ><em>Shaky Israel-Iran Cease-Fire Appears to Hold After Trump Publicly Rebukes Both Countries</em></a></p>



<p>In his televised message, Khamenei threatened to attack more U.S. military bases should any further aggression from the U.S. side occur.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Islamic Republic slapped America in the face. It attacked one of the important American bases in the region,&rdquo; <a href="https://time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/" >Khamenei said</a>, referring to his country&rsquo;s air assault on Al Udeid Air Base, a U.S. airbase in Qatar. The strikes were intercepted by the U.S. (except for one that was allowed to proceed as there was no risk of contact), and no casualties were reported. The military action was retaliatory, a direct response to the U.S. strikes on nuclear facilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Khamenei claimed &ldquo;total victory&rdquo; over Israel. But Israel, the U.S., and Iran have all claimed to have won the war that started on June 13, when Israel launched strikes on Iranian nuclear and military targets, amid growing concern over <a href="https://time.com/7297970/iran-nuclear-program-jcpoa-trump/" >Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities</a>. When the U.S. actively joined the conflict on June 21, striking three key Iranian nuclear facilities, <a href="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" >world leaders urged de-escalation </a>and a return to negotiations, amid fears of a far-reaching war erupting.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" >&lsquo;Gravely Alarmed&rsquo; World Leaders React After U.S. Strikes Iran</a></em></p>



<p>Though Trump continues to say that Iran&rsquo;s nuclear sites were <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114756430889057942"  target="_blank">&ldquo;totally obliterated,&rdquo;</a> others have cast doubts on how effective the U.S. strikes were in setting back Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program. Leaked U.S. intelligence suggested that the damage to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program may not be as severe as Trump has stated. CIA director John Ratcliffe said on Wednesday that the sites had been &ldquo;severely damaged&rdquo; by the U.S. strikes, and that it would take years to be rebuilt. Amid the debate, the White House has <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/06/irans-nuclear-facilities-have-been-obliterated-and-suggestions-otherwise-are-fake-news/"  target="_blank">put out statements</a> arguing Trump&rsquo;s stance that the facilities were &#8220;obliterated,&#8221; labelling reports to the contrary as &#8220;fake news.&#8221;</p>



<p>But some Democrats left a <a href="https://time.com/7298188/iran-strikes-classified-briefing-senators/" >classified meeting</a> with lingering questions over the effectiveness of the strikes.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s no doubt there was damage done to the program, but the allegations that we have obliterated their program just don&rsquo;t seem to stand up to reason,&rdquo; said Sen. Chris Murphy of Connecticut on Thursday. &ldquo;To me, it still appears that we have only set back the Iranian nuclear program by a handful of months.&rdquo;</p>



<p>When asked about concerns of Iran having &ldquo;secret nuclear sites&rdquo; at Friday&rsquo;s press conference, Trump said he was &ldquo;not worried about it at all.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;They&rsquo;re exhausted. The last thing they&#8217;re thinking about right now is nuclear,&rdquo; he told reporters.  &ldquo;You know what they&#8217;re thinking of? They&#8217;re thinking about tomorrow, trying to live in such a mess. The place was bombed to hell.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7297698/nato-2025-summit-trump-iran-ukraine-defense-topics/" >Key Takeaways From the 2025 NATO Summit</a></em></p>



<p>Meanwhile, Iran&#8217;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1938716761450520678"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a> on Friday that Trump needs to retire his &#8220;disrespectful&#8221; tone towards Khamenei if he wants a deal to be struck between the U.S. and Iran.<br><br>&ldquo;If President Trump is genuine about wanting a deal, he should put aside the disrespectful and unacceptable tone towards Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader, Grand Ayatollah Khamenei, and stop hurting his millions of heartfelt followers,&rdquo; he said. &#8220;The great and powerful Iranian people, who showed the world that the Israeli regime had no choice but to run to &#8216;Daddy&#8217; to avoid being flattened by our missiles, do not take kindly to threats and insults.&#8221;</p>



<p>Araghchi was referencing remarks made by NATO chief Mark Rutte who, during the NATO Summit on Wednesday, <a href="https://time.com/7297698/nato-2025-summit-trump-iran-ukraine-defense-topics/" >referred to Trump as the &#8220;daddy&#8221;</a> who had to intervene in the conflict between Israel and Iran.</p>



<p>Amid the back-and-forth between Trump and Iran, on Saturday, thousands of mourners gathered in Tehran for the funerals of top <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >Iranian military commanders and scientists</a> that were killed in the Israeli strikes. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-us-trump-06-28-25-intl-hnk#cmcfxthf200003b6mbyc9so60"  target="_blank">According to reports</a>, crowds chanted &#8220;death to&#8221; Israel and America.</p>



<p>Araghchi paid tribute to those who had been killed, and went on to tell Iranians on Saturday that the &#8220;pride of a nation is paramount,&rdquo; pledging that Iran would return to &ldquo;new glory and greater strength.&#8221;<br><br>As the funerals took place, <a href="https://x.com/Khamenei_fa/status/1938954701204025779"  target="_blank">Khamenei spoke out</a> via a post on his Farsi-language social media account, sharing a message that translated to: &#8220;The Iranian nation should know that the reason for the opposition to America is that they want Iran to surrender, and this is a great insult to the Iranian nation by the Americans, and such a thing will never happen.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298477/trump-iran-threat-khamenei-nuclear-bombs-sanctions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298477</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Helped Negotiate the 2015 Iran Nuclear Deal. It&#8217;s Still the Best Way Forward</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297970/iran-nuclear-program-jcpoa-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297970/iran-nuclear-program-jcpoa-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josh Black]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The JCPOA was working before the U.S. pulled out in 2018, and another accord is still the best way forward.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297970"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297970/iran-nuclear-program-jcpoa-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220353710.jpg" alt="President Trump Departs White House For New Jersey"/>



<p>Questions remain over the true damage to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program. But as conflicting <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/26/politics/trump-iran-nuclear-program-damage"  target="_blank">comments</a> and <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/25/politics/cia-iran-nuclear-strikes-assessments"  target="_blank">reports</a> come in from the Trump Administration and <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/ckglxwp5x03o"  target="_blank">Pentagon intelligence estimates</a>, one thing is certain: Trump&rsquo;s failed diplomacy got us in this mess.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I should know. Ten years ago, I was in Vienna as part of the U.S. team negotiating a deal to stop Iran from getting a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Those negotiations culminated in the 2015 Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA). It was Trump&rsquo;s decision in 2018 to withdraw from the Iran nuclear deal that ultimately led to the perilous situation in the Middle East today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The JCPOA was the result of a sustained campaign of principled, effective U.S. diplomacy. President Obama began laying groundwork for this nuclear deal as soon as he came to office in 2009. His view&mdash;shared then and now across the U.S. political spectrum&mdash;was that the U.S. cannot accept a nuclear-armed Iran. At the time, Iran claimed that its nuclear energy program was for exclusively peaceful uses. Yet given evidence of Iran&rsquo;s <a href="https://graphics8.nytimes.com/packages/pdf/international/20071203_release.pdf"  target="_blank">past interest</a> in possessing a nuclear bomb prior to 2003, the U.S. could not take this claim at face value.</p>



<p>To get the nuclear deal, Obama and his national security team rallied the world to increase pressure on Tehran. The U.S., E.U., and other allies put in place punishing sanctions. The U.N. Security Council followed suit with a <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-10768146"  target="_blank">fresh round of sanctions</a> in June 2010 that were wide-ranging and <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/fact-sheet-new-un-security-council-sanctions-iran"  target="_blank">targeted the nuclear program</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These sanctions worked: they convinced Iran to come to the negotiating table. To iron out the technical provisions of a deal, the U.S. then put together a team of top career diplomats, nuclear scientists, lawyers, and sanctions experts. It was a remarkable lineup of American patriots and professionals. It was my great honor to serve on that team.</p>



<p>Our goal was to offer Iran phased and reversible sanctions relief in exchange for far-reaching limits on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear activities. To maximize leverage, we coordinated with other countries, including not just European allies but also Russia and China. It was difficult, exacting, high-stakes work&mdash;for months on end.</p>



<p>The effort paid off. Iran agreed to substantial limits on its nuclear activities, including to export out of the country around 98% of its enriched uranium stockpile. Iran&rsquo;s commitments were then subject to intrusive and permanent international monitoring. By the end of the Obama Administration, the deal was working, with <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2017/07/17/trump-iran-nuclear-deal-240641"  target="_blank">all sides implementing their commitments</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s abrupt withdrawal from the JCPOA in 2018 led to the predictable result: Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program surged ahead, breaking free of the deal&rsquo;s constraints. </p>



<p>When Trump returned to office in January, he launched a hasty effort to negotiate a new deal. But it bore a striking resemblance to the deal negotiated by Obama, with one nuclear expert calling the Trump framework a &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/ArmsControlWonk/status/1929619015561105652"  target="_blank">dollar store JCPOA</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu tanked these talks with airstrikes on June 12. The U.S. launched its own strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities on June 22.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/5368881-trump-iran-nuclear-deal-talks/"  target="_blank">seems convinced</a> the matter is now resolved. But what will be the fate of the tons of enriched uranium that Iran stockpiled after Trump withdrew from the JCPOA? How much Iranian nuclear infrastructure remains intact? Will Iran ever welcome back intrusive international monitoring of its nuclear activities, such as specified in the JCPOA?</p>



<p>To resolve these questions, the Trump Administration will need to do the tedious, difficult work of pursuing complex negotiations. Talks <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/26/politics/us-iran-talks-nuclear-program"  target="_blank">look set</a> to<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-25/trump-says-us-iran-to-hold-talks-next-week-mideast-war-over"  target="_blank"> resume</a> next week.</p>



<p>But it will require a high level of technical expertise and diplomatic capacity. And the timing couldn&rsquo;t be worse, as Trump and Elon Musk&rsquo;s culture war on the so-called &ldquo;Deep State&rdquo; has hollowed out and demoralized the ranks of government experts whose support was critical to achieving the JCPOA in the first place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This sad saga has reminded me of what we&rsquo;ve lost in the Trump era. The JCPOA was a product of effective and principled American diplomacy, undertaken in close coordination with our closest allies. It was a team effort by countless government professionals and specialists, all motivated by patriotism and a sense of mission, and operating in an era where they were celebrated not denigrated. It was a victory of dialogue and diplomacy over bluster and bombs.</p>



<p>Ten years ago that approach delivered results for the American people and the world. I worry about what comes next.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297970/iran-nuclear-program-jcpoa-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297970</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The World Is Doubling Down on Climate Business—With Or Without the U.S.</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298399/london-climate-week-corporate-action/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298399/london-climate-week-corporate-action/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Worland / London]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 19:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leadership Report]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The work goes on, but the U.S. is no longer at the center of the climate universe.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298399"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298399/london-climate-week-corporate-action/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/london-climate-week-finance-sustainability-2025.jpg" alt="View looking along Threadneedle Street past old low rise financial buildings in the City of London on June 3 2025 in London, United Kingdom. "/>



<p>Greetings from London. A week of interviews, events, and meetings&mdash;both on the record and behind closed-doors&mdash;at the city&rsquo;s Climate Action Week has left me with many reflections, but one stands out: the <a href="https://time.com/section/climate/" >climate </a>work goes on, but the U.S. is no longer at the center of the universe. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>That reality is evident almost just from the scale. The organizers tout 700 events and 45,000 participants spread across the sprawling London metropolis. This was the biggest London climate week yet, and the first time for many (myself included).&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it was also evident in the meat of the conversations. Investors talked about opportunities outside the U.S., particularly in Asia and Europe. Climate focused executives waffled about how much of a presence they wanted to have at this year&rsquo;s iteration of New York Climate Week, usually an important moment on the climate calendar each September. And British officials emphasized their ability to serve as a global hub for sustainable finance. &ldquo;As investors look around the world and they look for places to put capital, I think we sit in a very good position because of what&#8217;s happening geopolitically,&rdquo; says Chris Hayward, policy chairman of City of London, the historic center of London, now best known as a financial hub. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7290141/wmo-climate-report-2c-business-impact/" >How Soon Should Companies Prepare for a 2&deg;C World?</a></em></p>



<p>To get from event to event in London required dashing around the city in the quickest fashion: typically the tube subway system, consistently overheated given the unseasonably hot London temperatures. But the geographic center of the week was undeniably the City of London, the one square mile that hosts the country&rsquo;s premier banking and financial institutions. There&rsquo;s a reason for that: organizers in London see an economic opportunity in supporting the energy transition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&rsquo;s at the core of the global shift visible here in London. The companies that gathered this week have, for the most part, doubled down on efforts to make or save money with climate and sustainability initiatives&mdash;whether that&rsquo;s an industrial company cutting bills with energy efficiency or a financial firm creating new products to allow companies to invest in renewable power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reality of this profit-oriented approach means the U.S. will fall behind given the policy uncertainty. The observation was underscored by data released throughout the week. A <a href="https://www.wbcsd.org/resources/business-breakthrough-barometer-2025/"  target="_blank">survey</a> of business executives globally, released by the World Business Council for Sustainable Development (WBCSD) and Bain &amp; Company to coincide with the event, found that large global companies are continuing to invest in green solutions&mdash;but are shifting those investments away from the U.S. toward Europe and Asia. Three quarters of surveyed companies said they were increasingly interested in focusing on those regions.</p>



<p>Even still, that&rsquo;s not to say that climate work in the U.S. is dead. The report from WBCSD found that 50% of companies now have less interest in investing in climate work in the U.S. That&rsquo;s a striking figure when contrasted with the global picture. At the same time, it means a significant fraction of global companies continue to see potential.  </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7288050/brazil-finance-minister-fernando-haddad-climate-change-interview/" >Brazil&rsquo;s Finance Chief Sees Climate Change as an Economic Opportunity</a></em></p>



<p>In background chats I had, many American business and financial sector leaders were quick to share that they continue to find <a href="https://time.com/7026187/climate-week-corporate-pragmatic-action/" >opportunities</a> to cut emissions in a way that saves them money&mdash;though several expressed fear that talking about it publicly could prompt scrutiny from the administration. &ldquo;Businesses are not giving up on the decarbonization journey,&rdquo; says Peter Bakker, president and CEO of WBCSD, &ldquo;depending on where businesses are stationed, they are more or less willing to talk about it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>And I was surprised by the response to my informal, totally anecdotal poll about this year&rsquo;s New York Climate Week. In conversations, I asked sustainability executives how they planned to approach the gathering this year. While many said they had considered pulling out, the vast majority said that they have ultimately decided they still plan to show up&mdash;perhaps with a smaller footprint than in years past.</p>



<p>The calibration of the message in New York this fall will be interesting, to say the least. In more than a decade on this beat, I have never felt more of a reluctance from business leaders to speak on the record. Many long standing sources preferred to talk without attribution, wary of the political consequences of speaking truthfully even while they eagerly highlighted their work to me.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>While that makes it more challenging to clearly tell the full story of what&rsquo;s happening, I suppose it&rsquo;s somewhat good news if your biggest concern is whether companies are still focused on capping emissions.</p>



<p><em>To get this story in your inbox, subscribe to the TIME CO2 Leadership Report newsletter <a href="https://www.time.com/co2-newsletter"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298399/london-climate-week-corporate-action/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Carries Out String of Executions and Arrests Amid Fears of Infiltration of Israeli Spies</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298282/iran-israel-war-executions-arrests/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298282/iran-israel-war-executions-arrests/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 15:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iran has executed three men convicted of spying for Israel and detained hundreds more civilians in a widening crackdown that rights groups say reflects growing paranoia within the Islamic Republic&#8217;s leadership following a deadly exchange of strikes with Israel. The executions, carried out by hanging in the northwestern city of Urmia, targeted Edris Ali, Azad&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298282"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298282/iran-israel-war-executions-arrests/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221237993.jpg" alt="Iran And Israel Agree To Ceasefire After Nearly Two Weeks Of Daily Airstrikes"/>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7297123/trump-warns-israel-bombs-iran-ceasefire/" >Iran</a> has executed <a href="https://iranhr.net/en/articles/7682/"  target="_blank">three men</a> convicted of spying for Israel and <a href="https://iranhumanrights.org/2025/06/iran-launches-sweeping-crackdown-hundreds-detained-executions-underway/"  target="_blank">detained hundreds</a> more civilians in a widening crackdown that rights groups say reflects growing paranoia within the Islamic Republic&#8217;s leadership following a deadly exchange of strikes with Israel.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The executions, carried out by hanging in the northwestern city of Urmia, targeted Edris Ali, Azad Shojaei, and Rasoul Ahmad Rasoul&mdash;ethnic Kurds accused of aiding the Israeli Mossad in the 2020 <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-55128970"  target="_blank">assassination</a> of Mohsen Fakhrizadeh, a prominent nuclear scientist. Their names had previously appeared on a <a href="https://iranhr.net/en/articles/7662/"  target="_blank">list published </a>by Iran Human Rights (IHR), an Oslo-based advocacy group, which warned that at least ten men faced imminent execution on similar charges.</p>



<p>The timing of the executions appears intended less to inflame anti-Israel sentiment than to project strength internally, a source familiar with the matter told TIME, describing it as a signal of resolve by a government increasingly consumed with fears of infiltration.</p>



<p>The recent crackdown has also renewed international concern over the fate of Ahmadreza Djalali, a Swedish-Iranian doctor and academic who has spent more than seven years on death row. IHR reported this week that Djalali was moved from Tehran&rsquo;s Evin Prison to <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/israeli-strike-damages-tehrans-evin-prison-families-report/story?id=123124238"  target="_blank">an undisclosed location</a> shortly after an Israeli strike on the facility. &ldquo;There is an imminent risk that his death sentence will be carried out at any moment,&rdquo; the group warned.</p>



<p>Since the outbreak of open hostilities with <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >Israel</a> on <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >June 13,</a> Iranian authorities have arrested more than <a href="https://www.iranintl.com/en/202506250530"  target="_blank">700 people</a> on charges related to alleged collaboration with Israel, according to rights monitors. This week&rsquo;s executions bring to six the number of Iranians put to death for espionage since the start of the conflict.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7297535/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-prospects/" >Why Trump Must Now Negotiate With Iran</a></em></p>



<p>Though Iran&rsquo;s government has presented these arrests and executions as evidence of a crackdown on foreign meddling, public sentiment appears to be shifting in a more complex direction. A source in Iran, speaking on condition of anonymity, told TIME that for the first time in decades, &ldquo;widespread hatred&rdquo; toward Israel is growing among ordinary Iranians&mdash;fueled not by government propaganda, but by firsthand <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/statements/joint-statement-on-the-unlawful-targeting-of-civilians-and-civilian-infrastructure-in-iran/"  target="_blank">experience of violence</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Israel was very willing to kill six Iranian civilians for their [military] target, and that&rsquo;s something which has really made a lot of Iranians angry,&rdquo; the source said. &ldquo;Iranians feel very critical of their own government because it wasn&#8217;t able to defend them&hellip; and at the same time, they&rsquo;re extremely resentful, verging on hatred, toward the Israeli government because of all the civilian deaths.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Iranian government has become increasingly paranoid about intelligence leaks since its almost two-week long conflict with Israel, which began with <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >Israeli attacks</a> on key military and nuclear targets on June 13.</p>



<p>The first strikes <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >resulted in the deaths</a> of multiple highly ranked military officials and top scientists working on Tehran&rsquo;s nuclear program.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" ><em>Where the U.S. Could Face More Retaliation From Iran</em></a></p>



<p>Israel has previously conducted covert operations and targeted strikes within Iran&rsquo;s borders,  including the high-profile <a href="https://time.com/7006644/israel-iran-gaza-haniyeh-assassination/" >assassination</a> of Hamas political leader Ismael Haniyeh in 2024. </p>



<p>However, the scale and visibility of the latest campaign have been unprecedented. During nearly two weeks of conflict, Israeli missile strikes killed at least 974 Iranians&mdash;including 387 civilians and 268 military personnel&mdash;according to the <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/the-eleventh-day-of-israeli-strikes-key-developments/"  target="_blank">Human Rights Activists News Agency.</a> Israel reported <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">28 deaths</a> from Iranian missile retaliation.</p>



<p>Though <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >a cease-fire </a>is now in place, the fallout from the confrontation continues to unfold. Iranian authorities remain focused on rooting out suspected espionage networks, while the public contends with a shifting landscape of fear, anger, and mistrust&mdash;directed both at their own government and at Israel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298282/iran-israel-war-executions-arrests/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thailand Moves to De-Legalize Weed in Major Drug-Policy U-Turn</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298262/thailand-cannabis-marijuana-weed-recriminalization-delegalization-pheu-thai-new-policy/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298262/thailand-cannabis-marijuana-weed-recriminalization-delegalization-pheu-thai-new-policy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a major policy U-turn, the Thai government is tightening restrictions on the sale of cannabis just three years after loosening them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298262"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298262/thailand-cannabis-marijuana-weed-recriminalization-delegalization-pheu-thai-new-policy/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cannabis-bud-thailand-e1751015847840.jpg" alt="Marijuana flowers are pictured for sale at a cannabis store along Khao San Road in Bangkok, Thailand, on May 23, 2025."/>



<p>In 2022, Thailand bucked a trend in Asia. While many other countries in the region have historically meted out <a href="https://time.com/6301702/singapore-death-penalty-drug-cases/" >harsh punishments</a> for drug use and even <a href="https://time.com/6251453/hong-kong-cbd-ban-facts/" >tightened restrictions</a> in recent years, Thailand became the continent&rsquo;s first to <a href="https://time.com/6187449/southeast-asia-drugs-thailand/" >remove marijuana from its list of illegal narcotics</a>.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Since then, marijuana production and sale became a sprawling national industry, spawning around <a href="https://weed.th/"  target="_blank">11,000</a> dispensaries, sourcing from farms across the country. The industry, which also helped Thailand become a tourist haunt for those looking to access the substance, was estimated in 2022 to hit <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-07-21/cannabis-market-in-thailand-seen-growing-to-1-2-billion-by-2025"  target="_blank">$1.2 billion</a> by 2025.</p>



<p>Now, however, the Thai government is harshing that buzz as it moved to restrict access to the drug.</p>



<p>Public Health Minister Somsak Thepsutin signed an order Monday, which took effect this week, that reclassified cannabis buds as a controlled herb and banned shops from selling cannabis to customers without a prescription. A version of the policy is now available on the <a href="https://ratchakitcha.soc.go.th/documents/76076.pdf"  target="_blank">Thai Royal Gazette online</a>.</p>



<p>But Somsak isn&rsquo;t stopping there: he <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/politics/40051671"  target="_blank">vowed</a> to reclassify cannabis as a Category 5 narcotic&mdash;effectively recriminalizing its recreational use.</p>



<p>While the government says that this was a move to protect children and youth, who <a href="https://world.thaipbs.or.th/detail/explainer-everything-you-need-to-know-about-thailands-cannabis-rule-change/57878"  target="_blank">reportedly suffer</a> because of increased access, critics and activists say that political infighting has played a key role in the tightening of marijuana policies, at the expense of small businesses.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What does the new order say?</h2>



<p>The new order requires licenses for those who wish to study, export, sell, or process cannabis buds for commercial reasons. They must report data on the source, use, and amount of cannabis that they possess&mdash;and the cannabis buds should be sourced from a producer that meets the Department for Development of Thai Traditional and Alternative Medicine&rsquo;s Good Agricultural and Collection Practices (GACP) standards.</p>



<p>Cannabis can no longer be sold through vending machines, electronic channels, or computer networks. It and its derivative products cannot be sold in religious sites, dormitories, public parks, zoos, and amusement parks. It can also no longer be advertised.</p>



<p>The sale of cannabis for smoking in cannabis business establishments will also be banned unless sold by medical practitioners, including Thai and Chinese medicine practitioners and dentists, for the treatment of their patients. Prescriptions from medical professionals will be accepted, though they must specify the amount of drug, which should not exceed 30-day use.</p>



<p>Violators may face up to a year in prison and a 20,000-baht fine. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cannabis-store-thailand.jpg" alt="Trippy Nation legal cannabis storefront in the Sukhumvit district near Soi Cowboy in central Bangkok, Thailand" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How is politics involved?</h2>



<p>Decriminalization in 2022 was <a href="https://time.com/6273768/anutin-charnvirakul-interview-cannabis/" >pushed by then-Health Minister Anutin Charnvirakul</a>, who ran for Prime Minister in 2023 as head of the Bhumjaithai Party but lost.</p>



<p>Bhumjaithai did, however, join the governing coalition of Pheu Thai, the populist party that ended up taking power but that had campaigned on recriminalizing marijuana.</p>



<p>Since the removal of cannabis from the illegal narcotics list, no comprehensive law regulating its use was passed. This allowed the quick, albeit <a href="https://time.com/6208192/thailand-war-on-drugs-weed-legal/" >legally complex, boom of marijuana businesses</a>, but authorities say it also facilitated the smuggling of marijuana, reaching countries as far as the <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/thailand-british-tourists-cannabis-smuggling-b2757794.html"  target="_blank">United Kingdom</a> and <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/mumbai/marijuana-women-arrested-8-5cr-thailand-india-10047248/"  target="_blank">India</a>.</p>



<p>Following tensions over a Cabinet seat and a <a href="https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/" >border-dispute flareup with Cambodia</a>, the Bhumjaithai Party left the coalition earlier this month, raising concerns that Pheu Thai Prime Minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7295978/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-government-collapse-coup-cambodia-economy-democracy-analysis/" >rule may end</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as Paetongtarn clings to power for now, Bhumjaithai leaving the coalition has allowed Pheu Thai to pursue its promises of restricting the use of marijuana to medical purposes only.</p>



<p>The Thai public has <a href="https://time.com/6992859/thailand-cannabis-criminalization-public-survey/" >viewed marijuana negatively</a>, with a 2024 poll showing a <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/general/40038141"  target="_blank">majority in favor of relisting it as a narcotic</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How has the industry reacted?</h2>



<p>Speaking to the <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3059036/cannabis-dreams-go-up-in-smoke"  target="_blank"><em>Bangkok Post</em></a>, small- and medium-sized cannabis growers said the tightening of restrictions will force some farms to close.</p>



<p>A producer named Somkiat Nitiketkosol told the paper that such stringent requirements would also open the floodgates for corrupt practices: &ldquo;Most permits are going to big players, while small farmers like me are left waiting or falling victim to scams.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Chokwan Chopaka, a Thai cannabis activist who leads Writing Thailand&rsquo;s Cannabis Future Network&mdash;a group of users, business owners, and producers of the plant&mdash;said they plan to protest the order. Chokwan argues that businesses will not disappear overnight following the new rules, which will only push sales of the drug underground.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Thailand had always been known for <em>sabai sabai</em> [easygoing, lax] culture where many illegal products from sex toys, prescription drugs, vape pens, illegal money exchange, and sex workers are readily available on the side of the road to service all types of tourist, together with well organised groups, to supply and manage those products locally (massage parlour, gogobars, illegal gambling house etc.),&rdquo; she tells TIME. &ldquo;With the new announcement, cannabis will be just but another thing that will go back to being managed by the corrupt underground system.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298262/thailand-cannabis-marijuana-weed-recriminalization-delegalization-pheu-thai-new-policy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the Israel-Iran War and Ceasefire Mean for China’s Relations With the U.S. and World</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298254/china-us-diplomacy-military-intervention-taiwan-israel-iran-war-ceasefire/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298254/china-us-diplomacy-military-intervention-taiwan-israel-iran-war-ceasefire/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trump’s leadership style evinced with the Middle East, at once volatile and commanding, could be both an obstacle and an opportunity for Beijing.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298254"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298254/china-us-diplomacy-military-intervention-taiwan-israel-iran-war-ceasefire/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/china-military.jpg" alt="Man looking at a submarine"/>



<p>Donald Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7297452/trump-doctrine-vance-peace-through-strength-america-first-presidents-history/" >leadership style</a>, at once volatile and commanding, could be both an obstacle and an opportunity for Beijing.</p>



<p>There might be no better example than the recent events involving the Middle East: After nearly two weeks of <a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" >traded attacks between Israel and Iran</a>, the President made the controversial decision to <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >authorize U.S. strikes</a> on three Iranian nuclear facilities, risking prolonged American involvement in yet another unpopular war in the Middle East. Then just two days later, Trump announced that he had <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >brokered a ceasefire</a> between Israel and Iran&mdash;one that <a href="https://time.com/7297098/israel-iran-ceasefire-broken-missile-strikes-tehran/" >almost collapsed</a> but then appeared to hold as Trump let off an <a href="https://time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/" >expletive-filled rant</a> against both countries, warning Israel not to drop more bombs.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Trump even boasted of the benefits his truce would bring to other countries.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China can now continue to purchase Oil from Iran,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114738521695017472"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social on Tuesday. &ldquo;Hopefully, they will be purchasing plenty from the U.S., also. It was my Great Honor to make this happen!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s comments came after Secretary of State Marco Rubio <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=APD5gNeIJjY&amp;t=1095s"  target="_blank">said</a> on Fox News on Sunday that he had encouraged China to advise Iran not to close the <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >Strait of Hormuz</a>&mdash;the narrow waterway through which much of the world&rsquo;s oil trade flows through and which Iran had threatened to close in response to U.S. intervention. China relies on crude oil imports from the Middle East, particularly Saudi Arabia, which pass through the strait, but is also the largest importer of Iranian oil, which is under economic sanctions by the U.S.</p>



<p>Reports suggested that Trump&rsquo;s post indicated possible sanctions relief, but the White House later <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-us-trump-06-25-25-intl-hnk#cmcc2fl2h001b3b6qv8l08mf2"  target="_blank">clarified</a> to media outlets: &ldquo;The president was simply calling attention to the fact that, because of his decisive actions to obliterate Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities and broker a ceasefire between Israel and Iran, the Strait of Hormuz will not be impacted, which would have been devastating for China.&rdquo;</p>



<p>China, unlike the U.S. with Israel, made no indication that it would step in to militarily assist its longtime friend Iran. Instead, the Asian nation, which has in recent years tried to <a href="https://time.com/6262985/china-saudi-arabia-iran-ukraine-peace-talks/" >position itself as a global peacebroker</a>, made fervent calls for deescalation, verbal condemnations of Israel&rsquo;s attacks, and <a href="https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/" >urged the U.S. not to get involved</a>. Ultimately, though, China&rsquo;s offers to mediate were not taken up, and instead it was&mdash;at least according to himself&mdash;Trump&rsquo;s strongman stance that managed to bring an <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >end for now</a> to the hostilities between Israel and Iran.</p>



<p>But experts tell TIME it was no surprise to anyone, including China, that only the U.S. could have brought an end to the war.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It is not surprising that Israel signs a cease-fire when the United States applies real pressure, because they could not pursue any conflict, in Iran or in Gaza, without the continual supply of weapons, ammunition, and military tech from the United States,&rdquo; says William Figueroa, an assistant professor of international relations at the University of Groningen. &ldquo;When the person signing the checks says they really mean it, you listen.&rdquo;</p>



<p>While China has deepened its investment in the Middle East over the years and developed close economic ties with Iran while maintaining ties with Israel, it does not hold the same level of either economic or political leverage over either country as the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran sees China more as an economic partner than a security ally,&rdquo; Lin Jing, a research fellow at the Middle East Institute at the National University of Singapore, tells TIME.</p>



<p>China has also offered sharp criticisms of Israel&rsquo;s bombardment of Gaza, and of its attacks on Iran, which would have made it unlikely for Israel to accept it as a mediator. China seemed to know this, Figueroa says, and was instead pushing the U.S. to exert its influence over Israel to end the war.</p>



<p>Still, experts say, China will learn from how the war and its ceasefire played out, if only to reinforce its view of the U.S. as an unpredictable power.</p>



<p>And Rubio will <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/us/diplomacy/article/3316003/marco-rubio-welcome-asian-quad-counterparts-back-washington?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=homepage"  target="_blank">meet</a> next week with foreign ministers from Australia, India, and Japan to build on &ldquo;momentum to advance a free, open, and secure Indo-Pacific&rdquo;&mdash;language that suggests the U.S. wants to return focus to countering the regional threat from China.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Strikes reinforce Chinese view of U.S. instability</h2>



<p>China already saw the U.S. under the Trump Administration as an unstable partner, particularly after Trump <a href="https://time.com/7274195/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-world-responses-china-eu-countries-leaders-countermeasures/" >slammed the world</a> with <a href="https://time.com/7274194/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-highest-country-rates-calculation-math-imports-exports/" >staggering tariff rates</a> before <a href="https://time.com/7276293/trump-tariffs-reversal-world-leaders-countries-responses-uncertainty-trade-war/" >abruptly reversing course</a>.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7275987/trump-tariffs-global-economy-recession-trade-war-asia-world-impacts/" >Trump&rsquo;s tariffs</a> &ldquo;were accelerating a trend of Chinese businesses looking more and more overseas,&rdquo; Figueroa says. China <a href="https://time.com/7277920/china-manufacturing-us-trump-factory-workers-ai-videos-social-media/" >exports heavily</a> to U.S. markets, and Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/" >tariffs on China</a>&mdash;which rose to a prohibitive 145% before being temporarily lowered to 30%&mdash;<a href="https://time.com/7286933/trump-trade-war-us-china-tariff-pause-businesses-costs-uncertainty/" >left many Chinese and American businesses in a state of uncertainty</a>.</p>



<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping has made attempts to strengthen trade relations with other countries in recent months, assuring the world of its stability as a trading partner in contrast with the U.S. In a meeting with Singaporean Prime Minister Lawrence Wong this week, Xi <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Politics/International-relations/Singapore-seeks-stronger-China-ties-amid-uncertainty-over-Trump-tariffs"  target="_blank">pointed</a> to &ldquo;the current complex and turbulent international situation&rdquo; to emphasize the need for closer ties.</p>



<p>The Middle East too has become an important market and site of diplomacy for China. Figueroa says U.S. backing of Israel &ldquo;will only intensify the trend of China leaning towards the Arab states and linking regional instability to the United States and Israel.&rdquo;</p>



<p>That the U.S. intervened to strike Iranian nuclear facilities, potentially <a href="https://time.com/7297464/nuclear-diplomacy-iran-us-strikes-damage-non-proliferation-treaty-weapon/" >upending decades of global nuclear diplomacy</a>, &ldquo;reinforces [China&rsquo;s] view of the U.S. as a disruptive power, intent on setting rules, but not following them when inconvenient,&rdquo; Lin says.</p>



<p>Isaac Kardon, a senior fellow for China studies at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3315690/are-trumps-iran-strikes-wake-call-china-us-unpredictability?module=top_story&amp;pgtype=homepage"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>South China Morning Post</em> that the U.S. strikes on Iran might ring alarm bells for China. American escalation showed China that &ldquo;massive use of force actually is &lsquo;on the table&rsquo; and may be employed very quickly and even impulsively by a leader who is showing himself to be less gun-shy and more risk-acceptant than his first term,&rdquo; Kardon said.</p>



<p>China&rsquo;s approach to the Israel-Iran war showed that it wanted to &ldquo;avoid direct confrontation with the U.S.,&rdquo; Lin, the Singapore-based researcher, adds. While China <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/mfa_eng/xw/fyrbt/202506/t20250617_11651839.html"  target="_blank">urged</a> &ldquo;countries with special influence on Israel&rdquo; not to fan the flames of the war, it did not explicitly name the U.S. But having seen that the U.S. is willing to engage militarily, China may recalculate its own foreign policy approach, including over Taiwan, Lin says.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China may also look a bit more skeptically at Trump&rsquo;s efforts to negotiate, having seen where negotiations got Iran,&rdquo; Figueroa says.</p>



<p>At the same time, Lin says protracted U.S. involvement in the Middle East, which may result as the U.S. aims to enforce the ceasefire between Tehran and Tel Aviv while <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/26/politics/us-iran-talks-nuclear-program"  target="_blank">reentering diplomatic talks with Iran</a> and <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/netanyahu-trump-said-working-on-plan-to-end-gaza-war-and-expand-abraham-accords/"  target="_blank">pushing Israel to end its war in Gaza</a>, could advantage China &ldquo;by drawing its attention away from Asia.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;U.S. power is finite&mdash;political bandwidth and strategic bandwidth is also limited,&rdquo; Mohammed Alsudairi, an international relations lecturer at the Australian National University, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/06/24/iran-israel-us-china/"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>Washington Post</em>. &ldquo;The U.S. could be dragged into a quagmire, not of its own making.&rdquo;</p>



<p>And Beijing would support such a quagmire, Kardon told <em>SCMP</em>, as it would &ldquo;keep U.S. naval and air forces tied up in Western Asia instead of in the Western Pacific where China&rsquo;s strategic attention is concentrated.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Uncertainty around Taiwan</h2>



<p>Tensions around Taiwan have been <a href="https://time.com/6251419/us-china-general-war-2025/" >on the rise in recent years</a>. Beijing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-taiwan-clash-over-history-beijing-says-cant-invade-what-is-already-chinese-2025-06-25/"  target="_blank">views Taiwan as part of China</a> and has stepped up political and military pressure towards its reunification with mainland China. A majority of countries do not recognize Taiwan as an independent country, including the U.S., although the U.S. opposes the use of force by Beijing to claim Taiwan and provides Taiwan with defensive military capabilities.</p>



<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s Defense Minister Wellington Koo <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-military-vows-boost-combat-readiness-after-taiwan-president-speeches-2025-06-26/"  target="_blank">said</a> Thursday that the island is determined to defend itself, after outlining annual military exercises for July. The defense ministry reported earlier that day <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/taiwan-accuses-china-carrying-out-provocative-military-patrol-near-island-2025-06-06/"  target="_blank">another</a> Chinese &ldquo;joint combat readiness patrol&rdquo; around Taiwan, involving warships and warplanes. China previously <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-20/china-sends-warplanes-near-taiwan-after-us-lawmakers-visit"  target="_blank">sent</a> 46 military aircraft over the Taiwan Strait in the 24 hours before last Friday morning, according to <a href="https://x.com/MoNDefense/status/1935865206892380258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1935865206892380258%7Ctwgr%5E1913e36c1f4e440fab3bfa21b7f70a659de9a989%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bloomberg.com%2Fnews%2Farticles%2F2025-06-20%2Fchina-sends-warplanes-near-taiwan-after-us-lawmakers-visit"  target="_blank">Taiwan&rsquo;s defense ministry</a>, after U.S. lawmakers <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-18/us-lawmakers-talks-with-top-taiwan-official-risks-irking-china"  target="_blank">met</a> with Koo in a rare publicly disclosed meeting.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/taiwan-drills.jpg" alt="Taiwan Coast Guard holds joint forces drill amid tensions with Beijing" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>On the morning of June 20, Taiwan <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/20/taiwan-detects-dozens-of-chinese-aircraft-near-island-after-uk-ship-patrol"  target="_blank">detected</a> a spike in Chinese movements near the island, after China <a href="http://eng.mod.gov.cn/xb/News_213114/NewsRelease/16392429.html"  target="_blank">criticized</a> a British navy vessel <a href="http://www.reuters.com/world/china/uk-royal-navy-vessel-sails-through-taiwan-strait-2025-06-19/"  target="_blank">patrolling</a> the Taiwan Strait for the first time since 2021.</p>



<p>&ldquo;No matter what they say or do, they cannot change the fact that Taiwan is part of China,&rdquo; Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson Guo Jiakun <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/lxjzh/202506/t20250620_11654061.html"  target="_blank">said</a>.</p>



<p>China&rsquo;s defense ministry <a href="http://www.mod.gov.cn/gfbw/xwfyr/jt/16393591.html"  target="_blank">said</a> on Thursday that its military drills are &ldquo;necessary to defend national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and a stern warning to &lsquo;Taiwan independence&rsquo; separatists and external interference.&rdquo; The ministry <a href="http://www.mod.gov.cn/gfbw/xwfyr/lxjzh_246940/16393525.html"  target="_blank">added</a> that U.S. support of Taiwan could &ldquo;mislead Taiwan into the flames of war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Qi Dongtao, a senior research fellow at the East Asian Institute at the National University of Singapore, tells TIME that Trump&rsquo;s approach to China makes it difficult to know whether the U.S. would militarily intervene to defend Taiwan. Former President Joe Biden moved the U.S. from &ldquo;strategic ambiguity&rdquo;&mdash;the policy of deliberately not clarifying whether the U.S. would militarily defend Taiwan&mdash;to &ldquo;strategic clarity,&rdquo; Qi says. On <a href="https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/front/archives/2024/06/06/2003818938"  target="_blank">multiple occasions</a>, including in an <a href="https://time.com/6984968/joe-biden-transcript-2024-interview/" >interview with TIME last year</a>, Biden said he wouldn&rsquo;t rule out &ldquo;using military force&rdquo; to defend Taiwan in the case of an invasion.</p>



<p>But Trump has <a href="https://time.com/7262281/us-taiwan-relations-trump-china-strategic-ambiguity-anxious-uncertainty-explainer/" >moved the U.S. position back towards uncertainty</a>.</p>



<p>Trump is, by and large, &ldquo;not ideologically driven,&rdquo; Qi says. Rather, his approach is &ldquo;transactional.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump Administration officials have also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-needs-hike-defense-spending-10-gdp-pentagon-nominee-2025-03-04/"  target="_blank">demanded</a> that Taiwan increase its defense spending to as much as 10% of its gross domestic product, as part of an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-scraps-us-meeting-after-washington-demands-more-defense-spending-ft-2025-06-20/"  target="_blank">overall push</a> for the U.S.&rsquo; partners to spend more on their own defenses.</p>



<p>Alexander Gray, a senior fellow at the Atlantic Council and former chief of staff of the National Security Council during Trump&rsquo;s first term, <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Policy-Asia/Iran-war-and-Trump-doctrine-blur-China-s-multipolar-vision"  target="_blank">told</a> Nikkei Asia that Israel&rsquo;s aerial campaign was &ldquo;the ultimate example of America First regional burden sharing&rdquo;&mdash;signalling that the Trump Administration expects its regional partners to do a bulk of the fighting.</p>



<p>&ldquo;For Trump, China is mainly an economic threat,&rdquo; Qi adds. For the most part, &ldquo;Trump doesn&rsquo;t want to fight a war with China.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">World still views China as a security concern</h2>



<p>NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3315549/beijings-massive-build-raises-threat-taiwan-strait-conflict-nato-chief"  target="_blank">said</a> Monday that NATO&rsquo;s Indo-Pacific partners&mdash;which includes Japan and South Korea&mdash;were &ldquo;very, very aware&rdquo; of China&rsquo;s &ldquo;massive&rdquo; military expansion, pointing to several Chinese defense companies that rank among the top arms makers globally. He warned that Chinese military expansion could also impact European security.</p>



<p>&ldquo;They don&rsquo;t do this only because they want to have nice parades in Beijing. I guess it&rsquo;s there for a reason,&rdquo; Rutte said. He pointed to &ldquo;the situation in Taiwan&rdquo; and cautioned that should China &ldquo;try anything with Taiwan,&rdquo; Beijing could rely on Russia to &ldquo;keep us busy here&rdquo; in Europe.</p>



<p>Rutte&rsquo;s comments signal that the West still views China mainly as a geopolitical security threat, even as Beijing tries to warm ties with Europe.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We firmly oppose NATO using China as an excuse to expand eastward into the Asia-Pacific and urge NATO to reflect on its own behaviors, change course, and contribute more to global security and stability,&rdquo; Chinese defense spokesperson Senior Colonel Zhang Xiaogang <a href="http://eng.mod.gov.cn/xb/News_213114/NewsRelease/16393598.html"  target="_blank">said</a> at a regular press conference on Thursday.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China wants to be seen as a neutral player,&rdquo; Lin says. But the U.S. is still &ldquo;the dominant power in the region&rdquo; and by most counts the world, whereas China is a &ldquo;relatively recent entry&rdquo; diplomatically and economically to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Even with some upgraded diplomatic ties in the Middle East, China is viewed mainly as an economic player, Lin adds. That informs China&rsquo;s need to balance its interests in and ties to several countries at once. If China were seen as &ldquo;too passive or too close to Iran,&rdquo; for example, &ldquo;it could limit China&rsquo;s Belt and Road ambitions in the region.&rdquo;</p>



<p>With other nations too, China is seen as a major economic player, but taken with a grain of salt with regards to diplomacy.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It is clear that China is one of the largest trading partners, and we have a few issues like climate change where we cooperate, but every relationship requires a dose of realism,&rdquo; European Union foreign policy chief Kaja Kallas <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3315553/eu-foreign-policy-chief-calls-dose-realism-china-relations"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters Monday after a meeting between E.U. foreign ministers. &ldquo;China is the key enabler of Russia&rsquo;s war against Ukraine. It carries out cyberattacks. It interferes in our democracies. It uses coercive trade practices. These aspects strain our relationship and make it increasingly hard to continue as before.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Even in the economic arena, China&rsquo;s relations have faltered. The E.U. earlier this month <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/81700fc4-8f23-4bec-87e9-59a83f215431"  target="_blank">cancelled</a> a flagship economic meeting with China over ongoing trade disputes.</p>



<p>U.S. sanctions have spurred collaboration between China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea, including through setting up international collaborative organizations like BRICS as alternatives to a U.S.-led international order. But the global influence of these organizations is hampered by a lack of &ldquo;sufficient critical mass,&rdquo; Stephen Olson, a visiting senior fellow at the ISEAS Yusof Ishak Institute, <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Policy-Asia/Iran-war-and-Trump-doctrine-blur-China-s-multipolar-vision"  target="_blank">told</a> Nikkei Asia. In another blow to China&rsquo;s push to become a regional leader, India on Thursday <a href="https://apnews.com/article/china-india-meeting-statement-refusal-67bfc09a329e93b9c721029c36e31176"  target="_blank">rejected</a> signing a joint statement facilitated by the Shanghai Cooperation Organization&mdash;one such grouping set up by China and Russia to counter U.S. influence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel-Iran conflict was &ldquo;a stage&rdquo; for U.S. and China&rsquo;s contrasting approaches</h2>



<p>China&rsquo;s continued policy of non-involvement contrasts sharply with what the world has seen from the U.S. in the past week&mdash;not to mention decades of its interventionist approach before Trump&mdash;which has allowed China to make &ldquo;great strides particularly in the Global South,&rdquo; Lin tells TIME. That&rsquo;s intentional, Lin says, lest China lets itself become &ldquo;indistinguishable from the hegemonic powers it criticizes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This conflict between Iran and Israel has somehow become a stage for China and the U.S. to showcase contrasting visions of global leadership,&rdquo; Lin says. &ldquo;The U.S. has demonstrated its military capabilities, its commitment to allies, and its influence in crisis management. But these are not the metrics by which China measures its global role.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Where the U.S. wielded threats and weapons, China offered words.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China&rsquo;s main stake is stability,&rdquo; Lin says. &ldquo;History shows that great power involvement often worsens long-term instability. China does not aspire to become a world policeman, nor does it believe any single country should assume that role.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298254/china-us-diplomacy-military-intervention-taiwan-israel-iran-war-ceasefire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298254</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exclusive: Thai Princes Banished Again as Eldest Says ‘I Did Nothing Wrong’</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7298029/thailand-king-sons-vajiralongkorn-exclusive/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7298029/thailand-king-sons-vajiralongkorn-exclusive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7298029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Juthavachara "Max" Vivacharawongse speaks exclusively with TIME about his family’s banishment from Thailand and his desire for reconciliation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7298029"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7298029/thailand-king-sons-vajiralongkorn-exclusive/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-king-sons-banishment-02.jpg" alt=""/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 27, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the economy, the impact of abortion bans, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>9b82c159-0ec8-4892-98d4-3941b320056f</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>6a18f8af-44ce-4b1c-9ab6-cf48ad3e4a9e</code></p></div>



<p>By right of his birth, the immigration officials should have prostrated themselves before Juthavachara Vivacharawongse, eyes glued to the sunbaked earth, before offering jasmine garlands and shepherding him toward a waiting limousine. Instead, Juthavachara, who goes by the anglicized name Max, and his younger brother Vatchrawee, were ushered into a dingy interrogation room at the Thai-Malay border on May 28 and politely asked for their U.S. passports. It was a jarring moment for two sons of Thailand&rsquo;s king&mdash;estranged nobles returning to their homeland after decades in exile.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>After 45 minutes, a visibly uncomfortable official issued the verdict: the brothers were refused entry to Thailand, the country where their father reigns as King Maha Vajiralongkorn, Rama X of the Chakri Dynasty, the world&rsquo;s wealthiest monarch with a fortune estimated at some $60 billion. The rejection left Max &ldquo;physically and mentally crushed,&rdquo; he tells TIME in an exclusive interview. &ldquo;Because I&#8217;ve missed my homeland every day of my life, and I&#8217;ve always dreamed of going back.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Aside from a fleeting 12-hour visit in January, during which the brothers were detained, interrogated, and harassed by security officials wherever they went, this would have been the first time they had set foot on Thai soil since being banished by their father in 1996, along with their mother and two other brothers, following their parents&rsquo; high-profile divorce. </p>



<p>The heartbreak at the border spurred Max, 45, and Vatchrawee, 40, to pen a Facebook<a href="https://www.facebook.com/share/p/19EBFtoTqN/"  target="_blank"> post</a> that pinned blame on &ldquo;a small yet powerful group of individuals, seeking to preserve their influence within the monarchy, legal system, and political sphere.&rdquo; Max returned to his life as an aerospace engineer living in downtown San Diego, where his American wife was born and they recently moved with their three children to be closer to her family. But he agreed to speak exclusively to TIME about his family&rsquo;s ordeal since their banishment and his burning desire for reconciliation.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I want to get word to my father that I want to go back to live and to work,&rdquo; Max said in a Zoom interview. &ldquo;I have no other ambition other than to go back and be his loyal subject. But unfortunately, there seems to be some kind of misunderstanding that has prevented us from entering the country.&rdquo;</p>



<p>That misunderstanding has only metastasized in recent days. In August 2023, another brother, Vacharaesorn, 44, shocked the nation by suddenly returning to Thailand, the first time any of the Vivacharawongse family had visited for nearly three decades. He visited schools, made merit at temples, and lent his support to humanitarian projects, such as building houses for flood victims. He rode Bangkok&rsquo;s BTS Skytrain and gushed that it was cleaner than the New York subway. In late May, he shaved his head and donned the saffron robes of a Buddhist monk, as is common for royalty to demonstrate piety. Max&rsquo;s thwarted trip was ostensibly to offer support in this new endeavor.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We were all novice monks when we were still in the palace, as every young male member of the royal family had to do,&rdquo; Vacharaesorn told TIME last week. &ldquo;And I&#8217;m the first sibling to become an adult monk in Thailand for our family. So this was a very big deal for us, and we were all looking forward to celebrating together.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-king-sons-banishment-04.jpg" alt="Vatchrawee after being ordained as a monk during the Vesak Day celebration at Wat Pariwas in Bangkok, Thailand on May 11, 2025."/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>However, on June 23, Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s stay in Thailand was abruptly curtailed. Scores of Thai security officials swooped on Wat Pariwat Ratchasongkram, a picturesque temple where Vacharaesorn was staying perched on the bank of Bangkok&rsquo;s Chao Phraya river, and detained him. After a quick stop at his home to pick up his belongings, Vacharaesorn was escorted to Suvarnabhumi International Airport and ordered on a flight to New York City, accompanied onto American soil by Thai security officials, who handed him straight to State Department representatives. Another brother, Chakriwat, would be deported from Thailand the following day, Vacharaesorn was told, although his location is currently unknown. All four are U.S. citizens. &ldquo;The officer who came for Vach informed him that they don&rsquo;t want any Vivacharawongse in the country,&rdquo; says Max, using a nickname for his brother.</p>



<p>TIME requested comment from Thailand&rsquo;s Royal Household Bureau regarding the reasons for Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s deportation and the Vivacharawongse family&rsquo;s status in Thailand but has not received a response. Thailand&rsquo;s Immigration Police has not responded to similar inquiries. A spokesperson for the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok declined to comment since they &ldquo;do not share information with the media about private U.S. citizens absent their written consent.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Why the Vivacharawongse brothers were exiled and partially rehabilitated only to be excommunicated once again lies at the core of a succession crisis that is roiling Thailand&rsquo;s royal household just as younger citizens are demanding reform of the institution. Although King Maha Vajiralongkorn has seven children, only three have royal titles, and none have been identified as heir. &ldquo;If no one really understands what&#8217;s going on, it&rsquo;s a source of instability, and it&rsquo;s a source of doubts,&rdquo; says Paul Handley, a journalist and author of The King Never Smiles, an unofficial biography of King Bhumibol that has been banned in Thailand.</p>



<p>Thailand is America&rsquo;s oldest ally in Asia whose revered palace historically served as a pillar of conservatism and permanence, as well as a bulwark against the communist fervor engulfing its Southeast Asian neighbors. Yet in the post-Cold War era, many young Thais feel alienated by the institution&rsquo;s opaque, hierarchical structures, and desire more accountability.</p>



<p>In 2020, unprecedented public protests erupted across Thailand that shattered taboos by openly calling for royal reform. Ten listed demands included permitting criticism of the King, properly accounting for the crown&rsquo;s finances, banning the sovereign from expressing political opinions, and prohibiting the monarchy from endorsing coups. In rare public comments around the time, King Vajiralongkorn called Thailand &ldquo;the land of compromise&rdquo; and said &ldquo;we love them all the same&rdquo; of the demonstrators.</p>



<p>Still, the lack of a clear succession plan is a cause of great anxiety in a country where the monarch has long served as a bastion of stability. The nation&rsquo;s 2014 <a href="https://time.com/108719/thai-army-declares-military-coup/" >coup d&rsquo;etat </a>was commonly ascribed to a desire by the nation&rsquo;s elites to micromanage the transition to King Vajiralongkorn. Yet he will turn 73 next month and nobody has a clue what the future of this paramount institution looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although primogeniture would make Max first in line for the throne, he currently has no royal titles, and Thailand&rsquo;s constitution excludes any potential heir with a foreign spouse. He insists that he and his brothers only want to be reunited with their homeland to live a simple life as regular folk. Yet forces are conspiring to ensure this never happens.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I just don&rsquo;t understand why this is such a problem,&rdquo; says Max. &ldquo;It hurts me even more to think that I don&#8217;t believe I did anything wrong in my life, and yet I feel like I&#8217;m being punished for things that I did not do.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>It is, of course, a sadly common sentiment among the progeny of broken homes, though the fallout from Max&rsquo;s parents&rsquo; split was anything but typical. King Vajiralongkorn inherited the throne following the death of his revered father, <a href="https://time.com/4043989/thailand-king-dead-obituary-bhumibol-adulyadej/" >King Bhumibol Adulyadej</a>, who was the world&rsquo;s longest-reigning monarch when he passed in 2016. The only son among Bhumibol&rsquo;s four children, then Crown Prince Vajiralongkorn, a former Royal Air Force pilot, was famed for his sybaritic lifestyle, spending much of his time in Germany, and has been married four times.</p>



<p>In a 1981 interview with the Dallas Times Herald during an American tour, Vajiralongkorn&rsquo;s mother, Queen Sirikit,<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/1982/01/23/thais-ban-asian-wall-street-journal-for-story-critical-of-monarch/ab6cbf0c-3282-46eb-a30f-f488f5c9da21/"  target="_blank"> said</a>: &ldquo;I have to be very frank. My son, the Crown Prince, is a little bit of a Don Juan. He is a good student, a good boy, but women find him interesting, and he finds women even more interesting. So his family life is not so smooth.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Vajiralongkorn&rsquo;s first wife bore him a daughter, Princess Bajrakitiyabha, but they divorced in 1991. His second wife, actress and dancer Sujarinee Vivacharawongse, gave birth to four sons and a daughter: Max, the eldest, followed by Vacharaesorn, Chakriwat, Vatchrawee, and Princess Sirivannavari.</p>



<p>The siblings grew up in the lap of luxury, dressed in the finest silks, with doting courtiers catering to their every whim. Though life wasn&rsquo;t always easy. When Max was young and living in the palace, the royal garage was his refuge, where he could escape domestic strife by clambering through dozens of luxury and vintage cars. &ldquo;Because there were a lot of unhappy times.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Vajiralongkorn divorced their mother in 1996 after accusing her of being unfaithful, stripping her and their sons of their titles and forbidding their return to Thailand. The family were living in the U.K., where the eldest two boys attended the prestigious Harrow private school, when the Thai Ambassador suddenly appeared and demanded they relinquish their diplomatic passports. Instead, ordinary ones were issued valid for just one year. Without her mother&rsquo;s knowledge, Princess Sirivannavari was spirited away to Thailand to live with her father. &ldquo;My mother got on the phone with His Majesty and said, &lsquo;Okay, you already have the girl. Do you want the boys as well?&rsquo;&rdquo; recalls Max. &ldquo;According to my mother, he said, &lsquo;Not at this time.&rsquo;&rdquo; The brothers have not seen their sister since.</p>



<p>Cast out from their homeland, Sujarinee and her sons moved to the U.S. as political refugees, settling in central Florida. &ldquo;I&#8217;m a diehard Tampa Bay Buccaneers fan,&rdquo; laughs Max. Sujarinee was the quintessential &ldquo;tiger mom,&rdquo; says Max, and ruled the household with an iron fist. &ldquo;She&#8217;s a very, very tough woman, and she pushed us extremely hard from a very young age. Education was extremely important. She said, &lsquo;just because you are not in Thailand doesn&#8217;t mean you have to lower yourself to the standards of commoner.&rsquo;&rdquo; Three brothers have law degrees; Chakriwat is a medical doctor.</p>



<p>Every year, the brothers would write a letter to their father on his birthday, as well as to mark important family events such as graduations, appraising him of their health and progress. No reply ever arrived. On occasions, the family would post public statements expressing their devotion and desire to return to Thailand. Early in their banishment, when the pain was still raw, the tenor was rebukeful. In 1998, a letter co-signed by the brothers <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/world/asia/article/thailand-s-new-king-neglected-sons-and-forced-wife-into-exile-ggtwzr6ls#:~:text=The%20letter%2C%20verified%20by%20The%20Times%2C%20is,of%20us%2C%E2%80%9D%20when%20he%20was%20crown%20prince."  target="_blank">accused</a> their father of &ldquo;trying to erase memories of us,&rdquo; saying that he never loved their mother and would force them outside of their house &ldquo;every time he found another woman.&rdquo; Asked about this missive, Max says early letters tended to be drafted by their mother and didn&rsquo;t necessarily reflect the sons&rsquo; true sentiments.</p>



<p>In 2003, the boys heard that their father was to visit the U.S., so they turned up unannounced at the Thai Consulate in Chicago to doorstop him. The 30-minute meeting, during which Max and his three brothers sat on the floor per royal protocol, was &ldquo;standoffish,&rdquo; says Max. &ldquo;He didn&rsquo;t quite treat me as his child.&rdquo; Still, the then-Crown Prince enquired after the brothers&rsquo; health, education, and interests. &ldquo;Then he says, &lsquo;hey, you kids didn&#8217;t do anything wrong,&rsquo;&rdquo; recalls Max. &ldquo;&rsquo;If you ever want to come back to Thailand, nobody&rsquo;s going to stop you.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>



<p>Max now regrets that the brothers didn&rsquo;t immediately seize that invitation, though he notes they were young and didn&rsquo;t want to abandon their mother, who was still patently unwelcome. Over time, the brothers came to terms with their exile, different as it was from the pampering of the palace. Max tried to put Thailand out of his mind and immerse himself in American life. &ldquo;At the time, all anybody could ever talk about was Thailand, Thailand, Thailand,&rdquo; says Max. &ldquo;I felt like it was holding us back. So I tried to go to school, get a job, move away from the family a little bit, and get my life going.&rdquo;</p>



<p>For nearly three decades, that&rsquo;s exactly what the family did. The brothers focused on school, worked casual jobs, and graduated college. As a young man, Vacharaesorn hawked hot dogs at sporting events and sold vacuums door-to-door.</p>



<p>In 2013, Max married an American woman, Riya Gough, and the couple have a son and two daughters. When not traveling for work, he plays pickleball, shops at Costco, and drives his kids to soccer practice in his custom BMW, which he sometimes races at the track. Thailand faded into the background.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-king-sons-banishment-03.jpg" alt="Sons of Thai King Maha Vajiralongkorn, Vacharaesorn"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>That all changed in August 2023, when Vacharaesorn suddenly returned to the Kingdom. &ldquo;I literally found out he was in Thailand through the media,&rdquo; says Max. &ldquo;He did not consult with me, my mother, or anybody in our family before going.&rdquo; It was a lightning bolt that left Max &ldquo;hurt and then somewhat angry,&rdquo; he says, &ldquo;because I thought that when it comes to Thailand, we&#8217;re all in it together.&rdquo;</p>



<p>However, Max softened after it emerged that Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s return had been generally well-received: &ldquo;I saw that he was making headway.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s return to Thailand spoke to a succession crisis that is roiling the nation of 70 million. Although King Vajiralongkorn was named heir aged 20, he still has not named his own successor. The presumed favorite had been Princess Bajrakitiyabha, the daughter of his first wife, but she collapsed while training her dogs in December 2022 and has been in a coma ever since. Hopes of a recovery are slim.</p>



<p>The King also has a son by his third wife, Prince Dipangkorn, although he is understood to have learning difficulties that could impede his ability to fulsomely discharge his royal duties. With few viable alternatives, Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s prodigal return has been seen by analysts as an attempt to road-test his suitability for the role.</p>



<p>However, after a few months, the tone soured. It emerged that Vacharaesorn had married an American woman, Elisa Garafano, and the couple have two daughters, which would bar him from consideration, just like Max. Although Vacharaesorn has steadfastly denied any desire for the throne, his desperate scrambling to explain that he was getting a divorce appeared to betray his furtive ambitions.</p>



<p>The perception among analysts was that Vacharaesorn was striving to thread the needle as a compromise candidate for succession, one who would appeal to progressives as a worldly, modernizing force, while still bearing blood blue enough to avoid alienating staunch royalists. But he may have misjudged just how precarious that tightrope had become, as the future of the institution was thrust to the center of political discourse.</p>



<p>In May 2023, Move Forward, a political party that openly campaigned on curbing the monarchy&rsquo;s powers, <a href="https://time.com/6279758/thailand-elections-move-forward-party-pheu-thai/" >won</a> the most seats in Thailand&#8217;s general elections but was <a href="https://time.com/6310002/pita-limjaroenrat-thailand-move-forward-interview-profile/" >blocked</a> from forming a government by the military-appointed Senate. The party&rsquo;s subsequent disbandment by the Constitutional Court last August added grist to the perception among Move Forward&rsquo;s predominantly young voters that the nation&rsquo;s elites are conspiring to expunge their democratic will.</p>



<p>Vacharaesorn appeared to align himself with reformers with veiled criticism of Thailand&rsquo;s draconian l&egrave;se-majest&eacute; royal defamation law, known as Article 112, which is the bedrock on which royal power is built. Under it, anyone who defames, insults or threatens the King, Queen, heir apparent, or regent faces three to 15 years in prison. Critics argue that far from protecting the dignity of the monarch, the law has been co-opted to silence all dissent.</p>



<p>At least 276 people, including 20 under the age of 18, were charged under Article 112 in the four years until November, according to Thai Lawyers for Human Rights. Last June, former Thai Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra, who was ousted in a 2006 coup and is father to current <a href="https://time.com/6271855/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-election-interview/" >Prime Minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra</a>, was<a href="https://apnews.com/article/thailand-thaksin-lese-majeste-srettha-move-forward-a3b4bfee63f4ed547fffe2ff153fd0b4"  target="_blank"> indicted</a> for l&egrave;se-majest&eacute; for an interview he gave nearly a decade ago. &ldquo;Article 112 prosecutions are becoming more and more aggressive,&rdquo; says Paul Chambers, a renowned American expert on Thailand, who fled the country in May following a l&egrave;se-majest&eacute; charge.</p>



<p>In his recent Facebook post, Max lamented how his family had been harassed &ldquo;using surveillance, threats, and abuse of Article 112.&rdquo; But asked by TIME to elaborate, he pointedly declines. &ldquo;Charlie, I&#8217;m going to stay away from that one,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s the palace&rsquo;s prerogative how that law is utilized.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-king-sons-banishment-05.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Regarding Article 112, it&rsquo;s possible Vacharaesorn flew close to the sun. In September 2023, a month following his initial return to Thailand, he attended an exhibition titled Faces of Victims of 112 at New York&rsquo;s Columbia University curated by Thai dissident Pavin Chachavalpongpun, a prominent academic who himself faces l&egrave;se-majest&eacute; charges. Afterwards, Vacharaesorn posted on Facebook that &ldquo;I love and hold my loyalty to the monarchy, but I believe that &lsquo;knowing&rsquo; is better than &lsquo;not knowing,&rsquo; and each individual has their own opinion which is derived from their own experiences.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Against this backdrop, Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s efforts to find the middle ground between reformists and royalists may have simply alienated both camps. His cause certainly hasn&rsquo;t been helped by several missteps. Other than the secret American family, it<a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/prodigal-thai-prince-agrees-pay-182442803.html"  target="_blank"> emerged</a> that he left the U.S. with $94,767.88 in credit card debt, which he later agreed to pay back. After arriving in Thailand, he set up a legal consulting firm, VVV Group, to help foreign companies come to Thailand, and has been working with brands from Chinese EV firm Zeekr to Hollywood actor Mark Wahlberg&rsquo;s tequila label.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The VVV Group website originally listed its chairman as &ldquo;Prince Vacharaesorn,&rdquo; despite his having been stripped of royal titles, but he has since removed the honorific. Still, the perception for many was that Vacharaesorn was attempting to cash in on his royal connections. He also reportedly had close contact with Thaksin, the former prime minister whose populist adulation has made him anathema to royalists. &ldquo;I think somehow he met up with the wrong people,&rdquo; says Pavin. &ldquo;And this encouraged rightwing royalists to go after him.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>Max still insists his father remains unaware he was blocked from returning to Thailand, nor of Vacharaesorn&rsquo;s forced departure, believing instead that some shadowy clique is working against his family to protect their own interests. &ldquo;His Majesty has no idea that I&#8217;m trying to get back in. I sincerely believe that,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;He would welcome me with open arms. Things would never be back the way they were, but he would definitely not tell me to go away.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Max suspects that a palace faction has been conspiring to temper any influence his family might generate, fearful that more returning brothers might form a stronger alternative power source that would be more difficult to tame. They would presumably be figures who are close to Prince Dipangkorn and would prefer him to take the throne. &ldquo;This is a zero sum game for them,&rdquo; says Pavin.</p>



<p>Some have suggested it could even be the brothers&rsquo; estranged sister, Princess Sirivannavari, who having toiled by her father&rsquo;s side for decades now objects to being sidelined by her returning kin. &ldquo;That is certainly the rumor that I&#8217;ve heard,&rdquo; says Max. &ldquo;But I don&#8217;t know if I could ever substantiate it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The opacity of the palace means no outsiders can know for sure. But the actions of King Vajiralongkorn following his rise to the apogee of Thai society don&rsquo;t suggest a monarch wanting for control.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-king-sons-banishment-01.jpg" alt="Commuters in Bangkok as Thai Court Ousts PM After Finding Him Guilty in Ethics Case"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>Since taking power, King Vajiralongkorn has taken personal command of the Crown Property Bureau, which handles the estimated $60 billion royal fortune, and brought several influential state offices under his direct supervision. In 2017, he ordered the transfer of two army units&mdash;the Bangkok-based 1st and 11th Infantry Regiments&mdash;from the military chain of command to the Royal Security Command under his direct supervision. The following year he established a new elite faction of the Thai Army&mdash;known as kho daeng, or red collar&mdash;whose members the palace nominates and from whom top leadership posts must be picked, including the Army Commander, Supreme Commander, and the Commander of the First Army Area, which covers central Thailand including Bangkok and has historically staged several coups. In addition, more than 1,600 police have been assigned to protect the King and his family.</p>



<p>Also in 2017, King Vajiralongkorn changed the national constitution to allow him to rule from abroad. Months later he dismissed or reassigned 96 palace staff on charges such as being &ldquo;lazy&rdquo; or &ldquo;arrogant,&rdquo; according to official royal proclamations, and later dismissed six palace officials for &ldquo;extremely evil&rdquo; conduct. When, in 2019, Vajiralongkorn&rsquo;s oldest sister Princess Ubolratana announced her candidacy for Prime Minister, Vajiralongkorn quickly blocked her, saying it would &ldquo;defy the nation&#8217;s culture.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In July 2019, King Vajiralongkorn designated Sineenatha Wongvajirapakdi as his official consort&shy;&mdash;rekindling a position that hadn&rsquo;t been seen for almost a century&mdash;only to strip her of her title and rank three months later. After she disappeared for 10 months, Sineenatha<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-53994198"  target="_blank"> reemerged</a> in August 2020 suddenly <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/09/03/asia/thai-royal-consort-intl-hnk"  target="_blank">restored</a> to her former position as &ldquo;untainted,&rdquo; though she briefly disappeared from public view again in late 2021. Today, other than his queen and official consort, Vajiralongkorn has increasingly been seen with two other minor consorts, who have even been charged with royal duties in his absence.</p>



<p>In fact, the line of succession is the only aspect of palace life that King Vajiralongkorn has yet to exert a firm hand over&mdash;but it is the one that threatens to be most destabilizing. &ldquo;It&#8217;s the king&rsquo;s prerogative; it&#8217;s the palace&rsquo;s prerogative,&rdquo; shrugs Max of the succession. &ldquo;I don&#8217;t care because that is not my intent in life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The bottom line is that I love and respect His Majesty and want nothing more than to literally kiss his feet again. I just want to make people around him understand that there is absolutely no danger of any kind. I don&#8217;t want anything. I respect the institution and just love my homeland.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Does his American family feel the same way? Max breaks into a weary grin. He reveals that he recently overheard a young friend of his 10-year-old son asking him what it was like being a part of a royal family. &ldquo;My son looked at his friend and says, &lsquo;Oh, it&rsquo;s crazy. There&rsquo;s nothing good about it.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7298029/thailand-king-sons-vajiralongkorn-exclusive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7298029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Trump Must Now Negotiate With Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297535/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-prospects/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297535/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-prospects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vali Nasr]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, after Iran targeted the largest U.S. military base in Qatar in a choreographed response to the American bombing of its nuclear facilities, President Donald Trump briskly dismissed Tehran&#8217;s attack and announced a ceasefire.&#160; In the short term, the U.S. leader&#8217;s declaration and subsequent lashing out against ceasefire violations might have ended the recent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297535"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297535/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-prospects/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220753716.jpg" alt="President Trump In The Situation Room During Strike on Iran"/>



<p>On Monday, after Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >targeted the largest U.S. military base in Qatar</a> in a choreographed response to the <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >American bombing</a> of its nuclear facilities, President Donald Trump briskly dismissed Tehran&rsquo;s attack and <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >announced a ceasefire</a>.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>In the short term, the U.S. leader&rsquo;s declaration and subsequent <a href="https://time.com/7297315/ceasefire-iran-israel-trump-f-bomb/" >lashing out</a> against ceasefire violations might have ended the recent war between the regional rivals&mdash;but over the long term, the future of the conflict between Tehran and Tel Aviv depends on how the various parties manage what remains a brittle peace.</p>



<p>It is clear that, when Trump announced the ceasefire, Iran and Israel were ready to stop fighting. Israel&rsquo;s military success was undisputed; it had assassinated scores of Iranian military leaders, damaged several Iranian nuclear facilities and missile sites, and dominated Iranian skies. Yet it was also incomplete, in terms of Israel&rsquo;s stated goal of destroying the Iranian nuclear program; U.S. bombings pushed the program back, but reportedly <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/24/us/politics/iran-nuclear-sites.html"  target="_blank">only by a few months</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other side, although bruised and bloodied, Iran could insist on being unbowed, on holding its own with enough of its missiles penetrating the Iron Dome and other Israeli air defense systems to compel Tel Aviv and the United States to seek a ceasefire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yet this tenuous pause in fighting does not lay the foundations of peace. Israel has already <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/jun/24/israel-iran-war-live-updates-trump-declares-ceasefire-tehran-attack-us-base-qatar?CMP=share_btn_url&amp;page=with%3Ablock-685af7b98f08baa326f708ec#block-685af7b98f08baa326f708ec"  target="_blank">said</a> it will strike Iran again if it resumes its nuclear efforts. And unless there is a new comprehensive nuclear deal between Iran and the United States, Tehran is likely to seek to reassemble its nuclear program. That sets the stage for another confrontation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It won&rsquo;t happen immediately, of course. Iran needs to introspect upon the <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/middle-east/how-iran-lost"  target="_blank">magnitude of its losses</a>, address its immense intelligence vulnerabilities, regroup its battered military apparatus after the spate of assassinations, and more generally rebuild its defenses. Israel, meanwhile, needs to rebuild and improve its air defenses which <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/middle-east/iron-dome-israel-iran-missiles-failing-tel-aviv-b2773584.html"  target="_blank">failed to prevent Iranian missiles</a> from striking strategic and civilian targets.</p>



<p>None of this, however, would stop Israel from continuing to launch lower-level attacks on Iran despite the ceasefire&mdash;<a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/7/israel-warns-of-more-attacks-on-lebanon-if-hezbollah-not-disarmed"  target="_blank">applying the same strategy</a> it has used in Lebanon despite its ceasefire with Hezbollah. Such attacks would elicit limited retaliation, as for now Iran&rsquo;s focus is likely to be on recovering from the recent war. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The long road to a lasting peace</h2>



<p>Further out, the question is: how do we go from the events of the past few weeks to real stability, not another return to war? How, in other words, does stability return to the region? </p>



<p>The answer hinges on two major factors&mdash;one inside Iran, and the other to do with diplomacy between the U.S. and Tehran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Domestically, beyond replenishing and rebuilding its military capacity, for there to be stablity in the Middle East, Iran has to address its greatest vulnerability: an angry population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iranians <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/08/14/the-protests-inside-irans-girls-schools"  target="_blank">have been at odds</a> with the country&rsquo;s leadership for some time. Economic hardship and isolation have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/05/24/iran-tehran-economy-trump-nuclear-negotiations/"  target="_blank">taken a toll</a>, and an increasingly large number of Iranian citizens no longer subscribe to the Islamic Republic&rsquo;s <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/iran-secular-shift-gamaan.html"  target="_blank">revolutionary values</a> or support its foreign policy, which they blame for the country&rsquo;s isolation and economic woes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The more ambiguously stated objective of Israel and the United States during the war was to incite the Iranians to rebel and topple the Islamic Republic. Iranians did no such thing. Yet in the coming days, domestic popular anger at Israeli aggression and the consequent material and psychological loss that Iranians have suffered is likely to lead to serious questioning of the Islamic Republic&rsquo;s policies.</p>



<p>After all, Iranians are patriotic but they also crave peace, security, and economic prosperity. Israeli attacks killed <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/press-releases/2025/06/iran-un-fact-finding-mission-special-rapporteur-call-civilian-protection-and"  target="_blank">hundreds of civilians</a> and injured thousands more, and destroyed or damaged hundreds of homes and civilian infrastructure, including oil refineries which have led to fuel shortages. The expected conversation and contestation between the Iranian people and the Islamic Republic and the response of the regime will be important in determining how Tehran manages the ceasefire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond Iran, the ceasefire also presents a test for President Trump. He took a risk by getting the U.S. involved in the attack on Iran. As we have already seen, unease about the U.S. getting dragged into another brutal, expensive, and potentially long war in the Middle East created factures within his <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/22/iran-attack-maga-reaction-trump"  target="_blank">MAGA movement</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, with the ceasefire, President Trump has a direct stake in ensuring that the peace holds. To make it last, he needs to effectively manage Israel&rsquo;s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who might see benefits in breaking the ceasefire to further establish military dominance over Tehran. It is also possible that he might break it to handicap any renewed diplomatic efforts between the U.S. and Iran over the latter&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that is precisely what the U.S. must do now to create a pathway for a durable peace: work towards resuming nuclear talks with Tehran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even after this war, Iran still possesses its stockpile of <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/three-things-will-determine-irans-nuclear-future-fordow-just-one-them#:~:text=According%20to%20the%20IAEA%2C%20Iran,first%2025%20kg%20of%20weapons%2D"  target="_blank">400 kilograms</a> of highly enriched Uranium that, if still intact, could be used to build as many as 10 nuclear bombs, according to <a href="https://armedservices.house.gov/uploadedfiles/uscentcom_posture_statement_2025.pdf"  target="_blank">U.S. military</a> estimates. And it retains the expertise to rebuild its nuclear program. The speed at which Iran could move toward weaponization&mdash;if it makes that decision&mdash;depends on how much of its highly enriched uranium survived the American and Israeli bombing of nuclear sites.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To learn that, the United States has to ensure ongoing access to nuclear sites by the International Atomic Energy Agency inspectors ( the Iranian parliament has moved a bill to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iranian-parliament-committee-approves-general-plan-suspend-cooperation-with-iaea-2025-06-23/"  target="_blank">suspend cooperation</a> with the IAEA). All this would have to be part of a nuclear deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran has been clearly weakened by this war but that won&rsquo;t make its nuclear diplomacy with the United States straightforward or easy; it also understands that President Trump has a stake in maintaining the ceasefire and ensuring that there isn&rsquo;t a resumption of a war that could easily spiral into a wider regional conflagration, exacting grave political costs for all involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, President Trump might now have to consider incentives other than coercion and the threat of further bombing Iranian nuclear sites. </p>



<p>This might mean offering Iran greater economic relief, giving it guarantees that the U.S. will not seek or support regime change, and provide a security guarantee against future Israeli attacks. Ultimately, the Iranians do not trust the U.S. leader. He walked away from the 2015 nuclear deal and allowed Israel to attack Iran while he was still negotiating a nuclear deal with Tehran. So the bar for him to win their trust is very high.</p>



<p>This fraught history is bound to make renewed nuclear negotiations more difficult. Still, Iran needs to address its economic challenges, and Trump could offer the incentive of sanctions relief, guarantee that it would happen quickly, and won&rsquo;t be easily reversed. And Trump too needs a deal to avoid the risk of entering the United States into yet another war. Successful nuclear diplomacy&mdash;hard as it might be&mdash;is still possible, and remains the best option for both Iran and the United States. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297535/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-prospects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297535</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran&#8217;s Supreme Leader Threatens to Attack More U.S. Military Bases: “We Slapped America in the Face”</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 13:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said Iran would respond to any future attack by striking U.S. military bases.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297975"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220124150.jpg" alt="Israel Launches Strikes Against Iran"/>



<p>Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has warned that Iran would respond to any further U.S. attacks by <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >targeting American military bases</a> in the Middle East, while declaring what he described as a &#8220;total victory&#8221; over Israel. </p>



<p>&ldquo;The Islamic Republic slapped America in the face. It attacked one of the important American bases in the region,&rdquo; Khamenei said during his first televised remarks since <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >a ceasefire was reached</a> to end the 12-day conflict between Iran and Israel.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>On Monday, Tehran launched 19 ballistic missiles at Al Udeid Air Base, a <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >U.S. airbase in Qatar</a>, in response to an American attack on three nuclear program sites inside Iran. All but one of the missiles were intercepted by air defenses, and no American or Qatari personnel were <a href="https://apnews.com/article/al-udeid-air-base-military-qatar-iran-501e9e64e80480ef3aa4ee43c1243235"  target="_blank">reported injured</a> in the attack.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Such an action can be repeated in the future too. Should any aggression occur, the enemy will definitely pay a heavy price,&rdquo; the Ayatollah <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1938189238324941169"  target="_blank">warned</a>, adding that Iran has &ldquo;access to key U.S. centers in the region.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" ><em>Where the U.S. Could Face More Retaliation From Iran</em></a></p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" ><em>What Is the Strait of Hormuz and What Impact Could It Have on International Trade If Iran Closes It?</em></a></p>



<p>The Iranian strike followed a major U.S. military operation <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >on June 21</a>, in which American forces  targeted three Iranian nuclear facilities. President Donald Trump later claimed the attacks <a href="https://time.com/7297698/nato-2025-summit-trump-iran-ukraine-defense-topics/" >&ldquo;obliterated&rdquo; </a>Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capability. </p>



<p>However, leaked U.S. intelligence suggests that the damage to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program may not be as severe as Trump has alluded. CIA director John Ratcliffe said on Wednesday that the sites had been &ldquo;severely damaged&rdquo; by the strikes, short of the damage described by the President.</p>



<p>Khamenei also <a href="https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-us-trump-06-26-25-intl-hnk#cmcd8j2kc001f3b6nb2hue1r7"  target="_blank">criticized</a> President Trump&rsquo;s call for the Islamic Republic&rsquo;s &ldquo;unconditional surrender&rdquo;, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699621000737127"  target="_blank">posted on TruthSocial </a>on June 17, calling it &#8220;unacceptable and illogical.&#8221;</p>



<p>Earlier in the conflict, Trump had suggested the possibility of regime change in Iran. &ldquo;If the current Iranian Regime is unable to make Iran great again, why wouldn&rsquo;t there be a regime change???&rdquo; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114729009239087163"  target="_blank">he said</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=yR9VMhV2 autostart="viewable"]</div>



<p>But on Tuesday, en route to the NATO Summit, Trump appeared to backtrack. &ldquo;I&rsquo;d like to see everything calm down as quickly as possible,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KOKfUQyOiJI"  target="_blank">he told reporters</a> onboard Air Force One.</p>



<p>The conflict began after Israel attacked military and nuclear facilities across Iran on June 13, <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">killing key military and scientific personnel</a>. After the strikes, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu <a href="https://time.com/7294186/israel-warns-tehran-will-burn-deadly-strikes-traded-nuclear-program/" >described</a> Operation Rising Lion as an attack to &ldquo;roll back the Iranian threat to Israel&rsquo;s very survival&rdquo; and that &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1933626898242056488"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">the goal</a> of Israel&#8217;s operation is to prevent the nuclear and ballistic missile threat of the Islamic regime.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" ><em>Air Supremacy Over Tehran Gives Israel a Decisive Edge&mdash;And Raises New Risks</em></a></p>



<p>Khamenei told viewers on Thursday that the U.S. had only intervened because &ldquo;if it didn&rsquo;t, the Zionist regime would be completely destroyed,&rdquo; claiming that Israel &ldquo;was practically knocked out and crushed under the blows of the Islamic Republic.&rdquo; </p>



<p>During the almost two week-long conflict, 974 Iranians were killed in Israeli missile strikes, including 387 civilians and 268 military personnel, according to the<a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/the-eleventh-day-of-israeli-strikes-key-developments/"  target="_blank"> Human Rights Activists News Agency.</a></p>



<p>In Israel, the Prime Minister&rsquo;s Office confirmed a total of <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">28 people killed</a> as a result of Iranian missile strikes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297975/iran-trump-khamenei-israel-war-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297975</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Iran Goes From Here</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297634/iran-israel-us-conflict/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297634/iran-israel-us-conflict/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sanam Vakil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 12:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The regime may have survived a war with Israel, but its legitimacy is more fragile than ever. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297634"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297634/iran-israel-us-conflict/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219259988.jpg" alt="Israel Launches Strikes Against Iran"/>



<p>As Israeli missiles <a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" >struck Iranian territory and Tehran fired back</a>, the Middle East veered closer to a full-blown regional war. For the first time since the 1980s, the Islamic Republic faced a direct military assault from another regional power that targeted not only its <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >military assets</a>, but the symbolic and political heart of the regime itself.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Today, that war is paused under a <a href="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" >tenuous ceasefire</a>, and despite the hopes and near hysterical levels of speculation, the regime remains in power. Iran&rsquo;s rulers may have survived this round, but their legitimacy is more fragile than ever. A tightening of its grip at home and the launching of internal purges to root out alleged Israeli collaborators is certainly on the horizon, if not already underway. The leadership will try to showcase its military resilience but underneath lies a deepening crisis and serious governance challenges remain. While Iranians demonstrated unity against the unprecedented Israeli and U.S. strikes, the war raised urgent questions about the regime&rsquo;s survival and Iran&rsquo;s evolution.</p>



<p>The immediate trigger was military. On June 12, Israel launched strikes deep into Iranian territory, <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >followed by U.S. attacks</a> on June 22 targeting nuclear sites. The Trump Administration framed the operation as a necessary step to &ldquo;permanently eliminate&rdquo; Iran&rsquo;s weapons capabilities. In typical fashion, Trump followed up the strike with a promise to &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >Make Iran Great Again</a>,&rdquo; implying that regime change was the goal.</p>



<p>But on June 24, Trump reversed course and announced a cease-fire. The terms are vague and the enforcement mechanism unclear. What is clear, however, is that Iran&rsquo;s political and military infrastructure remains largely intact. The idea that a decades-old regime could be brought down from an Israeli aerial campaign without boots on the ground or domestic support has once again proven to be fantasy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Islamic Republic is not a fragile dictatorship held together by a single man. Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei&rsquo;s health has long been the subject of conjecture, but the regime has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/succession-plans-irans-khamenei-hit-top-gear-2025-06-23/"  target="_blank">built-in mechanisms for succession</a>. The Revolutionary Guards remain powerful, deeply embedded, and invested in the system&mdash;if not their own survival.</p>



<p>Yet survival is not strength. The war exposed a regime unable to protect its own cities or citizens from foreign attack. The Islamic Republic is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/22/world/middleeast/iran-israel-hezbollah-houthis-hamas-iraq.html"  target="_blank">more isolated</a> and heavily sanctioned. It has spent decades portraying itself as a guardian of sovereignty, but its projection of power and defense strategy has proved hollow. That failure has opened new space not just for criticism, but for imagination.</p>



<p>For years, Iranians have mobilized to protest what they don&rsquo;t want: clerical rule, corruption, and repression. But in this moment of crisis, a more difficult and essential question of what Iranians want and who gets to decide is resurfacing.</p>



<p>That answer cannot come from exiled monarchs or foreign leaders. It must come from within. The <a href="https://time.com/heroes-of-the-year-2022-women-of-iran/" >Woman, Life, Freedom protests of 2022</a> offered a glimpse, as the most diverse and widespread protests in Iran&rsquo;s modern history. The Iranian diaspora responded with unprecedented energy, organizing rallies and proposing blueprints for a post-Islamic Republic transition. But much of that momentum faltered, in part due to the re-entry of Reza Pahlavi, the exiled son of the former Shah, who is again echoing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Nentayahu in his call for Iranians to &ldquo;<a href="https://www.ft.com/content/fd7bba67-bb2a-410f-ab3e-024267f35c4f"  target="_blank">rise up</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The path forward doesn&rsquo;t lie in restoring monarchy, nor in a foreign-brokered government-in-exile. It lies in the hard, deliberate work of building a representative system that reflects and includes the full spectrum of Iranian society across ethnic, religious, regional, and gender lines. It means prioritizing transitional justice over revenge, and institutions over personalities.</p>



<p>Iranians know the perils of externally driven regime change. In 1953, a U.S.- and U.K.-backed coup toppled the democratically elected Prime Minister Mohammad Mossadegh, restoring the Shah and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2019/01/31/690363402/how-the-cia-overthrew-irans-democracy-in-four-days"  target="_blank">burying Iran&rsquo;s early experiment in parliamentary democracy</a>. In 1979, a revolution for freedom was hijacked by a theocratic elite. In both cases, Iranians lost control of their future to opportunists who promised salvation and delivered repression.</p>



<p>Iranians have also long feared the prospect of a Syrian-style civil war, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/how-libyas-years-crisis-unfolded-after-2011-uprising-2024-08-28/"  target="_blank">Libyan-style state collapse</a>, or foreign intervention masked as liberation. These anxieties are not merely historical abstractions or distant lessons drawn from the broader Middle East. They are actively reinforced by the country&rsquo;s ongoing experience of <a href="https://time.com/7210555/iran-shaky-regime/" >international sanctions and economic isolation</a>. Decades of sweeping sanctions have eroded the economic foundations of everyday life, hollowed out state capacity, and left a broken social contract. </p>



<p>The war may be on hold. But the reckoning is far from over. The Iranian state is bloodied but intact, and will certainly seek a way out, possibly through a Trump-led deal that secures its survival, curbs further Israeli attacks, and brings long-awaited sanctions relief. But any diplomatic resolution abroad must be matched by a reckoning at home.</p>



<p>What&rsquo;s at stake is not just foreign policy but political agency. The challenge ahead for Iran is to imagine a future not built by strongmen or imagined by external actors, but on pluralism and new governance that derives its legitimacy from the people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297634/iran-israel-us-conflict/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297634</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
