<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 23:08:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Trump Says Israel and Iran Agree to ‘Complete and Total’ Ceasefire</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chantelle Lee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 23:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iran and Israel did not immediately issue official statements.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297049"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Trump-Israel-Iran.jpg" alt="President Trump Addresses Nation After US Bombs Iranian Nuclear Sites"/>



<p>President Donald Trump said Monday evening that <a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" >Israel and Iran</a> have agreed to a &ldquo;complete and total ceasefire.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It has been fully agreed by and between Israel and Iran that there will be a Complete and Total CEASEFIRE (in approximately 6 hours from now, when Israel and Iran have wound down and completed their in progress, final missions!), for 12 hours, at which point the War will be considered, ENDED!&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114734934153569653"  target="_blank">said</a> in a post on Truth Social. He added that the ceasefire would bring &ldquo;an Official END to THE 12 DAY WAR.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Iran and Israel did not issue official statements at the time. News outlets, including <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/23/world/iran-trump-israel-news"  target="_blank">The New York <em>Times</em></a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/live/iran-israel-war-updates-6-23-2025?version=1750718953602"  target="_blank">The Associated Press</a>, were not immediately able to verify Trump&rsquo;s claim with either country.</p>



<p>&ldquo;During each CEASEFIRE, the other side will remain PEACEFUL and RESPECTFUL,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;On the assumption that everything works as it should, which it will, I would like to congratulate both Countries, Israel and Iran, on having the Stamina, Courage, and Intelligence to end, what should be called, &lsquo;THE 12 DAY WAR.&rsquo; This is a War that could have gone on for years, and destroyed the entire Middle East, but it didn&rsquo;t, and never will!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s post comes after Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >launched</a> missiles at a U.S. military base in Qatar earlier on Monday, in response to the U.S. <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >bombing</a> three key Iranian nuclear sites over the weekend. Iranian officials had <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >vowed</a> to retaliate after the U.S. launched its attack. No U.S. casualties were reported in Iran&rsquo;s attack on Monday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297049/iran-israel-ceasefire-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297049</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where the U.S. Could Face More Retaliation From Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 21:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7297022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After its attack in Qatar, analysts warn Iran may not be done retaliating.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7297022"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221062591.jpg" alt="Israel-Iranian-Ballistic-Missile-June-23"/>



<p>American military and diplomatic outposts across the globe are on high alert after a U.S. bombing raid on Saturday struck three of Iran&rsquo;s most sensitive nuclear facilities, prompting <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >vows of retaliation</a> from Tehran and raising fears of a widening regional war. </p>



<p>Already on Monday, Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >fired</a> 14 ballistic missiles at the Al Udeid Air Base in Qatar, one of the largest U.S. installations in the Middle East and a critical hub for U.S. air operations across the region. The missiles, a mix of short- and medium-range weapons, were intercepted by Qatari defenses and no casualties were reported.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>President Donald Trump dismissed Tehran&rsquo;s attack as a &ldquo;very weak response,&rdquo; saying the U.S. had been warned by Iran in advance. &ldquo;Most importantly, they&rsquo;ve gotten it all out of their &lsquo;system,&rsquo; and there will, hopefully, be no further HATE,&rdquo; he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114734424268466099"  target="_blank">posted on Truth Social</a>. Trump also suggested that Iran might now &ldquo;proceed to Peace and Harmony&rdquo; and said he would encourage Israel to do the same.</p>



<p>But even as both Tehran and Washington signal interest in avoiding an all-out war, fears remain that the conflict is far from over. Analysts warn that Iran, armed with a deep arsenal and a regional web of proxy forces, is still weighing its next moves&mdash;ones that could target global energy supplies, U.S. military installations, or even escalate its <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >nuclear program</a>.</p>



<p>Iran has threatened to choke off the vital <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >Strait of Hormuz</a>, through which nearly a quarter of the world&rsquo;s oil supply flows, and the U.S. Department of Homeland Security has <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/ntas/advisory/national-terrorism-advisory-system-bulletin-june-22-2025"  target="_blank">warned</a> of the potential for Iranian-backed cyber attacks and terrorism on American soil.</p>



<p>The rapid escalation marks a dangerous new phase in the widening conflict. The State Department has issued a series of warnings in recent days urging Americans abroad to exercise &ldquo;increased caution&rdquo; and ordering the departure of nonessential staff from diplomatic missions in Iraq and Lebanon. In Qatar, where the missiles were fired, embassy officials advised American citizens to shelter in place.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s a look at how Iran could retaliate after the U.S. strikes on its nuclear program.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Targeting the Strait of Hormuz</h2>



<p>While there have been no major disruptions to the global oil supply so far, many fear that Iran could retaliate in part by disrupting shipping in the <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >Strait of Hormuz</a>, a narrow maritime corridor between Iran and Oman through which nearly 20% of the world&rsquo;s traded oil passes.</p>



<p>The strait is a vital artery for global energy markets&mdash;and a vulnerability that Iran has long threatened to exploit. The Iranian Parliament on Sunday approved a measure to close the Strait of Hormuz, a move that would likely send global oil prices skyrocketing, shaking energy markets, and putting pressure on Washington from allies and consumers alike.</p>



<p>&ldquo;EVERYONE, KEEP OIL PRICES DOWN. I&rsquo;M WATCHING! YOU&rsquo;RE PLAYING RIGHT INTO THE HANDS OF THE ENEMY. DON&rsquo;T DO IT!,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/114732938285152785"  target="_blank">posted</a> Monday on Truth Social.</p>



<p>Secretary of State Marco Rubio on Sunday urged China to intervene to prevent Iran from closing the Strait of Hormuz, which can handle the world&rsquo;s largest crude oil tankers.</p>



<p>Very few alternatives exist if the strait is closed, making it a critical choke point for oil shipments. Around 20 million barrels flowed through the strait in 2024.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attacks on U.S. military bases</h2>



<p>In addition to the strike on Al Udeid, Iran has indicated it could target other U.S. military installations across the region&mdash;many of them far closer than Israel and potentially more vulnerable to rapid missile or drone attacks.</p>



<p>Abbas Araghchi, the Iranian foreign minister, <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1936638107169722536"  target="_blank">posted on X</a> that Iran had a legitimate right to respond to U.S. attacks on its nuclear facilities and warned that &ldquo;Iran reserves all options to defend its sovereignty, interest, and people.&rdquo; Trump previously <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114724683855260695"  target="_blank">warned</a> that Iranian retaliation against U.S. assets &#8220;will be met with even greater force than what was unleashed&rdquo; in Saturday&rsquo;s strikes.</p>



<p>The United States maintains tens of thousands of troops across the Middle East, including at permanent bases in Kuwait, Bahrain, Iraq, and the United Arab Emirates. While these bases are outfitted with sophisticated air defense systems, Iran&rsquo;s expanding arsenal of drones and short-range ballistic missiles could pose a threat.</p>



<p>Just before the explosions at Al Udeid, Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian framed Monday&rsquo;s missile strike as a calibrated response: &ldquo;We neither initiated the war nor wanted it,&rdquo; he <a href="https://x.com/drpezeshkian/status/1937179974609367299"  target="_blank">wrote on X</a> in Persian. &ldquo;But we will not leave the aggression against the great Iran unanswered.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In addition to potentially striking American military bases across the Middle East, Iran may also consider striking oil infrastructure in Gulf states allied with the United States.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Qatar-missile-attacks.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">American vessels in the Red sea</h2>



<p>Another way Iran may retaliate is by calling on its regional partners to target U.S. naval and commercial vessels in the Red Sea, a major artery for global trade and energy shipments.</p>



<p>The Houthis, who are backed by Iran and control large parts of Yemen&rsquo;s western coastline, have already shown their ability to strike vessels transiting the Bab el-Mandeb Strait, the narrow chokepoint connecting the Red Sea to the Arabian Sea. Earlier this year, the Houthis launched dozens of missile and drone attacks against American ships and commercial tankers, prompting shipping routes to be temporarily shut down.</p>



<p>The Trump Administration reached a ceasefire with the Houthis in May, but the Houthis said at the time they would resume attacks in the Red Sea if the U.S. entered the war.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Asymmetric attacks&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The U.S. intelligence community is also worried about the potential for asymmetric retaliation from Iran, which could involve cyberattacks on American infrastructure, terrorist plots against U.S. or allied targets overseas, or covert operations carried out through proxy groups.</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security on Sunday issued a <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/ntas/advisory/national-terrorism-advisory-system-bulletin-june-22-2025"  target="_blank">bulletin warning</a> of a &ldquo;heightened threat environment&rdquo; within the U.S. linked to Iranian actors. The warning said that Iranian-backed hackers &ldquo;routinely target poorly secured U.S. networks and Internet-connected devices for disruptive cyber attacks&rdquo; and that &ldquo;low-level cyber attacks&rdquo; are likely as a response to the American bombing.</p>



<p>DHS is also monitoring for signs of potential terrorist attacks orchestrated by Iranian operatives or their partners abroad. Iran has a long history of sponsoring or supporting bombings and assassinations far from its borders, and had plotted to assassinate Trump after he ordered the <a href="https://time.com/5758250/qasem-soleimani-iran-retaliation/" >assassination</a> of Gen. Qasem Soleimani, who led the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps&rsquo; Quds Force.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran also has a long-standing commitment to target U.S. Government officials it views as responsible for the death of an Iranian military commander killed in January 2020,&rdquo; the DHS bulletin warning reads. &ldquo;The likelihood of violent extremists in the Homeland independently mobilizing to violence in response to the conflict would likely increase if Iranian leadership issued a religious ruling calling for retaliatory violence against targets in the Homeland. Multiple recent Homeland terrorist attacks have been motivated by anti-Semitic or anti-Israel sentiment, and the ongoing Israel-Iran conflict could contribute to US-based individuals plotting additional attacks.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&mdash;<em>Brian Bennett contributed reporting</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7297022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is the Strait of Hormuz and What Impact Could It Have on International Trade If Iran Closes It?</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The closing of the Strait of Hormuz is something that would be extremely dangerous and not good for anybody.” ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296861"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221005993.jpg" alt="UAE-IRAN-ISRAEL-US-MARITIME-TANSPORT-CONFLICT"/>



<p>Iran has threatened to close the Strait of Hormuz, in what would serve as <a href="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" >another act of retaliation </a>after the U.S. launched <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >strikes on three key Iranian nuclear facilities</a> over the weekend.</p>



<p>Iran controls the Northern side of the Strait of Hormuz, a passage which sees significant global trade pass through daily. If it so wished, Iran could block vessels from journeying through, or disrupt trade by seizing and attacking shipping containers and oil or gas tankers in the area. With <a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=65504"  target="_blank">roughly 20 million barrels of oil</a> passing through the Strait daily, making up about a fifth of global consumption, any interruption could be catastrophic.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the Strait of Hormuz, its grave importance, and what stands to happen if the passage is disrupted amid the <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >ongoing Israel-Iran conflict</a>, of which the <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >U.S. is now an active participant</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>The Strait is narrow, stretching roughly 31 miles at its widest point. Iran is on its north bank opposite Oman and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</p>



<p>Most oil exports from Kuwait, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Qatar, and the UAE pass through, as well as Iran&rsquo;s own exports. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/qatar-met-with-energy-majors-discuss-risks-israel-iran-war-sources-say-2025-06-20/"  target="_blank">Around 20% of global liquid natural gas</a> exports also flow through the passage, mostly originating from Qatar. </p>



<p>The passage has long been <a href="https://time.com/5632388/strait-of-hormuz-iran-tanker/" >an area of tension and geopolitical significance</a>.</p>



<p>In 2019, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/jun/13/oil-tankers-blasts-reports-gulf-of-oman-us-navy"  target="_blank">two ships were struck</a>, one flying <a href="https://www.vesselfinder.com/vessels/details/9745902"  target="_blank">a Marshall Islands flag</a> and the other <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-48627014"  target="_blank">from Panama</a>,  whilst passing through. The U.S. blamed Iran for the attacks, which Tehran denied. A month prior, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-48245204"  target="_blank">four other tankers</a>&mdash;two from Saudi Arabia, the others from the UAE and Norway&mdash;were struck by suspected underwater mines, which the U.S. accused Iran of planting.</p>



<p>Noam Raydan, a senior fellow at the Washington Institute and an expert on energy and maritime risks, says that some countries, such as Iraq, rely on the Strait for nearly all of its energy exports, whereas other exporters have fairly reliable alternatives to fall back on, should disruption occur.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<em><a href="https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/" > Even Iranians Beaten and Imprisoned by an Unforgiving Regime Condemn Foreign Interference. Here&rsquo;s Why</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What has Iran said about closing the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>The Iranian Parliament on Sunday <a href="https://www.presstv.ir/Detail/2025/06/22/750031/iranian-parliament-moves-close-strait-hormuz-after-us-aggression-lawmaker"  target="_blank">voted in favour of closing </a>the Strait of Hormuz. The decision of whether to carry out that action now lies with Iran&#8217;s Supreme National Security Council and the Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Just verbal threats from Iran are causing concerns in the global market. So imagine how the impact will be if they <em>really</em> acted on their threats,&rdquo; says Raydan.</p>



<p>However, the maritime expert believes that a complete closure of the passage is unlikely as it would cause just as much harm to Iran themselves.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Strait of Hormuz is very important to Iranian allies such as China, because <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c78n6p09pzno#:~:text=In%202022%2C%20around%2082%25%20of,exports%20to%20the%20global%20market."  target="_blank">most of Iran&#8217;s oil</a> goes to China. Closing the Strait would also turn relations between Iran and the GCC [Gulf Cooperation Council] countries sour,&rdquo; Raydan says, adding that Iranian relations with GCC countries such as Saudi Arabia and the UAE are currently stable and also not worth risking.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran can cause disruptions and keep the oil markets jittery by only carrying out individual maritime attacks,&rdquo; Raydan argues, saying isolated assaults are far more likely than a closing of the entire passage.</p>



<p>She warns, however, that should Iranian energy infrastructure be targeted in further attacks, the Iranian response could be more severe, but &#8220;for right now, we should [instead] consider the maritime arena&hellip; there&#8217;s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iran-oil-doomsday-hormuz-may-be-more-fear-than-reality-bousso-2025-06-22/#:~:text=Moreover%2C%20while%20Hormuz%20has%20never,and%20even%20U.S.%20navy%20ships."  target="_blank">a track history of Iran</a> using that to retaliate.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Iran took part in the so-called Tanker War during the 1980s amid active conflict with Iraq, which saw oil tankers targeted by the Iranian military. The U.S. became involved and protected the tankers, in particular those flying U.S. flags, which it is bound to protect under maritime law.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Strait-of-Hormuz.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Has Iran threatened to close the Strait of Hormuz before&mdash;and did it follow through on its threat?</strong></h2>



<p>Iran previously threatened to block the strait in 2011, when Iran&rsquo;s then-Vice President Mohammad Reza Rahimi declared that oil would not pass through the waters if Western sanctions against Iran were widened. The sanctions were issued as a result of concerns over <a href="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" >Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities</a>&mdash;the very topic at the forefront of the current conflict.</p>



<p>In this instance, Iran did not follow through on its threat.</p>



<p>As <a href="https://nation.time.com/2011/12/28/can-iran-close-the-strait-of-hormuz/" >TIME noted in 2011</a>: International maritime law guarantees unimpeded transit through straits, and any deliberate military disruption can be considered an act of war.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What would be the impact on global trade if Iran closes the Strait of Hormuz?</strong></h2>



<p>Oil exporters and importers would stand to be vastly impacted by a closure. And the economic ripple effect would surely be felt far and wide.</p>



<p>According to Deutsche Bank, the cost of a barrel of oil could surge <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/business/oil-prices-iran-israel.html"  target="_blank">to around $120</a>, should Iran block the passage or cause disruption to its shipping lanes. The cost of a barrel currently stands <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/commodities/oil-price"  target="_blank">at around $75</a>.</p>



<p>John Konrad, author and founder of maritime news site gCaptain, says that barriers on new tanker constructions and any disruption to production chains could have a &ldquo;massive&rdquo; economic and social impact.</p>



<p>&ldquo;If you have a slowdown in natural gas, you could have a slowdown in fertilizer,&rdquo; he says, adding that this could lead to &ldquo;food shortages and unrest&rdquo; in a worst-case scenario. The &ldquo;ton mile cost&rdquo; of shipping oil and natural gas will largely increase if Iran were to block trade through the Strait of Hormuz, Konrad argues, even if importers find alternative sources.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The main thing about disruptions and shipping is the ton mile. How many miles does it take to move a ton of oil, and what is that cost?&rdquo; Kondrad notes. &ldquo;The United States is a lot further away from Europe, and much further away from the massive energy consumption in China and Japan and Korea than the Middle East. So what makes the Middle East [so powerful] is not only the abundance of oil, but its central location between Europe and Asia.&rdquo;</p>



<p>European consumers would also feel the impact of any disruption in Hormuz, specifically North-West Europe, when it comes to the prices of gas, oil, and jet fuel.</p>



<p>&ldquo;U.S. refineries might intervene and substitute any gap, but still, disruptions would be felt. Prices will be higher,&rdquo; Raydan says, adding that there would also be logistical issues, similar to those felt when <a href="https://time.com/6553141/red-sea-houthi-attacks-consumer-prices-cost/" >Houthi strikes disrupted trade in the Red Sea</a> following the start of the Israel-Hamas war.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296218/israel-iran-climate-change/" >What Conflict in the Middle East Means for Climate Change</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How have lawmakers from the U.S., U.K., China, and beyond responded?</strong></h2>



<p>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio warned against action in the Strait of Hormuz from Iran in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=APD5gNeIJjY"  target="_blank">an interview with Fox News</a> on Sunday. </p>



<p>&ldquo;I would encourage the Chinese government in Beijing to call him [Khamenei] about that because they [China] heavily depend on the Strait of Hormuz for oil,&rdquo; Rubio said when asked if he expected Iran to close the Strait and disrupt global oil supplies.</p>



<p>Rubio emphasized the U.S. viewpoint that any measures taken to disrupt supply chains in the Persian Gulf would be &ldquo;another terrible mistake.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s economic suicide it they do it and we retain options to deal with that. It would be a massive escalation that would merit a response,&rdquo; he warned.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/" >China has also expressed</a> deep concern over the escalating conflict, and the potential for disruption in trade.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Persian Gulf and nearby waters are [an] important route for international trade in goods and energy. Keeping the region safe and stable serves the common interests of the international community,&rdquo; said Guo Jiakun, the spokesperson for China&rsquo;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs, <a href="https://www.mfa.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/202506/t20250623_11655211.html"  target="_blank">during a press conference on Monday</a>. &#8220;China calls on the international community to step up effort to promote de-escalation of the conflict, and prevent the regional turmoil from having a greater impact on global economic growth.&#8221;</p>



<p>Jiakun went on to emphasize that &#8220;China stands ready to step up communication with Iran and other relevant parties to continue playing a constructive role for a de-escalation.&#8221;</p>



<p>U.K Foreign Minister David Lammy also spoke out on Monday, expressing concerns over the news from the Iranian parliament.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It would be a mistake to blockade the Strait of Hormuz, I think he [Khamenei] gets that and understands that,&rdquo; a hopeful Lammy told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ilThNAQrboI"  target="_blank">the BBC</a>.</p>



<p>In agreement, Kaja Kallas, the European Union representative for foreign affairs and security policy, told reporters on Monday:<strong> </strong>&ldquo;The closing of the Strait of Hormuz is something that would be extremely dangerous and not good for anybody.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Even Iranians Beaten and Imprisoned by an Unforgiving Regime Condemn Foreign Interference. Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Arrest and imprisonment has not changed our views," says one defiant Iranian.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296872"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-88775335-1.jpg" alt="Cell At Evin Prison"/>



<p>What began as a war on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program has developed into something far more imperial. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not politically correct to use the term, &lsquo;Regime Change,&rsquo;&rdquo; President Donald Trump <a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >posted</a> on Truth Social on Sunday. &ldquo;But if the current Iranian Regime is unable to MAKE IRAN GREAT AGAIN, why wouldn&rsquo;t there be a Regime change??? MIGA!!!&rdquo;</p>



<p>On Monday, Israel did its part, launching airstrikes not on military or nuclear sites, but on what Defense Minister Israel Katz <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/katz-idf-striking-with-unprecedented-force-regime-targets-in-tehran/"  target="_blank">called</a> &ldquo;government repression bodies in the heart of Tehran.&rdquo; Among the targets was the <a href="https://x.com/JasonMBrodsky/status/1937096800231367099"  target="_blank">entrance to Evin Prison</a>, notorious for holding political prisoners. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Yet the war is finding no visible support among Iranians once imprisoned there&mdash;the activists who have risked their lives opposing the regime Washington and Tel Aviv want to change.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is exactly what the hardline groups supporting the system wanted,&rdquo; explains twice-jailed Isa Saharkhiz, referring to Israel&rsquo;s military assault. &ldquo;And now, after the U.S. attacks, they are shouting slogans about <a href="https://time.com/7296861/strait-of-hormuz-function-iran-closure-threat-impact-trade/" >closing the Hormuz Strait</a>.&rdquo; </p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </a></em></p>



<p>Saharakhiz placed his name among more than 500 activists and groups that on Sunday condemned the assault on Iran, and voiced &ldquo;serious opposition to any foreign interference.&rdquo; The <a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >statement</a>&mdash;by advocates of a democratic Iran that answers to its people&mdash;was posted in Persian on Telegram, the messaging platform on which Saharkhiz also chatted with TIME.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The civil society has been urging Iran&#8217;s ruling system to continue talks with the U.S. and to reach a peaceful agreement and even establish diplomatic relations between Tehran and Washington, and expand political, economic, and trade relations between Iran and the U.S.,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;But the Israeli attack last week, which was against international law and regulations, helped to disrupt the talks and to begin a terrible war.&rdquo; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2213788011.jpg" alt="Imam Reza Birthday Anniversary In Tehran-Iran" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>That moderate approach was championed by Iran&rsquo;s now-vanquished reformist movement, which surged almost three decades ago with the 1997 election of a gentle librarian and cleric named <a href="https://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1905910_1905908_1905894,00.html" >Mohammad Khatami</a> as Iran&rsquo;s President. Saharkhiz had worked with him earlier, and took a prominent place in his Ministry of Culture, and later among the private newspapers that thrived in the fleeting years that greater personal freedoms seemed within reach. The reformists included activists who overran the U.S. Embassy, supporters of the 1979 revolution that brought theocracy to power who had since found its religious rule heavy-handed and intrusive.</p>



<p>But Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamanei, saw the movement as a challenge to the unelected, authoritarian clerics that held ultimate power. The reformists&rsquo; last gasp came in 2009, when hundreds of thousands took to the streets saying the Presidential election had been stolen from the reformist candidate. In the crackdown that answered it, Saharkhiz was among the hundreds of politicians, activists, professors, and journalists facing arrest.</p>



<p>He did not come easily. After eluding arrest, officials kidnapped his daughter and threatened to assault her if Saharkhiz did not surrender. When he relented, he was beaten so badly he was hospitalized for weeks. In 2024, in a lawsuit filed by his son, a U.S. District court ruled <a href="https://www.iranintl.com/en/202406047698"  target="_blank">Iran should pay $5 million</a> for Saharkhiz&rsquo;s torture during imprisonment.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>Aren&rsquo;t his feelings about the war complicated by his feelings about the regime it targets?</p>



<p>&ldquo;No, not at all,&rdquo; Saharkhiz replied. &ldquo;This is the view that me and many of my friends have had throughout the last two or three decades, and would propagate in the newspapers and magazines that we published, all of which were banned. Arrest and imprisonment has not changed our views.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I remember,&rdquo; he went on, &ldquo;that back during the presidency of Khatami, when reformists had a majority in the 6th parliament, I wrote an article and proposed that a meeting be arranged between Joe Biden, who was at that time the <a href="https://time.com/archive/7030497/joe-biden/" >head of the U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations</a>, and his counterpart in the Iranian parliament, as representatives of the two nations. If I&#8217;m not mistaken, Biden had proposed travelling to Tehran at that time.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The meeting did not happen, though Biden was Vice President when then-President Barack Obama negotiated a pact that effectively <a href="https://time.com/magazine/us/4101160/november-16th-2015-vol-186-no-20-u-s/" >sidelined Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program</a> until Trump <a href="https://time.com/5269746/donald-trump-iran-nuclear-deal-macron/" >withdrew</a> from it in 2018. The withdrawal emboldened Iranian hardliners who in April alone carried out at least <a href="https://deathpenaltyinfo.org/iran-sees-75-increase-in-executions-during-first-four-months-of-2025-over-2024"  target="_blank">110 executions,</a> and have crowded Evin Prison with political prisoners&mdash;some of whom were reportedly injured by Israel&rsquo;s strike on the facility.</p>



<p>A week earlier, as the airstrikes began, several prisoners, including women&rsquo;s rights advocate <a href="https://time.com/7288811/iran-womens-rights-evin-prison-reza-khandan/" >Reza Khandan</a>, wrote a <a href="https://rfkhumanrights.org/our-voices/translation-of-letter-from-reza-khandan-to-iranian-judiciary/"  target="_blank">letter</a> to judicial officials requesting freedom from the prison during the Israeli assault, noting that their ward &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t even have a single fire extinguisher.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296872/iranians-beaten-imprisoned-regime-condemn-foreign-interference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296872</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Fires Missiles at U.S. Base in Qatar; No U.S. Casualties Reported</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thousands of U.S. service members are stationed at Al-Udeid Air Base]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296830"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Al-Udeid-Air-Base-US-IRan.jpg" alt="WCup Qatar US Air Base"/>



<p>Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >retaliated</a> against the U.S. on Monday, launching missiles at a U.S. base in Qatar, according to a U.S. defense official and a statement from the Qatar foreign ministry. The missiles targeted Al Udeid Air Base outside Doha and were intercepted by air defenses before they could strike the base, the Qatari government said. &#8220;At this time, there are no reports of U.S. casualties&#8221; from the barrage of short-range and medium-range ballistic missiles, the U.S. defense official said.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Thousands of U.S. service members are stationed at Al Udeid Air Base, the forward headquarters for U.S. Central Command and an important American military outpost on the Persian Gulf.  Iranian officials had <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >promised</a> to strike back after an American bombing raid on Saturday hit three nuclear program sites inside Iran.</p>



<p>President Donald Trump called the volley of 14 missiles &ldquo;a very weak response&rdquo; from Iran. Of the 14 missiles Iran launched toward the U.S. base, Trump said, 13 were knocked down and one headed in a &ldquo;nonthreatening&rdquo; direction. Trump declared that Iran has gotten it &ldquo;all out of their &lsquo;system&rsquo;&rdquo; with the Qatar attack, and thanked Iran for giving the U.S. &ldquo;early notice.&rdquo; Trump signaled that he wanted to bring an end to the tit-for-tat attacks. &ldquo;Perhaps Iran can now proceed to Peace and Harmony in the Region, and I will enthusiastically encourage Israel to do the same,&rdquo; Trump wrote. </p>



<p>It&rsquo;s unclear if Iran&rsquo;s leaders will decide to <a href="https://time.com/7297022/iran-missiles-trump-attacks/" >retaliate further</a> against the U.S. The Iranian missile attack comes after the State Department on Monday told U.S. citizens living in Qatar to shelter in place. On Sunday, the State Department had warned all American travelers worldwide to exercise &#8220;increased <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >caution</a>.&#8221; The U.S. embassy in Baghdad ordered additional personnel to leave Iraq over the weekend and issued a security alert warning Americans in Iraq of an &#8220;increased potential for foreign terrorist organization-inspired violence or attacks against U.S. businesses and locations frequented by U.S. citizens.&#8221; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Qatar-missile-attacks.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The Pentagon dismissed early reports that U.S. forces on Al Asad Air Base in western Iraq were also targeted by Iranian missiles. &ldquo;We are not aware of any additional attacks against U.S. forces in the region today,&rdquo; said a U.S. defense official late in the afternoon on Monday.</p>



<p>Authorities inside the U.S. are <a href="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" >on alert</a> for cyber attacks and potential violence in the wake of the U.S. strikes on Iran. A Department of Homeland Security advisory issued an advisory on Sunday that the &ldquo;ongoing Iran conflict is causing a heightened threat environment in the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Ahead of the attack on Qatar on Monday, Iran&rsquo;s mission to the United Nations posted on X that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was &ldquo;dragging the United States into yet another costly war&rdquo; and the U.S. had &ldquo;recklessly chosen to sacrifice its own security merely to safeguard Netanyahu.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" > <em>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime</em></a></p>



<p>In an <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >address to Americans</a> after the air strike on Iran on Saturday, Trump threatened to hit more targets in Iran if the country&rsquo;s leaders refused to &ldquo;make peace.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296830/iran-qatar-air-base-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296830</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the L.A. Sheriff&#8217;s Department Has Apologized for &#8216;Offensive&#8217; Social Media Post About Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296772/los-angeles-sheriffs-department-social-media-post-iran-controversy/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296772/los-angeles-sheriffs-department-social-media-post-iran-controversy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["This post was unacceptable, made in error, and does not reflect the views of the Department,” a statement read.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296772"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296772/los-angeles-sheriffs-department-social-media-post-iran-controversy/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-1231070418.jpg" alt="US-JUSTICE-THEFT"/>



<p>The L.A. County Sheriff&rsquo;s Department has formally apologized for an &ldquo;offensive and inappropriate social media post&rdquo; related to the <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >ongoing conflict in Iran</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This post was unacceptable, made in error, and does not reflect the views of Sheriff Robert G. Luna or the Department,&rdquo; the Sheriff&rsquo;s Department said <a href="https://x.com/LASDHQ/status/1936981037021827216/photo/1"  target="_blank">in a statement online</a>, posted late Sunday. &ldquo;As a law enforcement agency, we do not comment on foreign policy or military matters. Our mission remains solely focused on protecting public safety and serving our diverse community.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The apology notice went on to say that the department understands that words and messages &rdquo;carry weight&#8221; and that they will be conducting an internal review into the social media post, which has since been deleted, to &ldquo;determine how it was created and published.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The original post was shared on X on June 22, hours after it was announced that the U.S. had completed strikes on<a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" > three Iranian nuclear sites.</a> According to a <a href="https://ktla.com/news/local-news/l-a-sheriffs-officials-delete-tweet-calling-iranians-victims-of-bombings/"  target="_blank">screenshot</a> obtained by KTLA, the caption read: &#8220;Our hearts go out to the victims and families impacted by the recent bombings in Iran. While this tragic event occurred overseas, the Los Angeles County Sheriff&#8217;s Department is closely monitoring the situation alongside our local, state, and federal partners.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="time-embed time-embed__twitter" data-provider="twitter" data-url="https://twitter.com/LASDHQ/status/1936981037021827216" ><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/z6MhYB8knl"  target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/z6MhYB8knl</a></p>&mdash; LA County Sheriffs (@LASDHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/LASDHQ/status/1936981037021827216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"  target="_blank">June 23, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/" >Critics Demand Pakistan &lsquo;Revokes&rsquo; Decision to Nominate Trump for Nobel Peace Prize After U.S. Strikes on Iran</a></em></p>



<p>The mention of &ldquo;victims and families&rdquo; has since been removed from edited versions of the post on other platforms, and the original post on X is no longer visible.</p>



<p>The message sparked controversy, with some people criticizing the Sheriff&#8217;s Department for commenting on military actions and sharing a message that appeared to be sympathetic.</p>



<p>One conservative commentator <a href="https://x.com/GuntherEagleman/status/1936949233132646623"  target="_blank">said</a> that the L.A. County Sheriff&rsquo;s Department &ldquo;should be ashamed of themselves,&rdquo; while <a href="https://x.com/BillMelugin_/status/1936948518633021866"  target="_blank">a Fox News correspondent</a> said he believed &ldquo;someone went rogue&rdquo; with an &ldquo;unapproved post,&#8221; calling it a &#8220;PR disaster.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </a></em></p>



<p><a href="https://www.migrationpolicy.org/article/iranian-immigrants-united-states-2021"  target="_blank">According to the Migration Policy Institute</a>, more than half of all Iranian immigrants in the U.S. live in California, and over a third live in the L.A. metropolitan area. Many of those Iranian Americans living in L.A. <a href="https://www.latimes.com/food/story/2025-06-22/israel-strikes-iran-los-angeles-iranian-community-tehrangeles"  target="_blank">are a part of the Iranian diaspora</a> that fled the 1979 Iranian revolution.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the U.S. strikes have <a href="https://time.com/7296602/united-states-iran-war-jd-vance-terrorism-threat/" >divided opinion among U.S. lawmakers</a> and beyond. Prominent world leaders and figures have expressed they are &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" >gravely alarmed</a>&rdquo; by the military action, while others have called for de-escalation and a return to negotiations over nuclear capabilities.</p>



<p>The world awaits a response from Iran, which has <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >threatened retaliation over the U.S. strikes</a> that targeted three key nuclear facilities after the U.S. joined the ongoing conflict alongside Israel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296772/los-angeles-sheriffs-department-social-media-post-iran-controversy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296772</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Issues ‘Worldwide Caution’ Alert as Iran Promises Retaliation</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 07:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here’s what to know about how the world is bracing for Iran’s response to Trump’s strikes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296680"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/iran-protests.jpg" alt="Protest Against U.S. Attacks On Iran"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 23, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the U.S. and Iran, Trump, the environment, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>d87ae9f8-77c2-48af-bf8d-b5d833ec6cfb</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>5156db06-bc63-4aa4-9421-450f1618bf05</code></p></div>



<p>The world is waiting with bated breath for Iran&rsquo;s next move after U.S. President Donald Trump authorized <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities</a>, despite warnings against such a move from some <a href="https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/" >U.S. lawmakers</a> and <a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" >foreign leaders</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Iran has <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >promised retaliation</a> against the U.S., and Trump has vowed to meet any retaliation with &ldquo;<a href="https://trumpstruth.org/statuses/31606"  target="_blank">far greater</a>&rdquo; force and even raised the prospect of seeking &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" >regime change</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=mSrygUbr autostart="viewable"]</div>



<p>&ldquo;For 40 years, Iran has been saying, Death to America, Death to Israel,&rdquo; Trump said after the strikes. &ldquo;There will be either peace or there will be tragedy for Iran far greater than we have witnessed over the last eight days.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Remember, there are many targets left,&rdquo; he added. &ldquo;If peace does not come quickly, we will go after those other targets with precision, speed, and skill.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the U.S. is preparing its citizens around the world for potential travel disruptions and &ldquo;demonstrations against U.S. citizens and interests abroad.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Department of State issued a &ldquo;Worldwide Caution&rdquo; alert on Sunday&mdash;the first global alert since the Oct. 7, 2023, Hamas attack on Israel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The conflict between Israel and Iran has resulted in disruptions to travel and periodic closure of airspace across the Middle East,&rdquo; the State Department said in a <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/ea/worldwide-caution2.html"  target="_blank">statement</a>. &ldquo;There is the potential for demonstrations against U.S. citizens and interests abroad. The Department of State advises U.S. citizens worldwide to exercise increased caution.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security also <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/ntas/advisory/national-terrorism-advisory-system-bulletin-june-22-2025"  target="_blank">issued</a> a National Terrorism Advisory on Sunday, warning that &ldquo;low-level cyber attacks against U.S. networks by pro-Iranian hacktivists are likely&rdquo; and that Iran may target U.S. government officials, as the country has repeatedly stated its desires to attack specific officials, including Trump, in retaliation for the U.S. assassination of Iranian Gen. Qasem Soleimani in 2020.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The likelihood of violent extremists in the Homeland independently mobilizing to violence in response to the conflict would likely increase if Iranian leadership issued a religious ruling calling for retaliatory violence against targets in the Homeland,&rdquo; the alert added.</p>



<p>Police in New York, Los Angeles, and Washington, D.C., have heightened vigilance at religious and diplomatic sites and public spaces, according to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-22/world-braces-for-iran-s-response-after-us-strikes-signal-new-era"  target="_blank">Bloomberg</a>.</p>



<p>Iran <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/22/key-players-tangle-at-unsc-at-perilous-turn-of-us-israel-iran-conflict"  target="_blank">condemned</a> the U.S. attacks and <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-22-25-intl-hnk#cmc85syip001w3b6s73j5ri3a"  target="_blank">asked</a> the United Nations Security Council to &ldquo;immediately act&rdquo; to address &ldquo;injustice and gross violations&rdquo; by the U.S. and Israel. Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said Israel with its surprise attack that sparked the war and the U.S. with its intervention this weekend each &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1936703124783112448"  target="_blank">decided to blow up</a>&rdquo; diplomacy.</p>



<p>Iran warned at the UNSC meeting that &ldquo;the timing, nature and the scale of Iran&rsquo;s proportionate response will be decided by its armed force,&rdquo; and Iranian officials have warned that &ldquo;all options&rdquo; are on the table and that U.S. military bases in the region are &ldquo;legitimate targets.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iran also holds significant leverage over global oil trade via the Strait of Hormuz, though disrupting that would also hurt its own economy as well that of its friends like <a href="https://time.com/7296139/china-iran-israel-us-weapons-mediate-war-peace-oil-diplomacy/" >China</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296680/worldwide-caution-alert-terrorism-advisory-iran-retaliation-us-military-bases-nuclear-oil/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296680</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Says ‘Regime Change’ May Be Necessary to ‘Make Iran Great Again’</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After Administration officials insisted the U.S. is not seeking “regime change,” the President posted that it may be necessary to “Make Iran Great Again.”]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296670"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran-vance-hegseth-rubio.jpg" alt="U.S. President Donald Trump delivers an address to the nation from the White House in Washington, D.C. on June 21, 2025. "/>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not politically correct to use the term, &lsquo;Regime Change,&rsquo;&rdquo; President Donald Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114729009239087163"  target="_blank">posted</a> Sunday on Truth Social, a day after the U.S. <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >bombed</a> Iran, raising questions of the ultimate end-goal of American military involvement in the Middle East. &ldquo;But if the current Iranian Regime is unable to MAKE IRAN GREAT AGAIN, why wouldn&rsquo;t there be a Regime change???&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Trump ended with an Iranian spin on his famous campaign acronym: &ldquo;MIGA!!!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Following the U.S. strikes, which targeted three nuclear facilities in Iran, multiple high-ranking members of the Trump Administration had insisted that the goal is not to topple the current Iranian government.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7296013/trump-strike-iran-war-regime-change/" ><em>In Bombing Iran, Trump Looked Past 80 Years of U.S. Regime Change Mistakes</em></a></p>



<p>&ldquo;This mission was not and has not been about regime change,&rdquo; Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t11MJCEAO98"  target="_blank">said</a> in a press conference on Sunday morning. &ldquo;The President authorized a precision operation to neutralize the threats to our national interests posed by the Iranian nuclear program and the collective self-defense of our troops and our ally Israel.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Vice President J.D. Vance <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/video/vice-pres-vance-says-us-has-substantially-delayed-iran-s-nuclear-weapon-program-full-interview-242050117543"  target="_blank">said</a> on NBC on Sunday morning: &ldquo;Our view has been very clear that we don&rsquo;t want a regime change. We do not want to protract this or build this out any more than it&rsquo;s already been built out.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Vance said that the U.S. is &ldquo;not at war with Iran&rdquo; but only with &ldquo;Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program.&rdquo; And he even suggested that the U.S. attack could help put negotiations between the current Iranian government and the U.S., which had <a href="https://time.com/7287313/iran-israel-strike-report-nuclear-us-trump-history-context-explainer/" >begun months ago</a> but had stalled when <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >Israel attacked Iran</a> earlier this month, back on track. &ldquo;I actually think it provides an opportunity to reset this relationship, reset these negotiations, and get us in a place where Iran can decide not to be a threat to its neighbors, not to be a threat to the United States,&rdquo; said Vance, &ldquo;and if they&rsquo;re willing to do that, the United States is all ears.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" ><em>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime</em></a></p>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said Israel and the U.S. &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1936703124783112448"  target="_blank">decided to blow up</a>&rdquo; diplomacy with their respective attacks.</p>



<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s certainly not the goal,&rdquo; Secretary of State Marco Rubio <a href="https://youtu.be/APD5gNeIJjY?t=294"  target="_blank">said</a> of regime change on Fox News on Sunday. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t like the regime, but we&rsquo;re not into the regime change business here. We&rsquo;re into the safety and security of the United States business.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;At the end of the day, if Iran is committed to becoming a nuclear-weapons power, I do think it puts the regime at risk,&rdquo; he added. &ldquo;I think it would be the end of the regime if they tried to do that.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" ><em>Russia Warns World Is &lsquo;Millimeters&rsquo; Away From Nuclear Catastrophe</em></a></p>



<p>Rubio urged Iran to negotiate seriously and directly with Trump, warning: &ldquo;What we are seeing is that this is a President that tells you what he&rsquo;s going to do, and then he does it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump had floated the idea of forcing a regime change by killing Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on June 17, before he authorized strikes on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities, when he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">posted</a> that the U.S. knows Khamenei&rsquo;s location and that he was &ldquo;an easy target&rdquo; but that &ldquo;for now&rdquo; he would be spared. &ldquo;But we don&rsquo;t want missiles shot at civilians, or American soldiers,&rdquo; Trump added. &ldquo;Our patience is wearing thin.&rdquo;</p>



<p>As Iran <a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >threatened</a> after Saturday&rsquo;s attack that it planned to retaliate, Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114724683855260695"  target="_blank">added</a>: &ldquo;ANY RETALIATION BY IRAN AGAINST THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA WILL BE MET WITH FORCE FAR GREATER THAN WHAT WAS WITNESSED TONIGHT.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" ><em>How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</em></a></p>



<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zz1KiQYxk0U"  target="_blank">said</a> last week, after Iran struck an Israeli <a href="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" >hospital</a>, that Khamenei &ldquo;cannot continue to exist.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Amid the threats on his life, the 86-year-old Khamenei, who has led Iran since 1989, is sheltering in a bunker and has even named potential successors in the event of his death, according to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/21/world/middleeast/iran-ayatollah-israel-war.html"  target="_blank"><em>New York Times</em></a>.Trump previously said, before this weekend&rsquo;s strikes, that what he wants from the Iranian regime is &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/" >UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER</a>.&rdquo; But Khamenei <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935296111444472296"  target="_blank">responded</a> then that the U.S. President &ldquo;should make threats against those who are afraid of being threatened. The Iranian nation isn&rsquo;t frightened by such threats.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296670/trump-iran-regime-change-khamenei-hegseth-vance-rubio-us-war/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking Out Iran’s Nuclear Facilities Could Usher In a New Dawn for Peace and Prosperity In the Middle East</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Sonnenfeld, Dennis Ross, Roya Hakakian and Steven Tian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trump’s strikes on Iran’s nuclear sites appear to mark a pivotal step toward Middle East peace.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296553"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran-2025.jpg" alt="President Trump Addresses Nation After US Bombs Iranian Nuclear Sites"/>



<p>Cyrus the Great, the compassionate and tolerant Babylonian who unified Iranian tribes in 549 BC to create the Persian empire, advised leaders to seek &ldquo;diversity in counsel and unity in command&rdquo;, and &ldquo;whenever you can, act as a liberator.&rdquo;  </p>



<p>While Cyrus&rsquo; Iranian descendants lost this wisdom, his message was heard by the U.S. For months, we have warned that Iran stood on the precipice of developing a nuclear weapon. While we do not agree with Donald Trump on many issues, we presciently predicted that in the face of this crisis, the president would act decisively to neutralize Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>It is premature to declare &ldquo;mission accomplished&rdquo; from <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >Trump&rsquo;s decision today </a>to bomb Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities at Fordow, Natanz and Isfahan, with many expecting potential retaliatory strikes against US forces, allies, and interests by Iran in the hours and days ahead. </p>



<p>But from a broader strategic perspective, it is already clear that today marks a potential turning point for the Middle East.</p>



<p>Far from an unnecessary escalation, as some critics suggest, these strikes represent a step closer to peace and prosperity for the U.S., the Middle East, and the world. The main threat to that &#8211; Iran and its proxy network &#8211; have been dramatically weakened. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/20250619-post-card-from-dc-brinkmanship-graph1.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>It is hard to overstate the significance of Trump&rsquo;s strike. A nuclear Iran was one of the gravest long-term security threats facing the world, and nobody wanted to see a regime &mdash; dominated by extremist clerics and fanatics responsible for the deaths of millions of innocent people &mdash; obtain weapons of mass destruction. </p>



<p>But for decades, the presence of Hezbollah, Hamas, and other Iran-backed proxies as threats on Israel&rsquo;s borders made the neutralization of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions unachievable and even unthinkable. For many, it became easier to live with the threat of a nuclear Iran than to deal with it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to Israel&rsquo;s decimation of Iran&rsquo;s proxies over the last two years, sometimes in defiance of western governments, that balance of power has gradually shifted.</p>



<p>Khamenei had a chance for a new nuclear deal, but misguidedly chose not to seize it, reflecting the same fundamental miscalculation that brought the demise of Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar and Hezbollah head Hassan Nasrallah, and culminating in today&rsquo;s<em> coup de grace.</em></p>



<p>With a substantively denuclearized Iranian regime now stripped of key military capabilities and regional leverage, with Hamas and Hezbollah largely neutralized as offensive forces, the greatest obstacles to peace and prosperity in the Middle East will soon be out of the way,&nbsp; creating potential conditions towards expanding the Abraham Accords and forging new economic, cultural, and diplomatic ties between Israel and the greater Arab world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, Hamas&rsquo;s attacks on October 7, 2023, were driven in part by Hamas&rsquo; objective of derailing a planned normalization between Israel and Saudi Arabia, the home of Mecca and the spiritual and symbolic center of Islam.</p>



<p>Riyadh will not be able to move immediately, even if Israel ends the war in Gaza and is able to bring the hostages back home, with the death and destruction in Gaza having soured Arab populaces toward Israel. But make no mistake, today&rsquo;s developments will help bring that process back on track over time, as the people of the Middle East continue to push forward with choosing a future of regional peace and economic prosperity over fear, terror and oppression.</p>



<p>As Jared Kushner, the architect of the Abraham Accords, put it: &ldquo;Iranian leadership has been stuck in the old Middle East, while their neighbors in the Gulf are sprinting toward the future by investing in their populations and infrastructure. They are becoming dynamic magnets for talent and investment while Iran falls further behind.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Despite criticism of the U.S. strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities from across the political spectrum &mdash; from Marjorie Taylor Greene, Tucker Carlson and Thomas Massie on the right, to Bernie Sanders and Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez on the left &mdash; many others have acknowledged its strategic implications and potential opportunities. Figures from both parties, including some of Trump&rsquo;s most frequent critics, such as President Obama and President Biden&rsquo;s top Mideast advisor, Brett McGurk, to former White House Chief of Staff and Ambassador to Japan, Rahm Emanuel &mdash; have recognized the potential significance of this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Emanuel pointed out on CNN, the biggest losers from Trump&rsquo;s strikes are America&rsquo;s enemies abroad, chiefly China and Russia, who were the biggest supporters and enablers of Iran&rsquo;s drive towards a nuclear weapon. Some have even suggested that Putin encouraged Tehran and its proxies as a diversion of attention away from Ukraine. It is now apparent that Iran&rsquo;s struggles have backfired catastrophically on its allies, with their efforts and investment having gone for naught.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </em></a></p>



<p>Ever since George W. Bush anointed Russia, Iran and North Korea as the Axis of Evil, the U.S. had failed to cripple its surge &mdash; until now.</p>



<p>To be clear, it is still far too early to declare &ldquo;mission complete&rdquo;. We are still in the earliest innings as retaliatory strikes from Iran appear imminent. Khamenei will need to do some kind of retaliation, perhaps targeting American forces and bases in the region or targeting the Saudis or Emiratis or another of our regional allies, or shutting down the Strait of Hormuz, to show Iran can hurt the US and its interests. </p>



<p>Regardless, the U.S. is well positioned to fend off Iran&rsquo;s next move, especially if Tehran should choose to engage in economic warfare and target global oil supplies. </p>



<p>If Iran moves to blockade or attack oil tankers traversing the crucial Strait of Hormuz &mdash; where 20% of the world&rsquo;s oil passes through &mdash; the U.S. 5th Fleet, based in Bahrain, can easily break the blockade or provide escorts to tankers as it did during the Gulf War. If Iranian oil is then taken off the market or if Tehran should target Gulf oil facilities, there is plenty of spare oil capacity globally to make up for what is lost. Iran&rsquo;s roughly two million barrels per day of exports pale in comparison to the approximately three million barrels per day of spare capacity possessed by Saudi Arabia alone, not to mention spare capacity within other OPEC+ countries as well as the U.S., now the world&rsquo;s single largest oil producer.</p>



<p>Similarly, on a military front, despite reports that Israel is running low on missile interceptors, which may be overstated anyhow; the U.S. is well prepared to continue supporting Israel while Iran runs hopelessly low on its own supply of ballistic missiles, not to mention the destruction of many missile launch sites.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Iran is still well incentivized to avoid an all-out war with the U.S., which they have long dreaded, for fear that the revolutionary regime led by the Ayatollah may be overthrown.</p>



<p>While the full extent of the damage to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities remains uncertain, what is clear is that Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions have been severely degraded and set back years, if not decades. After the U.S., during the Eisenhower administration, helped initiate Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program for civilian use, the Iranian revolutionary regime has invested half a trillion dollars over 40 years on weaponizing their nuclear program, inching ever closer to the atomic bomb. Between the imploding Iranian economy and the loss of dozens of key nuclear scientists, it will take even longer for Iran to build back what they have lost.</p>



<p>While it remains too soon to know how events will unfold, there is cautious optimism about the possibility of a more stable and peaceful future in the Middle East.</p>



<p>Far from marking a needless escalation, this week&rsquo;s strikes degrading Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities represent a step closer to peace and prosperity for the U.S., the Middle East, and the world.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Jeffrey Sonnenfeld</strong> is Lester Crown Professor of Management Practice at the Yale School of Management as well as founder and president of the Yale Chief Executive Leadership Institute, the world&rsquo;s first school for incumbent CEOs across sectors. He has informally advised five U.S. presidents, two Republicans and three Democrats; helped advise the development of the Abraham Accords; and helped catalyze the exit of over 1,000 companies from Russia.</p>



<p><strong>Dennis Ross</strong> is former special assistant to President Barack Obama in charge of the Middle East. He is the counselor at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy and also teaches at Georgetown University&rsquo;s Center for Jewish Civilization. He has worked on Mideast peace across six decades for both Democratic and Republican Presidents, including as Special Envoy for President George H.W. Bush and President Bill Clinton as well as a member of the National Security Council staff.</p>



<p><strong>Roya Hakakian</strong> is a public scholar at the Moynihan Center at City College, CUNY. She is the author of several books, including Journey from the Land of No: A Girlhood Caught in Revolutionary Iran.</p>



<p><strong>Steven Tian</strong> is research director of the Yale Chief Executive Leadership Institute. He previously worked in the U.S. State Department on Iranian nuclear nonproliferation in the Office of the Under Secretary.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 17:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Tehran, there is evidence the regime is gaining ground with a public it had largely lost. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296554"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2213788011.jpg" alt="Imam Reza Birthday Anniversary In Tehran-Iran"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 23, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the U.S. and Iran, Trump, the environment, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>d87ae9f8-77c2-48af-bf8d-b5d833ec6cfb</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>5156db06-bc63-4aa4-9421-450f1618bf05</code></p></div>



<p>Governments are not nations, especially in the Islamic Republic of Iran, but governments wage the wars that can define a nation.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Until 2:00 a.m. Iran Standard Time on Sunday, the conflict between America and Iran had remained on a low boil for a solid 45 years, flaring into actual military encounters only on the territory of others, notably Iraq. There, <a href="https://www.armytimes.com/news/your-military/2019/04/04/iran-killed-more-us-troops-in-iraq-than-previously-known-pentagon-says/?contentFeatureId=f0fmoahPVC2AbfL-2-1-8&amp;contentQuery=%7B%22includeSections%22%3A%22%2Fhome%22%2C%22excludeSections%22%3A%22%22%2C%22feedSize%22%3A10%2C%22feedOffset%22%3A355%7D"  target="_blank">every sixth U.S. fatality</a> perished by the efforts of Iran. President Donald Trump alluded to this history in announcing <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >the U.S. air strikes on three nuclear facilities</a> inside Iran&mdash;bringing the conflict to a regime that, even when it attacked the U.S., invariably arranged for someone else to do it.</p>



<p>In Iraq, the U.S. was an army of occupation, and its soldiers obliged to patrol the roads. They did so in Humvees heavily armored against the roadside bombs insurgents planted along the route. Iran, which wanted U.S. troops off its doorstep, organized its own insurgents, and gave them a new kind of roadside bomb, a shaped charge that could send a slug of copper through any armor, including an M1 Abrams tank. The soldiers who survived often lost limbs. The U.S. Army <a href="https://nllp.jallc.nato.int/iks/sharing%20public/the%20u.s.%20army%20in%20the%20iraq%20war%20%E2%80%93%20volume%201.pdf?utm_source=chatgpt.com"  target="_blank">history</a> of the <a href="https://time.com/6265077/how-iran-won-the-iraq-war/" >Iraq War</a> takes note of the U.S. unit intercepting crates of the copper plates fitted atop the explosive: &ldquo;All were turned on the same lathe in Iran.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Israeli officials had been warning the Americans about those bombs. Their own troops had encountered them while occupying Lebanon, where the diabolically lethal innovations had been<a href="https://time.com/6324011/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-hamas-war/" > planted by Hezbollah,</a> the militia Iran helped establish and subsequently armed. When the U.S. invaded Iraq in 2003, Tehran directed them to be used against an enemy it had been fighting, in one way or another, since 1979.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >Iran Delivers Furious Warning, Speaks of &lsquo;Unprecedented Level of Danger and Chaos&rsquo; After &lsquo;Heinous&rsquo; U.S. Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>That was the year everyday Iranians rose up against the King (or Shah) who had been put in place a quarter century earlier by the U.S. and British, in a CIA-directed coup bringing down a democratically-elected government (one that had kicked a British oil company out of the country). A half century later, Iranian citizens could be relied upon to bring up the coup to American reporters doing in-person interviews on Tehran streets decorated with wartime propaganda. The entire side of a tall building in Tehran shows the American flag with the stars replaced by skulls and the stripes formed by descending bombs. The mural, which had faded over the decades, was redone with fresh paint a few months ago.</p>



<p>The famous &ldquo;Death to America&rdquo; slogan is still on the wall of the park-like compound that once held the U.S. Embassy. The place was officially dubbed &ldquo;the Den of Spies&rdquo; when it was overrun by supporters of the regime that replaced the Shah&mdash;a revolutionary movement led by a charismatic Shi&rsquo;ite cleric named Grand Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini. (<a href="https://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,2019712_2019694_2019594,00.html" >TIME&rsquo;s Person of the Year in 1979</a> is not to be confused with his similarly named successor, 86-year-old Ali Khamenei, who finally has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/21/world/middleeast/iran-ayatollah-israel-war.html"  target="_blank">reportedly nominated</a> his own candidates as successor.) The former embassy is now a <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293999-d2296233-Reviews-US_Den_of_Espionage-Tehran_Tehran_Province.html#/media/2296233/?albumid=-160&amp;type=ALL_INCLUDING_RESTRICTED&amp;category=-160"  target="_blank">museum</a> and, as <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293999-d2296233-Reviews-US_Den_of_Espionage-Tehran_Tehran_Province.html#/media/2296233/?albumid=-160&amp;type=ALL_INCLUDING_RESTRICTED&amp;category=-160"  target="_blank">TripAdvisor</a> makes clear, an effective one. When Iranians were coming over the gates, American diplomats and spies scrambled to feed secrets into paper shredders, reducing their secret documents to strips of paper maybe an eighth-of-an-inch wide. The zeal of the 1979 revolution is still visible on the tables of the Den of Spies, in the papers true believers re-assembled strand-by-strand.</p>



<p>Over 50 U.S. diplomats remained in the embassy as hostages for 444 days. The humiliation the nascent Islamic Republic of Iran inflicted on the United States may have been on par with the humiliation the regime is experiencing now. </p>



<p>The hitch, for both the U.S. and Israel, is that bringing the attack to Iran, as a country, risks stirring the nationalist response of a nation that goes back 2,500 years. Most Iranians loathe their government, and may have looked on with a certain interest on June 13, when the Israeli warplanes and drones descended, both from abroad and from a base Mossad set up near Tehran. (A joke making the rounds in Tehran had one of Iran&rsquo;s retaliatory strikes hitting the headquarters of Mossad, but it was empty: All the agents were inside Iran.)</p>



<p>At the time its secret nuclear program <a href="https://thebulletin.org/2025/06/a-simple-timeline-of-irans-nuclear-program/"  target="_blank">was revealed</a> in 2002, people still held out hope that they could alter their government at the ballot box. But the political reform movement failed, and the stiffening, increasingly unpopular regime understood that it could no longer count on its population. Instead, it placed its hopes for survival in thugs beating protesters in the streets, and acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>A large majority of Iranians have no love for the regime. In small towns and cities alike, they have been <a href="https://time.com/6275538/iran-protests-eyewitness-report/" >rising up</a> against their oppressive government at irregular intervals, for decades.</p>



<p>But any kind of bomb is terrifying, and after the first night of attacks, Israel&rsquo;s warplanes moved beyond military targets and assassinations. An<a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" > oil refinery</a> was bombed. The casualties of a strike on Tajrish Square, a bustling bazaar in Tehran&rsquo;s north, <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/middle-east/20250617-anatomy-of-an-air-strike-israeli-strike-hits-busy-tehran-intersection"  target="_blank">included a water main</a> and a well-known graphic designer, who was waiting at a red light. The specter of Gaza now looms over every Israeli military operation. After Iran&rsquo;s retaliatory missiles claimed Israeli lives, <a href="https://time.com/7294186/israel-warns-tehran-will-burn-deadly-strikes-traded-nuclear-program/" >Israel&rsquo;s defense minister </a>threatened that &ldquo;Tehran will burn.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Inside Iran, opposing the government does not extend to supporting attacks by foreign militaries. A group of human rights, civil society, and political activists who, as they put it, &ldquo;have always been critical and opposed to the current wrong way of governing,&rdquo; posted a statement on Telegram saying: &ldquo;At this critical juncture in our country&rsquo;s history, when we are confronted with the aggression and arrogance of the racist Israeli government, which has a long history of warmongering, genocide and breaking the fundamental principles of morality and international law, we firmly condemn this attack. We emphasize our serious opposition to any foreign interference. We consider it to be detrimental to the human rights and democracy-seeking efforts of Iranian civil society, and we stand united and steadfast in defending the territorial integrity, independence, national defense capability of our homeland, defending the lives and dignity of human beings, and peace in the region and the world.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Dread swelled in the neighborhoods around the Tehran atomic research reactor, with the distribution of iodide potassium pills to protect the thyroid against radiation in the air. Experts say <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5ykjvl1y9jo"  target="_blank">the risk of radiation exposure</a> is fairly small around the atomic facilities that the U.S. and Israel have bombed to date, because the ones in Fordow, Natanz, and Isfahan all deal with enriching uranium, rather than sparking nuclear reactions. But though small, the <a href="https://www.nti.org/education-center/facilities/tehran-nuclear-research-center-tnrc/"  target="_blank">Tehran reactor</a> (set up by the U.S. in 1967, when the Shah still ruled), operates as Chernobyl or Three Mile Island once did, and in the center of a city of more than nine million people. Those living closest to the reactor were told the pills should be taken by those over the age of 60 and under 40, but only when instructed by state TV, which Israel <a href="https://time.com/7294791/iran-state-tv-israel-strike/" >has also bombed</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em><br><br>So, where do things go from here?</p>



<p>To a large extent, that depends on the actions of an Iranian regime that was already unpopular at the start of this assault. But any government bringing its own military inside Iran&rsquo;s borders should understand the nature of the country. Among Iranians, opposition to the government is grounded in a bedrock pride in their nation, which predates not only the Islamic Republic, but Islam itself. Some on the Iranian plateau still practice Zoroastrianism, the world&rsquo;s first monotheistic faith, and the foundation for an ancient empire that still informs Iranians&rsquo; sense of themselves. That identity can be glimpsed in first names like Darius and Cyrus&mdash;the names of Persian emperors&mdash;and actually visible in the ruins of Persepolis. There, in the friezes depicting supplicants from nations lining up to pay fealty to the ruler of an ancient empire, <a href="https://world.time.com/2011/11/13/behind-irans-nuclear-quest-an-ancient-civilizations-pride-and-insecurity/" >some Iranians find themselves</a> seeing the nuclear program exactly as the modern regime has cast it&mdash;as the &ldquo;<a href="https://www.nti.org/education-center/treaties-and-regimes/treaty-on-the-non-proliferation-of-nuclear-weapons/#:~:text=(Article%20IV):%20The%20Treaty,peaceful%20uses%20of%20nuclear%20energy."  target="_blank">inalienable right</a>&rdquo; of any signatory to Non Proliferation Treaty to pursue a nuclear program, so long as it&rsquo;s peaceful.<br><br>Back in Tehran, there was evidence the regime was gaining ground with a public it had largely lost. In a private chat, a university professor told a friend: &#8220;Even if Khamenei had packed up the whole nuclear program, Israel would have attacked. Their whole plan was to weaken Iran&#8217;s military.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296554</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
