<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:33:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Why People Around the World Are Having Fewer Kids, Even If They Want Them</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294161/fertility-rate-decline/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294161/fertility-rate-decline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chantelle Lee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 23:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nearly 20% of adults from 14 countries believe they won’t be able to have the number of children they want to, new research has found.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294161"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294161/fertility-rate-decline/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Fertility-Report-UN.jpg" alt="Mother uses her hand to hold her baby's tiny hand to make him feeling her love, warm and secure. Newborn."/>



<p>People across the world have been having <a href="https://time.com/6970873/us-declining-birth-rate-2023-total/" >fewer and fewer children</a>, and it&rsquo;s not always because they don&rsquo;t want them.</p>



<p>The global fertility rate has, on average, dropped to less than half what it was in the 1960s, the United Nations <a href="https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/sites/www.un.org.development.desa.pd/files/undesa_pd_2025_wfr_2024_final.pdf"  target="_blank">has found</a>, falling below the &ldquo;replacement level&rdquo; required to maintain the current population in the majority of countries.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Amid that historic decline, nearly 20% of adults of reproductive age from 14 countries around the globe believe they won&rsquo;t be able to have the number of children they want to, the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA), the UN&rsquo;s sexual and reproductive health and rights agency, said in a <a href="https://www.unfpa.org/sites/default/files/pub-pdf/swp25-layout-en-v250609-web.pdf"  target="_blank">report</a> released this week. For most of them, the report found it isn&rsquo;t infertility keeping them from doing so. They pointed to factors including financial limitations, barriers to fertility or pregnancy-related medical care, and fears of the state of the world that they say are hindering them from making their own fertility and reproductive choices.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There are a lot of people out there who are willing to have children&mdash;and have more children than they have&mdash;if the conditions were right, and the government&rsquo;s obligation is to provide those measures of well-being, of welfare, which enable good work-life balance, secure employment, reduce the legal barriers, provide better health care and services,&rdquo; says Shalini Randeria, the president of the Central European University in Vienna and the senior external advisor for the UNFPA report. But she says policies that some governments are implementing&mdash;such as cutting Medicaid in the U.S. and enforcing restrictions on reproductive health and autonomy&mdash;are both a step backward for people&rsquo;s rights and &ldquo;counterproductive from a demographic point of view.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/6965267/women-having-kids-later/" >Why So Many Women Are Waiting Longer to Have Kids</a></em></p>



<p>For the report, UNFPA conducted a survey, in collaboration with YouGov, of people in 14 countries in Asia, Europe, North America, South America, and Africa that, together, represent more than a third of the world&rsquo;s population.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There is a gap between the number of children people would have liked to have had and the number they had,&rdquo; Randeria says. &ldquo;For us, it was important to then figure out&mdash;by asking them&mdash;what it is that causes this gap.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Financial barriers</strong></h2>



<p>The most significant barriers survey respondents identified to having the number of children they desired were economic: 39% cited financial limitations, 19% housing limitations, 12% lack of sufficient or quality childcare options, and 21% unemployment or job insecurity.</p>



<p>The prices for all kinds of goods and services have climbed precipitously in recent years. Global inflation reached the highest level seen since the mid-1990s in July 2022, according to the <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/research/brief/global-inflation"  target="_blank">World Bank Group</a>. While it has declined since then, the current levels are still significantly above those seen before the COVID-19 pandemic. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/child-care-crisis/" >Why Affordable Childcare Is Out of Reach for So Many People</a></em></p>



<p>Rising costs have hit both housing and childcare hard. In the U.S., for instance, the Treasury Department has found that housing costs have <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/featured-stories/rent-house-prices-and-demographics"  target="_blank">increased faster than incomes</a> for the past two decades, surging about 65% since 2000 when adjusted for inflation. And research has found that the cost of child care in the U.S. has <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/child-care-costs-more-than-rent-in-some-u-s-counties-feds-find/"  target="_blank">shot up</a> in recent years, <a href="https://blog.dol.gov/2024/11/19/new-data-childcare-costs-remain-an-almost-prohibitive-expense"  target="_blank">surpassing</a> what many Americans pay for housing or college.</p>



<p>The current housing crisis is impacting &ldquo;every region and country,&rdquo; the United Nations Human Settlements Programme said in a <a href="https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2024/10/2416772e.pdf"  target="_blank">report</a> last year, estimating that between 1.6 billion and 3 billion people around the world do not have adequate housing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Reproductive obstacles</strong></h2>



<p>People cited other factors getting in the way of them having as many children as they want as well, including barriers to assisted reproduction and surrogacy.</p>



<p>Several countries&mdash;including France, Spain, Germany, and Italy&mdash;have <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c62rmv63069o"  target="_blank">banned</a> surrogacy. The UNFPA report also points out that many countries restrict or ban access to assisted reproduction and surrogacy for same-sex couples. In Europe, for instance, only 17 out of 49 countries allow medically-assisted insemination for people, no matter their sexual orientation or gender identity, according to the report.</p>



<p>The UNFPA <a href="https://www.unfpa.org/swp2025"  target="_blank">notes</a> that, as global fertility rates are declining, some governments are taking &ldquo;drastic measures to incentivize young people to make fertility decisions in line with national targets.&rdquo; But the report argues that the &ldquo;real crisis&rdquo; is &ldquo;a crisis in reproductive agency&mdash;in the ability of individuals to make their own free, informed and unfettered choices about everything from having sex to using contraception to starting a family.&rdquo;</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/"  target="_blank">Center for Reproductive Rights</a>, 40% of women of reproductive age around the world live under restrictive abortion laws. Many countries&mdash;including <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cyxx17zeydyo"  target="_blank">Brazil</a>, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/07/18/asia/philippines-abortion-ban-debate-women-rights-roe-wade-intl-hnk-dst"  target="_blank">the Philippines</a>, and <a href="https://reproductiverights.org/un-cedaw-report-poland-abortion/"  target="_blank">Poland</a>, among others&mdash;have severely restricted abortion. In 2022, the U.S. Supreme Court <a href="https://time.com/6189476/abortion-supreme-court-overturns-roe-v-wade/" >overturned</a> the landmark ruling <em>Roe v. Wade, </em>striking down the constitutional right to abortion. Since then, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/us/abortion-laws-roe-v-wade.html"  target="_blank">more than a dozen states</a> have enacted near-total bans or restricted abortion. There have been many reports of pregnant people being <a href="https://time.com/7216391/amanda-zurawski-texas-reproductive-rights/" >denied</a> critical care because of state laws restricting abortions, and many women have <a href="https://time.com/7175184/idaho-near-total-ban-court-case/" >said they don&rsquo;t feel safe</a> being pregnant in states where abortion is banned.</p>



<p>And while a growing share of women around the world are having their family planning needs met, around 164 million still were not as of 2021, the UN <a href="https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/sites/www.un.org.development.desa.pd/files/files/documents/2023/Feb/undesa_pd_2022_world-family-planning.pdf"  target="_blank">found</a> in a report released in 2022.</p>



<p>In addition to considering access to family planning a human right, the UN also <a href="https://www.unfpa.org/family-planning"  target="_blank">notes</a> that it is key to reducing poverty.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Fear for the future</strong></h2>



<p>About 14% of respondents in the UNFPA report said concerns about political or social situations, such as wars and pandemics, would lead or have already led to them having fewer children than they had wanted. And about 9% of respondents said concerns about climate change or environmental degradation would lead or had already led to them having fewer children than they had desired.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/5735388/climate-change-eco-anxiety/" >Terrified of Climate Change? You Might Have Eco-Anxiety</a></em></p>



<p>Violence and conflict have been on the rise around the globe in recent years. The period between 2021 and 2023 was the most violent since the end of the Cold War, according to <a href="https://ieg.worldbankgroup.org/sites/default/files/Data/reports/ap_FCV.pdf"  target="_blank">the World Bank Group</a>, and the numbers of both battle-deaths and violent conflicts have climbed over the past decade.</p>



<p>That violence has contributed to years of rising displacement: More than 122 million people across the world have been forcibly displaced, the UN&rsquo;s refugee agency <a href="https://www.unhcr.org/news/press-releases/number-people-uprooted-war-shocking-decade-high-levels-unhcr"  target="_blank">reported</a> Thursday, nearly double the number recorded a decade ago.</p>



<p>The impact of the global pandemic has been even more widely felt, and is unlikely to fade from anyone&rsquo;s memory any time soon as COVID-19 continues to spread, develop <a href="https://time.com/7289133/new-covid-variant-nb-181/" >new variants</a>, and take a toll on people whose recovery from the virus <a href="https://time.com/7292910/covid-symptoms-long-covid/" >can take months, or even years</a>. Even beyond COVID, outbreaks of infectious diseases are becoming <a href="https://time.com/6211430/infectious-disease-outbreaks-polio-covid-19/" >more commonplace</a>&mdash;and <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9175207/"  target="_blank">experts predict</a> that, in the years ahead, the risk of those outbreaks escalating into epidemics and pandemics will only rise.</p>



<p>In a 2024 <a href="https://climatepromise.undp.org/news-and-stories/worlds-largest-survey-climate-change-out-heres-what-results-show"  target="_blank">UN Development Programme survey</a>, which statistically represents about 87% of the global population, about 56% of respondents said they were thinking about climate change on a daily or weekly basis. About 53% of the respondents also said they were more concerned about climate change now than they were a year before. A third of respondents said that climate change is significantly affecting their major life decisions.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I want children, but it&rsquo;s becoming more difficult as time passes by,&rdquo; a 29-year-old woman from Mexico is quoted as saying in the report. &ldquo;It is impossible to buy or have affordable rent in my city. I also would not like to give birth to a child in war times and worsened planetary conditions if that means the baby would suffer because of it.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294161/fertility-rate-decline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What To Know About Iran’s Nuclear Program After Israel’s Strikes</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 21:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israel struck key Iranian nuclear sites to curb bomb development amid rapid uranium enrichment and rising tensions.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294133"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219270845.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-ISRAEL-IRAN-CONFLICT-NUCLEAR"/>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program suffered one of its most serious setbacks in years on Friday, after <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >Israel launched a series of airstrikes</a> on nuclear sites, top scientists, and military officials in a dramatic escalation of its long-running campaign to contain Tehran&rsquo;s atomic ambitions.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >Israeli officials described the strikes</a> as a preemptive operation aimed at crippling Iran&rsquo;s ability to build a nuclear weapon, following what they called a sharp and alarming expansion of uranium enrichment over the past six months.<strong> </strong></p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Initial damage assessments indicate that the strikes on Iran&rsquo;s Natanz nuclear facility were particularly effective, knocking out the electricity on the underground area where the centrifuges used to enrich uranium are stored, Israel Defense Forces said in a statement Friday. Natanz had been the centerpiece of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear infrastructure and the site where much of its uranium fuel has been produced.</p>



<p>On Friday evening, Iranian state media reported that Israel began striking Iran&rsquo;s other major enrichment site&mdash;Fordow, which is buried deep within a mountain and is considered nearly impervious to conventional airstrikes.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called the campaign a &ldquo;strike at the head of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear weaponization program,&rdquo; and said it would continue &ldquo;as many days as it takes&rdquo; to eliminate the threat. Explosions were <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >reported</a> over Jerusalem and Tel Aviv Friday evening as Iran launched a broad retaliatory strike against Israel.</p>



<p>Iran has insisted that it is not developing a bomb and that its nuclear program remains non-weaponized for peaceful energy purposes, though international inspectors have found increasing evidence to the contrary. The United Nations&rsquo; nuclear watchdog reported that Iran&rsquo;s stockpile of 60% enriched uranium&mdash;just below weapons-grade&mdash;has grown large enough to produce multiple bombs if further enriched. Analysts say Iran could theoretically produce a bomb&rsquo;s worth of material in as little as a week, and that no other country has that level of uranium without a nuclear weapons program.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This really was done as a last resort,&rdquo; says Matt Kroenig, the senior director of the Atlantic Council&rsquo;s Scowcroft Center on international security who served in the Department of Defense and the intelligence community during the Bush, Obama, and Trump Administrations. &ldquo;They were out of time. The best estimates were that Iran&#8217;s dash time to one bomb&#8217;s worth of weapons grade material was down to about a week.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Read more: <a href="https://time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/" ><em>Trump Issues Grave Warning to Iran After Israeli Strikes: &lsquo;No More Death, No More Destruction&rsquo;</em></a></p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How did Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program get this far?</h2>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s nuclear journey began with American support. In 1957, the United States helped launch Iran&rsquo;s atomic energy program under President Eisenhower&rsquo;s &ldquo;Atoms for Peace&rdquo; initiative, when the two nations were allies. By the 1970s, Iran was working on nuclear reactors with U.S. and European assistance, but that partnership collapsed after the 1979 Islamic Revolution.</p>



<p>Since then, the U.S. has watched with alarm as Iran pursued nuclear capabilities, largely in secret. The Natanz site has been a focal point of that concern. In the early 2000s, it was revealed as part of a covert network of nuclear sites that Iran had failed to disclose to international inspectors.</p>



<p>Iran has insisted that its nuclear program is peaceful, aimed at energy production and medical research. It is also a party to the UN&rsquo;s Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, which obliges members not to develop nuclear weapons. But international watchdogs have warned about the country&rsquo;s enrichment of uranium to levels far beyond civilian use and its concealment of key facilities.</p>



<p>Tensions escalated when President Donald Trump in 2018 pulled out of the Iran nuclear deal reached under President Barack Obama, an agreement that rolled back much of Iran&rsquo;s enrichment activity, capped its uranium stockpile, and subjected its facilities to rigorous international inspections. Trump had called the deal &ldquo;a disaster&rdquo; and instead initiated new sanctions on the regime to cripple its economy.</p>



<p>But Iran responded by gradually abandoning the agreement&rsquo;s restrictions and ramping up uranium enrichment. It also removed all of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) equipment that had been installed for surveillance and monitoring. By 2024, Iran had resumed operations at Natanz and Fordow at a pace not seen in over a decade, deploying more advanced centrifuges and enriching uranium to 60-percent&mdash;alarmingly close to the 90-percent purity required for a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Israel Gets the War It Wanted</em></a></p>



<p>In recent months, Iranian officials confirmed they were building a third enrichment site, further deepening concerns that Tehran was preparing to take its nuclear program underground and beyond the reach of future diplomacy or attack.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There are only really three key nuclear facilities [in Iran],&rdquo; says Jonathan Panikoff, the former deputy national intelligence officer for the Near East at the National Intelligence Council, pointing to Natanz, Fordow, and Isfahan. &ldquo;If they succeed in destroying those three facilities, it will really set Iran&#8217;s nuclear program back.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Could Iran build a nuclear weapon&mdash;and how soon?</h2>



<p>Technically, Iran has not yet built a nuclear weapon. But the infrastructure and know-how are in place, analysts say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before Israel&rsquo;s strikes, the IAEA found that Iran could enrich enough uranium for a bomb in about a week. That means that in five months, Iran could have had enough for 22 nuclear weapons. However, analysts note that uranium alone isn&rsquo;t enough for a viable nuclear weapon and that it would take additional time to manufacture it. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219239303.jpg" alt="Israeli Attacks On Iran-Reactions" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Israel and the U.S. oppose a nuclear Iran</h2>



<p>Netanyahu believes that a nuclear-armed Iran is an existential threat, claiming that Iranian leaders have openly called for the end of the Israeli state and have lent support for groups like Hezbollah and Hamas.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Eighty years ago, Jews were victims of a Holocaust perpetrated by the Nazi regime. Today, the Jewish state refuses to be the victim of a nuclear Holocaust perpetrated by the Iranian regime,&rdquo; Netanyahu declared on Friday.</p>



<p>For Israel, the fear is not just a direct nuclear strike, but that Iran could act more aggressively throughout the region under the protection of a nuclear deterrent.</p>



<p>Trump, a strong ally of Israel, has insisted that Iran &ldquo;cannot have a nuclear weapon&rdquo; and framed the moment as a possible &ldquo;second chance&rdquo; for Iran&rsquo;s leadership to quickly reach an agreement on curbing its nuclear program in order to avoid further destruction &ldquo;before there is nothing left and save what was once known as the Iranian Empire.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How has Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program been damaged?</h2>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s strikes on Friday marked the first overt attack on Iran&rsquo;s core nuclear infrastructure. While it remains unclear how Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program will ultimately be impacted, IAEA chief Rafael Grossi told the U.N. Security Council on Friday that Natanz, the facility at the heart of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambition, was destroyed in the strikes. Other major nuclear sites were not initially hit, though Grossi later noted that &ldquo;Iranian authorities are informing us of attacks on two other facilities, namely the Fordow fuel enrichment plant and at Isfahan.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Several high-ranking <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >Iranian military officials</a> were also killed in the strikes, according to state-affiliated media, including six nuclear scientists and security forces tasked with protecting its nuclear sites.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But analysts note that Iran still likely retains much of its expertise and equipment. A full dismantling of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear infrastructure would likely require a sustained campaign involving not only air power, but also cyber warfare, intelligence operations, and potentially ground forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even so, the deeply buried Fordow site&mdash;nearly half a mile inside a mountain&mdash;could be beyond the reach of Israel&rsquo;s current munitions. Only the U.S. is believed to possess the most advanced bunker-busting bombs capable of reliably penetrating such sites, says Panikoff.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294133</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israel Gets the War It Wanted</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 18:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israel strikes Iran after neutralizing Hezbollah as Tehran’s response falters, exposing deep regional shifts and vulnerabilities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293976"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219224540.jpg" alt="Protest in Qom against Israeli attacks on Iran"/>



<p>You can&rsquo;t see Iran from Israel, but on its scenic northern border stand the hills of Lebanon, which at the point where the two countries are closest, is done up to look just like the Islamic Republic. </p>



<p>In Kfar Kila, a town just yards from an Israeli town, <a href="https://world.time.com/2011/04/21/in-little-iran-theres-no-mistaking-the-stakes/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">you might be in Tehran</a>: Iran&#8217;s leaders, past and present, wave from a monument adorned with the emblem from its flag. <a href="https://www.unitedagainstnucleariran.com/ideological-expansion/imam-khomeini-relief-committee"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Blue metal</a> boxes on posts line the roadway, a slot beckoning a few coins to the Imam Khomeini Relief Foundation, named for <a href="https://content.time.com/time/covers/0,16641,19800107,00.html"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the cleric who, in 1979</a>, turned Iran from Israel&rsquo;s stalwart ally to its implacable foe. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>In the decades since, every other country in the region has made some sort of accommodation with Israel, persuaded on the one hand by its formidable U.S.-backed military, and on the other by the security-minded tech sector that grew out of that military. Iran was different. It cast Israel as the unifying nemesis in its unlikely ascension to leadership of a Muslim-only Middle East. The eradication of &ldquo;the Zionist entity&rdquo; remains core to the radical regime Khomeini installed some 1,000 miles away.</p>



<p>That distance was the largest challenge to the 200 warplanes the Israel Defense Forces <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >launched into Iran</a> the early morning hours of June 13. The primary target was nuclear facilities that have edged ever closer to producing a bomb, and Iranian state television showed footage of an attack on the Natanz facility where uranium is enriched. Bursts of orange flash under a half dozen columns of black smoke billowing just beyond a freeway where traffic continues as usual. It&rsquo;s daylight, which meant the assault had been under way for hours. It was not yet 3 a.m. when the apartments of senior commanders began exploding in northeast Tehran. Iran announced <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the deaths</a> of the head of the Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps, two other senior commanders, and as at least two of the 25 nuclear scientist Israel <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/13/how-israel-executed-strike-iran-nuclear?utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=newsletter_axiosam&amp;stream=top"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">reportedly targeted.</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219239303.jpg" alt="Israeli Attacks On Iran-Reactions" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>By first decapitating the military leadership before going after the hardware, Israel&rsquo;s plan of attack mirrored the one that had made it possible. Last September, it had carried out an <a href="https://time.com/7049289/hezbollah-israel-war/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extraordinarily effective campaign</a> against Hezbollah&mdash;the militia Iran had installed in Lebanon, then armed with <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/24/middleeast/hezbollah-weapons-visuals-intl-dg"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">more than 100,000 missiles</a>, with instruction that they were to be launched on its order. Those missiles were pointed at Israel, which lived in mortal fear of them. There were more than could be knocked out of the sky by Iron Dome or any other defense system. They were why Israeli hospitals made plans to treat mass casualties in underground garages. The missiles essentially protected Tehran by making Israeli leaders think hard about the consequences of an attack on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear sites.<br><br>&ldquo;We thought of it as an existential threat,&rdquo; an Israeli reserve officer told me on June 12, wonder in his voice at the reality that the missiles were gone. They vanished in waves of Israeli bombs last fall &ndash; precision strikes that followed the demise of Hezbollah&rsquo;s leadership deep in their bunkers. The militia&rsquo;s rank and file, meanwhile, was shattered first <a href="https://time.com/7022728/lebanon-israel-pagers-walkie-talkies-attacks/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">by pagers, then walkie-talkies that detonated </a>in their hands, having been boobytrapped by Mossad. After living in fear of Hezbollah for 20 years, Israel decimated it in the space of a month. Then turned to Iran.</p>



<p>The Islamic Republic was <a href="https://time.com/7202352/iran-islamic-revolution-regime-weakening-inside-syria/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">looking poorly</a>. Israel had already humiliated it by <a href="https://time.com/7006644/israel-iran-gaza-haniyeh-assassination/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exploding a bomb</a> in the most highly guarded zone of in Tehran, killing the leader of Hamas in a government guesthouse. None of its gains over the prior two decades&mdash;seeing Iraq turned from enemy to vassal by the U.S. invasion; getting to call the shots in Syria, where it saved the Assad regime; and finding a friend in Yemen, where it sponsors the Houthi militia&mdash;none of that compared to the loss of Hezbollah. Compelled to reply, Iran&#8217;s leaders <a href="https://time.com/7027518/iran-israel-attack-missile/" >launched</a> scores of missiles and drones toward Israel.  As had been the case in an even larger attack in April, when almost all were knocked down with the help of U.S., European, and even neighboring Arab forces, the result was ineffectual. </p>



<p>Worse, the attack gave Israel standing to retaliate, which it did by launching precision strikes that knocked out Iran&rsquo;s most important anti-aircraft defenses&mdash;in preparation for the assault now underway. In announcing it, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the attack would last at least a few days, and noted that the targets included Iran&rsquo;s ballistic missiles. Iran has so many that, even from 1,000 miles away, the numbers could overwhelm any interception systems. &ldquo;We can&rsquo;t leave these threats for the next generation,&rdquo; Netanyahu said. &ldquo;If we don&rsquo;t act now, there won&rsquo;t be a next generation.&rdquo;</p>



<p>President Trump called the attack &ldquo;excellent.&rdquo; Iran&#8217;s initial response, reportedly of 100 drones, produced no result. Meanwhile, Israel released footage of what it said were its own commandos on the ground in Iran, with a drone base prepositioned. It said it killed most of the leadership of Iran&rsquo;s air force, after luring them to a meeting. A half day in, the war was going well.</p>



<p>Like the cascading campaign against Hezbollah, it was the war Israel has been preparing for.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, in Gaza, the other kind drags on: 1,200 civilians and soldiers killed in Israel in one day (and 251 dragged into captivity) and 55,000 civilians and soldiers killed in Gaza over the next 20 months. Israel, accurately, calls Hamas a client of Iran, though <a href="https://world.time.com/2013/11/21/hamas-is-in-trouble-in-gaza-and-looking-to-iran-for-help/" >the relationship has had its ups and downs</a>. Iran counts itself the leader of the smaller of Islam&rsquo;s two branches, Shi&rsquo;ism, and all its other clients align with the sect in some fashion. Hamas is firmly Sunni, which has caused <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/middleeast/palestinianauthority/10091629/Iran-cuts-Hamas-funding-over-Syria.html"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">problems</a> in the past. The elimination of Israel is their common ground, and Hamas&rsquo; attack of Oct. 7 was intended to ignite. After overwhelming Israel with its strike out of Gaza in the south, its planners&rsquo; hope was that Hezbollah would unleash the assault Israelis had long feared from the north, and the &ldquo;Zionist entity&rdquo; would collapse.</p>



<p>Instead, Iran instructed Hezbollah to hold back. For the next year, as tens of thousands of Israelis fled their homes near the border, Tehran played the military equivalent of chess, sending a few <a href="https://time.com/6322633/israelis-hamas-attack-nightmare-essay/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">missiles a day</a> over the border in tit-for-tat exchanges that signaled no change, status quo. As if this could go on forever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293976</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boeing&#8217;s 787 Dreamliner Has a Long History of Safety Concerns</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293945/boeing-787-dreamliner-long-history-safety-concerns/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293945/boeing-787-dreamliner-long-history-safety-concerns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Kluger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 15:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explainer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The investigation into Air India flight 171 crash opens up questions into the many concerns surrounding Boeing's 787 Dreamliner planes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293945"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293945/boeing-787-dreamliner-long-history-safety-concerns/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219145109.jpg" alt="Air India Boeing 787 Headed to London Crashes After Takeoff"/>



<p>The odds were in your favor if you were one of the 242 people who boarded Air India flight 171 in Ahmedabad, India, bound for London on June 12. The plane you were flying was a Boeing 787 Dreamliner which has been in service since 2011 without a fatal crash. More than 1,100 Dreamliners are in use worldwide, carrying <a href="https://www.boeing.com/commercial/787/quality-info#at-a-glance"  target="_blank">more than 875 million passengers</a> over the last decade, according to Boeing. Your particular 787, delivered to Air India in 2014, <a href="https://www.cirium.com/"  target="_blank">had amassed 41,000 hours of flying time and just under 8,000 takeoffs and landings</a>, according to <a href="https://www.cirium.com/"  target="_blank">Cirium</a>, an aviation industry analytics firm.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>But none of that would have helped you. Just after takeoff, when the plane was barely 625 ft. in the air, it lost altitude and plunged into a residential area, killing all but one of the passengers and crew on board. The cause of the crash is as yet unknown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Our deepest condolences go out to the loved ones of the passengers and crew on board Air India Flight 171, as well as everyone affected in Ahmedabad,&rdquo; said Boeing president and CEO Kelly Ortberg <a href="https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=131555"  target="_blank">in a statement</a>. &ldquo;I have spoken with Air India Chairman N. Chandrasekaran to offer our full support, and a Boeing team stands ready to support the investigation led by India&rsquo;s Aircraft Accident Investigation Bureau.&rdquo;</p>



<p>That investigation is likely to go deeper than just Flight 171, ranging back over the 14 years the 787s have been flying&mdash;years that, it turns out, have seen numerous complaints, concerns, and whistleblower reports over the safety of the widebody jet. All of them are getting a second look today.</p>



<p>The problems began in early 2013, when <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-lithium-ion-batteries-grounded-the-dreamliner/"  target="_blank">fires broke out aboard two Dreamliners</a> owned by Japanese airlines. One plane had just landed at Boston&rsquo;s Logan Airport, the other was just leaving Japan and had to turn around and land. Both blazes were traced to overheating of the planes&rsquo; lithium-ion batteries that power the electrical system. The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) quickly stepped in, grounding the worldwide fleet of Dreamliners and temporarily halting the delivery of new ones to airlines that had placed orders for them. In April of 2013, the FAA <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/20/business/faa-endorses-boeing-remedy-for-787-battery.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0"  target="_blank">accepted Boeing&rsquo;s fixes</a>, which involved better insulation for the batteries and a stainless steel box that would house the batteries and prevent smoke or flames from escaping into the plane if a fire did start. The Dreamliners were cleared to fly and the company was cleared to resume deliveries within weeks of the FAA&rsquo;s decision.</p>



<p>The next incident occurred in 2019 when, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/20/business/boeing-dreamliner-production-problems.html"  target="_blank">as The New York<em> Times</em> reported</a> in an expos&eacute; at the time, John Barnett, a former quality manager who retired in 2017, revealed that he had filed a whistleblower complaint, alleging sloppy work around the wires that connect the planes&rsquo; flight control systems, with metal shavings being left behind when bolts were fastened. The risk existed that the shavings would penetrate the wires&rsquo; insulation, leading to consequences that Barnett called &ldquo;catastrophic.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Barnett also alleged that damaged or substandard parts were being installed in 787s, including a dented hydraulic tube that a senior manager retrieved from a bin of what was supposed to contain scrap. The FAA inspected several 787s that were said to be free of the shavings Barnett reported and found that they were indeed there, reported the <em>Times</em>. The FAA then ordered that Boeing correct the problems before the planes were delivered to customers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In retirement, Barnett sued Boeing, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-68534703"  target="_blank">alleging that the company</a> had denigrated his character and blocked his career advancement during his employment&mdash;charges Boeing denies. In March of 2024, he was in North Charleston, S.C., the site of the plant where he was employed, working on his case, when he was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/business/boeing-john-barnett-lawsuit.html"  target="_blank">found dead in his truck</a> from a self-inflicted gunshot wound.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Boeing may not have pulled the trigger,&rdquo; Barnett&rsquo;s family said in a <a href="https://www.courthousenews.com/the-family-of-an-airplane-safety-whistleblower-is-suing-boeing-over-his-death/"  target="_blank">wrongful death lawsuit</a> it filed, &ldquo;but Boeing&rsquo;s conduct was the clear cause.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The company sidestepped the charge: &ldquo;We are saddened by John Barnett&rsquo;s death and send our condolences to his family,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/03/21/g-s1-55175/whistleblower-john-barnett-lawsuit-boeing#:~:text=Boeing%20whistleblower%20John%20Barnett%2C%20who,a%20response%20to%20the%20lawsuit."  target="_blank">Boeing said</a> in a statement.</p>



<p>Last year turned out to be a bad one for Boeing and the Dreamliner for reasons other than Barnett&rsquo;s death. In January <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/boeing-787-dreamliner-is-flawed-fuselage-manufacture-whistleblower-rang-alarm-air-india-crash-ahmedabad-2739852-2025-06-12"  target="_blank">another whistleblower</a>, engineer Sam Salehpour, came forward, reporting that sections of the fuselage of the Dreamliner were improperly connected, with gaps that could cause the plane to break apart during flight. When the sections wouldn&rsquo;t fit, Salehpour claimed, workers would resort to brute force.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I literally saw people jumping on the pieces of the airplane to get them to align,&rdquo; Salehpour <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/boeing-787-dreamliner-is-flawed-fuselage-manufacture-whistleblower-rang-alarm-air-india-crash-ahmedabad-2739852-2025-06-12"  target="_blank">said in Capitol Hill testimony</a>. &ldquo;By jumping up and down, you&rsquo;re deforming parts so that the holes align temporarily. I called it the Tarzan effect.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.boeing.com/commercial/787/quality-info#at-a-glance"  target="_blank">In a statement on its website</a>, Boeing defended the integrity of the Dreamliner: &ldquo;For the in-service fleet, based on comprehensive analysis no safety issues have been identified related to composite gap management and our engineers are completing exhaustive analysis to determine any long-term inspection and maintenance required, with oversight from the FAA.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Nonetheless, in May, the <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/05/06/1249432229/faa-investigation-boeing-787-dreamliner"  target="_blank">FAA acted again</a>, announcing that Boeing had been ordered to reinspect &ldquo;all 787 airplanes still within the production system and must also create a plan to address the in-service fleet.&rdquo; That was not the first time the government had taken action on the problem of unacceptable gaps in the Dreamliner&rsquo;s fuselage. From May 2021 to August 2022, the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/02/24/business/boeing-787-dreamliner-halt#:~:text=While%20the%20787%20Dreamliners%20have,control%20during%20its%20assembly%20process."  target="_blank">FAA halted the delivery</a> of new Dreamliners to airline customers while the problem was addressed. Deliveries did resume but, as Salehpour testified, so did the shoddy work on the factory floor.</p>



<p>In March 2024, meantime, a LATAM Airlines flight from Sydney to Auckland <a href="https://www.flightglobal.com/safety/involuntary-captains-seat-shift-preceded-latam-787-in-flight-upset/157922.article"  target="_blank">suddenly plunged 400 ft</a>. when the pilot&rsquo;s seat in the 787 lurched forward unexpectedly. The captain recovered but 10 passengers and three members of the cabin crew were injured.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For now, the 1,100 Dreamliners criss-crossing the skies are still flying. That could change pending the results of the Air India investigation. Even a temporary loss of the plane&mdash;which is a workhorse for long-haul flights&mdash;could be a hardship for both the airlines and the flying public. But as the grieving families of the passengers aboard the Air India flight could attest, loss of life is much worse.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293945/boeing-787-dreamliner-long-history-safety-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Issues Grave Warning to Iran After Israeli Strikes: &#8216;No More Death, No More Destruction&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 13:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Certain Iranian hardliners spoke bravely, but... they are all DEAD now."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293906"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219814667.jpg" alt="President Trump Holds Bill-Signing Ceremony At The White House"/>



<p>President Donald Trump has issued a stark warning to Iran, urging the country to accept a nuclear deal to avoid further &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >planned attacks</a>,&rdquo; citing that &ldquo;there has already been great death and destruction, but there is still time to make this slaughter&hellip; come to an end.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump spoke out via his social media platform, Truth Social, on Friday morning, reacting to the news that Israel had launched an overnight attack on Iran, targeting multiple nuclear and military sites.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Referencing the ongoing negotiations over Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program, Trump said that he had given Iran a chance to make a deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;I told them, in the strongest of words, to &lsquo;just do it,&rsquo; but no matter how hard they tried, no matter how close they got, they just couldn&rsquo;t get it done,&rdquo; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114675456780398208"  target="_blank">Trump said</a>. &ldquo;Certain Iranian hardliners spoke bravely, but they didn&rsquo;t know what was about to happen. They are all DEAD now, and it will only get worse.&#8221; </p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=mRHZc9m5 autostart="viewable"]</div>



<p>Trump added that Iran was told how &ldquo;the United States makes the best and most lethal military equipment anywhere in the World, BY FAR, and that Israel has a lot of it, with much more to come. And they know how to use it.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran must make a deal, before there is nothing left, and save what was once known as the Iranian Empire. No more death, no more destruction, JUST DO IT, BEFORE IT IS TOO LATE.&rdquo; Trump warned.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >Iran Fires Back at Israel</a></em></p>



<p>The U.S. was decidedly not involved in the overnight military action, as confirmed by a statement from Secretary of State Marco Rubio, in which he urged Iran not to target the U.S.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Tonight, Israel took unilateral action against Iran. We are not involved in strikes against Iran and our top priority is protecting American forces in the region. Israel advised us that they believe this action was necessary for its self-defense,&rdquo; said Marco, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/06/statement-from-secretary-of-state-marco-rubio/"  target="_blank">in a statement shared by the White House shortly after the initial strikes</a>. &ldquo;President Trump and the Administration have taken all necessary steps to protect our forces and remain in close contact with our regional partners. Let me be clear: Iran should not target U.S. interests or personnel.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-june13.jpg" alt="Israel Launches Strikes Against Iran" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >A number of senior military officials</a> and nuclear scientists have been killed by the Israeli strikes on Iran, with <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334078/ayatollah-khamenei-warns-israeli-regime-of-tough-punishment-after-attack-on-iran"  target="_blank">Ayatollah Ali Khamenei vowing retaliation</a>, saying that Israel &ldquo;should anticipate a severe punishment&rdquo; and &ldquo;has prepared for itself a bitter, painful fate, which it will definitely see.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Israel Defence Forces (IDF) <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1933324595471454495"  target="_blank">announced the &ldquo;preemptive, precise offensive&rdquo; </a>in a statement in the early hours of Friday morning, local time.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran is closer than ever to obtaining a nuclear weapon. Weapons of mass destruction in the hands of the Iranian regime are an existential threat to the State of Israel and to the wider world,&rdquo; the statement read. &ldquo;The State of Israel has no choice but to fulfill the obligation to act in defense of its citizens.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1933340443343008068"  target="_blank">said the strikes</a>, part of Operation Rising Lion, &ldquo;will continue for as many days as it takes to remove this threat.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >Here Are the Top Iranian Generals and Scientists Targeted and Killed by Israeli Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>Iran has since responded with around 100 drone strikes on Israel, with Jordan confirming that drones also entered its airspace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prior to this, talks between the U.S. and Israel had appeared to be heading in a more positive direction after Ali Shamkhani&mdash;senior adviser to Ayatollah Khamenei&mdash;<a href="https://time.com/7285832/trump-middle-east-tour-key-moments/" >said in May</a> that Iran was willing to accept a deal subject to conditions.</p>



<p>Talks were still ongoing as of early June. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-present-counter-proposal-us-nuclear-talks-foreign-ministry-says-2025-06-09/"  target="_blank">Iran rejected</a> a U.S. proposal and offered a counter-offer on June 9. The following day, Iranian lawmakers accused the U.S. of turning negotiation talks into a trap.</p>



<p>&#8220;The U.S. is not serious in negotiations at all. It has set the goal of talks as imposing its demands and has adopted offensive positions that are diametrically opposed to Iranians&#8217; inalienable rights,&#8221; Iranian lawmakers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iranian-lawmakers-accuse-us-israel-planning-nuclear-talks-trap-2025-06-10/"  target="_blank">said in a statement</a>.</p>



<p>Now, with Israel and Iran trading strikes, world leaders are looking to the Middle East and urging restraint.</p>



<p>A <a href="https://www.un.org/sg/en/content/sg/statement/2025-06-12/statement-attributable-the-spokesperson-for-the-secretary-general-%E2%80%93%C2%A0-israeli-strikes-against-the-islamic-republic-of-iran"  target="_blank">spokesperson for U.N. Secretary-General Ant&oacute;nio Guterres</a> has relayed his concerns.</p>



<p>Guterres &#8220;condemns any military escalation in the Middle East&#8221; and &#8220;is particularly concerned by Israeli attacks on nuclear installations in Iran, while talks between Iran and the U.S. on the status of Iran&#8217;s nuclear programme are underway.&#8221;<br> <br>Another round of nuclear talks between Iran and the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/oman-confirms-next-round-us-iran-nuclear-talks-amid-fears-regional-risks-2025-06-12/"  target="_blank">was set to take place in the Sultanate of Oman&#8217;s capital of Muscat this weekend,</a> but it remains to be seen if those will go ahead, now that Israel and Iran are engaged in military action.</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How have other U.S. lawmakers reacted to Israel&rsquo;s attack?</strong><br></h1>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. Lindsey Graham</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina, a Republican, has issued a number of comments on the strikes in Iran. &ldquo;Game on. Pray for Israel,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/LindseyGrahamSC/status/1933318401608282411"  target="_blank">read his initial reaction to the attack</a>, which he called &ldquo;one of the most impressive military strikes in Israeli history.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Graham followed up with<a href="https://x.com/LindseyGrahamSC/status/1933357900602196028"  target="_blank"> a statement</a> remarking on the possibility of Iranian retaliatory strikes on &ldquo;American military personnel or interests throughout the region.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The Senator said if such actions were taken by Iran, then &ldquo;America should have an overwhelming response, destroying all of Iran&rsquo;s oil refineries and oil infrastructure putting the Ayatollah and his henchmen out of the oil business.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/LindseyGrahamSC/status/1933522205142348185"  target="_blank">He also expressed support</a> for Trump&rsquo;s comments, saying: &ldquo;I very much appreciate President Trump&rsquo;s strong statement in support of this Israeli operation and his urging for the Iranian Regime to make a deal to abandon their nuclear enrichment program to avoid further bloodshed.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. Ted Cruz</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. Ted Cruz of Texas, a Republican, <a href="https://x.com/tedcruz/status/1933342444638159344"  target="_blank">has relayed support</a> for Israel&rsquo;s attack on Iran, citing it as an act of self-defense. </p>



<p>&ldquo;President Trump has been clear that Iran must completely dismantle their nuclear capacity. Iran has given President Trump the middle finger. Israel is acting to defend themselves, and we should stand with them.&rdquo; he said, <a href="https://x.com/tedcruz/status/1933351157940040093"  target="_blank">later adding</a>: &ldquo;Tonight, pray for Israel. Pray for the American servicemen and women who are in harms way. And to the Ayatollah: If you attack American military bases, President Trump will respond with overwhelming force.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. Tom Cotton</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. Tom Cotton of Arkansas, a Republican, <a href="https://x.com/SenTomCotton/status/1933339069406232860"  target="_blank">said</a>: &ldquo;Iran is the world&rsquo;s worst state sponsor of terrorism, has the blood of thousands of Americans on its hands, and is rushing to build not only nuclear weapons, but also missiles that can strike the United States. We back Israel to the hilt, all the way&hellip; And if the Ayatollahs harm a single American, that will be the end of the Ayatollahs.&rdquo; </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. Chris Murphy</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. Chris Murphy of Connecticut, a Democrat,<a href="https://x.com/ChrisMurphyCT/status/1933345572443783580"  target="_blank"> criticized Israel </a>and the Trump Administration over the strikes in Iran.</p>



<p> &ldquo;Israel&#8217;s attack on Iran, clearly intended to scuttle the Trump Administration&#8217;s negotiations with Iran, risks a regional war that will likely be catastrophic for America and is further evidence of how little respect world powers&mdash;including our own allies&mdash;have for President Trump,&#8221; he said, describing Iran&rsquo;s progression towards possible nuclear weapons as &ldquo;a disaster of Trump and Netanyahu&#8217;s own making.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. Andy Kim</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. Andy Kim of New Jersey, a Democrat, has <a href="https://x.com/SenatorAndyKim/status/1933331658821812482"  target="_blank">cautioned Iran on its response</a>, whilst also issuing criticism at Israel&rsquo;s decision to launch the overnight attack.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>&ldquo;</strong>Iran should know that any targeting of U.S. forces and personnel stationed across the Middle East in retaliation for Israel&#8217;s actions would be a grave mistake,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;This action ordered by Prime Minister Netanyahu appears to deliberately undermine ongoing American diplomatic negotiations about Iran&#8217;s nuclear program&hellip; We should do everything we can to stop this moment from spiraling into a wider conflict and bring parties back to the table to ensure that Iran does not obtain a nuclear weapon.&rdquo; </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Sen. John Fetterman</strong></h2>



<p>Sen. John Fetterman of Pennsylvania, a Democrat,<a href="https://x.com/SenFettermanPA/status/1933337901963903335"  target="_blank"> also responded</a> to Israel&rsquo;s strikes on Iran. &ldquo;Our commitment to Israel must be absolute and I fully support this attack,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Keep wiping out Iranian leadership and the nuclear personnel. We must provide whatever is necessary&mdash;military, intelligence, weaponry&mdash;to fully back Israel in striking Iran.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here Are the Top Iranian Generals and Scientists Targeted and Killed by Israeli Strikes—and What We Know About Them</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 11:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israel attacked Iran in a “precise and integrated preemptive strike” against Iranian nuclear facilities and military targets. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293886"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2209436186.jpg" alt="Iran's Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei"/>



<p>Israel attacked Iran in a &ldquo;precise and integrated preemptive strike&rdquo; against Iranian nuclear facilities and military targets. The Israeli Air Force (IAF) <a href="https://x.com/IAFsite/status/1933327825349603456"  target="_blank">said in a statement</a> that the overnight strikes were carried out with the &ldquo;aim of damaging the Iranian nuclear program and in response to the Iranian regime&#8217;s ongoing aggression against Israel.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu confirmed that the aim of the strikes, part of &ldquo;Operation Rising Lion,&rdquo; was to dismantle the Iranian nuclear programme, which has long been a cause of concern.</p>



<p>&ldquo;In recent months, Iran has taken steps that it has never taken before. Steps to weaponize this enriched uranium and if not stopped, Iran could produce a nuclear weapon in a very short time,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1933340443343008068"  target="_blank">Netanyahu said in a video statement</a>. &ldquo;This operation will continue for as many days as it takes to remove this threat.&rdquo;</p>



<p>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio announced that the U.S. was not involved in the military action and warned Iran not to target the U.S.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Tonight, Israel took unilateral action against Iran. We are not involved in strikes against Iran and our top priority is protecting American forces in the region. Israel advised us that they believe this action was necessary for its self-defense,&rdquo; said Marco, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/06/statement-from-secretary-of-state-marco-rubio/"  target="_blank">in a statement shared by the White House</a>.  &ldquo;President Trump and the Administration have taken all necessary steps to protect our forces and remain in close contact with our regional partners. Let me be clear: Iran should not target U.S. interests or personnel.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Speaking out via Truth Social on Friday morning, Trump urged Iran to make a deal regarding its nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>&#8220;I gave Iran chance after chance to make a deal. I told them, in the strongest of words, to &#8216;just do it,&#8217; but no matter how hard they tried, no matter how close they got, they just couldn&rsquo;t get it done&#8230;. Certain Iranian hardliner&rsquo;s spoke bravely, but they didn&rsquo;t know what was about to happen. They are all DEAD now, and it will only get worse,&#8221; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114675456780398208"  target="_blank">Trump said</a>. &#8220;There has already been great death and destruction, but there is still time to make this slaughter, with the next already planned attacks being even more brutal, come to an end. Iran must make a deal, before there is nothing left, and save what was once known as the Iranian Empire. No more death, no more destruction, JUST DO IT, BEFORE IT IS TOO LATE.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-june13.jpg" alt="Israel Launches Strikes Against Iran" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Iran <a href="https://x.com/ME_Observer_/status/1933392557867737446"  target="_blank">vowed retaliation soon after</a> Israel&rsquo;s strikes landed, saying &ldquo;this is the voice of a nation and a government that calls the world to witness that we were not the initiators of war, but the end of this story will be written by Iran&#8217;s hand.&rdquo; The country has since <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >launched around 100 drones </a>to strike Israeli targets. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.jaf.mil.jo/NewsView.aspx?NewsId=59813"  target="_blank">Jordan</a> has confirmed that drones entered its airspace overnight.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >Iran Vows &lsquo;Painful&rsquo; Response After Israeli Attack</a></em></p>



<p>The initial Israeli strikes targeted a number of locations across the Iranian capital, Tehran, including the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps HQ.  </p>



<p>On Friday, the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed the deaths of three top Iranian commanders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We can now confirm that the Chief of staff of the Iranian Armed Forces, Commander of the IRGC and the Commander of Iran&rsquo;s Emergency Command were all eliminated in the Israeli strikes across Iran by more than 200 fighter jets,&rdquo;<a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1933390314766516522"  target="_blank"> the statement read</a>. &ldquo;These are three ruthless mass murderers with international blood on their hands. The world is a better place without them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>An additional update from the IDF confirmed that another commander of the IRGC (Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps) Air Force has been &#8220;eliminated.&#8221;</p>



<p>Scientists working on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear development have also been reported killed.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the figures reportedly killed by the Israeli strikes.</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Military personnel</strong></h1>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Major General Hossein Salami</strong></h2>



<p>Gen. Hossein Salami, commander-in-chief of the Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps, Iran&rsquo;s main military force, was a key figure in the political sphere. It&rsquo;s understood he  <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/13/middleeast/israel-iran-strikes-military-deaths-intl-hnk"  target="_blank">reported directly</a> to Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>



<p>Salami rose to power around six years ago, and during his time as Major General of the IRGC, he <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-iran-revolutionary-guard-hossein-salami-ce75eb0aad963c6f6257e9a2c4b376ff"  target="_blank">repeatedly threatened Israel and the U.S.</a> with military action.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/5758250/qasem-soleimani-iran-retaliation/" >After the 2020 death</a> of Qasem Soleimani, the head of IRGC Qud&rsquo;s Force, who was killed in a U.S. airstrike on a base in Baghdad, Salami said: &ldquo;If they [Israel and the U.S.] threaten our commanders, none of their commanders will find a safe place&rdquo; to live. Days after the death of Soleimani, Iran launched a number of missiles at American military facilities in Iraq, with no casualties reported. </p>



<p>Khamenei has announced that Salami will be replaced by <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334436/irgc-gets-new-chief-after-martyrdom-of-general-salami"  target="_blank">Brigadier General Mohammad Pakpour</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Major General Mohammad Bagheri</strong></h2>



<p>Mohammad Bagheri served as the Chief of Staff to Iran&rsquo;s armed forces, a position he acquired in 2016 which saw him oversee an estimated <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/10/2/iran-and-israel-what-are-their-attack-and-defence-capabilities#:~:text=Number%20of%20soldiers,than%20640%20armoured%20personnel%20carriers."  target="_blank">610,000 personnel.</a> He was the second-highest commander after Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>



<p><a href="https://sanctionssearch.ofac.treas.gov/Details.aspx?id=27850"  target="_blank">Born in 1960</a>, Bagheri was head of &ldquo;the most senior military body in Iran, which implements policy and monitors and coordinates activities within the armed forces,&rdquo; according to <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm824"  target="_blank">U.S. Treasury documents</a> detailing sanctions against the general in 2019.</p>



<p>Bagheri will be replaced by <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334391/army-chief-appointed-as-iran-s-top-general"  target="_blank">Major General Abdolrahim Mousavi</a>, as announced by Ayatollah Khamenei.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>General Gholamali Rashid</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334062/major-general-rashid-his-son-confirmed-dead-in-israeli-strike"  target="_blank">Rashid was confirmed dead </a>after the airstrikes in Tehran, alongside his son. He was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/13/world/middleeast/iran-military-generals-killed-israel.html"  target="_blank">deputy commander in chief</a> of the armed forces, and <a href="https://www.opensanctions.org/entities/Q4391340/"  target="_blank">commander</a> of Khatam-al Anbiya Central Headquarters, a branch of the IRGC.</p>



<p>Rashid was key in the operations of Iran&rsquo;s unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) programme, mostly consisting of the use of drones in warfare.</p>



<p>In February, <a href="https://www.tehrantimes.com/news/510192/Senior-Iranian-commander-vows-retaliation-against-origins-of"  target="_blank">the general vowed </a>to retaliate against any strikes on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program after reports of plans from Israel and the U.S. to strike nuclear targets in Iran by &ldquo;mid-2025.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Rashid is set to be replaced by <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334484/khatam-al-anbia-central-headquarters-of-iran-gets-new-chief"  target="_blank">Major General Ali Shadmani</a> as head of the Khatam-al Anbiya Central Headquarters.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Commander Amir Ali Hajizadeh</strong></h2>



<p>Ali Hajizadeh was the commander of the IRGC.</p>



<p>Upon announcing his death, <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1933475985812259063"  target="_blank">the IDF said Hajizadeh</a> &#8220;had assembled in an underground command center to prepare for an attack on the State of Israel.&#8221;</p>



<p>The IRGC described the general as &ldquo;a prominent and influential figure of the resistance front and a symbol of development, innovation, and might in the defense and missile spheres.&rdquo;</p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Nuclear Scientists</strong></h1>



<p>Key scientists working on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear programme have also been reported as killed in Israel&rsquo;s strikes on Iran overnight. <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/13/3334216/reports-suggest-loss-of-at-least-6-iranian-nuclear-scientists-in-israeli-attacks"  target="_blank">Tasnim News Agency</a> reports at least six have died.</p>



<p>Among the scientists thought to have died are Fereydoon Abbasi, Mohammad Mahdi Tehranchi, and Seyed Amir Hossein Feqhi.</p>



<p>Abbasi was the former head of Iran&rsquo;s atomic energy, and also served as an MP (Member of Parliament.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tehranchi was a theoretical physicist and<a href="https://isis-online.org/isis-reports/detail/highlights-of-irans-perilous-pursuit-of-nuclear-weapons/"  target="_blank"> a key expert involved in the AMAD plan</a>, Iran&rsquo;s significant programme to advance nuclear capabilities launched in the early 2000s. Tehranchi was also the President of Islamic Azad University in Tehran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Feqhi was deputy head of the Atomic Energy Organization of Iran, as well as on the faculty for Nuclear Engineering at Shahid Beheshti University in Tehran.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293886</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Fires Back at Israel</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Air sirens sounded in Jerusalem and Tel Aviv as Iran launched a retaliatory attack against Israel.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293839"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219307342.jpg" alt="Israeli-Iranian conflict - Tel Aviv"/>



<p>Explosions were reported over Jerusalem and Tel Aviv Friday evening as Iran launched a broad retaliatory strike against Israel, marking a significant escalation in an already volatile regional conflict.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s ongoing attacks on Iranian nuclear sites, <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >generals, and scientists</a> killed 78 people and wounded more than 320 on Friday, Iran&rsquo;s ambassador told the U.N. Security Council, but he said &ldquo;the overwhelming majority&rdquo; of victims were civilians. Israel described the new wave of hostilities as the beginning of &ldquo;Operation Rising Lion.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=mRHZc9m5 autostart="viewable"]</div>



<p>The ambassador spoke shortly after Iran retaliated with a barrage of long-range missiles targeting Israel&rsquo;s commercial capital, Tel Aviv, wounding at least 34 people, Israel&rsquo;s paramedic service said.</p>



<p>Iran had <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >warned Israel that it would pay a &ldquo;heavy price&rdquo; for its strikes</a>. Iran&#8217;s state-run news agency IRNA claimed that the country&#8217;s air defense systems had shot down at least two Israeli fighter jets, though the report could not be independently verified. The fate of the pilots remains unknown.</p>



<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >Israel Gets the War It Wanted</a></em></p>



<p>Israel Defense Forces (IDF) spokesperson Effie Defrin said, according to <a href="https://x.com/jimsciutto/status/1933394730404008240"  target="_blank">CNN</a>, that Iran had launched more than 100 drones toward Israeli territory. Such drones can reportedly take up to seven hours to reach Israel from Iran. </p>



<p>&ldquo;All [aerial] defense arrays have been operating to intercept the threats,&rdquo; Defrin was quoted as saying. &ldquo;This is a different event to what we&rsquo;ve experienced thus far, and we&rsquo;re expecting difficult hours. We should show resilience and patience.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Around 9:30 a.m. in Tel Aviv (2:30 a.m. ET), an IDF official <a href="https://x.com/mrconfino/status/1933413205411234049"  target="_blank">told</a> the media that Israel&rsquo;s military had begun to shoot down Iranian drones. About two hours later, the IDF said, according to <em>Times of Israel</em> correspondent <a href="https://x.com/manniefabian/status/1933439945084903443"  target="_blank">Emanuel Fabian</a>, that it had &ldquo;control over the situation,&rdquo; though it did not specify at the time whether it had shot down all the drones.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219304834.jpg" alt="Iranian-missiles-strike-Israel" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz earlier <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >said</a> Israel should expect an &ldquo;immediate&rdquo; retaliation from Tehran following the strikes, which came a day after the U.S. began <a href="https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/" >evacuating embassy personnel</a> across the Middle East amid concerns of possible escalation of conflict. The State Department on Thursday evening directed embassy employees and their families in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza to take shelter.</p>



<p>U.S. President Donald Trump <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >called on Iran</a> to return to nuclear negotiations, warning that continued escalation would lead to further loss of life. &ldquo;There has already been great death and destruction,&rdquo; he wrote in a post on social media, &ldquo;but there is still time to make this slaughter come to an end.&rdquo;</p>



<p>U.S. Special Envoy to the Middle East Steve Witkoff <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/12/israel-strike-iran-response-witkoff"  target="_blank">warned</a> Senate Republicans last week, according to a report by Axios, that Iran&rsquo;s response to an attack by Israel could involve hundreds of missiles launched at Israeli and U.S. sites that could overwhelm defense capabilities and result in mass casualties.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel braces for attack</h2>



<p>A number of moves were made within Israel in seeming preparation for an attack, including the cancellation of a Pride parade scheduled for Friday in Tel Aviv.</p>



<p>Israeli authorities instructed all hospitals to move their services to protected areas and underground facilities, according to the <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/health-ministry-idf-instruct-all-hospitals-to-move-medical-services-to-protected-areas/"  target="_blank"><em>Times of Israel</em></a>, and they asked the public to only come to hospitals for urgent cases.</p>



<p>Hadassah Hospital in Jerusalem was in &ldquo;full emergency mode,&rdquo; the <a href="https://apnews.com/live/israel-iran-attack#00000197-67d0-d617-a597-7fd9762f0000"  target="_blank">Associated Press</a> reported, and it was releasing patients whose conditions permitted as well as cancelling non-urgent operations.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/head-of-israels-manufacturers-association-essential-industries-will-operate-continuously/"  target="_blank"><em>Times of Israel</em></a> also reported that Israel Manufacturers Association president Dr. Ron Tomer said essential industries will continue to operate throughout any potential emergency &ldquo;so that supplies will be available to the public throughout the country at any given moment.&rdquo; Tomer warned against hoarding, saying &ldquo;there is no need to storm the shelves,&rdquo; in an effort to prevent shortages of foods, medicines, and other essential products.</p>



<p>And Reuters <a href="https://english.alarabiya.net/News/middle-east/2025/06/13/israir-airline-evacuating-its-aircraft-from-ben-gurion-airport"  target="_blank">reported</a> that Israeli airline Israir, as well as airlines Arkia and El Al, would evacuate and relocate its aircraft from the Ben Gurion International Airport in Tel Aviv as part of a contingency plan developed in recent days. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">International involvement</h2>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s National Security Council also <a href="https://www.gov.il/he/pages/travelwarningsjune"  target="_blank">warned</a> Israelis overseas to &ldquo;take precautions&rdquo; as &ldquo;terrorist elements will seek to carry out acts of revenge against Israeli and Jewish targets around the world.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jordan, which shares a border with Israel, <a href="https://www.petra.gov.jo/Include/InnerPage.jsp?ID=72392&amp;lang=en&amp;name=en_news"  target="_blank">announced</a> early Friday that its airspace would be closed in light of the &ldquo;military escalation&rdquo; in the region. Iran and Iraq have similarly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/after-israel-strikes-iran-airlines-divert-flights-airspace-closed-2025-06-13/"  target="_blank">closed</a> their respective airspaces.</p>



<p>Jordanian state media <a href="https://www.petra.gov.jo/Include/InnerPage.jsp?ID=72398&amp;lang=en&amp;name=en_news"  target="_blank">reported</a> that its Air Force jets and air defense systems intercepted &ldquo;several missiles and drones&rdquo; that entered its airspace Friday morning, adding that these were intercepted &ldquo;based on military assessments indicating that the missiles and drones were likely to fall within Jordanian territory, including populated areas, posing a potential threat to civilian safety.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Dubai-based international airline Emirates also <a href="https://www.emirates.com/sg/english/help/travel-updates/#6313"  target="_blank">announced</a> flight cancellations to and from Iran, Iraq, Jordan, and Lebanon and announced that customers connecting through Dubai with their final destinations in those countries &ldquo;will not be accepted for travel at their point of origin until further notice.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other countries are reportedly choosing not to get involved. Larisa Brown, defense editor at <em>The Times</em> of London, <a href="https://x.com/larisamlbrown/status/1933416719374004661"  target="_blank">posted</a> on X: &ldquo;UK defence sources say there aren&rsquo;t any UK plans to help protect Israel. Clearly this could change throughout the course of day.&rdquo; </p>



<p>In response to a request from TIME about the report, a British government spokesperson pointed to Prime Minister <a href="https://x.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1933401302442111457"  target="_blank">Keir Starmer&rsquo;s</a> and Foreign Minister <a href="https://x.com/DavidLammy/status/1933391783125295416"  target="_blank">David Lammy&rsquo;s</a> statements urging restraint and deescalation. The spokesperson noted that the U.K. <a href="https://x.com/HFalconerMP/status/1933440269325627769"  target="_blank">did not play a part</a> in the military action in Iran and that British nationals should monitor <a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice"  target="_blank">official travel advisories</a>.</p>



<p>Iran requested an emergency session of the United Nations Security Council to discuss the Israeli strikes, claiming its right to respond &ldquo;in a decisive, proportionate, and deterrent manner&rdquo; in a letter submitted by its permanent mission to the U.N., the <a href="https://www.tehrantimes.com/news/514239/Iran-calls-for-emergency-UN-meeting-vows-response-to-Israeli"  target="_blank"><em>Tehran Times</em></a> reported. A statement by the General Staff of the Armed Forces of Iran, however, <a href="https://english.alarabiya.net/News/middle-east/2025/06/13/iran-armed-forces-say-no-limits-in-response-to-israel"  target="_blank">said</a> that its response will have &ldquo;no limits.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iran has <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >threatened to retaliate against the U.S.</a>, too, for the Israeli attack, despite the U.S. claiming no involvement. The Israeli military <a href="https://www.facebook.com/idfonline/posts/1121807236647957"  target="_blank">released</a> images of U.S.-made warplanes used in its strikes against Iran. The U.S. is Israel&rsquo;s top weapons supplier.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293839</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Vows ‘Painful’ Response After Israeli Attack: What to Know</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israel launched “preemptive” strikes early Friday across Iran, amid growing regional tensions and concerns about Iran’s nuclear capabilities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293795"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/iran-israel-strikes.jpg" alt="APTOPIX Iran Mideast Wars"/>



<p>Iran has vowed that Israel and the U.S. will pay a &ldquo;<a href="https://en.irna.ir/news/85860969/Armed-Forces-spokesperson-Israel-will-pay-a-heavy-price"  target="_blank">heavy price</a>,&rdquo; according to a military spokesperson, after Israel launched &ldquo;preemptive&rdquo; strikes early Friday local time on Iran, amid growing regional tensions and concerns about Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities.</p>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei <a href="https://en.irna.ir/news/85860975/Ayatollah-Khamenei-Israel-today-sealed-a-bitter-and-painful"  target="_blank">said</a> in a message to his nation that Israel &ldquo;sealed for itself a bitter and painful destiny.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The U.S. has disclaimed involvement in the strikes, but Iran&rsquo;s foreign ministry <a href="https://x.com/IrnaEnglish/status/1933371705486950552"  target="_blank">said</a> in a statement that the attack, which it alleged violated international law, &ldquo;could not have been carried out without coordination with and approval of the United States&rdquo; and that the U.S. as Israel&rsquo;s main supporter will also &ldquo;be held responsible for the dangerous consequences of Israel&rsquo;s adventurism.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" ><em>Iran Fires Back at Israel</em></a></p>



<p>Calling the operations &ldquo;Rising Lion,&rdquo; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1933340443343008068"  target="_blank">said</a> in a video statement that the strikes targeted areas focused on &ldquo;nuclear enrichment&rdquo; and &ldquo;nuclear weaponization&rdquo; programs. The operation &ldquo;will continue for as many days as it takes to remove this threat,&rdquo; Netanyahu said.</p>



<p>The Sultanate of Oman, which was meant to host a sixth round of nuclear talks between Iran and the U.S. in its capital Muscat this weekend, blamed Israel for the &ldquo;escalation and its consequences,&rdquo; according to <a href="https://x.com/ONA_eng/status/1933370146564784208"  target="_blank">Omani state media</a>. Oman said Friday after Israel&rsquo;s attack that &ldquo;such conduct threatens to marginalize diplomatic solutions and undermine regional security and stability.&rdquo; Iranian media, citing officials, <a href="https://x.com/IranIntl_En/status/1933399224973951168"  target="_blank">reported</a> that the talks will no longer happen following the strikes.</p>



<p>Global leaders have called for calm, including United Nations Secretary-General Ant&oacute;nio Guterres, who according to a <a href="https://www.un.org/sg/en/content/sg/statement/2025-06-12/statement-attributable-the-spokesperson-for-the-secretary-general-%E2%80%93%C2%A0-israeli-strikes-against-the-islamic-republic-of-iran"  target="_blank">statement</a> &ldquo;condemns any military escalation in the Middle East&rdquo; and &ldquo;asks both sides to show maximum restraint, avoiding at all costs a descent into deeper conflict, a situation that the region can hardly afford.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel&rsquo;s attack</h2>



<p>Explosions were seen and heard across Iran, including in the capital Tehran as well as in the city of Natanz, where a nuclear facility is located. Sources on the ground tell TIME that apartment buildings where senior Iranian officers and officials were believed to reside appear to have also been targeted.</p>



<p>A journalist based in Tehran who requested anonymity for security reasons tells TIME that he first heard strikes at around 3:24 a.m. local time (7:54 p.m., Thursday, ET). &ldquo;It was very close to my home &hellip; It woke me up,&rdquo; the journalist said, describing a very loud noise. &ldquo;The windows were shaking, and I immediately realized this was an attack of some sort.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The journalist confirmed that some residential complexes were hit in the attack, adding that the strength of the strikes caused some to collapse. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m pretty sure that there has been civilian casualties,&rdquo; the journalist said.</p>



<p>Panic ensued on the ground, the journalist recounted, with people pouring onto the capital&rsquo;s streets. &ldquo;Nobody really knows where it&rsquo;s safe to go.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/iran-apartments-attacked.jpg" alt="Israel launches attacks on Iran" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Iranian state media <a href="https://en.irna.ir/news/85861042/Top-Iranian-military-commanders-and-two-civilian-figures-are"  target="_blank">reported</a> that Armed Forces chief of staff Mohammad Bagheri and Islamic Revolution Guards Corps Chief Commander Major General Hossein Salami as well as nuclear scientists Mohammad-Mehdi Tehranchi and Fereydoun Abbasi were among those killed.</p>



<p>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1933324595471454495"  target="_blank">said</a> in a statement that<strong> </strong>it launched a &ldquo;preemptive, precise, combined offensive to strike Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program,&rdquo; with dozens of Air Force jets targeting &ldquo;nuclear targets in different areas of Iran.&rdquo; Axios Reporter Barak Ravid <a href="https://x.com/BarakRavid/status/1933337111375327271"  target="_blank">reported</a> that a senior Israel official said the airstrikes were accompanied by a series of Mossad-led &ldquo;covert sabotage operations deep inside Iran&rdquo; that were designed to damage Iran&rsquo;s missile sites and air defense capabilities.</p>



<p>IDF spokesperson Effie Defrin <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1933328551333216407"  target="_blank">said</a> its &ldquo;preemptive and precise strikes&rdquo; were targeted to prevent Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;ability to build a nuclear bomb in the immediate time frame.&rdquo; Defrin added: &ldquo;We have no choice&mdash;we are operating against an imminent and existential threat.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7287313/iran-israel-strike-report-nuclear-us-trump-history-context-explainer/" ><em>The Tense History and Modern Context Behind Israel&rsquo;s Reported Plan to Attack Iran</em></a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Iran&rsquo;s response</h2>



<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said in a <a href="https://x.com/efenigson/status/1933320590833619376/photo/1"  target="_blank">statement</a> that a retaliatory attack on Israel and its civilian population &ldquo;is expected in the immediate timeframe.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s attack comes a day after the U.S. began <a href="https://time.com/7293392/us-embassy-iraq-iran/" >evacuating embassy personnel</a> across the Middle East amid rising regional tensions as negotiations between the U.S. and Iran over the latter&rsquo;s nuclear program have appeared to stall.</p>



<p>Axios reported Thursday that U.S. Special Envoy to the Middle East Steve Witkoff <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/12/israel-strike-iran-response-witkoff"  target="_blank">warned</a> Senate Republicans last week that if Israel were to attack Iran, Iran&rsquo;s response could involve hundreds of missiles launched at Israeli and U.S. sites that could result in a &ldquo;mass casualty&rdquo; event.</p>



<p>The State Department on Thursday night <a href="https://il.usembassy.gov/security-alert-u-s-embassy-jerusalem-june-13-2025/"  target="_blank">directed</a> all embassy employees and their families in Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza to shelter in place.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/israel-iran-attack-retaliation.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-ISRAEL-PALESTINIAN-IRAN-CONFLICT" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">U.S. reactions</h2>



<p>President Donald Trump <a href="https://x.com/JenGriffinFNC/status/1933369583726920116"  target="_blank">reportedly told Fox News</a> after Israel&rsquo;s attack began that he was aware the strikes would take place but that the U.S. was not involved. He added that the U.S. still hopes to engage with Iran in nuclear talks but will defend itself and Israel if Iran retaliates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/world/iran/live-blog/israel-strikes-iran-middle-east-conflict-live-updates-rcna212727/rcrd81870?canonicalCard=true"  target="_blank">NBC</a>, Trump&rsquo;s national security team monitored Israel&rsquo;s strikes on Iran from the Situation Room. The White House said Trump will attend a National Security Council meeting on Friday morning.</p>



<p>Secretary of State Marco Rubio said in a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/06/statement-from-secretary-of-state-marco-rubio/"  target="_blank">statement</a>: &ldquo;Tonight, Israel took unilateral action against Iran. We are not involved in strikes against Iran and our top priority is protecting American forces in the region. Israel advised us that they believe this action was necessary for its self-defense. President Trump and the Administration have taken all necessary steps to protect our forces and remain in close contact with our regional partners. Let me be clear: Iran should not target U.S. interests or personnel.&rdquo;</p>



<p>U.S. Ambassador to Israel Mike Huckabee <a href="https://x.com/GovMikeHuckabee/status/1933302492147687876"  target="_blank">posted on X</a> amid the strikes: &ldquo;At our Embassy in Jerusalem and closely following the situation. We will remain here all night. &lsquo;Pray for the peace of Jerusalem!&rsquo;&rdquo; </p>



<p>U.S. lawmakers have had mixed reactions. House Speaker Mike Johnson (R, La.) <a href="https://x.com/SpeakerJohnson/status/1933351802990113091"  target="_blank">posted on X</a>: &ldquo;Israel IS right&mdash;and has a right&mdash;to defend itself!&rdquo; Sen. Chris Murphy (D, Ct.) <a href="https://x.com/ChrisMurphyCT/status/1933338988116390397"  target="_blank">posted</a>: &ldquo;Israel&rsquo;s attack on Iran, clearly intended to scuttle the Trump Administration&rsquo;s negotiations with Tehran, is further evidence of how little respect world powers&mdash;including our own allies&mdash;have for President Trump.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Mongolia’s New Prime Minister Means for Its Democracy</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s either a triumph for people power or a worrying lurch towards authoritarianism, depending on whom you ask.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293415"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Gombojav-Zandanshatar-Mongolia-PM.jpg" alt="Hungary Mongolia"/>



<p>It&rsquo;s either a triumph for people power or a worrying lurch towards authoritarianism, depending on whom you ask, but Mongolia has a new Prime Minister: Zandanshatar Gombojav, a Russian-educated former banker who previously served as Foreign Minister, Chief of the Cabinet Secretariat, and speaker of the State Great Khural parliament.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I will work forward, not backward,&rdquo; Zandanshatar told the State Great Khural, whose lawmakers overwhelmingly approved his elevation to the premiership by 108 out of the 117 members present. &ldquo;By respecting unity, we will overcome this difficult economic situation.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>They&rsquo;re economic woes that contributed to the downfall of outgoing <a href="https://time.com/7209066/mongolia-prime-minister-oyun-erdene-luvsannamsrai-uranium-france-putin-trump/" >Prime Minister Luvsannamsrain Oyun-Erdene</a>, who belongs to the same Mongolian People&rsquo;s Party (MPP) but <a href="https://time.com/7290686/mongolia-prime-minister-oyun-erdene-luvsannamsrain-resigns-protests-corruption-son/" >quit</a> after failing to receive sufficient backing in a June 3 confidence vote he called to quell popular protests demanding his ouster.</p>



<p>For several weeks, thousands of predominantly young demonstrators have thronged central Ulaanbaatar&rsquo;s Sukhbaatar Square in outrage at the lavish displays of wealth that Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s son and fianc&eacute;e posted on social media, including helicopter rides, an expensive engagement ring, a luxury car, and designer handbags.</p>



<p>The crowds called for Oyun-Erdene to disclose his personal finances, but he declined saying that they had already been provided to the nation&rsquo;s Anti-Corruption Agency, as required by law. However, public trust in that body and the wider judiciary is scant following a slew of high-profile <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2023/1/25/after-anti-corruption-protests-mongolia-rethinks-coal-sales"  target="_blank">graft scandals</a> coupled with a conspicuous lack of prosecutions or accountability.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Oyun-Erdene was the one who was talking about morals, transparency, and corruption,&rdquo; protest leader Unumunkh Jargalsaikhan, 27, tells TIME. &ldquo;But Mongolia is actually degrading when it comes to the economy and freedoms. The corruption scandal was just the spark.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Unumunkh blames rising living costs and torpid wages for driving public anger, especially among young people. Mongolia is facing an economic crunch with government spending <a href="https://www.fitchratings.com/research/sovereigns/mongolias-next-government-may-face-rising-fiscal-risk-09-06-2025"  target="_blank">rising</a> 20% year-on-year for the first four months of 2025 but goods exports falling by 13% over the same period, owed not least to a 39% decline in coal exports. Still, Oyun-Erdene was dismissive of the protesters and in a statement instead blamed &ldquo;a web of interests, tangled like a spider&rsquo;s web&rdquo; for toppling him.</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s supporters say his ouster had three drivers: Firstly, and with a dash of irony, his relentless pursuit of official graft, including a <a href="https://www.parliament.mn/en/nn/74900/"  target="_blank">draft law</a> his cabinet just submitted that would compel all public officials to justify their income.</p>



<p>Secondly, last year&rsquo;s updated Minerals Law, which puts 34% of the equity of &ldquo;strategic&rdquo; mines&mdash;defined as producing over 5% of GDP&mdash;into a Sovereign Wealth Fund. Today, nine of Mongolia&rsquo;s 16 strategic deposits are privately owned by influential industrialist families. &ldquo;Those private companies are very unhappy and completely opposed to 34% belonging to the state,&rdquo; says Jargalsaikhan Dambadarjaa, a Mongolian broadcaster and political commentator.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6976412/nuclear-power-mongolia-uranium-climate-change/" ><em>The Promise of Nuclear Energy Brings the West to Mongolia</em></a></p>



<p>The third alleged driver is more contentious: that Mongolian President Ukhnaagiin Khurelsukh deviously undermined Oyun-Erdene in order to change the constitution to boost presidential powers and extend term limits from the single, six-year stint currently permitted.</p>



<p>True, incoming Prime Minister Zandanshatar&rsquo;s most recent posting was as chief-of-staff to Khurelsukh, who chose to give a midnight speech to the State Great Khural on the eve of Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s no-confidence vote that urged lawmakers to represent their constituents rather than a single political leader. Despite the MPP having enough lawmakers to reach the 64-vote threshold required to save Oyun-Erdene, his own party deserted him, with the secret ballot totaling just 44 votes for, 38 against.</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s camp paints Khurelsukh as an aspiring autocrat intent on aligning Mongolia with authoritarian neighbors China and Russia, noting how he hosted Vladimir Putin in Ulaanbaatar in September, flouting an International Criminal Court arrest warrant, and also <a href="https://president.mn/en/2025/05/10/president-khurelsukh-attends-the-victory-day-parade/"  target="_blank">attended</a> Moscow&rsquo;s Victory Day Parade in May. A doctored <a href="https://x.com/HansGutbrod/status/1929465880821325841"  target="_blank">photo</a> depicting Khurelsukh as having commissioned a giant golden statue of himself in the manner resembling a Central Asian despot is doing the rounds on social media.</p>



<p>However, this narrative has some problems. Gladhanding Putin is a political necessity for landlocked Mongolia, whose 3.5 million population relies on Moscow for 90% of imported gas and petroleum and is completely beholden to Russia for security. &ldquo;Turning up in September was Putin showing the rest of the world his middle finger,&rdquo; says Prof. Julian Dierkes, a Mongolia expert at the University of Mannheim in Germany. &ldquo;There was no option for Mongolia to say no.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, Khurelsukh has proven an internationalist, first <a href="https://blogs.ubc.ca/mongolia/2021/khurelksukh-un-general-assembly-security-council/"  target="_blank">addressing</a> the U.N. General Assembly soon after his inauguration in 2021 and returning every year since. (His predecessor, Khaltmaagiin Battulga, rarely showed up.) While not outright condemning Russia&rsquo;s aggression in Ukraine, Khurelsukh&rsquo;s latest UNGA address in September did pointedly <a href="https://gadebate.un.org/sites/default/files/gastatements/79/mn_en.pdf"  target="_blank">voice opposition to</a> &ldquo;using force against the territorial integrity and political independence of any state.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Khurelsukh has also repeatedly <a href="https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/06/01/mongolian-president-i-will-not-support-constitutional-amendments"  target="_blank">gone on record</a> to oppose amending the constitution, which was just updated in 2019 to strengthen the legislative branch. &ldquo;Honestly, there isn&rsquo;t a lot of worry about the President trying to stay in power,&rdquo; says Bolor Lkhaajav, a Mongolian political analyst and commentator. Dierkes agrees: &ldquo;I call baloney on the &lsquo;evil President thesis.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s also a thesis that completely ignores the concerns of the Sukhbaatar Square protesters while presuming that things in Mongolia were otherwise rosy and improving under Oyun-Erdene. However, Mongolia&rsquo;s score on the Transparency International Corruption Perceptions Index had fallen from 35 out of 100 when he came to power in 2021 to just 33 last year. Meanwhile, human-rights groups have <a href="https://monitor.civicus.org/explore/mongolia-press-freedom-at-risk-with-arrest-and-prosecution-of-journalists-while-protesters-detained/"  target="_blank">condemned</a> the prosecution of peaceful protesters and prominent journalists under his watch. Mongolia&rsquo;s press freedom ranking <a href="https://rsf.org/en/country/mongolia"  target="_blank">dropped</a> to 109 out of 180 countries last year, down from 88 in 2023, according to Reporters Without Borders.</p>



<p>&ldquo;On corruption, he&rsquo;s taken rhetorical actions,&rdquo; Dierkes says of Oyun-Erdene. &ldquo;And on democracy promotion, he&rsquo;s taken negative actions. He is no democracy warrior.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, while Zandanshatar is clearly close to the President, he is by no means a lacky, being a highly educated career politician&mdash;a former visiting scholar at Stanford&mdash;with his own power base. Still, what Zandanshatar&rsquo;s rise to the premiership means for Mongolia going forward is a big question.</p>



<p>A married father-of-four, Zandanshatar, 55, developed a reputation as a thoughtful, steady speaker of parliament. Following his posting at Stanford, he returned enthused about <a href="https://deliberation.stanford.edu/what-deliberative-pollingr"  target="_blank">deliberative polling</a>, which was subsequently employed to <a href="https://cddrl.fsi.stanford.edu/news/deliberative-polling-fosters-peace-and-instigates-positive-change-among-people-mongolia"  target="_blank">gauge public opinion</a> prior to the 2019 constitutional amendment. Zandanshatar does, however, have a democratic deficit given he&rsquo;s one of the few senior MPP figures not to have won a seat in the 2024 election, though he had been elected three times previously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although choosing a non-lawmaker as Prime Minister is not unprecedented, Dierkes fears this may serve as a &ldquo;legitimacy achilles heel&rdquo; should the winds turn against him. Jargalsaikhan also notes Zandanshatar was one of the proponents of Mongolia&rsquo;s 2006 &ldquo;windfall tax&rdquo; on copper and gold mining profits. (The 68% levy&mdash;the world&rsquo;s highest&mdash;was repealed in 2009 after decimating investor confidence.)</p>



<p>Oyun-Erdene had earmarked 14 new mega projects to boost economic growth, including a major expansion of renewable energy and cross-border railway connections with China, which receives 90% of Mongolian exports. He also promised to diversify the country&rsquo;s economy, which is heavily dependent on a mining industry that accounts for a quarter of GDP. But policy continuity is key to attracting the foreign investment necessary to realize these goals.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Until investment laws are consistent here, investors are going to be wary,&rdquo; says Steve Potter, an honorary member and former chairman of the American Chamber of Commerce in Ulaanbaatar. &ldquo;Constant changes in rules and regulations have long been a problem. Consequently, foreign investment has been very lackluster.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Investor uncertainty isn&rsquo;t the only worry. Having lasted in power four-and-a-half years, Oyun-Erdene was the longest-serving of Mongolia&rsquo;s 18 Prime Ministers since its 1990 democratic revolution. The revolving door of governments and leaders has augmented the idea that parliamentarian democracy is flawed or inherently unsuited to Mongolian society, while rendering a centralized political system more appealing for some&mdash;an idea that is being amplified by shadowy actors on social media and galvanized by Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s tone deaf response to protesters&rsquo; demands.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The protests were organic, but instead of showing his financial papers the Prime Minister&rsquo;s response was so political,&rdquo; says Bolor. &ldquo;His reaction showed just how disconnected he was from the people, who only care about how his policies are impacting their daily lives, such as air pollution, unemployment, and corruption.&rdquo;</p>



<p>So while Oyun-Erdene&rsquo;s demise was likely rooted in factional bickering rather than a nefarious power grab, the debacle contains a stark warning that Mongolia&rsquo;s political class needs to start pulling in the same direction for cherished freedoms to be secured. &ldquo;Democracy itself is very fragile,&rdquo; says Jargalsaikhan. &ldquo;But it&rsquo;s so important and can only be protected by a thriving parliamentarian system. And we must not lose democracy in Mongolia.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293415/mongolia-prime-minister-gombojav-zandanshatar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293415</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Know About the Air India Crash and the &#8216;Miracle&#8217; of Its Sole Survivor</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7293469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Of the 242 aboard, there are 241 confirmed fatalities. The sole survivor is being treated in a hospital," Air India said.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7293469"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/4582932_56544b0b3f2d4325a48149438f16c71a_1080i60ESSENCE.mp4.00_01_08_15.Still001-1.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>An Air India passenger plane heading to London, England, carrying 242 people (including 12 crew members), crashed shortly after takeoff from Ahmedabad, India, on Thursday. While the authorities initially said no one made it out of the crash alive, the world was stunned to learn that there was, in fact, a sole survivor.</p>



<p>&#8220;The aircraft crashed shortly after takeoff. We regret to inform that, of the 242 aboard, there are 241 confirmed fatalities. The sole survivor is being treated in a hospital,&#8221; read a statement shared by Air India on Friday, local time. &#8220;The passengers comprised 169 Indian nationals, 53 British nationals, seven Portuguese nationals, and one Canadian national. The survivor is a British national of Indian origin.&#8221;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The British national in question has been widely identified as Viswashkumar Ramesh, who was travelling home alongside his brother.</p>



<p>The Ramesh family, who are both celebrating Viswashkumar&#8217;s survival and mourning the loss of his brother, <a href="https://news.sky.com/video/air-india-british-survivor-called-dad-moments-after-plane-crash-13382902"  target="_blank">has since spoken to Sky News</a>.</p>



<p>Speaking from Leicester, England, Viswashkumar&#8217;s brother Nayan Kumar Ramesh reported that Viswashkumar spoke to his father before takeoff and after surviving the crash.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know where my brother is; I don&rsquo;t see any other passengers. I don&rsquo;t know how I&rsquo;m alive, how I exited the plane,&rdquo; Nayan reported his brother saying after the crash.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is a miracle that he survived,&rdquo; Nayan said of Viswashkumar. &ldquo;But what other miracle for my other brother?&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219203380.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Modi visits site of deadly Air India plane crash in western India" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Vishwashkumar, who was sitting in seat 11a on the Air India flight, is receiving treatment at Ahmedabad&rsquo;s Civil Hospital, where he has been visited by India&#8217;s Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who also attended the bedside of locals who were not onboard the plane but were struck and injured by the crash.</p>



<p>&#8220;Met those injured in the aftermath of the tragic plane crash in Ahmedabad, including the lone survivor and assured them that we are with them and their families in this tough time. The entire nation is praying for their speedy recovery,&#8221; <a href="https://x.com/narendramodi/status/1933441130001043693"  target="_blank">Modi said on Friday</a>.</p>



<p>The Air India flight struck a medical school hostel when it crashed, killing at least one person on the ground. At least seven people have been reported missing and over 50 from the building have been hospitalized and are receiving treatment.</p>



<p>Sambit Patra, a lawmaker from Modi&rsquo;s ruling Bharatiya Janata Party, said Gujarat&rsquo;s former chief minister, Vijay Rupani, was among the plane passengers who died.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-024.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-INDIA-AVIATION-CRASH" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How did the crash in Ahmedabad unfold?</strong></h2>



<p>The plane took off from Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel International Airport at 1:38 p.m local time. Early signs of a problem came shortly thereafter, when Air India announced the aircraft had been &ldquo;involved in an accident.&rdquo;</p>



<p>FlightRadar, which displays live updates for flights worldwide, <a href="https://www.flightradar24.com/data/flights/ai171#3ac3097f"  target="_blank">shows that the path of the plane</a> ended shortly after takeoff. The signal with the aircraft was lost at around 625 ft.</p>



<p>A large ball of flames could be seen rising from the crash site, followed by clouds of dark smoke as emergency services rushed to the scene. Images of the crash site show extensive damage to buildings in the vicinity, with charred rubble and parts of the plane scattered across the landscape. The rear of the aircraft could be seen partially intact on top of a nearby building.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-026.jpg" alt="All 242 people aboard crashed Air India plane believed dead: Report" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-022.jpg" alt="APTOPIX India Plane Crash" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What are the details of the flight?</strong></h2>



<p>Flight 171, a Boeing 787-8 aircraft travelling from Ahmedabad to London Gatwick, was carrying 242 people, including 12 crew members.</p>



<p>The flight was scheduled to land at Gatwick Airport at approximately 6:25 p.m. local time on Thursday evening.</p>



<p>Aviation expert <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/india-plane-crash-gatwick-latest-ahmedabad-airport-live-sky-news-13382494?postid=9717222#liveblog-body"  target="_blank">Julian Bray has said</a> that the pilot made a mayday call before the crash, indicating that the crew was aware of a problem with the aircraft.</p>



<p>According to the Directorate General of Civil Aviation, pilot Sumeet Sabharwal had 8,200 hours of flight experience and co-pilot Clive Kundar had 1,100 hours.</p>



<p>It is the first ever Boeing 787-8 plane to crash, according to the <a href="https://asn.flightsafety.org/"  target="_blank">Aviation Safety Network</a> database. </p>



<p>However, generally speaking, Boeing has a history of high-profile crashes. This latest incident comes a month after the aircraft company<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/jun/12/air-india-first-crash-of-boeing-787-model-comes-weeks-after-1bn-dollar-737-max-payout"  target="_blank"> agreed to pay $1.1bn</a> in a deal with the U.S. Department of Justice to avoid prosecution over two crashes in 2018 and 2019 that together killed 346 people.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=131555"  target="_blank">a statement about the Air India crash</a>, Boeing president and CEO Kelly Ortberg said:&ldquo;Our deepest condolences go out to the loved ones of the passengers and crew on board Air India Flight 171, as well as everyone affected in Ahmedabad. I have spoken with Air India Chairman N. Chandrasekaran to offer our full support, and a Boeing team stands ready to support the investigation led by India&rsquo;s Aircraft Accident Investigation Bureau.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Boeing has said it will defer to India&rsquo;s Aircraft Accident Investigation Bureau (AAIB) to provide information about Air India Flight 171, in adherence with the United Nations International Civil Aviation Organization protocol.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/india-787-plane-crash-021.jpg" alt="India Plane Crash" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The overall investigation will involve various faculties and countries pooling their resources.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://x.com/NTSB_Newsroom/status/1933147382331445483"  target="_blank">U.S. National Transportation Safety Board has announced</a> it &#8220;will be leading a team of U.S. investigators travelling to India to assist the Aircraft Accident Investigation Bureau with its investigation into the crash of an Air India Boeing 787.&#8221; While the U.S. Secretary of Transportation Sean Duffy said his department is &ldquo;prepared to assist India with anything it needs to investigate this tragedy.&rdquo;</p>



<p>U.K. Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer, who referred to the crash as &#8220;devastating,&#8221; <a href="https://x.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1933213493966074069"  target="_blank">confirmed he has dispatched an investigation team</a>, led by the Foreign Secretary, to work closely with the Indian authorities.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Tata Group, the parent company of Air India, said that it is &ldquo;deeply anguished&rdquo; by the crash. The company announced it will be providing &#8377;1 crore, equivalent to over $116,000, to the families of those who died in the crash.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We remain steadfast in standing with the affected families and communities during this unimaginable time,&rdquo; the Tata Group relayed <a href="https://x.com/TataCompanies/status/1933159585772367969"  target="_blank">in a statement</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=WR5E1Isu]</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7293469/india-london-bound-airplane-crash-boeing-fatalities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7293469</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
