<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:52:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>How Closures at Food Distribution Hubs Are Impacting Gazans</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explainer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deadly shootings at Gaza aid centers force repeated closures, deepening hunger and fear among civilians.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291862"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/gaza.jpg" alt="Food Distribution in Gaza"/>



<p>The organization tasked with delivering food aid in <a href="https://time.com/tag/gaza/" >Gaza</a> halted operations at its distribution centers this week following a series of fatal incidents near aid sites, raising urgent questions about how humanitarian assistance can be delivered safely in the weeks ahead.</p>



<p>The Gaza Humanitarian Foundation (GHF), a private group backed by Israel and the U.S. said <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=122100056516897655&amp;id=61576929655481&amp;ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">in a statement on social media</a> Wednesday that centers would be &ldquo;closed for update, organization, and efficiency improvement work.&#8221;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>On Thursday, the organization said&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/world/gaza/us-backed-aid-group-gaza-reopens-sites-closures-delays-israel-rcna211160"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">two of its aid centers were open</a>, while&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=122101533404897655&amp;id=61576929655481&amp;ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">two other hubs remained closed</a>. In total,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=122101922234897655&amp;id=61576929655481&amp;ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">over 1.4 million meals</a>&nbsp;were distributed on the day, across the two centers, according to the GHF.&nbsp;But on Friday, June 6, the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=122102204348897655&amp;id=61576929655481&amp;ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">GHF announced</a>&nbsp;that all aid hubs would once again be closed for the day, warning people to stay away from sites for their own safety.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what has been reported regarding the circumstances surrounding the closure of aid centers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Deaths at Gaza aid distribution hubs</strong></h2>



<p>The closures came after a number of incidents in which Palestinians collecting aid from hubs have been killed.</p>



<p>On Sunday, June 1, 31 Palestinians were killed at an aid hub, according to Reuters and the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-news-hostages-aid-06-01-2025-67688833abb96fc068c42d10da90a0a4"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Associated Press</a>, citing Gaza&rsquo;s Health Ministry and witnesses, after Israeli soldiers opened fire near crowds.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1929205105242394756"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">In a statement on X</a>, the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) said it &ldquo;did not fire at civilians while they were near or within the humanitarian aid distribution site and that reports to this effect are false.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/04/middleeast/israel-military-gaza-aid-shooting-intl-invs"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">CNN reported</a>&nbsp;that sound and video of gunfire from the site was consistent with that of weapons used by the IDF, and that the rate of fire &ldquo;appears to rule out&rdquo; weapons used by Hamas. Pictures of bullets from the scene were also consistent with machine guns used by the IDF as they can be mounted on tanks, according to the news outlet.&nbsp;Weapons experts&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c8xg7rv9g4yo"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">told the BBC</a>&nbsp;that both the IDF and armed Palestinian groups have access to weapons that use these types of rounds.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=122097592910897655&amp;set=a.122095438160897655&amp;type=3&amp;ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">In a post by the GHF</a>&nbsp;Sunday, civilians were warned that Israeli troops were operating in the area surrounding the aid hub at the time of the shooting, and that it was prohibited to enter before 5 a.m.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Monday, June 2, three Palestinians were killed, the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) told the BBC, at the same location as Sunday&rsquo;s killings.</p>



<p><a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1929778190253281517"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">The IDF said on Monday morning that</a>&nbsp;it&nbsp;&ldquo;was aware of reports regarding casualties, and the details of the incident are being looked into.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The statement added that approximately half a kilometer from the aid site, &ldquo;IDF troops identified several suspects moving toward them, deviating from the designated routes. The troops carried out warning fire, and after the suspects failed to retreat, additional shots were directed near individual suspects who advanced toward the troops.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The IDF has not provided any further statement to TIME regarding the incidents on Sunday and Monday.</p>



<p>Tuesday marked the third day in a row of deadly incidents at the distribution center.&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7290702/27-dead-rafah-gaza-israel-aid-hub/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">At least 27 people were killed</a>, according to the Red Cross.</p>



<p>The Red Cross&nbsp;<a href="https://www.icrc.org/en/statement/israel-and-occupied-territories-icrc-urges-civilian-protection-red-cross-field-hospital"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said Tuesday</a>&nbsp;that its field hospital in Khan Younis, southern Gaza, received 184 patients, 19 of whom were dead upon arrival and an additional eight who died at the hospital.</p>



<p>The majority of cases had suffered gunshot wounds, the Red Cross <a href="https://www.icrc.org/en/statement/israel-and-occupied-territories-icrc-urges-civilian-protection-red-cross-field-hospital"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said</a>. A spokesperson told TIME that all responsive patients from Tuesday&#8217;s mass casualty event had told the aid organisation they were trying to reach an aid distribution site.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The ICRC urgently reiterates its call for the respect and protection of civilians. Civilians trying to access humanitarian assistance should not have to confront danger,&rdquo; the Red Cross said.</p>



<p>The IDF however said that troops fired warning shots Tuesday towards suspects that had deviated from designated aid routes.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Troops are not preventing the arrival of Gazan civilians to the humanitarian aid distribution sites,&rdquo; the IDF&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1929778190253281517"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said in a statement</a>. &ldquo;The warning shots were fired approximately half a kilometer away from the humanitarian aid distribution site toward several suspects who advanced toward the troops in such a way that posed a threat to them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>United Nations human rights chief Volker T&uuml;rk <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/press-releases/2025/06/opt-attacks-around-aid-distribution-site-gaza"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">condemned Tuesday&rsquo;s incident</a>, calling for &ldquo;a prompt and impartial investigation into each of these attacks,&rdquo; adding that those responsible must be &ldquo;held to account.&rdquo; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2218024167.jpg" alt="Food Distribution in Gaza" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation?</strong></h2>



<p>GHF is a U.S. private organization that has <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/05/15/middleeast/gaza-humanitarian-foundation-aid-israel-intl"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">been backed by Israel</a> and the U.S. to be the sole distributor of aid in Gaza. </p>



<p>This came after Israel imposed an 11-week blockade on the territory&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/02/israel-cuts-off-humanitarian-supplies-to-gaza-as-it-seeks-to-change-ceasefire-deal"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">in early March</a>. Israel allowed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c3d4kz8p00eo"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">aid into Gaza</a>&nbsp;in May, following international pressure and condemnation of the humanitarian situation.</p>



<p>But the United Nations called the initial aid &ldquo;<a href="https://www.unocha.org/news/un-relief-chief-welcomes-renewed-aid-deliveries-gaza-stresses-its-only-drop-ocean-what-needed"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">a drop in the ocean</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The GHF was designated to distribute aid in Gaza. But the day before operations began, on May 25, the foundation&rsquo;s lead Jake Wood&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c1e6d97x99qo"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">resigned</a>, saying he would not be able to work in a way that met &ldquo;humanitarian principles.&rdquo;</p>



<p>On May 27, just two days into the new GHF-led distribution program, it was reported that one Palestinian had been killed and dozens more injured near an aid hub.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://msf.org.uk/article/gaza-msf-statement-us-israel-plan-militarise-aid"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Medicin San Frontieres reacted</a> on May 30 to the incident, saying: &ldquo;The disastrous start of the food distribution coordinated by the newly created Gaza Humanitarian Foundation confirmed that the U.S.-Israel plan to instrumentalise aid is ineffective,&rdquo; adding that it was a &ldquo;dangerous and reckless approach,&rdquo; to aid distribution. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The impact on aid</strong></h2>



<p>The U.N. Office for Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs <a href="https://www.ochaopt.org/content/humanitarian-situation-update-294-gaza-strip"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">said on Thursday</a> that since Israel resumed military operations in March, 640,000 Palestinians have been displaced. </p>



<p>Over half of those displaced since May are based in the North of Gaza, on the other end of the strip from three of the GHF&rsquo;s four aid centers. </p>



<p>&ldquo;Palestinians have been presented the grimmest of choices: die from starvation or risk being killed while trying to access the meagre food that is being made available through Israel&rsquo;s militarized humanitarian assistance mechanism,&rdquo; said T&uuml;rk. </p>



<p>Since the start of the war, as of June 5, over 54,600 Palestinians have been killed,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/MOHGaza1994/posts/1030210155950593?ref=embed_post"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">according to Gaza&rsquo;s Health Ministry</a>&nbsp;&mdash;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/how-many-palestinians-has-israels-gaza-offensive-killed-2025-01-15/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">primary source for casualty data</a>&nbsp;relied upon by humanitarian groups, journalists, and international bodies in the absence of any independent monitoring on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A peer-reviewed study, undertaken by London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine epidemiologists,<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.thelancet.com/action/showPdf?pii=S0140-6736%2824%2902678-3"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">published in January in <em>The Lancet</em></a> found that the official Gaza death toll reported by the enclave&rsquo;s Ministry of Health between October 7, 2023 and June 30, 2024 likely<strong> </strong>undercounted the number of fatalities during that period.</p>



<p>The war was triggered after the Hamas terror attack on Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, killing over 1,200 people and taking around 250 hostages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Oday Basheer, <a href="https://time.com/7283191/gaza-israel-military-plan-netanyahu/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who helps run a food kitchen in Deir al-Balah</a>, told TIME that he has not collected any food from the GHF centers yet, describing the process as &ldquo;messy and dangerous.&rdquo; </p>



<p>His kitchen has partnered with World Central Kitchen (WCK), founded by chef&nbsp;<a href="https://wck.org/team"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Jos&eacute; Andr&eacute;s</a>, to help provide food for displaced Palestinians. WCK halted operations in Gaza twice in the past year after Israeli strikes&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/pictures/pictures-israeli-airstrike-kills-7-world-central-kitchen-aid-workers-gaza-2024-04-02/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">killed seven</a>&nbsp;in April 2024 and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c4g2g6w4109o"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">three last November</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite aid entering the strip, Basheer says that prices are still rising, with people paying up to $20 for a kilo of flour. &ldquo;There is not enough coming in to replace what we are buying, people are dying to get a bag of flour,&rdquo; he says.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7286150/gaza-food-prices-starvation/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$25 Butter and $40 Eggs: The Search for Food in Gaza</a></p>



<p>He also described that people who successfully get into the aid hubs can take as much as they want, with aid not distributed equally among those waiting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;From where I am, you have to walk 20 kilometers there and back, carrying food. Just the strongest and fastest can get there,&rdquo; he explains.</p>



<p>Jehad Miri, a journalist from Tel al-Hawa in Gaza City who has been displaced over a dozen times, says that despite having not eaten properly for weeks, he has not gone to the GHF aid sites. </p>



<p>&ldquo;Going to those aid centers feels like walking into death,&rdquo; he told TIME from Deir al-Balah. &ldquo;Just two days ago, a close friend of mine was killed. He used to go to the aid centers to help families who couldn&rsquo;t reach them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Several of Miri&rsquo;s family members have chronic health conditions, and he has been supporting them however he can.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been trying to take care of them getting food, water, and whatever they need. Every day feels like a mission finding water, finding a way to charge batteries, finding internet, finding safety,&rdquo; he says.</p>



<p>Wednesday&rsquo;s aid hub closure affected everyone, Miri says, not only those who go to collect aid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We get some food from traders who risked their lives to bring it from the aid hubs. Now, that&rsquo;s gone. We can&rsquo;t buy anything anymore, the prices are insane.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Basic food supplies are staggeringly high, with 500 grams of butter costing up to $25 and a dozen eggs priced at over $40, civilians in Gaza&nbsp;<a href="https://time.com/7286150/gaza-food-prices-starvation/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have told TIME.</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Friday marked the beginning of Eid Al Adha, an important festival in Islam that will be honored across the Gaza Strip, despite the continuing war. But Miri explains: &ldquo;In Gaza, Eid doesn&rsquo;t feel like Eid anymore.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Basheer agrees, saying: &ldquo;It was a custom to get new clothes, new food before Eid. Now you cannot find anything. There is no joy, there is no celebration for this Eid. Every day there is lots of killing, you don&rsquo;t know if you will be alive.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291862/gaza-israel-aid-shooting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump and Xi Hold First Call in Months, Setting Stage For More Trade Talks</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291416/trump-and-xi-have-first-call-in-months/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291416/trump-and-xi-have-first-call-in-months/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 15:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The 90-minute call was focused on trade, according to Trump]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291416"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7291416/trump-and-xi-have-first-call-in-months/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2209787147.jpg" alt="VIETNAM-CHINA-DIPLOMACY"/>



<p>President Donald Trump spoke with Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Thursday morning about their ongoing trade war, with Trump saying the two leaders agreed to have their teams resume talks &ldquo;shortly.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114631295762726849"  target="_blank">wrote on Truth Social</a> that the call lasted about 90 minutes and focused &ldquo;almost entirely on trade,&rdquo; after representatives from the two largest economies met in Geneva last month and agreed to temporarily reduce tariffs. He said the call &ldquo;resulted in a very positive conclusion for both Countries&rdquo; and that the export of rare earth minerals, which are critical to the U.S. automotive industry, had been addressed during the conversation.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>China&rsquo;s official Xinhua News Agency said the call took place at Trump&rsquo;s request. The White House did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump said that upcoming talks will include Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick and U.S. Trade Representative Jamieson Greer. He added that Xi invited him to visit China and that he reciprocated the offer. &ldquo;President Xi graciously invited the First Lady and me to visit China, and I reciprocated. As Presidents of two Great Nations, this is something that we both look forward to doing.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The call was likely the first time the two leaders spoke since Trump took office in January. However, in an <a href="https://time.com/7280114/donald-trump-2025-interview-transcript/" >April interview with TIME</a>, Trump claimed that Xi had already called him&mdash;which Chinese officials disputed.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation/?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=editorial&amp;utm_term=world_diplomacy&amp;linkId=828160522" >talks</a> came one day after Trump said it was difficult to reach a deal with Xi: &ldquo;I like President XI of China, always have, and always will, but he is VERY TOUGH, AND EXTREMELY HARD TO MAKE A DEAL WITH!!!,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social on Wednesday.</p>



<p>Trade negotiations between the two leaders had stalled after both countries agreed on May 12 to temporarily lower tariffs, with Trump dropping his 145% tariffs on Chinese goods to 30% for 90 days, and Xi easing its levies from 125% to 10%. But the Trump Administration has accused China of reneging on the terms by curbing exports of rare earth minerals used by American manufacturers. China has rejected that charge, saying its export controls apply globally and are not targeted at the United States. In response, the Trump Administration has proposed revoking visas for some Chinese students and issuing new export controls on advanced technologies such as jet engine components and A.I. chips.</p>



<p>&ldquo;China, perhaps not surprisingly to some, HAS TOTALLY VIOLATED ITS AGREEMENT WITH US,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social last week. &ldquo;So much for being Mr. NICE GUY!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Following the call with Xi, Trump said &ldquo;there should no longer be any questions respecting the complexity of Rare Earth products.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump has made reducing America&rsquo;s dependency on Chinese manufacturing a cornerstone of his second-term agenda. Xi, facing a sluggish post-COVID economy and persistent pressures from a real estate slowdown, is pushing to secure China&rsquo;s dominance in future technologies like electric vehicles and artificial intelligence.</p>



<p>The United States ran a $295 billion trade deficit with China in 2024, according to U.S. Census Bureau data, a figure Trump frequently cites as evidence of unfair trade practices. His Administration maintains that only top-level talks can break the current deadlock. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent recently said that a leader-to-leader exchange was essential to restart negotiations in earnest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291416/trump-and-xi-have-first-call-in-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291416</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fishing Communities in the Philippines Are Fighting for their Future as Waters Rise</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7289533/philippines-fishing-communities-rising-water/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7289533/philippines-fishing-communities-rising-water/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell and Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magazine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7289533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As sea levels rise, coastal families in the Philippines tackle the fear of displacement]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7289533"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7289533/philippines-fishing-communities-rising-water/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/joshua-irwandi-philippines-climate-change-aurora.jpg" alt="View of the Philippine Sea from Dipaculao municipality, Aurora Province, Central Luzon Region, the Philippines, March 10, 2025. "/>



<p>It&rsquo;s around 10 a.m. each morning that Noemi Reyes&rsquo;s heart fills with hope. That&rsquo;s when her husband Marionito&rsquo;s boat appears on the shimmering horizon of the Pacific. By the time his skiff has been hauled onto the shingle beach, it&rsquo;s already clear whether his toil has been profitable. Today was not: just eight small sardines and mackerel from five hours casting handlines at sea. &ldquo;Almost nothing,&rdquo; laments their 11-year-old son, Cjay, as he clambers back up the slope to their shack.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The catch is sufficient to provide the family a proper meal but won&rsquo;t help rebuild their home, which was destroyed late last year when a record-breaking six consecutive storms battered the Philippines. Ever since November, the Reyes family has lived here, beneath tarpaulin and nipa palm, wedged between crashing waves and a coastal highway in northeastern Luzon. When it rains, water gushes through gaps in the roof. At night, passing juggernauts rattle the structure, shaking them from their slumber. With no locks or even doors, passing strangers sometimes wander inside. &ldquo;I find it hard to sleep and worry that one of the trucks might hit us,&rdquo; says Noemi, 42, as she cleans and guts the fish for traditional <em>sinigang </em>sour soup.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s a precarious existence that is all too common in the Philippines, an archipelago nation of 115 million people scattered across more than 7,000 islands. The sea remains the lifeblood of the country. Fishing employs over 1.6 million people, whose catch is the nation&rsquo;s principal protein source, a daily bounty of some 12,000 tons. But it&rsquo;s a relationship that has become increasingly strained. Intensifying typhoons and dwindling catches are transforming what has always been the font of life into a source of destruction and despair. &ldquo;Sometimes the sea is all about luck,&rdquo; shrugs Marionito, 50, as he collapses exhausted onto the timber platform that sleeps the couple and five of their nine children.</p>



<p><strong>Read more from TIME&#8217;s Ocean Issue</strong></p>



<p><em><a href="https://time.com/7290417/world-oceans-value/" >The World Isn&#8217;t Valuing Oceans Properly</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://time.com/7290408/sylvia-earle-ocean-interview/" >&#8216;Ignorance&#8217; Is the Most Pressing Issue Facing Ocean Conservation, Says Sylvia Earle</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://time.com/7290414/deep-sea-mining-diva-amon-biologist-interview/" >Meet the Marine Biologist Working to Protect Our Oceans from Deep-Sea Mining</a></em></p>



<p><em><a href="https://time.com/7290403/geopolitical-tensions-future-of-oceans/" >Geopolitical Tensions are Shaping the Future of our Oceans</a></em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/TIM250623-Oceans-Cover.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>If fortune has deserted the Reyes family, odds are increasingly stacked against all the 600 million people around the globe who depend on small-scale fisheries and aquaculture. Coastal communities from Bangladesh to Cuba and from Senegal to Vanuatu are finding their livelihoods and security increasingly challenged. Rising greenhouse gases are increasing the intensity of extreme-weather events that both reduce fish stocks and make accessing them more difficult and dangerous for this generation and the next.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Coastal communities are on the front lines, facing rising seas, brutal storms, and tidal surges that destroy millions of homes, businesses, public infrastructure,&rdquo; Simon Stiell, executive secretary of the U.N. Framework Convention on Climate Change, and a former senior government minister of Grenada, tells TIME. Stiell is no mere onlooker. Just last July, Hurricane Beryl devastated his home island of Carriacou, where 98% of homes and buildings were severely damaged or destroyed, displacing over 3,500 people.</p>



<p>Society&rsquo;s most vulnerable are bearing the brunt, especially the young. UNICEF estimates that around the world, an average of 20,000 children are displaced every day, 95% by the same floods and storms that render coastal fishing communities increasingly hazardous. And the Philippines has the dubious distinction of hosting the most child climate refugees. According to UNICEF, the Philippines experienced a record 9.7 million child displacements from 2016 to 2021, owing partly to 60% of the population living by the ocean&mdash;more people than live in Canada&mdash;as well as sea levels rising at up to four times the global average.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Children are seeing their schools flooded, health services and water systems damaged, and crops and other food sources washed away,&rdquo; says UNICEF executive director Catherine Russell. Along with a litany of health risks including malnutrition and waterborne disease like cholera and dengue, displaced youngsters suffer disrupted education and are more likely to drop out of school to support their families, meaning fewer opportunities for them to build more prosperous and secure lives than those of their parents, whose own occupations are ever more fraught.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-Philippines-Aurora_250410_0005587-crop.jpg" alt="Children play on Diniog Beach as fishermen come in traditional boats in Aurora Province, Central Luzon Region, the Philippines, March 10, 2025. The region was affected when Typhoon Man-yi, known in the Philippines as Super Typhoon Pepito, hit the city. "/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>&ldquo;Constant threats of displacement create chronic anxiety and trauma, particularly among children,&rdquo; says Gwendolyn Pang, secretary general of the Philippine Red Cross. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no semblance of normalcy because they constantly move, evacuate, relocate. Frequent disasters become emotionally and mentally exhausting.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The cascade of hardships stands to compound a larger peril. Each pound of fish caught by wild fisheries involves just 1&frasl;2 to 3 lb. of carbon, while red-meat production ranges from 15 to 50 lb. But the tropics are predicted to see communities displaced from the coast to cities, and declines in potential seafood catch of up to 40% by 2055, turning coastal populations from sustainable food producers into urban consumers with an exponentially larger carbon footprint. In response, governments, NGOs, and the local people are striving to instill resilience into coastal communities, strengthen homes and infrastructure to better cope with extreme weather, and diversify incomes to mitigate the impact of a changing climate. But providing future generations with greater prospects than the last is an uphill battle.</p>



<p>&ldquo;What people told me is simple: they want their families, their wider communities, their businesses and livelihoods to be better protected,&rdquo; says Stiell. &ldquo;They want to focus on education, health care, economic opportunity&mdash;not have to scramble to survive the next storm.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>Few nations have internalized<strong> </strong>the ocean like the Philippines. For centuries before Ferdinand Magellan first set foot here in 1521, the inhabitants were natural seafarers, docking on its islands and thriving aboard floating communities on boats called balangay, a word that today has come to mean the country&rsquo;s smallest political unit, or village.</p>



<p>Filipinos make up over a quarter of the global seafaring worker community. Put differently, 1 out of every 5 Filipinos currently employed abroad are working on the water. Manila remains one of Southeast Asia&rsquo;s top ports, while the surrounding waters, including those within the hotly contested South China Sea, teem with oil and gas deposits.</p>



<p>But this kinship with the ocean has also made the Philippines acutely vulnerable to the extreme weather that is becoming both more fierce and frequent. Situated in the Pacific&rsquo;s &ldquo;typhoon belt,&rdquo; the Philippines experiences an average of 20 tropical cyclones annually, most occurring from July to October. Typhoons are known as compound events, since low pressure effectively sucks up seawater to inundate land just as heavy rainfall surges down hillsides and high winds batter homes and infrastructure. &ldquo;The coast is really where all the problems meet and the intensity is increasing,&rdquo; says Robert Vautard, a working group co-chair at the U.N. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</p>



<p>Many Filipinos live with the constant fear of displacement. At the opposite end of Luzon from the Reyes family, the village of Sula, Vinzons, in the Bicol region sits nestled on a sandbank barely 400 ft. wide separating the Pacific Ocean from tidal mangroves. Without even an access road, life here revolves around fishing, shrimping, and farming oysters and crab. The only non-aquatic industries are a nearby watermelon farm and the occasional cluck and snuffle of chickens and pigs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0001634.jpg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-Philippines-Naga-City&ndash;Daet-250408_0001000-crop.jpg" alt="Portraits of Ricky San Juan Pioquinto (41), his wife Janice Magana Balon (22), and their daughters Princess Michaela Balon (7) and Rich Jane Pioquinto (3) in front of what was previously their house in Barangay Sula, Vinzons municipality, Camarines Norte Province, Bicol Region, the Philippines, March 8, 2025. The family&rsquo;s house was flattened during Typhoon Man-yi, but has since started rebuilding a new house."/><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0001706.jpg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/></figure>



<p>Around four times each year, village captain Rosemarie Abogado gives the order to evacuate,<br>and Sula&rsquo;s 269 families clamber onto boats for the 20-minute journey to a nearby elementary school. There they must hunker down on mats for days while inclement weather submerges the village in swirling eddies of seawater, destroying crab pots, fishing nets, and homes. &ldquo;Usually, it&rsquo;s men who are reluctant to leave the village because they want to take care of their livestock,&rdquo; says Abogado, sitting beneath the mango tree whose shade serves as an informal village hall.</p>



<p>After the typhoon passes, the villagers return to see what remains. Following last November&rsquo;s storms, Ricky Pioquinto found his two-room thatch house had been flattened. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s only luck whether the pigs get flooded or not,&rdquo; says the dad of three. A fattened swine can fetch 12,000 pesos, or $215. &ldquo;Sell a pig and you can buy anything,&rdquo; Pioquinto, 41, says. By comparison, fishing and crabbing are less profitable these days. A pound of crabs brings between 100 and 200 pesos ($1.75 to $3.50) depending on the size and quality. But catches have been getting sparser. &ldquo;Sometimes we don&rsquo;t catch anything,&rdquo; says Pioquinto.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0001497.jpg" alt="A woman dries fish in Barangay Sula, Vinzons municipality, Camarines Norte Province, Bicol Region, the Philippines, March 8, 2025. Dried fish is one of the local commodities in the area."/><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0001553.jpg" alt="Ricky San Juan Pioquinto&rsquo;s (41) pig cages near his house in Barangay Sula, Vinzons municipality, Camarines Norte Province, Bicol Region, the Philippines, March 8, 2025. Pigs can be kept as food stock when disasters hit."/></figure>



<p>Around one-third of the world&rsquo;s fish stocks are overfished, including those in Southeast Asia, where China operates a colossal fishing operation. Climate change is compounding the problem. Oceans play a major role in climate dynamics: 83% of the global carbon cycle is circulated through the oceans, which have absorbed 93% of the excess heat from greenhouse-gas emissions since the 1970s.</p>



<p>But warmer waters alter the distribution of fish species, pushing those more suited to cooler temperatures farther and deeper, while reducing oxygen levels, impacting fish survival and productivity. Estimates suggest that at current rates of warming, fish and other marine species will be pushed around 20 km (12 miles) every decade. Meanwhile, ocean acidification, caused by increased carbon dioxide absorption from the atmosphere, is degrading coral reefs vital for marine life, while harming shellfish and other organisms with calcium carbonate shells. &ldquo;On top, these cyclones and storms have a really negative impact on the ecosystems as well as fishing infrastructure,&rdquo; says Michelle Tigchelaar, senior scientist and impact area lead for climate and environmental sustainability at the WorldFish NGO.</p>



<p>All of this means future generations of artisanal fishers will not see the catches that sustained their parents.</p>



<hr/>



<p>The frequency of typhoons, locally called <em>bagyo, </em>means Filipinos are used to responding to them. The national weather bureau has an alphabetical list of names for storm systems which repeats every four years. A name is retired only when it is attached to a cyclone that has caused widespread destruction and loss of life.</p>



<p>One name that will never return is Yolanda&mdash;what Filipinos call Typhoon Haiyan&mdash;which killed more than 7,000 people, displaced 47.5 million, and caused more than $12 billion in damage in 2013. Yolanda was the deadliest storm to have ever struck the Philippines and more than anything served to redefine the nation&rsquo;s relationship with the ocean. Stretching 500 miles from tip to tip, its sustained winds of 195 m.p.h. tore into the central Visayas region, where storm surges of up to 23 ft. snapped coconut palms like matchsticks and razed entire towns.</p>



<p>Marinel Sumook Ubaldo was just 16 years old when the maelstrom ripped apart her home perched on the shoreline of Matarinao, Salcedo municipality, in Eastern Samar. &ldquo;Only three concrete pillars remained,&rdquo; she recalls. Survivors were isolated for days without food or clean water and spent months with no electricity nor proper shelter. &ldquo;We were literally eating whatever we could find floating on the water,&rdquo; says Ubaldo.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/joshua-irwandi-philippines-climate-change-naga-city-daet.jpg" alt="School students Dane Echano (15), Marcela Cristobal (14), Jillian Delmiguez (15), Kate Galang (14), Hanna Avellano (15), and Charmaine Salva (15) of Mabini Colleges Inc. play on Bagasbas Beach, Daet municipality, Camarines Norte Province, Bicol Region, the Philippines, March 7, 2025. The students are not concerned about erosion as they believe that the President Cory C. Aquino Boulevard will ward off water away from the Philippine Sea.
"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>All the Ubaldo family possessions disappeared; dead bodies littered the devastation. Like nearly all the local fishermen, her father lost his boat, destroying both his livelihood and sense of self-worth. Even if it had survived, the seas remained too rough for small vessels for some six months after the storm, and people recoiled at the thought of consuming fish that may have grown plump on the corpses of their departed neighbors. &ldquo;He has been fishing since he was 8 years old,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;So it really affected him.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Yolanda&rsquo;s wake left hundreds of orphans, but even those like Ubaldo whose family had survived had their childish innocence ripped away. &ldquo;Afterwards, I felt grown up,&rdquo; she recalls. &ldquo;We lost our home. We literally went back to zero. I don&rsquo;t know how I would be able to go to college, so I became a breadwinner.&rdquo;</p>



<p>While working multiple jobs including at a fast-food restaurant to support her family, Ubaldo eventually won scholarships to study social work at university. But that helpless feeling stuck with her. A month after Yolanda, another typhoon struck, but this time nobody would take in her family, which was forced to shelter huddled next to a mountain. &ldquo;I felt like I was just done being &lsquo;resilient,&rsquo;&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;So we lobbied our local government unit to be more proactive.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In 2019, Ubaldo organized the Philippines&rsquo; first youth climate strike. Today, she works in Washington, D.C., for the League of Conservation Voters environmental advocacy group, and has testified on climate issues at the U.N. and U.S. Senate. &ldquo;During disasters, people are gracious that they help each other,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;But trauma really comes after a disaster: What should I do now?&rdquo;</p>



<p>After Yolanda, the Philippine government added a new &ldquo;level 5&rdquo; to the existing four grades of storms, stressing the imperative for people to seek shelter when the worst arrives. But for many, the psychological bond with the ocean had been forever broken. &ldquo;That relationship of the ocean both giving life and unfortunately, with these climate disasters, increasingly taking life away, is something that&rsquo;s very difficult to wrestle with,&rdquo; says Sean Devlin, a Filipino Canadian comedian and filmmaker who has been documenting displaced communities for over a decade.</p>



<hr/>



<p>Yolanda exposed other vulnerabilities that have made the Philippines a test case of disaster response. The sheer force of these storms can remake the very shoreline where communities exist. Too often, poor villagers don&rsquo;t have deeds or other documentation to codify their ownership of land that has been used by their families for generations.</p>



<p>This lack of documentation exposes these communities to disaster capitalism. Around the world, natural disasters&mdash;including the Indian Ocean tsunami in 2004 and Hurricane Katrina the following year&mdash;have entrenched this concept, whereby crises create a blank sheet ready to be exploited by Big Business. It can happen even where ownership is clear. In post-Katrina New Orleans, destroyed public schools, housing, and health care facilities were replaced by private alternatives. In effectively commercializing the response, financial interests clashed with humanitarian goals. Something similar is now happening in the Philippines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0002293_f9d821.jpg" alt="Shrimps are being dried on a part sea wall, part highway is being built in Barangay Sabang, Vinzons municipality, Camarines Norte Province, Bicol Region, the Philippines, March 8, 2025."/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Naga-City&ndash;Daet_250408_0002315.jpg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>After Yolanda, the Philippine government enlisted the help of influential private firms to lead the recovery effort. Tellingly, those that secured development partners were mostly urbanized areas or strategic locations for transport and other investments, while remote municipalities found it harder to attract help. In the city of Tacloban, the epicenter of Yolanda, previously thriving communities were declared &ldquo;no-build zones&rdquo; as they were deemed too dangerous for human habitation. Instead, retail shops and strip malls sprang up.</p>



<p>If alternative housing was provided, it was typically set back many miles from the coast&mdash;while seemingly safer, it was impractical for those making a living at sea. &ldquo;One of the fundamental things that I see anger expressed over is lack of consultation in terms of the response to storms and how people are relocated,&rdquo; says Devlin.</p>



<p>In 2023, Devlin released <em>Asog, </em>a black comedy set amid a real Visayan community still struggling from the social and economic fallout of Yolanda. The film features residents of Sicogon Island, some 6,000 of whom were subjected to a poststorm land grab perpetrated by Ayala Land Inc. to build a luxury resort. Following <em>Asog</em>&rsquo;s success on the festival circuit, Ayala eventually started listening to residents&rsquo; demands and has agreed to pay $5.1 million in reparations to 784 displaced families.</p>



<p>Most of the cash has been used to build 474 new storm-resistant homes within easy reach of the ocean. Still, the local community continues to fight with Ayala over the deeds. &ldquo;Ayala has delivered just a portion of what they committed to,&rdquo; Amelia Dela Cruz, president of the Federation of Sicogon Island Farmers Fisherfolks Association (FESIFFA), said in a statement. &ldquo;We won&rsquo;t give up until they fully comply with the agreement they signed and we have been given the titles to our land.&rdquo; (Ayala Land Inc. did not respond to repeated requests for comment from TIME.) It&rsquo;s a remarkable victory of society&rsquo;s poorest over entrenched corporate interests.</p>



<p>The Philippines has also become a leader in securing legal protections for communities displaced by climate change. In September, lawmakers for the Bangsamoro Autonomous Region in Muslim Mindanao&mdash;a swath of the nation&rsquo;s second largest island boasting over 2,000 miles of coastline with rich fishing waters&mdash;passed a Rights of Internally Displaced Persons Act to safeguard people&rsquo;s access to basic necessities, health care, education, employment, cultural practices, freedom of movement, and popular representation.</p>



<p>The law is the first of its kind in the Philippines and one of only a handful worldwide. While refugees have specific charters governing their rights, including the 1951 U.N. Refugee Convention, people displaced within their own borders still technically enjoy all their national protections, as well as those enshrined by international human-rights and humanitarian law. However, in reality they often slip through the cracks. &ldquo;Displacement has been a painful reality in our homeland,&rdquo; Bangsamoro Government Chief Minister Ahod Balawag Ebrahim said upon the law&rsquo;s passing. &ldquo;But today, we declare that the Bangsamoro will no longer be a region where displacement defines our people&rsquo;s lives.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>The need to instill resilience in communities is key&mdash;and remains an ongoing debate. Regions across the Philippines have begun building towering seawalls to protect against storm surges, though many locals doubt their efficacy. Tacloban residents have criticized the fact that their new seawall is shorter than the storm surge from Yolanda. And if the walls are breached, the fear is these concrete perimeters may impede receding floodwaters and increase the chance of drownings and destruction.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Aurora_250410_0004739.jpeg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Aurora_250410_0004853.jpg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/></figure>



<p>Half an hour&rsquo;s drive from the Reyes family in northern Aurora, Lucy Faner Ruiz also had her home destroyed in last winter&rsquo;s storms and now resides with her son. The 68-year-old retired teacher believes a half-built seawall 200 m from her home exacerbated the damage by retaining the floodwater and preventing it from draining away. &ldquo;I won&rsquo;t rebuild until the seawall is completed,&rdquo; she says, standing amid the splintered wood and corrugated-iron scraps of her toppled home.</p>



<p>Others favor natural alternatives to seawalls. Standing in gum boots by the lapping water of northern Luzon&rsquo;s Casiguran Sound, Jose Bitong stabs the mud with a metal spear, pumps his arm to widen the hole, and then thrusts in a mangrove seedling. It&rsquo;s a routine Bitong and his small army of volunteers at the Casiguran Mangrove Rehabilitation and Protection Organization have repeated more than a million times since 1996, helping to regreen over 1,160 acres of coastline.</p>



<p>Aside from acting as natural barriers against storms and floods, mangroves reduce erosion while providing vital habitats for aquatic species that help replenish fish stocks. In addition, mangroves and coastal wetlands sequester carbon at rates 10 times that of mature tropical forests. &ldquo;My goal is to plant as many mangroves as possible for climate-change mitigation,&rdquo; says Bitong, who operates two nurseries that cultivate 20,000 mangrove seedlings for his own organization and to donate to others.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s not the only way local people are taking charge of their future. In the face of depleted fish stocks, younger coastal residents&mdash;aided by foreign and domestic NGOs&mdash;are leading the charge in trying to diversify into previously shunned species and develop new revenue streams, like cultivating seaweed for export.</p>



<p>On Sicogon Island, once the Ayala compensation was announced, FESIFFA could&rsquo;ve just congratulated themselves and waited for their new homes. Instead, they insisted that local people join the building work. That way, islanders can learn new trades and take charge of future renovations and construction, enhancing capacity while keeping more money inside the community. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s so impressive and just a testament to allowing communities to really envision and lead solutions to these disasters,&rdquo; says Devlin. &ldquo;They understand their situations better than anyone else.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-story-showcase"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Climate-Change-&ndash;-Philippines-&ndash;-Aurora_250411_0006571.jpg" alt="Climate Change &ndash; Philippines &ndash; Aurora"/><img decoding="async" src="" alt="Secondary image"/></figure>



<p>It&rsquo;s for this reason that aid groups like Oxfam Pilipinas concentrate on targeted cash donations for vulnerable families to use on housing, livelihood tools, or education as they see fit. In the 2024&ndash;2025 financial year, Oxfam Pilipinas spent over $4.5 million toward humanitarian interventions, around half in cash for 189,807 individuals belonging to 37,961 households, including the Reyes, Ruiz, and Pioquinto families.</p>



<p>Few want to rely on a dilatory and distracted state. When TIME visited these communities, campaigning was in full swing for May&rsquo;s Philippines general election, and seemingly every pillar and beam had been festooned with party colors. In absurdist irony, even the Reyes family&rsquo;s shack had not escaped crass political adornment. &ldquo;Two candidates visited and asked if they could stick up their posters,&rdquo; shrugs Noemi, glancing forlornly at the coiffured hair and beaming smiles stapled overhead. &ldquo;But neither said they would help us.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Help is desperately needed&mdash;and fast. Our mid-April visit was only the third occasion that Marionito had managed to take his boat out this year, owing to treacherous, churning currents left over from the winter storms. Instead, he&rsquo;s been working as a day laborer cutting grass and planting crops on a nearby farm. Now he has only until the returning monsoon renders fishing too dangerous in August to earn sufficient cash to rebuild their home. Noemi is doing her best to contribute. After preparing breakfast for her kids, she trudges to the wreckage of their former house to collect palm fronds to bundle into brooms, which she then sells for 12 pesos, or 22&cent;. &ldquo;Working from morning until afternoon, I can make 10 brooms,&rdquo; she says. In every way, the Reyes family feels their lives drifting farther away from the ocean.</p>



<p>Asked whether he wants his kids to follow in his footsteps, Marionito doesn&rsquo;t hesitate. &ldquo;Never,&rdquo; he says, gazing out at the deep blue. &ldquo;The fisherman&rsquo;s life is full of uncertainty.&rdquo; And one fighting a relentlessly rising tide.</p>



<p><em>Campbell and de Guzman reported this story out of</em> <em>the Philippines.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7289533/philippines-fishing-communities-rising-water/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7289533</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Trumps Harvard Visa Restriction Means for International Students</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291333/harvard-university-trump-international-students-visa-suspension-sevp/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291333/harvard-university-trump-international-students-visa-suspension-sevp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. President has launched his latest attack on the countrys most prestigious university.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291333"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291333/harvard-university-trump-international-students-visa-suspension-sevp/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/harvard-university.jpg" alt="Harvard banners hang in front of Widener Library during the 374th Harvard Commencement in Harvard Yard in Cambridge, Mass., on May 29, 2025. "/>



<p>President Donald Trump has escalated his <a href="https://time.com/7283245/harvard-trump-funding-timeline/" >standoff with Harvard University</a>, seeking another path to prevent international students from attending the school after a judge <a href="https://time.com/7289514/trump-harvard-international-students-court-battle/" >blocked</a> an attempt to revoke Harvard&rsquo;s ability to enroll international students.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I have determined that the entry of the class of foreign nationals described above is detrimental to the interests of the United States because, in my judgment, Harvard&rsquo;s conduct has rendered it an unsuitable destination for foreign students and researchers,&rdquo; Trump said Wednesday, the same day he issued a &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7291314/trump-new-travel-ban-countries-immigrant-entry-restrictions-nonimmigrant-visas/" >travel ban</a>&rdquo; restricting nationals from 19 countries on entering the U.S., in a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/06/enhancing-national-security-by-addressing-risks-at-harvard-university/"  target="_blank">proclamation</a> that seeks to limit foreigners&rsquo; ability to travel to the U.S. to study at Harvard.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;This is yet another illegal retaliatory step taken by the Administration in violation of Harvard&rsquo;s First Amendment rights,&rdquo; a Harvard spokesperson tells TIME. &ldquo;Harvard will continue to take steps to protect the rights of our international students and scholars, members of our community who are vital to the University&rsquo;s academic mission and community&mdash;and whose presence here benefits our country immeasurably,&rdquo; the university said in a <a href="https://www.hio.harvard.edu/news/court-ruling-preserves-your-visa-status"  target="_blank">previous statement</a>.</p>



<p>The proclamation comes days after the State Department <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-administration-orders-extra-vetting-all-visa-applicants-linked-harvard-2025-05-30/"  target="_blank">reportedly</a> instructed embassies and consulates to increase vetting of visa applicants looking to travel to Harvard for any purpose&mdash;with the word &ldquo;any&rdquo; underlined and bolded. Last week, the State Department <a href="https://time.com/7289060/us-student-visa-interviews-paused-embassies-trump-social-media-vetting/" >paused the scheduling of new student visa interviews</a> at embassies across the world to look into intensifying the scrutiny of applicants&rsquo; social media accounts, citing concerns about antisemitism and terrorism.</p>



<p>Harvard has also faced the threat of <a href="https://time.com/7289000/harvard-university-trump-administration-federal-funding-cuts/" >federal funding cuts</a> and the rescinding of its <a href="https://time.com/7282282/trump-revoking-harvard-tax-exempt-status-what-that-means/" >tax-exempt status</a>. The Cambridge, Mass.-based university is one of <a href="https://time.com/7278236/university-funding-trump-harvard-cornell-northwestern-brown-princeton-penn-columbia/" >several</a> elite higher education institutions in the U.S. that have come under attack by the Trump Administration.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know.</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=aIxPziXV]</div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What does the latest proclamation do?</h2>



<p>The proclamation suspends the entry of foreign nationals seeking to study or participate in exchange programs at Harvard, effective immediately. After 90 days, it will be reassessed for extension; otherwise, it will expire in six months.</p>



<p>The proclamation applies to those who attempt to enter the country to attend Harvard through the Student Exchange Visa Program. It does not apply to those attending other universities through SEVP. It also directs Secretary of State Marco Rubio to &ldquo;consider&rdquo; on a case-by-case basis whether foreign nationals who attend Harvard and are already in the U.S. under F, M, or J visas should have their visas revoked.</p>



<p>The order allows for exceptions to be made for those &ldquo;whose entry would be in the national interest,&rdquo; as determined by Rubio, Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem, or their respective designees.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7288422/harvard-university-international-students-trump/" ><em>Harvard&rsquo;s International Students Left in Limbo Amid Legal Battle With Trump Administration</em></a></p>



<p>Harvard currently has nearly 7,000 <a href="https://oneworld.worldwide.harvard.edu/international-students-at-harvard/"  target="_blank">international students</a>, representing more than a quarter of its enrollees. <a href="https://time.com/7288747/trump-harvard-international-students-transfer-universities-asia-hong-kong-japan/" >Several universities across the globe</a> have already offered to accept impacted students.</p>



<p>If international students are forced to transfer, Harvard would suffer financially, as many international students pay full tuition and other associated costs of attendance, which can be as high as about <a href="https://registrar.fas.harvard.edu/tuition-and-fees"  target="_blank">$87,000</a> per year for undergraduates to <a href="https://www.gse.harvard.edu/admissions-and-aid/financial-aid/learn/international-students"  target="_blank">$102,000</a> per year for some graduate students.</p>



<p>The latest proclamation comes as Trump&rsquo;s second-term Administration has already sought to cancel thousands of international students&rsquo; visas across the country, before abruptly <a href="https://time.com/7280506/trump-student-visas-f1/" >reversing course</a>. Recently, the Administration has also <a href="https://time.com/7289945/us-china-trump-rubio-international-student-visa-restrictions-trade-negotiations/" >targeted students from China</a>, who account for nearly a quarter of all international students in the U.S., citing national security concerns.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is Trump targeting Harvard?</h2>



<p>According to the latest proclamation, the government has concluded &ldquo;Harvard University is no longer a trustworthy steward of international student and exchange visitor programs.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The proclamation points to concerns about crime; insufficient cooperation with the Department of Homeland Security; foreign entanglements, including with China; and alleged civil rights violations.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Crime rates at Harvard University&mdash;including violent crime rates&mdash;have drastically risen in recent years,&rdquo; the proclamation asserts, adding that the university &ldquo;has failed to discipline at least some categories of conduct violations on campus.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It also alleges that Harvard &ldquo;has refused the recent requests of the DHS for information about foreign students&rsquo; &lsquo;known illegal activity,&rsquo; &lsquo;known dangerous and violent activity,&rsquo; &lsquo;known threats to other students or university personnel,&rsquo; &lsquo;known deprivation of rights of other classmates or university personnel,&rsquo; and whether those activities &lsquo;occurred on campus,&rsquo; and other related data.&rdquo; It concluded: &ldquo;Harvard&rsquo;s actions show that it either is not fully reporting its disciplinary records for foreign students or is not seriously policing its foreign students.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The proclamation also cites student newspaper the <em>Harvard Crimson</em>, which <a href="https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2025/2/28/foreign-funding-donations/"  target="_blank">reported</a> earlier this year that the university has received over $150 million in funding from foreign governments, more than any of its Ivy League peers. A university spokesperson told the <em>Crimson</em> that donations are used to fund financial aid as well as educational and operational expenses. Trump&rsquo;s latest proclamation also cited a <a href="https://selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/Harvard%20Letter%3AXPCC.pdf"  target="_blank">May letter</a> by the Republican-led House Select Committee on the Chinese Communist Party that alleged &ldquo;Harvard repeatedly hosted and trained members of a CCP paramilitary organization.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Lastly, the proclamation claimed that Harvard &ldquo;continues to flout the civil rights of its students and faculty.&rdquo; It referred to the 2023 Supreme Court case <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/20-1199_hgdj.pdf"  target="_blank"><em>Students for Fair Admissions, Inc. v. President and Fellows of Harvard College</em></a>, in which admissions policies that consider race as a factor were ruled unconstitutional, to suggest that the university engages in &ldquo;blatant&rdquo; &ldquo;discrimination against disfavored races.&rdquo; Harvard, the proclamation alleged, continues to &ldquo;deny hardworking Americans equal opportunities,&rdquo; while it &ldquo;admits students from non-egalitarian nations, including nations that seek the destruction of the United States and its allies, or the extermination of entire peoples.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291333/harvard-university-trump-international-students-visa-suspension-sevp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Warns Putin Plans to Retaliate &#8216;Very Strongly&#8217; Against Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291210/trump-says-putin-plans-to-retaliate-against-ukraine/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291210/trump-says-putin-plans-to-retaliate-against-ukraine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 20:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trumps remarks after a call with Putin raise fears of escalation following Ukrainian drone attacks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291210"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291210/trump-says-putin-plans-to-retaliate-against-ukraine/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/putin.jpg" alt="VIETNAM-APEC-SUMMIT"/>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7280114/donald-trump-2025-interview-transcript/" >President Donald Trump</a> said Wednesday that <a href="https://time.com/collection/100-most-influential-people-2022/6177689/vladimir-putin-leaders/" >Vladimir Putin</a> intends to retaliate &ldquo;very strongly&rdquo; against Ukraine for a <a href="https://time.com/7290551/ukraines-drone-strikes-against-russia-could-soon-become-the-global-norm/" >surprise drone strike on Russian airfields</a> over the weekend, a declaration that provoked alarm in Washington and abroad even as Trump touted his efforts to bring peace to the region.</p>



<p>The revelation came in a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114626383407680212"  target="_blank">social media post</a> shortly after Trump spoke with the Russian President for more than an hour by phone&mdash;a call he described as &ldquo;a good conversation, but not a conversation that will lead to immediate peace.&rdquo; In his statement, Trump appeared to accept Putin&rsquo;s warning at face value and offered no indication that he had urged restraint.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;President Putin did say, and very strongly, that he will have to respond to the recent attack on the airfields,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social, referring to Ukraine&rsquo;s surprise drone strike that targeted five Russian airbases and damaged or destroyed at least 41 military aircraft, including strategic bombers. The Ukrainian operation, which spanned five time zones and caused an estimated $7 billion in damage, marked one of Kyiv&rsquo;s boldest assaults deep inside Russian territory since the war began more than three years ago.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7290551/ukraines-drone-strikes-against-russia-could-soon-become-the-global-norm/" ><em>Ukraine&rsquo;s Drone Strikes Against Russia Could Become the Global Norm</em></a></p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s post briefly vanished from his platform before reappearing later on Wednesday, prompting speculation about whether he had second thoughts about its tone. The White House has not released a transcript of the call or clarified whether Trump pushed back on Putin&rsquo;s vow to retaliate or offered support to Ukraine.</p>



<p>The statement was Trump&rsquo;s first public comment on the drone strikes, which many experts saw as a significant blow to Russia. While Trump has long promised he could end the war quickly&mdash;<a href="https://time.com/7206595/donald-trump-day-one-promises-pardons-border-executive-order/" >even before he took office</a>&mdash;his latest interaction with Putin did little to clarify how. Instead, some Democrats say it underscored his continued reluctance to criticize the Russian leader, even in the face of a threatened escalation that could cost more Ukrainian lives.</p>



<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7287693/trump-discovers-the-war-in-ukraine-may-be-too-complicated/" ><em>Trump Discovers the War in Ukraine May Be Too Complicated to Fix</em></a></p>



<p>&ldquo;Trump is being played,&rdquo; Sen. Richard Blumenthal, a Connecticut Democrat who met with Ukrainian delegates on Wednesday morning, told TIME in an interview. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m disappointed that Trump didn&#8217;t come down on him and say there&rsquo;s no need for you to respond. No Russian was injured or killed in this operation. Sure, it makes you look bad, because it&#8217;s humiliating. But there&#8217;s no reason you need to kill people by bombing Ukrainian civilians, which is what you&rsquo;re planning to do.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s silence on Putin&rsquo;s threats contrasted with a growing bipartisan push in the Senate to impose severe new sanctions on Russia. A recent <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/senate-bill/1241"  target="_blank">sanctions bill</a> co-authored by Blumenthal and Republican Sen. Lindsey Graham of South Carolina would slap massive penalties&mdash;including 500% tariffs&mdash;on any country buying Russian oil, gas, uranium and other exports. The legislation is aimed squarely at China and India, which bankroll much of Russia&rsquo;s war economy, and is supported by more than 80 Senators.</p>



<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s what Trump could have said to Putin for starters,&rdquo; Blumenthal told TIME. &ldquo;I&#8217;m supporting sanctions on anybody who buys your energy product.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But Trump has so far refused to endorse the measure. He has mused about sanctions, but remains skeptical that economic pressure will end the war&mdash;particularly if it jeopardizes his efforts to broker a broader foreign policy agenda, including curbing Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program.</p>



<p>In the same post where he described Putin&rsquo;s planned reprisal against Ukraine, Trump expressed optimism about working with the Russian leader to resolve the <a href="https://time.com/tag/iran-nuclear-deal/" >Iranian nuclear crisis</a> after Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei criticized the U.S. proposal for a deal.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I stated to President Putin that Iran cannot have a nuclear weapon and, on this, I believe that we were in agreement,&rdquo; Trump wrote. &ldquo;President Putin suggested that he will participate in the discussions with Iran and that he could, perhaps, be helpful in getting this brought to a rapid conclusion.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Sen. Mark Warner of Virginia, the top Democrat on the Senate Intelligence Committee, described Trump&rsquo;s willingness to let Putin help secure a nuclear deal with Iran as the &ldquo;total opposite of what has been traditional U.S. policy&mdash;actually standing with democracies,&rdquo; he said in an interview with TIME. &ldquo;Are you really gonna tell me somebody&#8217;s gonna take the word of Vladimir Putin? I&rsquo;ll tell you, somebody&mdash;that&rsquo;s a fool.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Blumenthal added: &ldquo;I wouldn&rsquo;t trust Putin to mediate or negotiate anything on my behalf.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The phone call between Trump and Putin came as the war, which has dragged on for nearly 3.5 years, shows no signs of abating despite mounting pressure for a diplomatic breakthrough. While the front lines have largely frozen since late last year, the latest wave of Ukrainian attacks&mdash;and Russia&rsquo;s vow to retaliate&mdash;have renewed fears of a broader escalation. In addition to last weekend&rsquo;s drone strikes, Ukraine&rsquo;s security agency said it had detonated explosives beneath the Kerch Bridge&mdash;a critical Russian supply line to Crimea. Russian officials denied the bridge was damaged, but said that its troops had taken another village in Ukraine&rsquo;s Sumy region, part of an effort to create a buffer zone on the border.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7285523/how-putin-misplayed-the-trump-zelensky-split/" >How Putin Missed His Shot at Peace</a></em></p>



<p>The Ukrainian government has dismissed Russia&rsquo;s latest offers for a ceasefire as a stalling tactic. Ukraine&rsquo;s President <a href="https://time.com/7270880/zelensky-trump-putin-ukraine-endgame-interview/" >Volodymyr Zelensky</a> on Wednesday labeled the Kremlin&rsquo;s latest proposal &ldquo;an ultimatum&rdquo; and derided the second round of peace talks in Turkey as &ldquo;a political performance.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump, who previously called Zelensky a &ldquo;dictator,&rdquo; has insisted that he can bring both sides to the table. He has taken credit for the recent talks in Turkey&mdash;though neither delegation made concessions&mdash;and is open to the idea of a summit that could include himself, Zelensky, and Putin. But his critics say such overtures ring hollow without a clear strategy. They argue that Trump&rsquo;s equivocations, praise for Putin, and attacks on Ukraine&rsquo;s leadership have only muddled U.S. policy.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This war doesn&rsquo;t have to go on,&rdquo; Blumenthal told TIME. &ldquo;Trump doesn&#8217;t have to remain silent.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291210/trump-says-putin-plans-to-retaliate-against-ukraine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s in Canada&#8217;s Immigration Billand Why It&#8217;s Facing Backlash</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291118/canada-immigration-bill-strong-borders-act-reactions/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291118/canada-immigration-bill-strong-borders-act-reactions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canadas new immigration bill proposes sweeping changes in policy. And it's already prompting backlash.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291118"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291118/canada-immigration-bill-strong-borders-act-reactions/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2214753393.jpg" alt="Wrong Turn at Bridge Leads to Arrest of Immigrants"/>



<p>Canada&rsquo;s new bill&mdash;<a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/public-safety-canada/news/2025/06/the-strong-borders-act---government-of-canada-strengthens-border-security.html"  target="_blank">The Strong Borders Act</a>&mdash;proposes a sweeping shift in immigration that, among other items, expands the Canadian Coast Guard&rsquo;s authority to conduct security patrols, restricts asylum access, and attempts to deal with the flow of fentanyl into the country.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Bill will strengthen our laws and keep Canadians safe by ensuring law enforcement has the right tools to keep our borders secure, combat transnational organized crime, stop the flow of illegal fentanyl, and crack down on money laundering,&rdquo; the bill states.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Introduced on June 3 by Canada&rsquo;s Minister of Public Safety, Gary Anandasangaree, the 127-page measure proposes a shift in how the government interacts with the U.S.-Canada border.</p>



<p>The bill comes after President Donald Trump voiced concerns about what he referred to as cross-border fentanyl traffic and irregular migration, when he imposed tariffs on <a href="https://time.com/7272192/us-cities-most-vulnerable-to-canadian-tariffs-report-trump-trade-war/" >Canada</a> during his Feb. 1 <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/imposing-duties-to-address-the-flow-of-illicit-drugs-across-our-national-border/"  target="_blank">Executive Order titled</a> &ldquo;Imposing Duties to Address the Flow of Illicit Drugs Across Our Northern Border.&rdquo; Trump argued that &ldquo;Canada has played a central role&rdquo; in the &ldquo;challenges&rdquo; against &ldquo;illicit drugs&rdquo; entering the country, alleging there is &ldquo;a growing presence of Mexican cartels operating fentanyl and nitazene synthesis labs in Canada&rdquo; and that Canada must &ldquo;do more to arrest, seize, detain, or otherwise intercept DTOs, other drug and human traffickers, criminals at large, and drugs.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what you need to know about Canada&rsquo;s Strong Borders Act.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is in Canada&#8217;s immigration bill?</strong></h2>



<p>Canada&rsquo;s new immigration bill seeks to impact various areas&mdash;from asylum rules to search and seizure, to giving police more power to control and monitor the U.S. border.</p>



<p>The new bill would allow Canada Post&rsquo;s inspection authority to open mail and would also remove barriers to allow law enforcement to open mail during an investigation&mdash;attempting to curb fentanyl movement by what authorities say is performed by <a href="https://rcmp.ca/en/federal-policing/serious-and-organized-crime/what-fentanyl"  target="_blank">organized crime groups.</a> It would expand the power of the Canadian Coast Guard to &ldquo;conduct security patrols and collect, analyze and share information and intelligence for security purposes,&rdquo; by amending the Oceans Act, creating a new role for the department. It also would expand the ability for Canadian intelligence agencies to share information with U.S. intelligence.</p>



<p>Related to organized crime, the bill proposes additional restrictions on transactions over $10,000 and cash deposits by any one individual into another&#8217;s account.</p>



<p>The process of gaining access to asylum would also change, as the bill looks to bar asylum seekers who have been in the country for over a year, retroactively applying to anyone who arrived after June 24, 2020.</p>



<p>It would further allow the government the ability to pause the acceptance of new applications and &ldquo;cancel, suspend, or change immigration documents&rdquo; immediately.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why is the bill facing backlash?</strong></h2>



<p>The proposal has been met with strong opposition from immigration and human rights advocates in Canada, who argue it could restrict civil liberties and violate international refugee obligations.</p>



<p>Jenny Wai Ching Kwan, a Canadian politician who serves at the member of Parliament for Vancouver East, issued a warning about the measure, stating that it should be &ldquo;alarming&rdquo; to Canadians.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Looking at [the bill], particularly with respect to the immigration provisions, it is very concerning to me that the government will now be breaching, I think, people&#8217;s civil liberties, I think violating people&#8217;s due process and taking away people&#8217;s basic rights right now,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/player/play/video/9.6783803"  target="_blank">Kwan told reporters</a>. &ldquo;What we&#8217;re looking at is the government giving broad, sweeping authority within the government to cancel applications, to withdraw applications, to suspend applications, even those that are already in the inventory that is under process.&rdquo;</p>



<p>She also shared concerns about citizens&rsquo; privacy, and the lack of apparent appeals processes in relation to the new sweeping immigration law.</p>



<p>Canadian migrant justice group Migrant Rights Network also &ldquo;condemns&rdquo; the bill, stating that it would &ldquo;drastically restrict refugee protections and allow for mass deportations and immigration exclusion.&rdquo; They argue that the &ldquo;unchecked power&rdquo; enabled through this bill could allow for migrant groups to have their immigration status revoked &ldquo;en masse.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Prime Minister [Mark] Carney campaigned on being different from Donald Trump, yet his very first bill is a shameful capitulation to racism and xenophobia, which abandons Canada&rsquo;s legal and moral obligations to refugees and migrants,&rdquo; said Migrant Rights Network spokesperson Syed Hussan <a href="https://migrantrights.ca/c2pressrelease/"  target="_blank">in a statement.</a> &ldquo;With over 3,000 study and work permits already expiring daily because of [Former Prime Minister Justin] Trudeau&rsquo;s immigration cuts, this Bill will only worsen a humanitarian catastrophe. This bill is immoral, it is illegal, and it will be stopped.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.thestar.com/politics/federal/carney-government-introduces-bill-to-beef-up-border-security/article_7a336390-fb90-4ece-a46d-bd9233a7b67a.html"  target="_blank">Speaking with reporters on Friday</a>, Canadian Council of Refugees co-executive director Gauri Sreenivasan stated that the bill mirrors U.S. immigration policy and could &ldquo;force many people who have no choice because they are under threat in their country or in the U.S. to live underground without status.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Kelly Sundberg, a former officer with the Canada Border Services Agency (CBSA), also spoke out against the bill, admitting they&rsquo;re &ldquo;not optimistic&rdquo; about it.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I think all [the bill] does is try to appease the Trump Administration. But I&#8217;d like to see legislation that&#8217;s designed to keep Canadians safe,&rdquo; Sundberg <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPshO0zR4qI"  target="_blank">said during an interview</a> with CTV News. &ldquo;So does this legislation improve our border security, improve our immigration integrity, and improve the public safety of Canadians? No, it does not. It doesn&#8217;t even come close.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Anandasangaree was asked whether the immigration bill appeases the U.S. government during a press conference.</p>



<p>&ldquo;These measures are being taken for a number of reasons. First and foremost, Canadians elected a new government on April the 28th with a mandate to ensure the safety and security of Canadians, including securing our border,&rdquo; Anandasangaree responded. &ldquo;Of course, there&#8217;s elements that will strengthen the relationship with the United States. There are a number of elements in the bill that have been irritants for the U.S.&rdquo;</p>



<p>David Bier, director of immigration studies at the Cato Institute, says it&rsquo;s not surprising that Canada is &#8220;moving more in the direction of the American immigration system.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;[Canada is] enhancing the power of the executive in many respects, to deny people asylum, to suspend processing of applications, limiting the right of people to to request asylum,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;These are all things that I&#8217;ve been part of U.S. law for a long time.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Still, according to Bier, this bill is more about &#8220;domestic politics than international relations.&#8221;</p>



<p>Sharry Aikan, a law professor at Queen&#8217;s University, is also apprehensive about the bill. Its intent to address concerns with a broken immigration system lies in the right place, she says&mdash;but its execution is wrong.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is a legislative fix for a set of challenges that should have been addressed through operational measures, not new laws,&rdquo; Aikan says. &ldquo;We need to make sure that when people show up at the border, you know that we have the resources to address them. Yes, 100%. But why dismantle what is in effect?&rdquo;</p>



<p>Aikan argues in particular against the one year deadline for asylum claims&mdash;something she says is a direct mirror of the <a href="http://um/asylum-manual/immigration-basics-the-one-year-filing-deadline/"  target="_blank">U.S.&rsquo;s one-year policy</a>. She provides multiple examples&mdash;including one where a foreign national comes to Canada, and year two of their stay in Canada, the circumstances in their home country change and it is no longer safe to return.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&#8217;s basically shutting off the pipeline to the hearing altogether and saying, the mere fact that you&#8217;ve been in a country for 12 months and two days means that you don&#8217;t have access to a full fledged refugee hearing,&rdquo; Aikan says. &ldquo;What it signals about the priorities of the government is that appeasing the White House right now is a number one concern.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291118/canada-immigration-bill-strong-borders-act-reactions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291118</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hajj Begins With World&#8217;s Largest Air Conditioner, Surveillance Drones, and a Ban on Children</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291105/hajj-2025-saudi-arabia-new-rules/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291105/hajj-2025-saudi-arabia-new-rules/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juwayriah Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 16:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia's 2025 Hajj overhaul includes policy updates and high-tech safety measures following last year's heat deaths.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291105"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291105/hajj-2025-saudi-arabia-new-rules/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Hajj-2025.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>Saudi Arabia has announced drastic changes for the 2025 Hajj pilgrimage that begins today, including new rules prohibiting children from accompanying pilgrims, and prioritizing pilgrims traveling for the first time. The changes represent the most significant transformation of pilgrimage access in modern history.</p>



<p>The Hajj, one of the five pillars, or obligations, of Islam, draws about two million Muslims annually to Saudi Arabia to complete the spiritual journey that every mature, able-bodied Muslim is required to undertake at least once in their lifetime. Once a desert journey guided by revelation, the Hajj has become a logistical marvel, and the new policies mark some of the most significant shifts in its 1,400-year history.&nbsp;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The pilgrimage involves a series of rituals over several days, including circling the Ka&rsquo;ba in Mecca, standing in prayer at Mount Arafat, and acts of devotion that trace the footsteps of the Prophet Abraham and his family. &ldquo;&#8202;Hajj represents a profound spiritual journey for Muslims,&rdquo; says Shaykh Waleed Basyouni, the President of AlMaghrib Institute, which hosts its own <a href="https://www.almaghrib.org/hajj-2025/"  target="_blank">Hajj program</a>. &#8220;It&#8217;s a time for reflection, repentance, and a renewal of faith.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Children Banned</strong></h3>



<p>The most controversial change prohibits children from accompanying their guardians on the pilgrimage. &ldquo;&#8202;People were surprised, shocked,&rdquo; says Basyouni, who has made the pilgrimage multiple times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Saudi Ministry of Hajj and Umrah cited safety for the decision. In 2024, more than 1,300 people <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S3050456224000075"  target="_blank">died</a> during the pilgrimage, primarily from extreme heat and overcrowding. But the new policy breaks with centuries of tradition where families often traveled together to fulfill a religious duty.</p>



<p>The minimum age for attendance was unclear, however. Some sources cite 12 years as the <a href="https://www.thedailystar.net/life-living/news/too-young-hajj-saudis-child-participation-ban-divides-pilgrims-3821881"  target="_blank">cutoff</a>, while others indicate Saudi Arabia has set <a href="https://www.bssnews.net/news/254311"  target="_blank">15 years</a> as the minimum age. The confusion may be rooted in the variables of personal development: in Muslim legislation anyone who has not reached puberty is considered a child.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Hajj-2025-No-Kids.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Another variable is the weather. Once again this year, the desert pilgrimage coincides with intense summer heat. But because the Islamic calendar shifts about 10 days earlier each year, Hajj will be in the winter from 2034 to 2041 in a natural progression through the seasons over a 33-year cycle.</p>



<p>&ldquo;&#8202;They might put restrictions on children in the summer where Hajj comes during the high season when it&rsquo;s very hot,&rdquo; Basyouni says. &ldquo;But they might change that later on when the weather is much better, because Hajj comes in the lunar calendar.&rdquo;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>First-Time Pilgrims Get Priority</strong></h3>



<p>In another major shift, the host kingdom has instituted a system favoring Muslims who have never completed the Hajj. The change addresses long-standing equity concerns within the global Muslim community, where repeat pilgrims from wealthier nations could more easily secure spots than first-time pilgrims from developing countries. Hajj travel packages <a href="https://tablighajj.com/affordable-hajj-costs-from-the-usa-in-2025/#:~:text=Hajj%20is%20a%20sacred,to%20%2415%2C000%20per%20person."  target="_blank">range</a> from $10,000 to $15,000 per person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;&#8202;I hope that this is an issue that can be solved,&rdquo; says Basyouni. &ldquo;It&#8217;s one of the pillars of [our] religion. It&#8217;s very hard. &#8202;I don&#8217;t know of any ritual in the world for any religion that costs that much money.&rdquo;</p>



<p></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI, A.C. and Access</strong></h3>



<p>Watching over this year&rsquo;s Hajj will be a network of AI-powered drones, with thermal imaging technology that enables authorities to monitor millions of pilgrims in real-time and respond swiftly to potential safety threats. For the first time, the Saudi Civil Defense has introduced the AI-powered &#8220;Saqr&#8221; ( Falcon) <a href="https://gulfnews.com/world/gulf/saudi/saudi-arabia-ai-powered-saqr-drone-deployed-for-firefighting-and-rescue-missions-during-hajj-1.500149537"  target="_blank">drone</a>, which can identify and <a href="https://gulfnews.com/world/gulf/saudi/saudi-drones-spot-illegal-hajj-pilgrims-video-1.500143114"  target="_blank">intercept</a> unauthorized pilgrims, supporting the kingdom&rsquo;s &#8220;No Hajj Without a Permit&#8221; <a href="https://www.spa.gov.sa/en/N2102459"  target="_blank">campaign</a>.</p>



<p>In the Grand Mosque, the world&#8217;s largest cooling system, with a capacity of 155,000 <a href="https://www.arabtimesonline.com/news/saudi-arabia-activates-worlds-largest-cooling-system-at-grand-mosque-ahead-of-hajj/"  target="_blank">tons</a> of refrigeration, represents the Saudis&#8217; response to increasingly extreme heat conditions during Hajj. A year ago temperatures soared to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/06/23/hajj-heat-saudi-arabia-pilgrims/"  target="_blank">125 degrees</a> Fahrenheit during the annual rites. Other heat mitigation measures for 2025 include <a href="https://www.al-monitor.com/originals/2025/06/hajj-pilgrims-gather-mecca-under-scorching-desert-sun"  target="_blank">expanding</a> shaded areas by 50,000 square meters, deploying over 400 cooling units, and placing thousands of additional medics on standby. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Hajj-2025-AC.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>&ldquo;It gets very hot, so I think [the change] is wonderful,&rdquo; says Abdul-Malik Merchant, an Imam for the All Dulles Area Muslim Society (ADAMS) in Virginia. Merchant has gone for Hajj seven times, both as a guide and a traveller. He was there in 2015 when a <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2018/01/the-mecca-stampede-that-made-history-hajj?srsltid=AfmBOoq8nzPApvBOlPBHX00X5clu26hkokeW1NbYYhcLbiOvf9fzi_Wy"  target="_blank">stampede</a> ended the lives of 2,400 travellers, a catastrophic death toll even in a setting with a <a href="https://www.statista.com/chart/3834/tragedies-in-mecca-are-far-from-rare/"  target="_blank">history</a> of mass casualty events.<br><br>Saudi Arabia had also <a href="https://sa.usembassy.gov/sareimph/"  target="_blank">changed</a> its visa policy, <a href="https://newlandchase.com/saudi-arabia-temporary-suspension-of-short-term-visas-for-14-countries/"  target="_blank">limiting</a> travellers from 14 countries&mdash;including Pakistan, Iraq and Morocco&mdash;to only a single-entry visa. In past years, people with multiple-entry visas would enter the country during the Hajj season and attend without a permit. The duration of a Hajj visa has also been <a href="https://saudivisa.com/saudi-hajj-visa/#:~:text=Please%20note%20that%20the%20Saudi%20Hajj%20visa%20is%20granted%20exclusively%20for%20Hajj%20pilgrimage%20purposes.%20All%20pilgrims%20are%20required%20to%20leave%20Saudi%20Arabia%20after%20Hajj%2C%20no%20longer%20than%20the%2010th%20day%20of%20Muharram."  target="_blank">standardized</a>, expiring on the 10th of Muharram, which is July 6th, 2025. Entry to the holy cities has likewise been tightened. Since late April, only holders of those official Hajj visas, valid residency, or authorized personnel were allowed into Makkah. So far this year, 269,000 people have been stopped from entering the city for a lack of correct permits.</p>



<p>&ldquo;&#8202;Muslim jurists say it is allowed &#8202;for the government to put restrictions on some religious rituals,&rdquo; Basyouni says. During COVID-19, for instance, the Saudi government required that people be vaccinated before performing Hajj during the height of the pandemic in order to protect travellers. The guidelines for any new rule, Basyouni says, is that it must have a clear benefit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291105/hajj-2025-saudi-arabia-new-rules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Expect From a Phone Call Between Trump and Xi</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House officials have said the U.S. and Chinese leaders could speak directly as soon as this week.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291016"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-xi-talks.jpg" alt="Portraits of U.S. President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping on April 10, 2025"/>



<p><em>Will you call President Xi if he doesn&rsquo;t call you?</em> TIME asked Donald Trump during an <a href="https://time.com/7280114/donald-trump-2025-interview-transcript/" >interview</a> in April.</p>



<p>&ldquo;No,&rdquo; the U.S. President responded.</p>



<p><em>You won&rsquo;t?</em></p>



<p>&ldquo;Nope.&rdquo;</p>



<p><em>Has he called you yet?</em></p>



<p>&ldquo;Yep.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p><em>When did he call you?</em></p>



<p>&ldquo;He&rsquo;s called. And I don&rsquo;t think that&rsquo;s a sign of weakness on his behalf,&rdquo; Trump said of his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping.</p>



<p><em>But you would think it&rsquo;s a sign of weakness if you called him?</em></p>



<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t&ndash;I just look&mdash;&rdquo;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s unclear what Trump was referring to at the time. Beijing <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/lxjzh/202504/t20250428_11606273.html"  target="_blank">denied</a> that any recent conversation between the two leaders took place. The latest acknowledgement of direct contact was before Trump took office in January, when he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/113844165549788304"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social that he &ldquo;just spoke&rdquo; to Xi and that the pair would &ldquo;solve many problems together&rdquo; and &ldquo;do everything possible to make the World more peaceful and safe!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Now, however, White House officials suggest a call between Trump and Xi may be imminent.</p>



<p>Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/scott-bessent-treasury-secretary-face-the-nation-06-01-2025/"  target="_blank">said</a> Sunday that he expected the two leaders will hold a call &ldquo;very soon.&rdquo; Trump &ldquo;is going to have a wonderful conversation about the trade negotiations this week&rdquo; with Xi, <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/hassett-confident-courts-uphold-trumps-tariffs/story?id=122392800"  target="_blank">said</a> National Economic Council Director Kevin Hassett, a timeline <a href="https://x.com/Acyn/status/1929590866475471318"  target="_blank">reiterated</a> by Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt to reporters on Monday: &ldquo;I can confirm that the two leaders will likely talk this week.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about a potential call between Trump and Xi.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What would be on the agenda?</h2>



<p>Trade will undoubtedly be the focus of any conversation between Trump and Xi.</p>



<p>The world&rsquo;s two largest economies have been engaged in a trade war since Trump&rsquo;s first term, though it dramatically escalated when Trump hiked &ldquo;reciprocal&rdquo; tariffs on China in April, raising the baseline levy on imports from China to 145%, while Beijing retaliated with a 125% tax on U.S. goods.</p>



<p>Both countries accused the other of playing unfairly, but in May, representatives from each side met in Geneva, where they reached a <a href="https://time.com/7284765/us-china-trade-war-pause/" >truce</a>, temporarily reducing the tariffs amid continuing negotiations.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7285023/china-tariffs-prices-trump/" ><em>With Tariff Retreat, Trump Cedes Leverage to China</em></a></p>



<p>Another topic, albeit related, that is anticipated to come up is critical minerals, the rare earths used to manufacture a gamut of goods from auto parts and chips to munitions.</p>



<p>In a May 30 post on <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114596705340367716"  target="_blank">Truth Social</a>, Trump referred to the Geneva agreement, claiming it was a gesture of kindness from the U.S.: &ldquo;I saw what was happening and didn&rsquo;t like it, for them, not for us. I made a FAST DEAL with China in order to save them from what I thought was going to be a very bad situation, and I didn&rsquo;t want to see that happen. Because of this deal, everything quickly stabilized and China got back to business as usual. Everybody was happy! That is the good news!!! The bad news is that China, perhaps not surprisingly to some, HAS TOTALLY VIOLATED ITS AGREEMENT WITH US. So much for being Mr. NICE GUY!&rdquo;</p>



<p>Speaking to CBS<em> </em>on Sunday, Bessent <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/scott-bessent-treasury-secretary-face-the-nation-06-01-2025/"  target="_blank">said</a> that China had breached some of the terms of the Geneva agreement, particularly regarding export controls over rare earths and critical minerals. &ldquo;I am confident that when President Trump and [Chinese Communist] Party Chairman Xi have a call, that this will be ironed out,&rdquo; Bessent said. &ldquo;But the fact that they are withholding some of the products that they agreed to release during our agreement&mdash;maybe it&#8217;s a glitch in the Chinese system, maybe it&rsquo;s intentional.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>When Press Secretary Leavitt was asked Tuesday<strong> </strong>about whether the U.S. was pressuring China to release its hold on rare earths, she <a href="https://youtu.be/E9KW7xNK02E?t=1373"  target="_blank">referred</a> to the &ldquo;leader-to-leader talk very soon.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7275818/rare-earth-china-tariffs-metals-minerals/" ><em>How Rare Earths Are Playing a Pivotal Role in the U.S.-China Trade War</em></a></p>



<p>Education policy may also be discussed. Recently the Trump Administration has made moves to restrict Chinese students at U.S. universities. Secretary of State Marco Rubio <a href="https://www.state.gov/releases/office-of-the-spokesperson/2025/05/new-visa-policies-put-america-first-not-china/"  target="_blank">said</a> on May 28 that the U.S. will &ldquo;aggressively revoke&rdquo; the visas of Chinese students, including those with ties to the CCP and those studying in critical fields, because of national security concerns. Beijing <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xw/fyrbt/lxjzh/202505/t20250529_11636603.html"  target="_blank">firmly opposed</a> the move, calling the policy &ldquo;fully unjustified.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>China&rsquo;s Ministry of Commerce on June 2 <a href="https://www.mofcom.gov.cn/xwfb/xwfyrth/art/2025/art_6b2d4a2b91644a8ca0284867769a9713.html"  target="_blank">accused</a> the U.S. of violating its side of the Geneva deal, saying that since the agreement the U.S. &ldquo;has successively introduced a number of discriminatory restrictive measures&rdquo; against China. According to the ministry, these include &ldquo;issuing export control guidelines for AI chips, stopping the sale of chip design software to China, and announcing the revocation of Chinese student visas.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7289945/us-china-trump-rubio-international-student-visa-restrictions-trade-negotiations/" ><em>How Trump&rsquo;s Crackdown on International Students Could Escalate Trade Tensions With China</em></a></p>



<p>The inflow of <a href="https://time.com/6269011/fentanyl-overdose-unique-challenges/" >fentanyl</a> into the U.S. may also be a point of discussion, as the illegal narcotic that has been tied to some <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/pressroom/nchs_press_releases/2025/20250514.htm"  target="_blank">48,000 deaths</a> in 2024 in the U.S. was ostensibly the initial motivation behind Trump&rsquo;s second-term <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/02/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-imposes-tariffs-on-imports-from-canada-mexico-and-china/"  target="_blank">tariff war</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What has each side said about the other?</h2>



<p>&ldquo;I like President Xi of China, always have, and always will, but he is VERY TOUGH, AND EXTREMELY HARD TO MAKE A DEAL WITH,&rdquo; Trump said Wednesday in a post on <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114623632387180206"  target="_blank">Truth Social</a>.</p>



<p>A person familiar with the trade talks <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/03/trump-xi-call-trade-talks-00381858"  target="_blank">told Politico</a> that Trump is &ldquo;obsessed&rdquo; with getting Xi on the line, especially since relations have been strained by China&rsquo;s alleged violations of the Geneva agreement.</p>



<p>A former official close to the White House also told Politico that Trump feels that &ldquo;a call between principles is a way to cut through a lot of this noise, and get right to the heart of the matter.&rdquo;</p>



<p>For China, the Trump Administration&rsquo;s recent actions&mdash;on<strong> </strong>trade and student visas&mdash;&ldquo;seriously violate the consensus reached by the two heads of state on January 17, seriously undermine the existing consensus of the Geneva economic and trade talks, and seriously damage China&rsquo;s legitimate rights and interests,&rdquo; said a Ministry of Commerce spokesperson on June 2.</p>



<p>Beijing, however, has also consistently repeated the need for &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/MFA_China/status/1894681813215588798"  target="_blank">equal-footed dialogue and consultation with mutual respect</a>&rdquo; to iron out the trade dispute. Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi, after meeting with newly installed U.S. Ambassador to China David Perdue, <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/wjbzhd/202506/t20250603_11639777.shtml"  target="_blank">said</a> on Tuesday that the U.S. should &ldquo;create the necessary conditions for China-U.S. relations to return to the right track&rdquo; after it &ldquo;introduced a series of negative measures on unfounded grounds.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But analysts say that Xi is less inclined to approach deals via a call. &ldquo;Donald Trump&rsquo;s way&rdquo; of &ldquo;pick[ing] up the phone &hellip; to resolve issues,&rdquo; Pang Zhongying, a former visiting senior fellow at the ISEAS-Yusof Ishak Institute in Singapore, <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3297656/why-chinese-president-xi-jinping-wont-just-hop-call-donald-trump"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>South China Morning Post</em> in February, is not the &ldquo;Chinese way.&rdquo;</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-02-07/why-xi-isn-t-in-a-hurry-to-get-trump-on-the-phone"  target="_blank">Bloomberg&rsquo;s John Liu</a>, direct talks with Trump may not play well for Xi domestically, especially &ldquo;if he&rsquo;s seen as bowing to American pressure.&rdquo; The Chinese President &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t need the embarrassment of making nice with Trump,&rdquo; wrote Liu in February. Plus, &ldquo;keeping Trump at arm&rsquo;s length has its benefits,&rdquo; as the U.S. loses international standing over issues like the tariffs as well as continued support for Israel in its deadly war in Gaza, &ldquo;it makes China appear like the more responsible global power.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think [China] wants to be caught unaware or caught by surprise with demands or things that it wasn&#8217;t expecting over the course of this phone conversation,&rdquo; Huang Chin-hao of the National University of Singapore&rsquo;s Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy tells TIME.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Trump might fancy himself as a dealmaker, but Xi is not one to make sudden decisions on the fly,&rdquo; says Kevin Chen Xian An, an associate research fellow at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies in Singapore. &ldquo;The best we can hope for is that the two leaders can reach an understanding on certain principles that provide a modest boost to trade talks.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291016/trump-xi-phone-call-us-china-trade-tariffs-direct-negotiation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291016</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Japan May Help the U.S. Develop Trumps Golden Dome</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7291005/trump-golden-dome-japan-ishiba-tariffs-technology-missile-defense-cooperation/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7291005/trump-golden-dome-japan-ishiba-tariffs-technology-missile-defense-cooperation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7291005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Asian ally is reportedly considering lending its technological capabilities to the missile-defense project in hopes of negotiating a better trade deal.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7291005"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7291005/trump-golden-dome-japan-ishiba-tariffs-technology-missile-defense-cooperation/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-golden-dome-space-missile-defense-cooperation.jpg" alt="President Trump Makes Announcement With Defense Secretary Hegseth In The Oval Office"/>



<p>After Japan&rsquo;s Prime Minister <a href="https://time.com/7025753/shigeru-ishiba-japan-prime-minister-ldp-leadership-election-result-analysis/" >Shigeru Ishiba</a>, who came to power in September, met with U.S. President Donald Trump for the first time in February, the two leaders issued a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/02/united-states-japan-joint-leaders-statement/"  target="_blank">joint statement</a> promising to pursue &ldquo;a new golden age&rdquo; for U.S.-Japan relations.</p>



<p>The statement included commitments to cooperate on economic growth, security, and space. Then Trump <a href="https://time.com/7274195/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-world-responses-china-eu-countries-leaders-countermeasures/" >imposed heavy tariffs on the entire world</a>, including Japan, throwing that commitment to cooperation into question.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Now, however, it seems there may be a way for the two countries to get back on track toward that pursuit of a golden era.</p>



<p>Japan, according to a <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Politics/Defense/Japan-considers-working-on-US-Golden-Dome-missile-shield"  target="_blank">report</a> this week in Japanese financial newspaper the <em>Nikkei</em>, is &ldquo;exploring support&rdquo; for Trump&rsquo;s so-called <a href="https://time.com/7287304/golden-dome-trump-missile-defense-space-costs-concerns-elon-musk/" >&ldquo;Golden Dome&rdquo;</a> project&mdash;a massive missile-defense system modeled after Israel&rsquo;s Iron Dome and consisting of a network of satellites, sensors, and interceptors to prevent aerial attacks on the U.S. mainland. Trump promised that the system, which is estimated to cost hundreds of billions if not trillions of dollars, will be operational by the end of his term in 2029.</p>



<p>The report comes after Trump and Ishiba spoke for over an hour across two phone calls last month in which they &ldquo;<a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/na/na1/us/pageite_000001_01000.html"  target="_blank">exchanged their views on diplomatic and security challenges</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;had a constructive dialogue that will further advance Japan-U.S. cooperation in a wide range of fields, including foreign affairs and security as well as the economy.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://japan.kantei.go.jp/103/statement/202505/29kaiken.html"  target="_blank">statement</a> about the second call on May 29, Ishiba said he wouldn&rsquo;t comment on the specifics of his discussion with Trump but said &ldquo;we had a truly candid exchange of views that resulted in each of us further deepening our understanding of the other&#8217;s stance. I intend to continue to work together with President Trump to further reinforce the Japan-U.S. alliance and our cooperative relationship, as well as to deepen our relations, through which will be able to play a greater role in fostering world peace, stability, and prosperity.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Japan has to offer</h2>



<p>Facing increasing regional threats, Japan has in recent years ramped up its national security investments, since <a href="https://time.com/6278122/fumio-kishida-japan-prime-minister-interview-g7/" >former Prime Minister Fumio Kishida</a> in December 2022 unveiled the country&rsquo;s biggest military buildup since World War II, raising its defense budget to be the third-largest in the world, after the U.S. and China.</p>



<p>At the same time, the world&rsquo;s third-largest economy has faced a <a href="https://time.com/7003107/japan-record-population-decline/" >demographic crisis</a> that by necessity has <a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/research/2024/10/japans-aging-society-as-a-technological-opportunity?lang=en"  target="_blank">spurred technological innovation</a>, including <a href="http://www.dsei-japan.com/news/japan-becomes-global-emerging-technology-leader"  target="_blank">making strides in</a> areas such as AI, robotics, and <a href="https://www.nippon.com/en/in-depth/d01090/japan%E2%80%99s-do-or-die-space-defense-program-commercial-technology-to-play-key-role-in-new-ar.html"  target="_blank">space</a>&mdash;all of which are vital to defense.</p>



<p>In its <a href="https://apnews.com/article/japan-military-budget-us-australia-china-f82c70bd6f5cbfc184f15cf17f2fde21"  target="_blank">record $55 billion defense budget for 2025</a>, Japan earmarked about $6 billion for a  &ldquo;standoff&rdquo; defense system that includes long-range missiles and a satellite network.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/japan-space-defense.jpg" alt="ASDF Space Operations Group facility" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Tokyo has also ramped up cooperation with Washington, its only official treaty ally, pledging more than $3 billion this year to purchase missile interceptors and a mobile reconnaissance radar for Okinawa, which hosts a large presence of U.S. military bases.</p>



<p>As Japan makes space surveillance and security a <a href="https://www.japan.go.jp/kizuna/2024/08/protecting_space_security.html"  target="_blank">priority</a>&mdash;in fiscal year 2026, it plans to launch its first &ldquo;space domain awareness&rdquo; satellite&mdash;the U.S. Space Force, which has been tasked with <a href="https://www.space.com/space-exploration/satellites/u-s-space-force-general-selected-to-lead-trumps-usd175-billion-golden-dome-space-defense-program"  target="_blank">leading</a> the development of Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;Golden Dome,&rdquo; has called the country one of its &ldquo;<a href="https://www.spoc.spaceforce.mil/news/article-display/article/4066124/us-space-force-leaders-visit-japan-to-strengthen-partnership"  target="_blank">closest allies</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I believe what you see from the United States is a recognition that throughout our history, we don&rsquo;t go it alone when deterring conflict,&rdquo; U.S. Space Force Lt. Gen. David N. Miller Jr. said during a visit to Japan in February. &ldquo;We have found willing and abiding partnerships as fundamental to our ability to deter and ultimately, if necessary, defeat threats and deal with any crises that evolves.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S. and Japan should collaborate on missile warning and missile defense, Steve Jordan Tomaszewski, vice president of space systems at the Aerospace Industries Association, said during a Center for Strategic and International Studies event in April, <em>National Defense</em> magazine <a href="https://www.nationaldefensemagazine.org/articles/2025/6/4/space-programs-golden-dome-could-strengthen-us-japan-partnership"  target="_blank">reported</a>. &ldquo;Golden Dome could be a golden opportunity for collaboration at the end of the day.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What Japan has to gain</h2>



<p>It&rsquo;s not just defense, however, that is the bedrock of cooperation between the two countries. &ldquo;Economic security is another area that has become increasingly important in the U.S.-Japan alliance,&rdquo; according to a <a href="https://www.stimson.org/2025/the-us-japan-alliance-in-the-world/"  target="_blank">policy memo</a> by the Stimson Center, a Washington-based nonpartisan think-tank.</p>



<p>While collaboration on Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;Golden Dome&rdquo; may help to provide some security assurances to Japan, which is geographically closer to adversaries like North Korea, China, and Russia&mdash;all of which have <a href="https://time.com/7288728/golden-dome-trump-north-korea-russia-china-response-space-militarization/" >criticized the missile-defense project</a> for escalating a global arms race&mdash;according to the <em>Nikkei</em> report, Japan may try to use participation in the project as a &ldquo;bargaining chip&rdquo; in <a href="https://time.com/7283809/japan-us-trade-talks-rice-agriculture-protectionism-reform-trump-tariffs/" >trade talks</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7289035/trump-golden-dome-canada-51st-state-missile-defense-cost-carney/" ><em>Trump Offers Canada Free &lsquo;Golden Dome&rsquo; Protection to Become 51st U.S. State</em></a></p>



<p>Japan, which is a highly import-and-export-reliant <a href="https://afe.easia.columbia.edu/japan/japanworkbook/economics/factshe.htm"  target="_blank">economy</a>, has urged Trump to lower or altogether nix his tariffs on the country, which include a 25% levy on automotive parts as well as a 24% &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7274194/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-highest-country-rates-calculation-math-imports-exports/" >reciprocal</a>&rdquo; tariff, <a href="https://time.com/7276293/trump-tariffs-reversal-world-leaders-countries-responses-uncertainty-trade-war/" >temporarily reduced</a> to 10% <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/03/trump-tariffs-pause-federal-court-apple"  target="_blank">until July 8</a>. According to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-pushes-countries-best-offers-by-wednesday-tariff-deadline-looms-2025-06-02/"  target="_blank">Reuters</a>, the Trump Administration has asked countries to give their best offers in negotiations over the tariffs by Wednesday, June 4.</p>



<p>After his latest call with Trump, Ishiba said Japan&rsquo;s position on the tariffs has remained unmoved: &ldquo;The Japanese side has consistently advocated for &lsquo;investment rather than tariffs&rsquo; all along. By making investments in the U.S., we will generate employment in the United States while also leveraging Japan-U.S. cooperation to create better products. Japan&rsquo;s calls to make what can be called a &lsquo;win-win&rsquo; relationship have not changed in the slightest.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7291005/trump-golden-dome-japan-ishiba-tariffs-technology-missile-defense-cooperation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7291005</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lee Jae-myung Hopes to Heal South Korea. That Wont Be Easy</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7290981/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-election-challenges/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7290981/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-election-challenges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7290981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Koreas presidential election result was never really in doubt. The real question is which version of Lee Jae-myung will now govern the highly polarized nation of 50 million.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7290981"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7290981/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-election-challenges/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/lee-jae-myung-president-south-korea.jpg" alt="South Korea Holds Presidential Election"/>



<p>The result was never really in doubt. <a href="https://time.com/7289366/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-trump-economy-challenges-interview/" >Lee Jae-myung</a> is the new President of South Korea after winning a commanding 49% of the vote in Tuesday&rsquo;s snap election, which was called following the <a href="https://time.com/7274736/south-korea-constitutional-court-confirms-impeachment-president-yoon-suk-yeol/" >impeachment</a> of former President Yoon Suk-yeol, who plunged Asia&rsquo;s fourth biggest economy into turmoil with his December declaration of <a href="https://time.com/7199919/south-korea-martial-law-yoon-impeach-what-next/" >martial law</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The real question is which version of Lee will now govern this highly polarized East Asian nation of 50 million. The former labor-rights lawyer and activist is a political chameleon who has lurched from being a U.S.-skeptic, China-friendly progressive to a pragmatic moderate on the campaign trail, lavishing praise on U.S. President Donald Trump in an <a href="https://time.com/7289366/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-trump-economy-challenges-interview/" >exclusive interview</a> with TIME.</p>



<p>At the least, South Koreans will hope Lee, 61, can restore stability following six months of political paralysis that has hampered efforts to negotiate a vital reprieve for this export-reliant economy from April&rsquo;s &ldquo;reciprocal&rdquo; U.S. tariffs. Lee has promised a fiscal stimulus package to boost growth from just 2% last year, though tackling chaos in schools&mdash;both <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/asia/east-asia/inside-south-koreas-empty-classrooms-and-efforts-to-reimagine-them"  target="_blank">empty classrooms</a> and <a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/southkorea/society/20240908/teachers-in-korea-quit-jobs-at-alarming-rate"  target="_blank">teachers quitting</a> in droves&mdash;and reversing the world&rsquo;s lowest <a href="https://time.com/7286940/south-korea-nonmarital-childbirth-out-of-wedlock-fertility-rate-explainer/" >fertility rate</a> of just 0.75 births per woman won&rsquo;t have easy fixes.</p>



<p>Speaking to around 5,000 supporters gathered near Seoul&rsquo;s National Assembly, Lee promised to restore democracy, focus on mending a riven society, and work to alleviate rising costs of living to &ldquo;prevent people&rsquo;s livelihoods from further worsening.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Other than reasserting South Korea&rsquo;s democratic foundation following the martial law debacle, Lee&rsquo;s victory has huge implications for America&rsquo;s East Asian security alliances, as well as South Korea&rsquo;s ties with China and relations with estranged, nuclear-armed sibling North Korea across the demilitarized zone (DMZ) that has split the peninsula since the 1950&ndash;53 Korean war.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s critical that we secure peace and stability on the Korean peninsula,&rdquo; Lee told TIME in his only media <a href="https://time.com/7289366/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-trump-economy-challenges-interview/" >interview</a> on the campaign trail. &ldquo;And in so doing, the cornerstone is the military alliance between South Korea and the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<p>In hailing links with Washington, Lee is going against Democratic Party orthodoxy, which has typically been skeptical of U.S. ties. Indeed, historically Lee had been colder towards the U.S. and more positive toward China, though he tempered these views on the campaign trail to keep his tent as wide as possible, declaring at the stump that the Democratic Party is &ldquo;originally center-right, not progressive.&rdquo;</p>



<p>While domestic issues such as a cost of living crisis, stagnant economy, and <a href="https://www.chosun.com/english/national-en/2025/03/12/ZFUTRHCN25B7TKCMFPIDHQGORA/#:~:text=The%20number%20of%20young%20South,harder%20for%20young%20job%20seekers.%E2%80%9D"  target="_blank">record youth unemployment</a> dominated the vote, inter-Korean relations as ever loom in the background. North Korean &ldquo;Supreme Leader&rdquo; Kim Jong Un has sent troops, weapons, and ammunition to aid Vladimir Putin&rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine, while Pyongyang conducted 47 missile tests last year alone and has an estimated arsenal of some 70 nuclear bombs.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The security environment in Northeast Asia is unfolding very unfavorably for us,&rdquo; said Lee. &ldquo;South Korea and the U.S. need to keep a very close watch and make sure that we build on our deterrence and eventually move to disarmament of nuclear and missile capabilities and to denuclearization.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump has indicated his willingness to restart negotiations with Kim following their failed 2019 Hanoi summit and Lee will want to ensure that his government doesn&rsquo;t get squeezed out of talks as happened under his Democratic Party predecessor, former President <a href="https://time.com/6075235/moon-jae-in-south-korea-election/" >Moon Jae-in</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;When it comes to the U.S. and North Korea, the role the South Korean government can render regarding dialogue and cooperation will be required,&rdquo; said Lee. &ldquo;I don&#8217;t think there will be any need to sideline South Korea.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s not the only Moon misstep that Lee will be keen to avoid. A son of refugees from the North, Moon was so personally invested in rapprochement across the DMZ that he plowed endless time and political capital into that ultimately fruitless endeavor. The result was his own citizens felt overlooked and ignored, especially as the country was gripped by soaring real estate prices just as government officials were accused of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/23/world/asia/korea-housing-lh-scandal-moon-election.html"  target="_blank">leveraging</a> insider information to profit from state land sales.</p>



<p>&ldquo;A lot of people lost confidence in Moon&rsquo;s leadership because of the real estate issues,&rdquo; says Youngmi Kim, a senior lecturer in the department of Asian studies at Edinburgh University. &ldquo;Lee Jae-myung won&rsquo;t want to repeat those mistakes and will likely focus more on economic sectors rather than North Korean politics.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Another issue will be healing a nation that feels as polarized as at any time in living memory. When TIME sat down with Lee on May 25, the meeting room had to be swept for explosives by a sniffer dog, and the future President showed off the neck scar where he had been <a href="https://time.com/6553798/south-korea-lee-jae-myung-stabbed-attacker-politics/" >stabbed</a> by a would-be assassin in January last year.</p>



<p>During campaign events, Lee, who grew up in an impoverished farming household and toiled in factories as a child, spoke from behind bullet-proof glass to crowds, which were surveyed by rooftop police snipers.</p>



<p>While Lee stressed the importance of &ldquo;engaging in dialogue and really understanding the differences of one another&rdquo; while speaking to TIME, at the stump he attacked Yoon&rsquo;s People Power Party (PPP) as a &ldquo;far-right criminal organization&rdquo; and warned how &ldquo;the return of rebellion forces&rdquo; would lead to &ldquo;the destruction of democracy, the deprival of people&rsquo;s human rights, the normalization of martial law, and our country&rsquo;s downfall into a backward, third-world nation.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Lee led the charge for Yoon&rsquo;s impeachment and successfully segued that perceived moral high ground into the subsequent presidential campaign despite himself being embroiled in a slew of criminal cases, including for alleged bribery, violating the nation&rsquo;s election law during his <a href="https://time.com/6154471/south-korea-president-election-lee-jae-myung/" >2022 campaign for President</a>, and corruption linked to a $1 billion property development scandal. (Lee denies any wrongdoing.)</p>



<p>Though Yoon was the first President in South Korean history to be detained on criminal charges while still in office, the position has long been a poisoned chalice, with four South Korean Presidents imprisoned, one killing himself amid a corruption investigation, and three now impeached.</p>



<p>After losing control of the National Assembly in April 2024 legislative <a href="https://time.com/6991526/world-elections-results-2024/" >elections</a>, Yoon, a former prosecutor general, found it impossible to enact his agenda, even to pass a budget. This prompted him on Dec. 3 to declare martial law, <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/asia/east-asia/full-text-of-south-korean-president-yoon-suk-yeols-address-to-the-nation-on-dec-12"  target="_blank">calling</a> the opposition-controlled legislature an anti-state &ldquo;monster&rdquo; allied to North Korea that had &ldquo;paralyzed&rdquo; his administration. The folly of his <em>autogolpe</em>, or self-coup, shouldn&rsquo;t disguise the fact that South Korean politics requires urgent reform.</p>



<p>South Korean Presidents serve a single five-year term, with lawmakers elected every four years. While separation of powers is a vital feature of democracies, critics argue that the propensity of South Korean leaders to quickly become lame ducks without any hope of redemption engenders a hyper-polarized system whereby the legislature is incentivized to thwart executive power at every turn.</p>



<p>Lee, who will <a href="https://time.com/7290682/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-election-win/" >enjoy</a> a healthy legislative majority for at least three years, has advocated amending the constitution to allow two, four-year presidential terms mirroring the U.S., though this is a deeply contentious issue despite a constitutional provision barring an incumbent from benefiting from any amendments.</p>



<p>But looming in the background is Lee&rsquo;s case for violating South Korea&rsquo;s election law that could potentially bar him from politics for at least five years. In March, an appeals court cleared Lee only for the Supreme Court to overrule its verdict and send the case back for judgement, which is expected in coming months.</p>



<p>The potential for South Korea to be plunged into yet another constitutional crisis is deeply unsettling for a nation longing for a return to stability and the addressing of pocketbook issues. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s a lot of a lot of legal issues that will be parsed over the next six or eight months and we&rsquo;ll just have to see how the chips fall and if that has a great effect on Lee,&rdquo; says Sean O&rsquo;Malley, a professor and political scientist at Dongseo University in Busan.</p>



<p>The Democratic Party is trying to push through a new law that will protect Presidents from undergoing investigation and criminal prosecution during their term, which would solve Lee&rsquo;s problems but risks deepening fissures in South Korean society, especially as his predecessor is due in the dock over subsequent months to answer charges of insurrection.</p>



<p>On the final day of campaigning, Lee&rsquo;s PPP opponent Kim Moon-soo, a former labor minister under Yoon, told supporters in the southeastern city of Busan that Lee planned to &ldquo;seize all power in South Korea and establish a Hitler-like dictatorship&rdquo; by using his party&rsquo;s legislative majority to shield him from prosecution while retaliating against his political opponents.</p>



<p>Speaking to TIME, Lee insisted that he has &ldquo;a very firm commitment not to resort to any retaliation. I will not be doing things that they have done to us.&rdquo; While that sentiment is laudable, elections are no panacea, and Lee&rsquo;s evocation of &ldquo;they&rdquo; and &ldquo;us&rdquo; may portend tempestuous waters ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7290981/lee-jae-myung-south-korea-president-election-challenges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7290981</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
