<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Taking Out Iran’s Nuclear Facilities Could Usher In a New Dawn for Peace and Prosperity In the Middle East</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Sonnenfeld, Dennis Ross, Roya Hakakian and Steven Tian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trump’s strikes on Iran’s nuclear sites appear to mark a pivotal step toward Middle East peace.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296553"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran-2025.jpg" alt="President Trump Addresses Nation After US Bombs Iranian Nuclear Sites"/>



<p>Cyrus the Great, the compassionate and tolerant Babylonian who unified Iranian tribes in 549 BC to create the Persian empire, advised leaders to seek &ldquo;diversity in counsel and unity in command&rdquo;, and &ldquo;whenever you can, act as a liberator.&rdquo;  </p>



<p>While Cyrus&rsquo; Iranian descendants lost this wisdom, his message was heard by the U.S. For months, we have warned that Iran stood on the precipice of developing a nuclear weapon. While we do not agree with Donald Trump on many issues, we presciently predicted that in the face of this crisis, the president would act decisively to neutralize Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>It is premature to declare &ldquo;mission accomplished&rdquo; from <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >Trump&rsquo;s decision today </a>to bomb Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities at Fordow, Natanz and Isfahan, with many expecting potential retaliatory strikes against US forces, allies, and interests by Iran in the hours and days ahead. </p>



<p>But from a broader strategic perspective, it is already clear that today marks a potential turning point for the Middle East.</p>



<p>Far from an unnecessary escalation, as some critics suggest, these strikes represent a step closer to peace and prosperity for the U.S., the Middle East, and the world. The main threat to that &#8211; Iran and its proxy network &#8211; have been dramatically weakened. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/20250619-post-card-from-dc-brinkmanship-graph1.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>It is hard to overstate the significance of Trump&rsquo;s strike. A nuclear Iran was one of the gravest long-term security threats facing the world, and nobody wanted to see a regime &mdash; dominated by extremist clerics and fanatics responsible for the deaths of millions of innocent people &mdash; obtain weapons of mass destruction. </p>



<p>But for decades, the presence of Hezbollah, Hamas, and other Iran-backed proxies as threats on Israel&rsquo;s borders made the neutralization of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions unachievable and even unthinkable. For many, it became easier to live with the threat of a nuclear Iran than to deal with it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to Israel&rsquo;s decimation of Iran&rsquo;s proxies over the last two years, sometimes in defiance of western governments, that balance of power has gradually shifted.</p>



<p>Khamenei had a chance for a new nuclear deal, but misguidedly chose not to seize it, reflecting the same fundamental miscalculation that brought the demise of Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar and Hezbollah head Hassan Nasrallah, and culminating in today&rsquo;s<em> coup de grace.</em></p>



<p>With a substantively denuclearized Iranian regime now stripped of key military capabilities and regional leverage, with Hamas and Hezbollah largely neutralized as offensive forces, the greatest obstacles to peace and prosperity in the Middle East will soon be out of the way,&nbsp; creating potential conditions towards expanding the Abraham Accords and forging new economic, cultural, and diplomatic ties between Israel and the greater Arab world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, Hamas&rsquo;s attacks on October 7, 2023, were driven in part by Hamas&rsquo; objective of derailing a planned normalization between Israel and Saudi Arabia, the home of Mecca and the spiritual and symbolic center of Islam.</p>



<p>Riyadh will not be able to move immediately, even if Israel ends the war in Gaza and is able to bring the hostages back home, with the death and destruction in Gaza having soured Arab populaces toward Israel. But make no mistake, today&rsquo;s developments will help bring that process back on track over time, as the people of the Middle East continue to push forward with choosing a future of regional peace and economic prosperity over fear, terror and oppression.</p>



<p>As Jared Kushner, the architect of the Abraham Accords, put it: &ldquo;Iranian leadership has been stuck in the old Middle East, while their neighbors in the Gulf are sprinting toward the future by investing in their populations and infrastructure. They are becoming dynamic magnets for talent and investment while Iran falls further behind.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Despite criticism of the U.S. strikes on Iranian nuclear facilities from across the political spectrum &mdash; from Marjorie Taylor Greene, Tucker Carlson and Thomas Massie on the right, to Bernie Sanders and Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez on the left &mdash; many others have acknowledged its strategic implications and potential opportunities. Figures from both parties, including some of Trump&rsquo;s most frequent critics, such as President Obama and President Biden&rsquo;s top Mideast advisor, Brett McGurk, to former White House Chief of Staff and Ambassador to Japan, Rahm Emanuel &mdash; have recognized the potential significance of this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Emanuel pointed out on CNN, the biggest losers from Trump&rsquo;s strikes are America&rsquo;s enemies abroad, chiefly China and Russia, who were the biggest supporters and enablers of Iran&rsquo;s drive towards a nuclear weapon. Some have even suggested that Putin encouraged Tehran and its proxies as a diversion of attention away from Ukraine. It is now apparent that Iran&rsquo;s struggles have backfired catastrophically on its allies, with their efforts and investment having gone for naught.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </em></a></p>



<p>Ever since George W. Bush anointed Russia, Iran and North Korea as the Axis of Evil, the U.S. had failed to cripple its surge &mdash; until now.</p>



<p>To be clear, it is still far too early to declare &ldquo;mission complete&rdquo;. We are still in the earliest innings as retaliatory strikes from Iran appear imminent. Khamenei will need to do some kind of retaliation, perhaps targeting American forces and bases in the region or targeting the Saudis or Emiratis or another of our regional allies, or shutting down the Strait of Hormuz, to show Iran can hurt the US and its interests. </p>



<p>Regardless, the U.S. is well positioned to fend off Iran&rsquo;s next move, especially if Tehran should choose to engage in economic warfare and target global oil supplies. </p>



<p>If Iran moves to blockade or attack oil tankers traversing the crucial Strait of Hormuz &mdash; where 20% of the world&rsquo;s oil passes through &mdash; the U.S. 5th Fleet, based in Bahrain, can easily break the blockade or provide escorts to tankers as it did during the Gulf War. If Iranian oil is then taken off the market or if Tehran should target Gulf oil facilities, there is plenty of spare oil capacity globally to make up for what is lost. Iran&rsquo;s roughly two million barrels per day of exports pale in comparison to the approximately three million barrels per day of spare capacity possessed by Saudi Arabia alone, not to mention spare capacity within other OPEC+ countries as well as the U.S., now the world&rsquo;s single largest oil producer.</p>



<p>Similarly, on a military front, despite reports that Israel is running low on missile interceptors, which may be overstated anyhow; the U.S. is well prepared to continue supporting Israel while Iran runs hopelessly low on its own supply of ballistic missiles, not to mention the destruction of many missile launch sites.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Iran is still well incentivized to avoid an all-out war with the U.S., which they have long dreaded, for fear that the revolutionary regime led by the Ayatollah may be overthrown.</p>



<p>While the full extent of the damage to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities remains uncertain, what is clear is that Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions have been severely degraded and set back years, if not decades. After the U.S., during the Eisenhower administration, helped initiate Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program for civilian use, the Iranian revolutionary regime has invested half a trillion dollars over 40 years on weaponizing their nuclear program, inching ever closer to the atomic bomb. Between the imploding Iranian economy and the loss of dozens of key nuclear scientists, it will take even longer for Iran to build back what they have lost.</p>



<p>While it remains too soon to know how events will unfold, there is cautious optimism about the possibility of a more stable and peaceful future in the Middle East.</p>



<p>Far from marking a needless escalation, this week&rsquo;s strikes degrading Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities represent a step closer to peace and prosperity for the U.S., the Middle East, and the world.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Jeffrey Sonnenfeld</strong> is Lester Crown Professor of Management Practice at the Yale School of Management as well as founder and president of the Yale Chief Executive Leadership Institute, the world&rsquo;s first school for incumbent CEOs across sectors. He has informally advised five U.S. presidents, two Republicans and three Democrats; helped advise the development of the Abraham Accords; and helped catalyze the exit of over 1,000 companies from Russia.</p>



<p><strong>Dennis Ross</strong> is former special assistant to President Barack Obama in charge of the Middle East. He is the counselor at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy and also teaches at Georgetown University&rsquo;s Center for Jewish Civilization. He has worked on Mideast peace across six decades for both Democratic and Republican Presidents, including as Special Envoy for President George H.W. Bush and President Bill Clinton as well as a member of the National Security Council staff.</p>



<p><strong>Roya Hakakian</strong> is a public scholar at the Moynihan Center at City College, CUNY. She is the author of several books, including Journey from the Land of No: A Girlhood Caught in Revolutionary Iran.</p>



<p><strong>Steven Tian</strong> is research director of the Yale Chief Executive Leadership Institute. He previously worked in the U.S. State Department on Iranian nuclear nonproliferation in the Office of the Under Secretary.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296553/us-iran-strike-israel-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How U.S. Strikes May Have Inadvertently Helped the Iranian Regime </title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 17:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Tehran, there is evidence the regime is gaining ground with a public it had largely lost. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296554"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2213788011.jpg" alt="Imam Reza Birthday Anniversary In Tehran-Iran"/>



<p>Governments are not nations, especially in the Islamic Republic of Iran, but governments wage the wars that can define a nation.</p>



<p>Until 2:00 a.m. Iran Standard Time on Sunday, the conflict between America and Iran had remained on a low boil for a solid 45 years, flaring into actual military encounters only on the territory of others, notably Iraq. There, <a href="https://www.armytimes.com/news/your-military/2019/04/04/iran-killed-more-us-troops-in-iraq-than-previously-known-pentagon-says/?contentFeatureId=f0fmoahPVC2AbfL-2-1-8&amp;contentQuery=%7B%22includeSections%22%3A%22%2Fhome%22%2C%22excludeSections%22%3A%22%22%2C%22feedSize%22%3A10%2C%22feedOffset%22%3A355%7D"  target="_blank">every sixth U.S. fatality</a> perished by the efforts of Iran. President Donald Trump alluded to this history in announcing <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >the U.S. air strikes on three nuclear facilities</a> inside Iran&mdash;bringing the conflict to a regime that, even when it attacked the U.S., invariably arranged for someone else to do it.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>In Iraq, the U.S. was an army of occupation, and its soldiers obliged to patrol the roads. They did so in Humvees heavily armored against the roadside bombs insurgents planted along the route. Iran, which wanted U.S. troops off its doorstep, organized its own insurgents, and gave them a new kind of roadside bomb, a shaped charge that could send a slug of copper through any armor, including an M1 Abrams tank. The soldiers who survived often lost limbs. The U.S. Army <a href="https://nllp.jallc.nato.int/iks/sharing%20public/the%20u.s.%20army%20in%20the%20iraq%20war%20%E2%80%93%20volume%201.pdf?utm_source=chatgpt.com"  target="_blank">history</a> of the <a href="https://time.com/6265077/how-iran-won-the-iraq-war/" >Iraq War</a> takes note of the U.S. unit intercepting crates of the copper plates fitted atop the explosive: &ldquo;All were turned on the same lathe in Iran.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Israeli officials had been warning the Americans about those bombs. Their own troops had encountered them while occupying Lebanon, where the diabolically lethal innovations had been<a href="https://time.com/6324011/hezbollah-israel-lebanon-hamas-war/" > planted by Hezbollah,</a> the militia Iran helped establish and subsequently armed. When the U.S. invaded Iraq in 2003, Tehran directed them to be used against an enemy it had been fighting, in one way or another, since 1979.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >Iran Delivers Furious Warning, Speaks of &lsquo;Unprecedented Level of Danger and Chaos&rsquo; After &lsquo;Heinous&rsquo; U.S. Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>That was the year everyday Iranians rose up against the King (or Shah) who had been put in place a quarter century earlier by the U.S. and British, in a CIA-directed coup bringing down a democratically-elected government (one that had kicked a British oil company out of the country). A half century later, Iranian citizens could be relied upon to bring up the coup to American reporters doing in-person interviews on Tehran streets decorated with wartime propaganda. The entire side of a tall building in Tehran shows the American flag with the stars replaced by skulls and the stripes formed by descending bombs. The mural, which had faded over the decades, was redone with fresh paint a few months ago.</p>



<p>The famous &ldquo;Death to America&rdquo; slogan is still on the wall of the park-like compound that once held the U.S. Embassy. The place was officially dubbed &ldquo;the Den of Spies&rdquo; when it was overrun by supporters of the regime that replaced the Shah&mdash;a revolutionary movement led by a charismatic Shi&rsquo;ite cleric named Grand Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini. (<a href="https://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,2019712_2019694_2019594,00.html" >TIME&rsquo;s Person of the Year in 1979</a> is not to be confused with his similarly named successor, 86-year-old Ali Khamenei, who finally has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/21/world/middleeast/iran-ayatollah-israel-war.html"  target="_blank">reportedly nominated</a> his own candidates as successor.) The former embassy is now a <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293999-d2296233-Reviews-US_Den_of_Espionage-Tehran_Tehran_Province.html#/media/2296233/?albumid=-160&amp;type=ALL_INCLUDING_RESTRICTED&amp;category=-160"  target="_blank">museum</a> and, as <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g293999-d2296233-Reviews-US_Den_of_Espionage-Tehran_Tehran_Province.html#/media/2296233/?albumid=-160&amp;type=ALL_INCLUDING_RESTRICTED&amp;category=-160"  target="_blank">TripAdvisor</a> makes clear, an effective one. When Iranians were coming over the gates, American diplomats and spies scrambled to feed secrets into paper shredders, reducing their secret documents to strips of paper maybe an eighth-of-an-inch wide. The zeal of the 1979 revolution is still visible on the tables of the Den of Spies, in the papers true believers re-assembled strand-by-strand.</p>



<p>Over 50 U.S. diplomats remained in the embassy as hostages for 444 days. The humiliation the nascent Islamic Republic of Iran inflicted on the United States may have been on par with the humiliation the regime is experiencing now. </p>



<p>The hitch, for both the U.S. and Israel, is that bringing the attack to Iran, as a country, risks stirring the nationalist response of a nation that goes back 2,500 years. Most Iranians loathe their government, and may have looked on with a certain interest on June 13, when the Israeli warplanes and drones descended, both from abroad and from a base Mossad set up near Tehran. (A joke making the rounds in Tehran had one of Iran&rsquo;s retaliatory strikes hitting the headquarters of Mossad, but it was empty: All the agents were inside Iran.)</p>



<p>At the time its secret nuclear program <a href="https://thebulletin.org/2025/06/a-simple-timeline-of-irans-nuclear-program/"  target="_blank">was revealed</a> in 2002, people still held out hope that they could alter their government at the ballot box. But the political reform movement failed, and the stiffening, increasingly unpopular regime understood that it could no longer count on its population. Instead, it placed its hopes for survival in thugs beating protesters in the streets, and acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>A large majority of Iranians have no love for the regime. In small towns and cities alike, they have been <a href="https://time.com/6275538/iran-protests-eyewitness-report/" >rising up</a> against their oppressive government at irregular intervals, for decades.</p>



<p>But any kind of bomb is terrifying, and after the first night of attacks, Israel&rsquo;s warplanes moved beyond military targets and assassinations. An<a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" > oil refinery</a> was bombed. The casualties of a strike on Tajrish Square, a bustling bazaar in Tehran&rsquo;s north, <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/middle-east/20250617-anatomy-of-an-air-strike-israeli-strike-hits-busy-tehran-intersection"  target="_blank">included a water main</a> and a well-known graphic designer, who was waiting at a red light. The specter of Gaza now looms over every Israeli military operation. After Iran&rsquo;s retaliatory missiles claimed Israeli lives, <a href="https://time.com/7294186/israel-warns-tehran-will-burn-deadly-strikes-traded-nuclear-program/" >Israel&rsquo;s defense minister </a>threatened that &ldquo;Tehran will burn.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Inside Iran, opposing the government does not extend to supporting attacks by foreign militaries. A group of human rights, civil society, and political activists who, as they put it, &ldquo;have always been critical and opposed to the current wrong way of governing,&rdquo; posted a statement on Telegram saying: &ldquo;At this critical juncture in our country&rsquo;s history, when we are confronted with the aggression and arrogance of the racist Israeli government, which has a long history of warmongering, genocide and breaking the fundamental principles of morality and international law, we firmly condemn this attack. We emphasize our serious opposition to any foreign interference. We consider it to be detrimental to the human rights and democracy-seeking efforts of Iranian civil society, and we stand united and steadfast in defending the territorial integrity, independence, national defense capability of our homeland, defending the lives and dignity of human beings, and peace in the region and the world.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Dread swelled in the neighborhoods around the Tehran atomic research reactor, with the distribution of iodide potassium pills to protect the thyroid against radiation in the air. Experts say <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5ykjvl1y9jo"  target="_blank">the risk of radiation exposure</a> is fairly small around the atomic facilities that the U.S. and Israel have bombed to date, because the ones in Fordow, Natanz, and Isfahan all deal with enriching uranium, rather than sparking nuclear reactions. But though small, the <a href="https://www.nti.org/education-center/facilities/tehran-nuclear-research-center-tnrc/"  target="_blank">Tehran reactor</a> (set up by the U.S. in 1967, when the Shah still ruled), operates as Chernobyl or Three Mile Island once did, and in the center of a city of more than nine million people. Those living closest to the reactor were told the pills should be taken by those over the age of 60 and under 40, but only when instructed by state TV, which Israel <a href="https://time.com/7294791/iran-state-tv-israel-strike/" >has also bombed</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em><br><br>So, where do things go from here?</p>



<p>To a large extent, that depends on the actions of an Iranian regime that was already unpopular at the start of this assault. But any government bringing its own military inside Iran&rsquo;s borders should understand the nature of the country. Among Iranians, opposition to the government is grounded in a bedrock pride in their nation, which predates not only the Islamic Republic, but Islam itself. Some on the Iranian plateau still practice Zoroastrianism, the world&rsquo;s first monotheistic faith, and the foundation for an ancient empire that still informs Iranians&rsquo; sense of themselves. That identity can be glimpsed in first names like Darius and Cyrus&mdash;the names of Persian emperors&mdash;and actually visible in the ruins of Persepolis. There, in the friezes depicting supplicants from nations lining up to pay fealty to the ruler of an ancient empire, <a href="https://world.time.com/2011/11/13/behind-irans-nuclear-quest-an-ancient-civilizations-pride-and-insecurity/" >some Iranians find themselves</a> seeing the nuclear program exactly as the modern regime has cast it&mdash;as the &ldquo;<a href="https://www.nti.org/education-center/treaties-and-regimes/treaty-on-the-non-proliferation-of-nuclear-weapons/#:~:text=(Article%20IV):%20The%20Treaty,peaceful%20uses%20of%20nuclear%20energy."  target="_blank">inalienable right</a>&rdquo; of any signatory to Non Proliferation Treaty to pursue a nuclear program, so long as it&rsquo;s peaceful.<br><br>Back in Tehran, there was evidence the regime was gaining ground with a public it had largely lost. In a private chat, a university professor told a friend: &#8220;Even if Khamenei had packed up the whole nuclear program, Israel would have attacked. Their whole plan was to weaken Iran&#8217;s military.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296554</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Gravely Alarmed&#8217; World Leaders React After U.S. Strikes Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Time]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 14:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“This is a dangerous escalation in a region already on the edge—and a direct threat to international peace and security."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296530"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/world-leaders-trump-iran.jpg" alt="UK Prime Minister Attends The G7 Leaders' Summit"/>



<p>The world is reacting after President Donald <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >Trump authorized U.S. strikes</a> on three key Iranian nuclear sites, joining Israel in its conflict with Iran.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran&#8217;s key nuclear enrichment facilities have been completely and totally obliterated,&rdquo; Trump said in an address to the nation on Saturday night. &ldquo;Iran, the bully of the Middle East, must now make peace. If they do not, future attacks will be far greater and a lot easier.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Iran has since responded with a grave new warning, threatening &ldquo;everlasting consequences&rdquo; and calling for an emergency meeting of the U.N. Security Council.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >Iran Delivers Furious Warning, Speaks of &lsquo;Unprecedented Level of Danger and Chaos&rsquo; After &lsquo;Heinous&rsquo; U.S. Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>As the world awaits to see what Iran&rsquo;s next step will be, global leaders are reacting to the news of the strikes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Argentina</strong></h2>



<p>Argentina&rsquo;s President Javier Milei, a right-wing ally of Trump&rsquo;s in Latin America, has yet to comment specifically on the U.S. strikes, but he re-posted a message in the early hours of the morning on June 22.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Today is a great day for Western civilization,&rdquo; read <a href="https://x.com/marcos_galperin/status/1936731633433915650"  target="_blank">the post</a>, authored by Argentine billionaire and businessman Marcos Galperin.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Australia</strong></h2>



<p>The Australian government, led by Anthony Albanese, <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-22/government-opposition-response-us-strikes-iran/105446620"  target="_blank">has called for de-escalation</a> but its statement, issued by a spokesperson, did not reveal much of whether or not the government supported the U.S. strikes.</p>



<p>&#8220;We note the U.S. President&rsquo;s statement that now is the time for peace. The security situation in the region is highly volatile. We continue to call for de-escalation, dialogue, and diplomacy.&#8221; </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Canada</strong></h2>



<p>Prime Minister Mark Carney reiterated Trump&rsquo;s belief that &ldquo;Iran can never be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon,&rdquo; something that he says Canada has been &ldquo;consistently clear&rdquo; about. He said that Trump&rsquo;s directive was meant to &ldquo;alleviate the threat&rdquo; but that the situation is still &ldquo;highly volatile.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Canada calls on parties to return immediately to the negotiating table and reach a diplomatic solution to end this crisis,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/MarkJCarney/status/1936755830784659757"  target="_blank">Carney emphasized. </a>&ldquo;As G7 leaders agreed in Kananaskis, the resolution of the Iranian crisis should lead to a broader de-escalation of hostilities in the Middle East, including a cease-fire in Gaza.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Chile</strong></h2>



<p>Chilean President Gabriel Boric condemned the <a href="https://x.com/GabrielBoric/status/1936599332024914293"  target="_blank">U.S. strikes</a>, calling them a violation of international law. He went on to &ldquo;demand peace.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We will defend respect for international humanitarian law at all times,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Having power does not authorize you to use it in violation of the rules we have established as humanity. Even if you are the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>China</strong></h2>



<p>China &ldquo;strongly condemns&rdquo; the U.S. strikes, according to <a href="https://english.news.cn/20250622/232fd95ee5494b10b0ea788e14b8f983/c.html"  target="_blank">state media</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The actions of the United States seriously violated the purposes and principles of the U.N. Charter and international law, and have exacerbated tensions in the Middle East,&rdquo; a spokesperson said. &ldquo;China calls on the parties to the conflict, Israel in particular, to reach a cease-fire as soon as possible, ensure the safety of civilians, and start dialogue and negotiation.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Czechia</strong></h2>



<p>Prime Minister of the Czech Republic Petr Fiala <a href="https://x.com/P_Fiala/status/1936700572939264345"  target="_blank">said</a> that the country supported the U.S. strikes, calling them &ldquo;an understandable effort to prevent Tehran from developing nuclear weapons.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;U.S. military action, which supported Israel&#8217;s efforts, may finally force the Iranian regime to take action that would lead to a calmer situation in the Middle East,&rdquo; he said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>I</strong><strong>ndia</strong></h2>



<p>India&rsquo;s Prime Minister Narendra Modi <a href="https://x.com/narendramodi/status/1936721293682131386"  target="_blank">said on social media</a> that he spoke with Iran&rsquo;s President after the U.S. strikes. Modi reported that he &ldquo;reiterated [India&rsquo;s] call for immediate de-escalation, dialogue and diplomacy as the way forward and for early restoration of regional peace, security and stability.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>European Commission</strong></h2>



<p>European Commission president <a href="https://x.com/vonderleyen/status/1936709917261402478"  target="_blank">Ursula von der Leyen said that</a> &ldquo;the negotiating table is the only place to end this crisis.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Von der Leyen maintained that &ldquo;Iran must never acquire the bomb,&rdquo; and said the Middle Eastern country should now &ldquo;engage in a credible diplomatic solution.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>France</strong></h2>



<p>The French government <a href="https://www.diplomatie.gouv.fr/en/country-files/iran/news/article/iran-reaction-to-us-strikes-on-iranian-nuclear-facilities-22-06-25?egn-publisher=Twitter&amp;egn-name=Twitter-RS"  target="_blank">released a statement</a> clarifying that France was not involved in the attacks.</p>



<p>The European country reiterated &ldquo;its firm opposition to Iran gaining access to nuclear weapons,&rdquo; but also urged both parties &ldquo;to exercise restraint.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;France is convinced that a lasting solution to this issue requires a negotiated solution within the framework of the Treaty of Non-Proliferation. We remain ready to contribute to this in conjunction with our partners,&rdquo; the statement read.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Germany</strong></h2>



<p>German Chancellor <a href="https://x.com/bundeskanzler/status/1936835633219039645"  target="_blank">Friedrich Merz said on Sunday</a>: &#8220;Today, I discussed the latest developments in the Middle East with Starmer [U.K. Prime Minister] and Macron [French President]. We reaffirm our commitment to peace and stability for all countries in the region, as well as our support for Israel&#8217;s security.&#8221;</p>



<p>Merz went on to emphasize their shared viewpoint, saying: &#8220;Iran must never acquire nuclear weapons. Iran must no longer pose a threat to regional security.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The International Atomic Energy Agency</strong></h2>



<p>The International Atomic Energy Agency&mdash;which works for the safe, secure, and peaceful uses of nuclear science and technology&mdash;<a href="https://x.com/iaeaorg/status/1936717589906129068"  target="_blank">said it would hold an emergency meeting</a> on Monday &#8220;in light of the urgent situation in Iran.&#8221; It confirmed there was no detectable radiation uncovered thus far as a result of the military attacks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Iran</strong></h2>



<p>Iranian Minister of Foreign Affairs Abbas Araghchi accused the U.S. of breaching international law and warned that the strikes will have &ldquo;everlasting consequences.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The United States, a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, has committed a grave violation of the U.N. Charter, international law, and the NPT [Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty] by attacking Iran&rsquo;s peaceful nuclear installations,&rdquo; Araghchi said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Ireland</strong></h2>



<p>T&aacute;naiste [Deputy Prime Minister] Simon Harris <a href="https://x.com/SimonHarrisTD/status/1936691860077973766"  target="_blank">has called for &ldquo;de-escalation&rdquo;</a> and said that he will be traveling to Brussels to speak with others at the European Union (E.U.) to work on making that a reality.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Israel</strong></h2>



<p>During Trump&rsquo;s address to the U.S., he thanked Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, stating that the two of them worked as a team on the Iran strikes.</p>



<p>Netanyahu praised Trump for conducting the strikes <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1936600958508618192"  target="_blank">in his own video address.</a></p>



<p>&ldquo;President Trump and I often say peace through strength. First comes strength, then comes peace,&#8221; he said. &ldquo;And tonight President Trump and the United States acted with a lot of strength.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog <a href="https://x.com/isaac_herzog/status/1936627914105106599"  target="_blank">also thanked Trump</a>, calling the evening a &ldquo;decisive moment between the axis of terror and evil and the axis of hope.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This brave step serves the security and safety of the entire free world. I hope it will lead to a better future for the Middle East&mdash;and help advance the urgent release of our hostages held in captivity in Gaza,&rdquo; he said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Mexico</strong></h2>



<p>Mexico&rsquo;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs &ldquo;urgently&rdquo; called for &ldquo;diplomatic dialogue and peace.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Under Mexico&rsquo;s constitutional principles of foreign policy and our nation&rsquo;s pacifist convictions, we reiterate our call to de-escalate tensions in the region,&rdquo; the Ministry said<a href="https://x.com/SRE_mx/status/1936616761404563876"  target="_blank"> in a statement</a>. &ldquo;Restoring peaceful coexistence among the States in the region remains the highest priority.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Oman</strong></h2>



<p>Oman, which had been hoping to mediate further nuclear talks between Tehran and Washington D.C., also condemned the U.S. strikes, with the Official Oman News Agency<a href="https://x.com/ONA_eng/status/1936692843503837357"  target="_blank"> reporting that</a> the Sultanate &ldquo;expressed profound concern and condemnation over the escalation caused by the United States&rsquo; direct airstrikes on targets&rdquo; within Iran.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Pakistan</strong></h2>



<p>Pakistan, the government of which had only recently announced its <a href="https://time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/" >intention to nominate Trump for the Nobel Peace Prize</a>, condemned the U.S. strikes, <a href="https://x.com/MIshaqDar50/status/1936688895003078721"  target="_blank">stating that they</a> &ldquo;violate all norms of international law and Iran has the legitimate right to defend itself.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We emphasise the imperative need to respect civilian lives and properties and immediately bring the conflict to end. All parties must adhere to international law, particularly international humanitarian law,&rdquo; the statement read.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Russia</strong></h2>



<p>Russia&rsquo;s Foreign Ministry shared a statement on Telegram condemning the airstrikes and calling them &ldquo;a dangerous escalation&#8230; fraught with further undermining of regional and global security.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The governmental body called the strikes &ldquo;a gross violation of international law, the U.N. Charter, and U.N. Security Council resolutions&rdquo; and called for an &#8220;end to aggression and for increased efforts to create conditions for returning the situation to a political and diplomatic track.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Saudi Arabia</strong></h2>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.spa.gov.sa/en/N2344168"  target="_blank">Saudi Press Agency</a>, the country has expressed &ldquo;deep concern&rdquo; over the U.S. strikes and see them as a &ldquo;violation&rdquo; of the sovereignty of Iran. </p>



<p>&ldquo;[The Kingdom] underscores the need to exert all possible efforts to exercise restraint, de-escalate tensions, and avoid further escalation,&rdquo; read a statement attributed to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. &ldquo;The Kingdom also calls upon the international community to intensify its efforts during this highly sensitive period to reach a political resolution that would bring an end to the crisis and open a new chapter for achieving security and stability in the region.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Spain</strong></h2>



<p>Prime Minister Pedro S&aacute;nchez <a href="https://x.com/sanchezcastejon/status/1936755188838039734"  target="_blank">said</a> that he is mourning the civilian lives lost amid the conflict. He highlighted an &ldquo;urgent need for restraint and de-escalation, for diplomacy and dialogue.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran must never have access to nuclear weapons, but stability in the region can only be achieved at the negotiating table, with full respect for international law,&rdquo; S&aacute;nchez said. &ldquo;We need a diplomatic solution that establishes a comprehensive framework of peace and security for all.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Ukraine</strong></h2>



<p>Though President Volodymyr Zelensky did not reveal his support or condemnation of the U.S. strikes, <a href="https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1936747450124898481"  target="_blank">he did </a>state that prior to the strikes, 176 Ukrainian citizens and citizens of partner states were evacuated from Israel to Egypt, and &ldquo;evacuation efforts are also ongoing from Iran to Azerbaijan.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>United Kingdom</strong></h2>



<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer <a href="https://x.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1936675855675035868"  target="_blank">called for Iran</a> to &ldquo;return to the negotiating table&rdquo; after the U.S. strikes  and referred to Iran&rsquo;s nuclear programme as a &ldquo;grave threat to international security.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The situation in the Middle East remains volatile and stability in the region is a priority. We call on Iran to return to the negotiating table and reach a diplomatic solution to end this crisis,&rdquo; Starmer said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>United Nations</strong></h2>



<p>Secretary General of the United Nations (U.N.) Ant&oacute;nio Guterres shared a strong statement <a href="https://x.com/antonioguterres/status/1936603735330898368"  target="_blank">on social media</a>, stating that he was &ldquo;gravely alarmed&rdquo; by the strikes. He called for de-escalation and shared concerns that the conflict could cause a &ldquo;spiral of chaos.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is a dangerous escalation in a region already on the edge&mdash;and a direct threat to international peace and security,&rdquo; Guterres said. &ldquo;I call on Member States to de-escalate and to uphold their obligations under the U.N. Charter and other rules of international law.&#8221;</p>



<p>He continued by saying there is &ldquo;no military solution,&rdquo; and that he believes the only way forward is &ldquo;diplomacy.&rdquo; </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296530</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Delivers Furious Warning, Speaks of &#8216;Unprecedented Level of Danger and Chaos&#8217; After &#8216;Heinous&#8217; U.S. Strikes</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia-Anne Cleary]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 12:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["The warmongering and lawless Administration in Washington is solely responsible for the dangerous consequences of its act of aggression."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296512"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-22-at-19.07.29.png" alt=""/>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi delivered blistering remarks on Sunday as he responded to the <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >overnight strikes conducted by the U.S.</a> which, overseen by President Donald Trump, targeted three key Iranian nuclear sites. Araghchi warned of &ldquo;everlasting,&rdquo; &ldquo;dangerous,&rdquo; and &ldquo;far-reaching&rdquo; consequences for what the Iranian Foreign Ministry called an &ldquo;egregious act of aggression and heinous crime.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Araghchi delivered his response in a speech at the 51st session of the Council of Foreign Ministers of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation in Istanbul, and also via a series of online posts.</p>



<p>&#8220;The warmongering and lawless Administration in Washington is solely and fully responsible for the dangerous consequences and far-reaching implications of its act of aggression,&#8221; Araghchi said. &ldquo;The U.S. military aggression against the territorial integrity and national sovereignty of a U.N. member state&mdash;carried out in collusion with the genocidal Israeli regime&mdash;once again laid bare the depth of depravity that governs American foreign policy and revealed the extent of hostility harbored by the U.S. ruling establishment against the peace-seeking and independence-loving people of Iran.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Iranian politician went on to request an emergency meeting of the U.N. Security Council, citing &ldquo;a violation of the U.N. Security Council Resolution 2231&rdquo; and threatened that silence on this matter would only worsen the situation.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Silence in the face of such blatant aggression would plunge the world into an unprecedented level of danger and chaos,&rdquo; he warned.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<a href="https://time.com/7296396/iran-new-warning-trump-united-states-israel-conflict-dangerous/" ><em> Iran Issues New Grave Warning, Says U.S. Involvement in Israel Conflict Would Be &lsquo;Very Dangerous for Everybody&rsquo;</em></a></p>



<p>Iran&#8217;s President Masoud Pezeshkian has also condemned the Trump-ordered strikes and referred to the U.S. as the &#8220;primary instigator.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This aggression showed that the United States is the primary instigator of the Zionist regime&rsquo;s hostile actions against the Islamic Republic of Iran,&rdquo; Pezeshkian said. &ldquo;Although they initially tried to deny their role, after our armed forces&rsquo; decisive and deterrent response and the Zionist regime&rsquo;s clear incapacity, they were inevitably forced to enter the field themselves.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Pezeshkian urged the public to come together in the face of the attacks from Israel and the U.S.</p>



<p>Prior to the initial Israeli strikes on Iranian nuclear and military targets on June 13, conducted amid a growing concern over Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities, Iran and the U.S. had been engaging in talks surrounding a potential nuclear deal. Those talks were suspended in light of the active conflict, and it remains to be seen if they will get back on track. But Araghchi said diplomacy is no longer an option following the U.S. military action. &ldquo;They crossed a very big red line by attacking nuclear facilities&hellip; We have to respond based on our legitimate right for self-defense,&rdquo; he said. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Iran-U.S.-strike.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Araghchi&rsquo;s warnings at the council meeting somewhat mirrored the initial reaction he shared via social media.</p>



<p>&#8220;The events this morning are outrageous and will have everlasting consequences. Each and every member of the U.N. must be alarmed over this extremely dangerous, lawless and criminal behavior,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/araghchi/status/1936638107169722536"  target="_blank">Araghchi said in the early hours of Sunday morning</a>. &ldquo;In accordance with the U.N. Charter and its provisions allowing a legitimate response in self-defense, Iran reserves all options to defend its sovereignty, interest, and people.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Trump has referred to the U.S.&rsquo; attack on three key Iranian nuclear sites as &ldquo;very successful.&rdquo; The U.S. launched a series of B-2 stealth bombers&mdash;some of which were reported as moving across the Pacific on Saturday, hours before the strikes were announced&mdash;and targeted the sites in Fordow, Natanz, and Esfahan.</p>



<p>&ldquo;A full payload of BOMBS was dropped on the primary site, Fordow. All planes are safely on their way home. Congratulations to our great American Warriors. There is not another military in the World that could have done this. NOW IS THE TIME FOR PEACE!&rdquo; Trump said in his initial announcement.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" ><em> </em><em>How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</em></a></p>



<p>The President then went on to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C7eSJ011Muc"  target="_blank">address the nation directly from the White House</a> on Saturday night. Flanked by Vice President J.D. Vance, Secretary of State Marco Rubio, and Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth, Trump said the U.S. bombers had &ldquo;totally obliterated&rdquo; the nuclear sites and called the mission &ldquo;a spectacular military success.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump instructed Iran to move toward peace, warning that the U.S. would pursue other targets with &ldquo;speed&rdquo; and &#8220;precision&#8221; if not.</p>



<p>Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Gen. Dan Caine appeared with Secretary Hegseth at the Pentagon on Sunday morning to share more information about the U.S. strikes on Iran&#8217;s nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Hegseth said the U.S. is hopeful the attack on Iran&rsquo;s Fordow facility &#8220;achieved destruction of capabilities.&#8221; However, Gen. Caine was clear that it is &ldquo;way too early&rdquo; to comment on whether Iran still retains some of its nuclear capabilities, as investigations and debriefs are ongoing.</p>



<p>The pair also said the U.S. is taking &ldquo;proactive&rdquo; steps to protect U.S. troops in the Middle East region.</p>



<p>The U.S. strikes mark a significant turning point in the Israel-Iran conflict. The U.S. is no longer supporting Israel from afar, but are now active participants in an extensive military operation aiming to stifle Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities.</p>



<p>As the world awaits to see what Iran&rsquo;s next move will be, Trump issued a stark warning to the Middle Eastern country, telling them not to retaliate to the U.S. strikes.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Any retaliation by Iran against the United States of America will be met with force far greater than what was witnessed tonight,&rdquo;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114724683855260695"  target="_blank"> Trump said in a charged social media post</a>. Hegseth doubled down on this point on Sunday morning, saying it &ldquo;would be a very bad idea for Iran or its proxies to attempt to attack American forces.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Israel and Iran continue to trade deadly missiles 10 days into their active conflict. Israel&rsquo;s military said Iran launched a fresh wave of missiles toward the country following the U.S. strikes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Joins Israel in Strikes on Iranian Nuclear Sites, Risking Wider War</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett and Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 01:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's the most direct American military intervention inside Iran in decades]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296469"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran-war-01.jpg" alt="Trump Iran War"/>



<p>President Donald Trump said in a brief address to the nation Saturday evening that U.S. bombers had &ldquo;totally obliterated&rdquo; three key Iranian nuclear sites and threatened to hit more targets if Iran refused to &ldquo;make peace.&rdquo; The strikes were a rare use of B-2 stealth bombers, a highly secret and central part of U.S. nuclear deterrence strategy, and marked the country unequivocally joining Israel&rsquo;s campaign to cripple Tehran&rsquo;s ability to build a nuclear weapon.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;Iran&#8217;s key nuclear enrichment facilities have been completely and totally obliterated,&rdquo; Trump said, after striding down the White House Cross Hall and stepping up to a microphone flanked by Vice President J.D. Vance, Secretary of State Marco Rubio, and Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth. &ldquo;Iran, the bully of the Middle East, must now make peace. If they do not, future attacks will be far greater and a lot easier.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The operation marks the most direct American military intervention inside Iran in decades and has reignited fears of a rapidly widening conflict that could draw in proxy forces, endanger U.S. troops, and disrupt global energy markets.</p>



<p>&ldquo;For 40 years, Iran has been saying, Death to America, Death to Israel,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;There will be either peace or there will be tragedy for Iran far greater than we have witnessed over the last eight days.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump warned of additional airstrikes targeting Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program, noting &ldquo;There are many targets left.&rdquo; </p>



<p>&ldquo;Tonight&#8217;s was the most difficult of them all, by far, and perhaps the most lethal,&#8221; the President continued. &#8220;But if peace does not come quickly, we will go after those other targets with precision, speed, and skill. Most of them can be taken out in a matter of minutes.&rdquo;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Iran-U.S.-strike.png" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Trump took a moment to thank Israeli Prime Minister <a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >Benjamin Netanyahu</a>, saying &ldquo;we worked as a team like perhaps no team has ever worked before.&rdquo; Trump finished his remarks by saying, &ldquo;God bless the Middle East, God bless Israel, and God bless America.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Earlier in the evening, Trump announced the strikes had been completed on his Truth Social account, calling the mission &ldquo;very successful&rdquo; and noting that all U.S. aircraft had exited Iranian airspace.</p>



<p> &ldquo;A full payload of BOMBS was dropped on the primary site, Fordow,&rdquo; Trump wrote on Truth Social at 7:50 pm, referring to the <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >heavily fortified nuclear enrichment site</a> built into a mountain outside the city of Qom. The U.S. also targeted the larger enrichment plant at Natanz and a facility near Isfahan believed to house highly enriched uranium.</p>



<p>&ldquo;All planes are safely on their way home,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;Congratulations to our great American Warriors. There is not another military in the World that could have done this. NOW IS THE TIME FOR PEACE!&rdquo;</p>



<p>The move represents a dramatic shift from Trump&rsquo;s earlier resistance to deeper U.S. entanglement in foreign wars. He had campaigned on a pledge to end foreign wars and not start new ones, but his decision to strike Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities underscores the growing pressure he faced from Israel and Republican allies in Congress who viewed this moment as an opportunity to permanently degrade Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In response to the strikes, the Atomic Energy Organization of Iran issued a statement that did not refute Trump&rsquo;s declarations that the targeted sites had been obliterated. The organization asserted that Iran &ldquo;will not allow the development of this national industry, which is the result of the blood of nuclear martyrs, to be stopped.&#8221; </p>



<p>Trump&#8217;s decision to ultimately strike Iran comes just over a week after Israeli forces had already damaged surface-level infrastructure at Natanz and eroded key elements of Iran&rsquo;s air defenses, in a move that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu described as a &ldquo;strike at the head of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear weaponization program.&rdquo; But intelligence officials have long said that only American stealth bombers and the 30,000-pound bunker buster bomb could successfully destroy Iran&rsquo;s deeply buried nuclear infrastructure, particularly at Fordow, a heavily fortified nuclear enrichment site built into a mountain outside the city of Qom. </p>



<p>In a <a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >February meeting</a>, TIME recently reported based on accounts from Israeli officials, Netanyahu warned Trump that <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >Iran was inching closer</a> to crossing the nuclear threshold: increasing its stockpile of highly enriched uranium and advancing its centrifuge technology. &ldquo;Look, Donald,&rdquo; Netanyahu said, &ldquo;this has to be tackled, because they&rsquo;re racing forward.&rdquo; He then paused for dramatic effect and looked at Trump directly in the eye. &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t have a nuclear Iran on your watch.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The conversation appeared to make an impression. Trump repeatedly vowed that Iran &ldquo;must never obtain a nuclear weapon&rdquo; and attempted to make a deal with Iran to limit its nuclear capabilities, but the talks stalled in recent weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran has insisted that it is not developing a bomb and that its nuclear program remains non-weaponized for peaceful energy purposes. However, the United Nations&rsquo; nuclear watchdog recently reported that Iran&rsquo;s stockpile of 60% enriched uranium&mdash;just below weapons-grade&mdash;had grown large enough to produce multiple bombs if further enriched. Analysts said Iran could theoretically produce a bomb&rsquo;s worth of material in as little as a week, and that no other country has that level of uranium without a nuclear weapons program.</p>



<p>The strikes have raised many questions about what comes next, including how Iran will retaliate and whether the conflict will spread across the region. Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei warned Trump on Wednesday that strikes against Iran will &ldquo;result in irreparable damage for them.&rdquo; Iranian Foreign Ministry spokesman Esmail Baghaei said that &ldquo;any American intervention would be a recipe for an all-out war in the region.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iranian-backed Houthi rebels in Yemen have previously threatened to resume attacks on U.S. forces in the Red Sea if the U.S. joined Israel&rsquo;s military operation.</p>



<p>Trump told reporters on Friday that he does not want to send ground forces into Iran, saying it&rsquo;s &ldquo;the last thing you want to do.&rdquo; He had previously said that he would make a final choice over the course of two weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;I may do it. I may not do it,&rdquo; he said Wednesday. &ldquo;Nobody knows what I&rsquo;m going to do.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It was not independently verified how much damage was inflicted or whether significant nuclear material and contamination had been released. Israel&rsquo;s initial strikes were particularly effective and had crippled Iran&rsquo;s air defenses. </p>



<p>The International Atomic Energy Agency has previously warned that bombing active enrichment sites, particularly Fordow, could pose environmental and health risks.</p>



<p>While many have praised Trump&rsquo;s decision to strike Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities, it has also sparked backlash on Capitol Hill, including from some members of his own party. &ldquo;This is not Constitutional,&rdquo; Rep. Thomas Massie, a Kentucky Republican, wrote on X, suggesting that Congress had not authorized the use of force. Other lawmakers warned that the operation risked triggering a prolonged conflict. &ldquo;We now have very serious choices ahead to provide security for our citizens and our allies and stability for the middle-east,&rdquo; Sen. Roger Wicker, a Mississippi Republican and chair of the Senate Armed Services Committee, wrote on X.</p>



<p>Multiple Democrats described the strike as &#8220;unconstitutional&#8221; and &#8220;unauthorized.&#8221; In a <a href="https://x.com/AOC/status/1936600627221565468"  target="_blank">post on X</a>, Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez of New York called the bombings &#8220;a grave violation of the Constitution and Congressional War Powers&#8221; and &#8220;clearly grounds for impeachment.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296469</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Critics Demand Pakistan &#8216;Revokes&#8217; Decision to Nominate Trump for Nobel Peace Prize After U.S. Strikes on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 19:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pakistan had praised Trump's "legacy of pragmatic diplomacy and effective peace-building" prior to the U.S. strikes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296429"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-palm-beach-2025.jpg" alt="Republican Presidential Nominee Donald Trump Holds Election Night Event In West Palm Beach"/>



<p>Just a day before the <a href="https://time.com/7296554/us-strikes-iranian-regime-benefits/" >U.S. launched strikes on Iran,</a> Pakistan had stated its intention to &ldquo;formally recommend&rdquo; U.S. President Donald Trump for the Nobel Peace Prize. The country expressed its desire to recognize Trump&rsquo;s role in helping <a href="https://time.com/7284654/india-pakistan-ceasefire-trump-us-mediation-kashmir-conflict-strikes/" >India and Pakistan reach a cease-fire</a> after conflict between the two long-time rivals resurged earlier this year. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Previous Nobel Prize recipients include former TIME100 Women of the Year honoree <a href="https://time.com/5793780/malala-yousafzai-100-women-of-the-year/" >Malala Yousafzai</a>, and previous TIME Person of the Year recipients <a href="https://content.time.com/time/covers/0,16641,19640103,00.html" >Martin Luther King Jr.</a>, and former <a href="https://poy.time.com/person-of-the-year-2012/" >President Barack Obama</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;At a moment of heightened regional turbulence, President Trump demonstrated great strategic foresight and stellar statesmanship through robust diplomatic engagement with both Islamabad and New Delhi, which de-escalated a rapidly deteriorating situation, ultimately securing a cease-fire and averting a broader conflict between the two nuclear states that would have had catastrophic consequences for millions of people in the region and beyond,&rdquo; the Government of Pakistan <a href="https://x.com/GovtofPakistan/status/1936159807326900577"  target="_blank">said in its announcement via social media</a>. &ldquo;This intervention stands as a testament to his role as a genuine peacemaker and his commitment to conflict resolution through dialogue.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Pakistani government went on to say that Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;leadership during the 2025 Pakistan-India crisis manifestly showcases the continuation of his legacy of pragmatic diplomacy and effective peace-building.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7284654/india-pakistan-ceasefire-trump-us-mediation-kashmir-conflict-strikes/" >India and Pakistan Cease-Fire Appears to Hold Despite Accusations of Violations</a></em></p>



<p>When Trump announced the cease-fire between India and Pakistan on May 10, he said the agreement had been reached after &ldquo;a long night of talks mediated by the United States.&rdquo; He later went on to thank Vice President J.D. Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio for their efforts.</p>



<p>Pakistan&#8217;s Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif <a href="https://x.com/CMShehbaz/status/1921220993101525318"  target="_blank">took to social media</a> to express gratitude to Trump at the time, saying: &#8220;We thank President Trump for his leadership and proactive role for peace in the region. Pakistan appreciates the United States for facilitating this outcome, which we have accepted in the interest of regional peace and stability.&rdquo;</p>



<p>By contrast, the Indian government did not mention U.S. involvement in the mediation talks. &#8220;India and Pakistan was worked out directly between the two countries,&#8221;<a href="https://x.com/mib_india/status/1921182932900729179?s=46"  target="_blank"> a statement read</a>.</p>



<p>Pakistan&rsquo;s announcement of its intentions regarding a nomination came as Trump posted on Truth Social about the Nobel Peace Prize when commenting on his international mediating.</p>



<p>Within <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114717932061341718"  target="_blank">that social media post,</a> Trump took credit for &ldquo;stopping the war&rdquo; between India and Pakistan.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I won&rsquo;t get a Nobel Peace Prize for stopping the war between India and Pakistan. I won&rsquo;t get a Nobel Peace Prize for stopping the war between Serbia and Kosovo. I won&rsquo;t get a Nobel Peace Prize for keeping peace between Egypt and Ethiopia,&#8221; Trump claimed.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" > A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>Pakistan&rsquo;s Nobel Peace Prize recommendation occurred just one day before Trump authorized the U.S. to strike three nuclear weapons bases in Iran, joining the Israeli conflict.</p>



<p>&#8220;Congratulations to our great American Warriors. There is not another military in the World that could have done this. NOW IS THE TIME FOR PEACE!,&#8221; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114724035571020048"  target="_blank">Trump said</a> late on Saturday night, as he announced the military action.</p>



<p>The Government of Pakistan, which shares a 560-mile border with Iran, spoke out on Sunday in condemnation of the strikes, <a href="https://x.com/GovtofPakistan/status/1936798288121934254"  target="_blank">calling them </a>a serious violation of international law and the IAEA Statute.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Pakistan reified its support of &ldquo;Iran&rsquo;s right to self-defence,&rdquo; but also urged that diplomacy is the only path forward. Still, Pakistan&rsquo;s alliance with Iran throws into doubt the country&rsquo;s intention to nominate Trump for the prestigious Nobel Peace Prize. </p>



<p>The Pakistani government has yet to publicly comment or retract its post announcing the nomination. But prominent figures have spoken out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Upon learning of the U.S. strikes, Maleeha Lodhi, the former Pakistan ambassador to the United States, <a href="https://x.com/LodhiMaleeha/status/1936749561608908962"  target="_blank">said the Pakistani government</a> &ldquo;should be ashamed of this ill-conceived move. It should now have the decency to revoke that decision.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Allama Raja Nasir, a member of the Pakistani Senate, had <a href="https://x.com/AllamaRajaNasir/status/1936296212308632010"  target="_blank">originally called the nomination</a> a &ldquo;deeply misguided and ethically hollow decision.&rdquo; He <a href="https://x.com/AllamaRajaNasir/status/1936593075763040264"  target="_blank">doubled down</a> on his stance after the strikes.</p>



<p>&ldquo;To now authorize such a devastating attack on a neighboring country while simultaneously praising his actions as efforts toward &lsquo;peace&rsquo; exposes a stark and troubling contradiction,&rdquo; Nasir said of Trump.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296429/pakistan-nominate-trump-nobel-peace-prize-win-india-conflict/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Down Trump&#8217;s Public Rebuke of Tulsi Gabbard&#8217;s Statement on Iran—and Her Response</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296421/trump-public-rebuke-tulsi-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapon-statement/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296421/trump-public-rebuke-tulsi-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapon-statement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 18:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trump told reporters that his Director of National Intelligence, Tulsi Gabbard, was "wrong" regarding her testimony in March.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296421"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296421/trump-public-rebuke-tulsi-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapon-statement/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2168360424.jpg" alt="US-VOTE-POLITICS-TRUMP"/>



<p>Ahead of launching <a href="https://time.com/7296469/u-s-strikes-iran-nuclear-trump-war/" >U.S. strikes at three Iranian nuclear sites</a>, President Donald Trump had said that his Director of National Intelligence, Tulsi Gabbard, was &#8220;wrong&#8221; to say that Iran is not currently building a <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >nuclear weapon</a>.</p>



<p>When asked about the claims made by his intelligence community, specifically Gabbard, Trump was clear, telling reporters on Friday: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/reel/1096464402326812/"  target="_blank">&ldquo;She&rsquo;s wrong.&rdquo;</a></p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>In March, Gabbard testified in front of Congress that the intelligence community [IC] &ldquo;continues to assess that Iran is not building a nuclear weapon, and Supreme Leader [Ali] Khamenei has not authorized the nuclear weapons program that he suspended in 2003. The IC continues to monitor, closely, if Tehran decides to reauthorize its nuclear weapons program.&#8221;</p>



<p>The testimony resurfaced as Trump weighed his options regarding U.S. involvement in <a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >the Israel-Iran conflict</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296512/iran-responds-united-states-strikes-trump-nuclear-sites-warning/" >Iran Delivers Furious Warning, Speaks of &lsquo;Unprecedented Level of Danger and Chaos&rsquo; After &lsquo;Heinous&rsquo; U.S. Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s latest comments echo those he made to reporters on Air Force One on June 17, when he said he did not &ldquo;care&rdquo; about what Gabbard had testified earlier in the year.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t care what she said, I think they were very close to having one,&rdquo;<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/06/17/politics/video/trump-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapons-collins-digvid"  target="_blank"> Trump said</a> of his belief that Iran was inching towards having a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Central to Trump&rsquo;s stance regarding Israel&rsquo;s initial assault on Iran is his belief that Iran has been <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_AMw2CUzwZ8"  target="_blank">moving closer to nuclear capability</a>. He plainly said that &ldquo;Iran cannot have a nuclear weapon.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s stance, bolstered by a <a href="https://www.iaea.org/sites/default/files/25/06/gov2025-25.pdf"  target="_blank">May 31 International Atomic Energy Agency report</a> (that stated Iran had accumulated roughly 120 kg of uranium enriched to 60%, dangerously close to weapons-grade levels of 90%), undermines previous reports by U.S. intelligence, including that of Gabbard, a former Democrat.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" ><em>How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</em></a></p>



<p>In response to Trump&rsquo;s new assertion that she was &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; in her previous testimony, Gabbard <a href="https://x.com/DNIGabbard/status/1936174674595008517"  target="_blank">took to social media</a> on Friday, stating that her words had been taken out of context by &#8220;dishonest media.&#8221; Gabbard maintains that she and Trump are on the same page.</p>



<p>&#8220;The dishonest media is intentionally taking my testimony out of context and spreading fake news as a way to manufacture division,&#8221; Gabbard said. &#8220;America has intelligence that Iran is at the point that it can produce a nuclear weapon within weeks to months, if they decide to finalize the assembly. President Trump has been clear that can&#8217;t happen, and I agree.&#8221;</p>



<p>Attached to the post was a longer video of her testimony, which also included her claims that &ldquo;Iran&rsquo;s enriched uranium stockpile is at its highest levels and is unprecedented for a state without nuclear weapons.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" >&lsquo;Gravely Alarmed&rsquo; World Leaders React After U.S. Strikes Iran</a></em></p>



<p>Trump reportedly still has &ldquo;full confidence&rdquo; in his intelligence team, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/17/gabbard-trump-00411685"  target="_blank">according to</a> White House communications director Steven Cheung, but the open disagreements between Trump and members of his Administration signal splinters over the Israel-Iran conflict.</p>



<p>The President faced questions from both within and outside the Republican party, as he weighed up his options about whether the <a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >U.S. would intervene</a> in the conflict, despite him campaigning on staying out of wars overseas. Following the U.S. strikes, leaders outside of the U.S. have spoken out, with some expressing they are &#8220;<a href="https://time.com/7296530/united-states-strikes-iran-world-leaders-react/" >gravely alarmed</a>&#8221; by the escalation. Meanwhile, Gabbard&mdash;in an apparent show of support&mdash;reposted Trump&#8217;s announcement about the U.S. strikes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296421/trump-public-rebuke-tulsi-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapon-statement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296421</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Issues New Grave Warning, Says U.S. Involvement in Israel Conflict Would Be &#8216;Very Dangerous for Everybody&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296396/iran-new-warning-trump-united-states-israel-conflict-dangerous/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296396/iran-new-warning-trump-united-states-israel-conflict-dangerous/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Schneid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 14:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["That would be very, very dangerous for everybody," Iran’s Foreign Minister said.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296396"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296396/iran-new-warning-trump-united-states-israel-conflict-dangerous/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220501172.jpg" alt="51st Meeting of the Council of Foreign Ministers of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation"/>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi warned on Saturday that <a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >if the U.S. were to get involved</a> in <a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >the Israel-Iran conflict</a>, the result would be &ldquo;very, very dangerous&rdquo; for everybody.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The tweets, interviews by the U.S. President, [it&rsquo;s] quite clear that he&#8217;s talking about the U.S. leadership on these questions [of a potential U.S. involvement],&rdquo; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXJEX4aWZ0E"  target="_blank">Araghchi told reporters</a>. &ldquo;Unfortunately, we have heard that the U.S. may join in this aggression. That would be very unfortunate and I think that would be very, very dangerous for everybody.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Araghchi also claimed that Iran has &ldquo;many indications&rdquo; that the U.S. has been involved in Israel&rsquo;s bombardments of Iran since &ldquo;day one.&rdquo;</p>



<p>These remarks come amid uncertainty and debate as to the potential U.S. involvement in the conflict and what that might look like moving forward. </p>



<p>Several U.S. Air Force B-2 bombers appeared to have taken off from the Whiteman Air Force Base in Missouri in the United States and were headed across the Pacific, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/21/world/iran-israel-trump/heres-the-latest?smid=url-share"  target="_blank">according to reporting</a> from the New York <em>Times</em> on Saturday citing flight tracker <a href="https://x.com/AircraftSpots/status/1936351184257953906"  target="_blank">data</a>. Military equipment is often moved from one base to another, and it&#8217;s not always indicative of an impending strike. TIME has reached out to the White House for comment and further information.</p>



<p>Trump, who has said that the U.S. has not been involved in the Israeli strikes thus far, has given himself <a href="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" >two weeks </a>to make the decision as to whether the U.S. will strike on Iran.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Based on the fact that there&#8217;s a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not take place with Iran in the near future, I will make my decision whether or not to go within the next two weeks,&rdquo; said Trump, in a statement delivered by the White House press secretary Karoline Leavitt on Thursday. Leavitt went on to add that &ldquo;if there&#8217;s a chance for diplomacy, the President&#8217;s always going to grab it, but he&#8217;s not afraid to use strength as well.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S. and Iran had long been engaged in talks, in the hope of reaching a nuclear deal. </p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</a></em></p>



<p>Officials from both countries were set to meet in Oman&#8217;s capital of Muscat last weekend for the next round of nuclear discussions. But <a href="https://x.com/badralbusaidi/status/1933909335291428917"  target="_blank">Oman&#8217;s Foreign Minister Badr Albusaidi announced</a> that, in light of the Israel-Iran active conflict, those talks would no longer be going ahead. This came after state television reported that Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Ministry spokesman Esmail Baghaei called nuclear talks with the U.S. &ldquo;meaningless.&rdquo; </p>



<p>While Trump has called for Iran to return to the table, Iranian officials appear to be reluctant.</p>



<p>&ldquo;In order for us to come back to diplomacy, the aggression should be stopped,&rdquo; Araghchi said on Saturday. &ldquo;I cannot go to negotiation with the United States when our people are under bombardment, under the support of the United States.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump has stated multiple times in the first months of his second term that a deal with Iran would have to include a ban on the nation enriching uranium&mdash;something that would allow them to produce nuclear weapons.</p>



<p>He has also called for something more permanent than a cease-fire.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We&#8217;re looking for better than a cease-fire,&rdquo; Trump told reporters on Air Force One on June 17 as he left the G7 summit. &ldquo;A real end, not a cease-fire. An end&hellip; giving up, entirely.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump later doubled down on his view of what Iran should do via a post on his social media platform, Truth Social, writing: &ldquo;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699621000737127"  target="_blank">UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER</a>!&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >Here Are the Top Iranian Generals and Scientists Targeted and Killed by Israeli Strikes</a></em></p>



<p>However, Trump has delivered cryptic responses when asked exactly if and how the U.S. might get involved in the Middle Eastern conflict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Wednesday, when asked if the U.S. is &ldquo;moving closer&rdquo; to striking Iranian nuclear facilities, Trump said: &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble. They want to negotiate. I said, &lsquo;Why didn&rsquo;t you negotiate with me before? All this death and destruction.&#8217;&rdquo;</p>



<p>He later <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9jKFpRokJ4"  target="_blank">said in the Oval Office</a>: &#8220;I like to make the final decision one second before it&#8217;s due, because things change, especially with war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Araghchi&rsquo;s new warning is the latest in a long line of stern words and threats from Iranian officials in regards to a potential U.S. involvement in the current combat.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<em><a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" > Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Calls Out Trump, Threatens &lsquo;Irreparable Damage&rsquo; If U.S. Joins Israeli Conflict </a></em></p>



<p>On Wednesday, Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >Ali Khamenei threatened &ldquo;irreparable damage&rdquo;</a> if the U.S. joins the Israeli conflict.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Americans should know that any U.S. military intervention will undoubtedly be accompanied by irreparable damage,&rdquo; Khamenei said in a televised address. &ldquo;The U.S. entering in this matter [war] is 100% to its own detriment. The damage it will suffer will be far greater than any harm that Iran may encounter.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Israel-Iran conflict has entered its ninth day<strong> </strong>and shows no signs of slowing down.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s<a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" > initial strikes on Iran</a>, conducted in the early hours of June 13, targeted multiple nuclear and military sites, amid rising concerns of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the strikes, part of Operation Rising Lion, &ldquo;would continue for as many days as it takes to remove this threat.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iran followed through on its promise to retaliate, and the rivals have been trading deadly missiles and threats since, with the <a href="https://dppa.un.org/en/mtg-sc-9939-usg-dicarlo-20-jun-2025"  target="_blank">reported death tolls</a> in both countries rising as a result.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296396/iran-new-warning-trump-united-states-israel-conflict-dangerous/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296396</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Poland&#8217;s Next President Will Boost the Far Right</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295966/poland-president-nawrocki-populist/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295966/poland-president-nawrocki-populist/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian Bremmer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The populist Karol Nawrocki, a historian with no political experience, takes office on Aug. 6. The country must buckle up for a bumpy ride.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295966"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295966/poland-president-nawrocki-populist/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2217527739.jpg" alt="POLAND-POLITICS-VOTE"/>



<p>The presidential election in Poland delivered the latest anti-incumbent surprise in what has been a tough period for establishment candidates the world over. The right-wing populist Karol Nawrocki, a historian with no political experience, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx27897vedno"  target="_blank">won a narrow victory</a> in a June 1 run-off vote over a candidate aligned with the centrist <a href="https://time.com/6965195/donald-tusk/" >Prime Minister Donald Tusk</a> and his plans for closer European integration. Nawrocki will take office on Aug. 6. Tusk must now buckle up for a bumpy ride.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>With a presidential veto, Nawrocki will halt Tusk&rsquo;s bid to liberalize abortion law and to overhaul a courts system packed with judges politically aligned with the previous far-right government led by the Law and Justice Party (PiS), a change demanded by the European Union. But Nawrocki won&rsquo;t just block Tusk&rsquo;s reform plans. He&rsquo;ll also work to exploit potential divisions within Tusk&rsquo;s four-party governing coalition, particularly among lawmakers in the conservative Polish People&rsquo;s Party, still the weakest link in Tusk&rsquo;s alliance. </p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/poland-abortion-laws-protest/" >Polish Women Fight Back Against Restrictive Abortion Laws</a></em></p>



<p>In fact, the one-point presidential election loss for his ally Rafal Trzaskowski leaves Prime Minister Tusk as a lame duck, and it underlines the growing frustration of many Poles with a rising cost of living and the now long-term presence of up to 2.5 million <a href="https://time.com/6234536/ukrainian-refugees-russia-ireland-poland/" >Ukrainian refugees</a> across the country. While support for Ukraine&rsquo;s defense and fear and loathing of Russia span most of Poland&rsquo;s political spectrum, a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-14/eu-s-biggest-eastern-economies-struggle-as-german-pull-falters"  target="_blank">sluggish economy</a> leaves many feeling Ukrainians should return home. A recent survery by Poland&#8217;s Centre for Public Opinion Research found that support for accepting Ukrainian refugees <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/clygv2dj78zo"  target="_blank">dropped from 81% in early 2023 to just 50%</a> in March. Nawrocki&rsquo;s ability to block Tusk&rsquo;s agenda will leave more voters fed up with Tusk&rsquo;s government, boosting right and far-right parties ahead of parliamentary elections in 2027.</p>



<p>It hasn&rsquo;t been all bad news for Tusk. He comfortably <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/tusk-survives-confidence-vote-poland-pm-parliament-nawrocki/"  target="_blank">survived a no-confidence vote</a> on June 11. He&rsquo;ll now make changes to the government itself, and focus only on the more broadly popular policies. Tusk will likely downsize the number of ministries, particularly for economic management, and placate key coalition partners with important new jobs. His government will prioritize social policies and new subsidies to take some of the edge off voters anxieties over Poland&rsquo;s economy, push plans to make housing more affordable, and avoid policies they know the new President will veto. Tusk&rsquo;s party will also try to undercut the right&rsquo;s hold on anti-immigration sentiment by focusing on border protection tougher laws. Even before the election, Tusk pushed through a <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c8719dl587zo"  target="_blank">temporary suspension</a> of the right to asylum, bringing his government closer to the anti-immigrant positions of the far-right.</p>



<p>But these are coping tactics, not a roadmap to winning the next elections. Its political base expects Tusk&rsquo;s Civic Platform party to loosen <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/07/polish-abortion-centre-opens-strict-laws-warsaw"  target="_blank">abortion restrictions</a>. (Since 2021, Polish law permit abortion only in cases of rape, incest, or the serious threat to a woman&rsquo;s life or health.) His supporters also want him to restore rule of law in the country after the previous PiS government undermined the independence of some of Poland&rsquo;s political institutions. But &ldquo;elections have consequences,&rdquo; as Dick Cheney, the U.S. Vice President now in the political wilderness, once said. Nawrocki will use the powers of the presidency to undermine Tusk on the European stage. He can&rsquo;t make foreign or security policy, but he can use his political alignment with <a href="https://time.com/7200212/person-of-the-year-2024-donald-trump/" >Donald Trump</a> and Hungary&rsquo;s Prime Minister Viktor Orban, as well as criticism of E.U. conformity, to remind leaders across Europe that Poland remains a polarized place and a shaky long-term bet for closer alignment with the bloc&#8217;s policies and political values. </p>



<p>In particular, support for neighboring Ukraine and its European aspirations will face new hurdles. Though Nawrocki supports Ukraine&rsquo;s war effort, he <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/polands-new-president-poses-challenge-eu-ukraine-ties-2025-06-02/"  target="_blank">opposes</a> E.U. and NATO membership for Ukraine and will push for cuts to benefits to Ukrainian refugees still in Poland. The new President won&rsquo;t have the power to create policy himself, but his willingness to criticize increasingly unpopular pro-Ukraine measures will make life much more difficult&mdash;for Ukrainians and for Tusk. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295966/poland-president-nawrocki-populist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295966</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>European Leaders Seek Diplomacy in Talks With Iran as Trump Weighs Strike</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 18:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European ministers met with an Iranian delegation in Geneva in hopes of reaching an agreement over the conflict between Israel and Iran.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296249"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/abbas-araghchi-un-speech-june20.jpg" alt="Iran's Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi News Conference"/>



<p>Officials from Europe met with their Iranian counterparts on Friday in hopes of reaching a diplomatic solution to the <a href="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" >ongoing conflict between Iran and Israel</a>, even as attacks continued.</p>



<p>U.K. <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4ve5mo001g3b6ncvzid95c"  target="_blank">Foreign Secretary David Lammy</a> said ahead of the meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, that a &ldquo;window now exists&rdquo; to end the crisis.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>After the talks concluded with no apparent breakthrough, Lammy <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/06/20/world/israel-iran-trump"  target="_blank">said</a> European ministers were &ldquo;keen to continue ongoing discussions and negotiations with Iran,&rdquo; and urged the country to continue talks with the U.S.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is a perilous moment,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;and it is hugely important that we don&rsquo;t see regional escalation of this conflict.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Lammy, French Foreign Minister Jean-No&euml;l Barrot, German Foreign Minister Johann Wadephul, and High Representative of the European Union Kaja Kallas said in a joint <a href="https://www.eeas.europa.eu/eeas/statement-ministers-foreign-affairs-france-germany-and-united-kingdom-together-high-representative-0_en"  target="_blank">statement</a> that they had &ldquo;reiterated their longstanding concerns&rdquo; about Iran&#8217;s nuclear program to their Iranian counterpart and &ldquo;discussed avenues towards a negotiated solution.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The good result today is that we leave the room with the impression that the Iranian side is ready to further discuss all the important questions,&rdquo; Wadephul <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250620-europe-powers-urge-iran-to-keep-up-diplomacy-despite-israeli-strikes"  target="_blank">said</a>. He stressed that the U.S. taking part in negotiations &ldquo;is of great importance.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2025/6/20/live-iran-israel-continue-missile-fire-irans-fm-to-meet-eu-counterparts"  target="_blank">told reporters</a> after the talks that &ldquo;Iran is ready to consider diplomacy once again&mdash;once the aggression is stopped and the aggressor is held accountable for the crimes committed.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Added uncertainty was cast on the possibility of reaching an agreement on Friday when Iran launched a fresh barrage of missile strikes on targets in <a href="https://mdauk.org/mda-on-highest-level-of-alert-june-2025/"  target="_blank">the south of Israel</a>, and on the <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4tecad000r3b6nlmk588i8"  target="_blank">northern city of Haifa</a>.</p>



<p>The attacks came after the Israel Defense Forces <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1935946673454268771"  target="_blank">said that it struck</a> a number of military targets in Iran overnight, including facilities used for missile manufacturing. The Israeli military says it has now destroyed around <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc50rnyk001g3b6ok4msle8a"  target="_blank">half of Iran&rsquo;s missile launchers</a>, as well as killing <a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" >a number of military personnel</a> since last week.</p>



<p>President Donald Trump has also been weighing whether to launch a military strike on Iran. He is <a href="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" >expected to make a decision</a> within two weeks, Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt said on Thursday, reading a statement from Trump in which the President said &ldquo;there&rsquo;s a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not take place with Iran in the near future.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The U.S. and Iran have been engaged in protracted talks over a possible nuclear deal for the past two months, but a scheduled round of negotiations was cancelled after Israeli strikes began. &ldquo;There is no room for negotiations with the U.S. until Israeli aggression stops,&rdquo; Araghchi <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2025/06/20/iran-israel-trump-ceasefire-nuclear-talks-live-updates/84283929007/"  target="_blank">reportedly said</a> while speaking on Iranian state TV earlier on Friday. </p>



<p>Before negotiations in Geneva began, French President Emmanuel Macron said while talking to reporters in Paris that &ldquo;Iran must show that it is willing to join the platform for negotiations we are putting on the table.&rdquo;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/c994v4gm9jmt?post=asset%3A2acb7df0-7d65-48c4-b9e4-9d4810afc294#post"  target="_blank">Macron outlined</a> particular focus points of the discussions, which included working towards zero uranium enrichment in Iran, the oversight of Iranian ballistic missiles, Iranian funding of proxy groups in the Middle East, and the release of foreign nationals in Iranian prisons.</p>



<p>As negotiations took place, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-conflict-06-20-25-intl-hnk#cmc4tmjm900003b6o4kycyba9"  target="_blank">a spokesperson for Iran&rsquo;s Presidency</a> said: &ldquo;Iran believes in civilian dialogue &hellip; Directly or indirectly is not important.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The spokesperson, Majid Farahani, added: &ldquo;President Trump can easily stop the war by only one telephone [call] to [the] Israelis.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Macron and Trump exchanged barbs earlier in the week after Trump departed the G7 summit early as the conflict between Iran and Israel mounted.</p>



<p>Trump called the French President &ldquo;publicity seeking&rdquo; after Macron <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/world/europe/trump-macron-israel-iran-ukraine.html"  target="_blank">told press</a> that the U.S. had assured &ldquo;they will find a cease-fire, and since they can pressure Israel, things may change.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;President Emmanuel Macron, of France, mistakenly said that I left the G7 Summit, in Canada, to go back to D.C. to work on a &lsquo;cease fire&rsquo; between Israel and Iran,&rdquo; Trump said in a post on Truth Social. &ldquo;Wrong! He has no idea why I am now on my way to Washington, but it certainly has nothing to do with a Cease Fire. Much bigger than that.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s latest stance on direct U.S. involvement comes after <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >some uncertainty earlier this week</a>, during which the President said: &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&rdquo; when asked if he was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Iranian Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935303824325108208"  target="_blank">warned</a> on Wednesday that &ldquo;the harm the US will suffer will definitely be irreparable if they enter this conflict militarily.&rdquo;</p>



<p>European officials began talks with Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi at around 4 p.m. local time (11 a.m. ET) on Friday. Before talks began, Araghchi addressed the United Nations Security Council, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/c994v4gm9jmt?post=asset%3A748632d5-7c1b-417e-abf2-ba850e2c8108#post"  target="_blank">calling</a> last week&rsquo;s initial attack from Israel as &#8220;an outrageous act of aggression&#8221; and a &#8220;stark violation of the U.N. charter&#8221; in his remarks.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s Ambassador to the U.N. Daniel Meron <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-slams-un-rights-council-giving-floor-iran-ahead-nuclear-talks-2025-06-20/"  target="_blank">criticized the body</a> for allowing Araghchi the floor at the meeting, saying in a letter addressed to council president Jurg Lauber, &#8220;Affording the Iranian foreign minister the floor before this body continues to undermine the council&#8217;s credibility and constitutes a blatant betrayal of the many victims of this regime worldwide.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israeli foreign minister Gideon Sa&rsquo;ar was dismissive of the talks in Geneva in an interview on Friday. &ldquo;All diplomatic efforts until now were not successful,&rdquo; he <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/israel-rejects-diplomacy-iran-europeans-tehran-geneva-gideon-saar-middle-east-donald-trump-eu/"  target="_blank">said</a>. &ldquo;They usually use these talks in order to deceive, in order to waste time.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296249/iran-israel-europe-talks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296249</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
