<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:38:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Trump to Decide &#8216;Within Two Weeks&#8217; Whether to Take Action on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Simmone Shah]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt told reporters the President will see through negotiations before deciding whether to strike.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module ad-300-250"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296098"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-iran.jpg" alt="IRAN-ISRAEL-CONFLICT-STRIKE"/>



<p>President Donald Trump will make a decision within two weeks on whether to strike on Iran, Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt told reporters during a press briefing on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reading a statement from Trump, Leavitt said, &ldquo;Based on the fact that there&rsquo;s a substantial chance of negotiations that may or may not take place with Iran in the near future, I will make my decision whether or not to go within the next two weeks.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The President&rsquo;s deadline comes amid escalating strikes between Iran and Israel&mdash;and as the U.S. considers direct military action against Iran. On Wednesday, <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >when asked</a> if the U.S. was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities, Trump told reporters, &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The United States government maintains this fact that Iran has never been closer to obtaining a nuclear weapon,&rdquo; Leavitt went on to say. She noted that the President continues to be briefed by his National Security Council and remains in &ldquo;constant communication&rdquo; with the Israeli government and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>



<p>The attacks between the two countries began last Friday, when Israel launched what it called &ldquo;preemptive air strikes&rdquo; targeting more than a dozen sites in Iran. The <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/day-six-of-israeli-strikes-on-iran-an-overview-of-the-events/"  target="_blank">Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA) says</a> that since Israel&rsquo;s initial missile attack on Iran, 639 people have been killed there and a further 1,329 injured&mdash;the organization says that 263 of those killed were civilians and 154 military personnel. <a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">In Israel</a>, 24 people have been killed so far by Iranian strikes, with 838 injured.</p>



<p>On Thursday, an <a href="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" >Iranian missile strike</a> damaged a hospital in southern Israel, as part of a barrage of strikes Israel said injured 271 people.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" >Trump&rsquo;s base is divided</a> as he weighs his options, especially given that he campaigned on a <a href="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" >pledge of no new wars</a>.</p>



<p>The two-week timeline opens the door for negotiations, but does not negate the possibility of U.S. involvement. &ldquo;The president has made it clear he always wants to pursue diplomacy,&rdquo; Leavitt said. &ldquo;But believe me the president is unafraid to use strength if necessary.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296098/trump-iran-action-deadline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296098</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israeli Hospital Damaged by Iranian Airstrike as Missile Exchange Continues</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7296012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The strike on the hospital in the southern city of Beersheba has left over 70 injured according to Israel's Health Ministry.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7296012"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/nurse-soroka-hospital-israel-june19.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-ISRAEL-IRAN-CONFLICT"/>



<p>Seventy-one people have been &#8220;slightly injured&#8221; after an Iranian missile strike damaged a hospital in Southern Israel, according to the country&rsquo;s <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMOH/status/1935649625060368823"  target="_blank">health ministry</a>.</p>



<p>The strike on Soroka Medical Center, in the city of Beersheba, was part of a wider barrage from Iran, <a href="https://x.com/ariel_oseran/status/1935567014674018647"  target="_blank">hitting neighborhoods in Tel Aviv</a>, including Holon and Ramat Gan. Israel&rsquo;s <a href="https://x.com/IsraelMOH/status/1935649625060368823"  target="_blank">health ministry</a> has said that a total of 271 people were injured in the strikes, including those at Soroka, with four in serious condition.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said that Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, &ldquo;can no longer be allowed to exist,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/jun/19/israel-iran-conflict-live-hospital-in-southern-israel-hit-in-iran-missile-strike-say-israeli-officials?CMP=share_btn_url&amp;page=with%3Ablock-6853e39e8f08a4f72f5f14a1#block-6853e39e8f08a4f72f5f14a1"  target="_blank">speaking to reporters</a> at the site of missile strikes in Holon.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Khamenei openly declares that he wants Israel destroyed&mdash;he personally gives the order to fire on hospitals. He considers the destruction of the state of Israel to be a goal,&rdquo; Katz said before threatening the Ayatollah.</p>



<p><a href="https://en.irna.ir/news/85866868/"  target="_blank">Iranian state media</a> has said that the strike in southern Israel targeted a military command and intelligence center near the hospital, and that the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-iran-war-latest-06-19-2025-14b868f4514a7c337d5b9859de130bf0"  target="_blank">blast from the strike</a> caused damage to the medical center, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-iran-war-latest-06-19-2025-14b868f4514a7c337d5b9859de130bf0"  target="_blank">The Associated Press reported</a>.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Israel has launched a series of its own missile attacks on Iran, targeting a nuclear reactor in Arak, nuclear facilities in Natanz, and ballistic missile sites, according to the <a href="https://x.com/IDF/status/1935583119320469744"  target="_blank">Israel Defense Forces</a>.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.en-hrana.org/day-six-of-israeli-strikes-on-iran-an-overview-of-the-events/"  target="_blank">Human Rights Activists News Agency (HRANA) says</a> that since Israel&rsquo;s initial missile attack on Iran, 639 people have been killed there and a further 1,329 injured.</p>



<p>HRANA reported on Thursday that 263 of these deaths have been confirmed as civilians and 154 as military personnel.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gov.il/en/pages/operation-rising-lion-update"  target="_blank">In Israel</a>, 24 people have been killed so far by Iranian strikes, with 838 injured.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Israel reacts to Iranian strike damaging hospital</strong></h2>



<p>Israeli government officials have responded to Thursday&rsquo;s strike on the hospital, with <a href="https://x.com/netanyahu/status/1935581234001809807"  target="_blank">Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying</a>, &ldquo;We will exact the full price from the tyrants in Tehran.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before his comments threatening Khamenei on Thursday morning, Katz said: &ldquo;The cowardly Iranian dictator sits in the depths of the fortified bunker and fires aimed shots at hospitals and residential buildings in Israel. These are war crimes of the most serious kind&mdash; and Khamenei will be held accountable for his crimes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Prime Minister and I have instructed the IDF to increase the intensity of attacks against strategic targets in Iran and against government targets in Tehran in order to remove threats to the State of Israel and undermine the ayatollahs&#8217; regime,&rdquo; Katz continued in <a href="https://x.com/Israel_katz/status/1935588198505173249"  target="_blank">a statement on social media</a>.</p>



<p>While visiting the damaged hospital in Beersheba, <a href="https://x.com/SkyNews/status/1935665849538424850"  target="_blank">Itimar Ben-Gvir</a>, Israel&rsquo;s Security Minister said: &ldquo;The regime of the ayatollahs needs to be annihilated.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is an historic moment, we have the opportunity to defeat the Iranian nukes, the Nazis, the ayatollahs, anyone who hates the state of Israel,&rdquo; he added.</p>



<p>Ben-Gvir has recently been in the spotlight after <a href="https://time.com/7292990/israel-ben-gvir-smotrich-sanctions-west-bank-gaza/" >he was sanctioned</a> by the British, Canadian, Australian, Norwegian and New Zealand governments for inciting violence against Palestinians in the West Bank. Israel&rsquo;s Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich also faces the same sanctions, including a travel ban and the freezing of all assets in those countries.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The question of U.S. involvement in the conflict continues</strong></h2>



<p>On Thursday,&nbsp; while visiting the Soroka Medical Center, Netanyahu was asked about potential U.S. involvement in the conflict with Iran. He said: &ldquo;President Trump will do what&#8217;s best for America. I trust his judgment, he is a tremendous friend, a tremendous world leader, a tremendous friend of Israel.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Donald Trump has been considering direct U.S. military action against Iran in recent days. On Wednesday, he told reporters, &ldquo; I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble,&rdquo; <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >when asked</a> if the U.S. was moving closer to striking Iranian nuclear facilities.</p>



<p>Iranian leader Khamenei issued a grave warning to the U.S. earlier on Wednesday, saying, &ldquo;The Americans should know that any U.S. military intervention will undoubtedly be accompanied by irreparable damage,&rdquo; during a public address.</p>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7295939/russia-iran-israel-us-war-nuclear-catastrophe-trump-putin-khamenei/" >Russia has also warned</a> about the consequences should President Trump decide to take action against Iran. Kremlin spokesperson <a href="https://tass.com/politics/1976159"  target="_blank">Dmitry Peskov</a> told Russian state media U.S. intervention would mar &ldquo;an expansion in the conflict&#8217;s geography. We are hearing from Tehran that this could lead to another dangerous escalation.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7296012/israeli-hospital-damaged-iran-airstrike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7296012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exclusive: Iranian Nobel Laureate Narges Mohammadi Calls for Israel-Iran Ceasefire</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman and Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The renowned rights advocate called on other Nobel Peace Prize winners to amplify the call for an end to the Israel-Iran war.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295994"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/narges-mohammadi.jpg" alt="Narges-Mohammadi-Iranian-Human-Rights-Activist"/>



<p>Iranian Nobel Peace Prize laureate <a href="https://time.com/6965015/narges-mohammadi-2024/" >Narges Mohammadi</a> has long fought for freedom and human rights, even at the expense of her own. With her country now at <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >war with Israel</a>, Mohammadi called on her fellow activists to band together and call for a ceasefire.</p>



<p>In an exclusive message to TIME from Iran, Mohammadi said that the outbreak of war, which began in the early morning of <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >June 13</a>, has forced millions of Iranians to leave their homes and caused damages to &ldquo;critical national infrastructure,&rdquo; compounding an economic crisis its citizens already bore the brunt of. Mohammadi herself has <a href="https://x.com/nargesfnd/status/1935140081116807410"  target="_blank">left Tehran</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;The scale of destruction already resembles that of a months-long conflict,&rdquo; Mohammadi writes.</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" ><em>A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</em></a></p>



<p>Mohammadi was <a href="https://time.com/6321287/narges-mohammadi-nobel-peace-prize/" >awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2023</a> for her women&rsquo;s rights advocacy in Iran. She is known for helping imprisoned activists, leading a campaign against the death penalty, and openly criticizing the Iranian regime&rsquo;s use of torture and sexualized violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has been arrested several times for her work, and sentenced to more than 36 years. Mohammadi was in prison when she became the Nobel Prize recipient in 2023, but she was furloughed in December 2024 for <a href="https://time.com/7159230/imprisoned-nobel-laureate-narges-mohammadi-fights-for-life-iran/" >medical reasons</a>.</p>



<p>Mohammadi called on other Nobel laureates &ldquo;to use all your individual, collective, and institutional capacities to amplify the call of &lsquo;No to War&rsquo; and support our urgent plea for a ceasefire and an end to this war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Earlier, Mohammadi told the BBC that she could possibly return to prison for speaking publicly against the war, but she said she&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/live/cx23e4jz2g0t?post=asset%3Aaffaf574-f769-4ec2-804e-e9c1af795eac#post"  target="_blank">not worried</a>.&rdquo; Mohammadi, alongside fellow Nobel laureate Shirin Ehbadi and other prominent Iranian voices, <a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/opinion/article/2025/06/16/israel-iran-this-conflict-poses-a-grave-threat-to-the-very-foundations-of-human-civilization_6742387_23.html"  target="_blank">wrote an op-ed</a> earlier this week demanding a halt to Iran&rsquo;s uranium enrichment program and an end to the attacks.</p>



<p>Israel launched an attack on Iran saying it intends to stop the country from achieving the capability of producing a nuclear weapon. Hundreds are believed to have been killed in the strikes on Iran, which has retaliated by firing missiles into Israel, killing at least 24.</p>



<p>Read Mohammadi&rsquo;s full statement below.</p>



<hr/>



<p><em>To the Nobel Peace Prize Laureates, Human Rights Orgs, people of the world peace lovers,</em></p>



<p><em>I urge you to take action to stop the war between Israel and the Islamic Republic of Iran.</em></p>



<p><em>Six days have passed since the beginning of this horrific war. The violence is accelerating at a devastating pace, and the scale of destruction already resembles that of a months-long conflict.</em></p>



<p><em>The growing fear that Israel may attack the Islamic Republic&rsquo;s nuclear facilities adds terrifying uncertainty to the war. Millions of Iranian citizens have fled their homes. Amid crushing economic hardship and soaring inflation, they are unable to afford basic daily expenses and have sought refuge in other cities.</em></p>



<p><em>The targeting of critical national infrastructure, the rising number of casualties, and the threat to evacuate the capital, Tehran, are deeply alarming.</em></p>



<p><em>I call on you&mdash;Nobel Peace Prize laureates&mdash;to use all your individual, collective, and institutional capacities to amplify the call of &ldquo;No to War&rdquo; and support our urgent plea for a ceasefire and an end to this war.</em></p>



<p><em>Let us rise together to form a united, global front for the right to peace. The scope of war expands by the day. Its fire will not remain confined to the lands directly involved&mdash;it will cross borders and engulf the entire world.</em></p>



<p><em>War casts a dark shadow over humanity&rsquo;s future&mdash;a darkness that cannot easily be erased from the eyes of humankind.</em></p>



<p><em>Let us stand together&mdash;loudly, clearly&mdash;for peace and for an end to war.</em></p>



<p><em>I demand an immediate halt to the war and the declaration of a ceasefire.</em></p>



<p><em>&mdash; Narges Mohammadi</em></p>



<p><em>18th June 2025</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295994/narges-mohammadi-israel-iran-ceasefire-nobel-peace-prize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Iran&#8217;s Nuclear Program Goes From Here</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The incentive to bury its nuclear program even deeper is stronger than ever]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295632"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/fate-of-iran-nuclear-01.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>Deep beneath the Zagros Mountains in central Iran, in a labyrinth of fortified tunnels outside the city of Natanz, centrifuges spun at speeds too fast for the eye to track. The cascade of machines, arranged in long halls and shielded by concrete and steel, have been central to Iran&rsquo;s most sensitive nuclear work, and, until recently, largely immune to airstrikes. But this month Israeli warplanes penetrated Iranian airspace and struck multiple nuclear sites, including underground facilities thought to be untouchable.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>While the full extent of the damage remains murky, satellite imagery and initial damage assessments by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) indicate that the strikes on Iran&rsquo;s Natanz nuclear facility were particularly effective, knocking out the electricity to the underground area.</p>



<p>The Israeli strikes also blew up the uneasy nuclear status quo that existed in the Middle East for years while raising a daunting question: What happens if Iran decides that the only true deterrent is to build a bomb?</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>For over a decade, Tehran has operated just below the threshold of nuclear breakout capability. But this spring it abandoned that restraint. The IAEA reported in May that Iran had accumulated roughly 120 kg of uranium enriched to 60%&mdash;&shy;dangerously close to weapons-grade levels of 90%&mdash;and enough to build 22 nuclear bombs within five months if further enriched. At the same time, Iran began building a third enrichment hall on top of the two already in use. U.S. officials saw it as a provocation; Israel viewed it as a casus belli.</p>



<p>The military strikes Israel launched on June 13 were swift, surgical, and calibrated. Israeli officials described them as a pre-emptive operation to cripple Iran&rsquo;s ability to build a nuclear weapon by targeting its main enrichment sites, nuclear scientists, and military officials.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/fate-of-iran-nuclear-02.jpg" alt="" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>But while the strikes appear to have disrupted Iran&rsquo;s enrichment operations, it retains scientific expertise and stockpiled material, and now possesses a stronger incentive to bury its program even deeper. &ldquo;If Iran survives the conflict, they could decide that a nuclear weapon is the only way to have deterrence,&rdquo; says Alex Vatanka, a senior fellow at the Middle East Institute.</p>



<p>Iran could attempt a dash for a nuclear weapon at one of its remaining sites. One, at Fordo, is buried so deeply in mountains near the city of Qom that only the U.S.&rsquo;s most powerful bunker-busting bomb&mdash;the 30,000-lb. GBU-57&mdash;is believed capable of reaching it.</p>



<p>The threat underscores the collapse of diplomatic efforts to constrain Iran&rsquo;s program. &ldquo;Trying to get to a deal now is infinitely harder than it used to be,&rdquo; says Richard Nephew, who worked on Iran sanctions in the Obama Administration. Others are more hopeful about the outcome of the war. Says Matt Kroenig of the Atlantic Council: &ldquo;We were on the verge of Iran becoming a nuclear power and it looks like now we&rsquo;ve set that threat into the future.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295632</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Campaigned on Staying Out of Wars. Now He&#8217;s Changing His Tune on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Bennett]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's a hair-trigger situation and the stakes for America are high]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295729"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-troops-middle-east-03.jpg" alt="Trump troops"/>



<p>When President Donald Trump ducked out early from a meeting with G-7 nations in the Canadian mountain resort of Kananaskis on June 16, he said he needed to get back to Washington as strikes escalated between Israel and Iran. He didn&rsquo;t like relying on phone calls, he told reporters on Air Force One, and he wanted to be a &ldquo;little bit, I think, more well versed.&rdquo; For the normally freewheeling Trump, it was a sign of the gravity of the moment, a rare acknowledgement that he didn&rsquo;t have enough information to handle a hair-trigger situation.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>The stakes for America are high. Backed into a corner by Israel&rsquo;s surprisingly effective attack, Tehran could decide to turn its proxy terrorist forces against the U.S. in the region and beyond. The strategic rapprochement between Israel and Arab states hangs in the balance as conflict threatens to spread. More broadly, the outcome of the war could decide whether the U.S. commits another generation of troops to the Middle East, once again diverting American might from countering China&rsquo;s expansion in the Pacific.</p>



<p>At the same time, an Israeli defeat of Iran could open a <a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >new era</a> of Arab-Israeli cooperation, defang Tehran&rsquo;s regional militias, and deliver a blow to China, which had sought to bolster &shy;Tehran as a regional counterweight to the U.S. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve got this axis with Beijing at the core,&rdquo; argues Matthew Pottinger, former Deputy National Security Adviser during Trump&rsquo;s first term.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>The U.S. could tip the balance either way, but Trump is constrained in how he manages the conflict. It&rsquo;s been four years since the disastrous U.S. pullout from Afghanistan. Trump campaigned on not getting the U.S. into more wars, and some of the fiercest opposition to further entanglement is coming from his own MAGA base.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-troops-middle-east-02.jpg" alt="Afghanistan troops" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Trump has already beefed up the U.S. military presence around Israel and Iran, ordering another guided-missile destroyer to the waters off Israel and directing the U.S.S. <em>Nimitz</em> aircraft carrier and its strike group to change course in the Pacific and motor toward the Arabian Sea.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</a></em></p>



<p>Iran sits at one of the world&rsquo;s most important strategic crossroads. Nearly one-third of the world&rsquo;s crude-oil production passes through the Strait of Hormuz&mdash;and within 30 miles of Iran&rsquo;s coastline. Tanker ships have been warned to sail closer to the coast of Oman, on the western side of the strait. Amid the massive military mobilization, maritime alerts are warning shipping vessels that &ldquo;electronic interference&rdquo; could jam their navigation equipment.</p>



<p>For Trump, a direct Iranian attack on the U.S. would trigger a military response. Iran ordered an assassination attempt against Trump and tried to kill an Iranian-American journalist living in Brooklyn. &ldquo;The fact that they have been open in these threats tells me they don&rsquo;t believe they are facing credible retaliatory risk from the United States,&rdquo; Pottinger says. &ldquo;The Israeli strikes might inject some reality into their calculus. But Iranians have been known to miscalculate on many occasions.&rdquo;</p>



<p>After his return to Washington, Trump issued noticeably more hostile rhetoric. He called for Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;unconditional &shy;surrender&rdquo; and chastised its leaders for not taking talks more seriously. &ldquo;Why didn&rsquo;t you negotiate with me two weeks ago? You could have done fine. You would have had a country,&rdquo; he said. Now all bets are off for Iran, and the U.S.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Cortellessa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With dramatic appeals amid failed nuclear negotiations, Bibi laid the groundwork for Trump to back a war with Iran]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295726"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/how-bibi-won-over-trump-01.jpg" alt="Bibi Trump"/>



<p>Through a mixture of audacity, ruthlessness, and luck, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has upended the balance of power between Israel and Iran, its most threatening regional adversary, and <a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >remade the Middle East</a> in just 20 months. But his most important victory may prove to have been winning over President Donald J. Trump on the need to attack Tehran with the full force of the -Israeli military.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Netanyahu&rsquo;s success bringing Trump on board can be traced to a series of strategic decisions, according to two Israeli officials involved in talks between the two sides. The initial step came on Feb. 4, when the Israeli Premier visited the White House for the first time since Trump returned to office. Sitting around the long table in the Cabinet Room, Netanyahu reminded Trump that Iran had plotted to assassinate him, according to one of the officials who attended the meeting. He then went through a detailed slide deck outlining how, in his view, <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >Iran was inching closer</a> to crossing the nuclear threshold: increasing its stockpile of highly enriched uranium and advancing its centrifuge technology. &ldquo;Look, Donald,&rdquo; Netanyahu said, &ldquo;this has to be tackled, because they&rsquo;re racing forward.&rdquo; He then paused for dramatic effect and looked at Trump directly in the eye. &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t have a nuclear Iran on your watch.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It seemed to make an impression. But Trump was plainly not prepared to bless a direct Israeli attack on Iran. He said he wanted to try diplomacy first. He had been elected, after all, on the promise to end wars, not start them. And he had tapped his longtime friend, the real estate mogul Steve Witkoff, to broker a deal with Tehran. &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s go for talks,&rdquo; he told Netanyahu, according to the official who was present.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reluctantly, Netanyahu said he would give Trump the time and space to see if an agreement was possible. Eventually, Trump&rsquo;s team settled on a 60-day framework to solidify the contours of an accord. Israeli officials say that letting talks run to the deadline was crucial because when Iran blew past it, Trump became comfortable with Israel&rsquo;s proposed military plans. &ldquo;It proved to Trump that we have nobody to talk to,&rdquo; the official tells TIME, that &ldquo;it was a ruse on the part of the Iranians.&rdquo;</p>



<p>So say the Israelis. But Trump has yet to fully explain his <a href="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" >sharp shift in posture</a>, from determined dealmaker to potential participant in the attack on Tehran. The White House did not respond to repeated requests for comment.</p>



<p>Just weeks ago, Trump acknowledged that he had warned Netanyahu against military action while diplomacy continued. Yet as talks unfolded, Netanyahu was preparing plans for a full-scale attack on Iran&rsquo;s nuclear capabilities. He got some help along the way. On May 31, the International Atomic Energy Agency reported that Iran was <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >concealing its development of nuclear material</a>, a violation of a 2019 agreement with the agency. The Israelis then shared intelligence with Trump that they claimed showed that Iran was intentionally delaying talks to secretly acquire the parts for a nuclear arsenal, according to the Israeli officials. &ldquo;They were using these talks with Steve to advance to a point where they&rsquo;d be able to say, &lsquo;We&rsquo;re there, we&rsquo;re a day away,&rsquo;&rdquo; one official says.</p>



<p>Not all Americans were convinced. The U.S. intelligence agencies believed, as Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard told Congress in March, that Tehran had not decided to build a bomb. But once Trump&rsquo;s 60-day window had closed, the Israelis seized on the President&rsquo;s frustrations. Iran was on the cusp of being able to have a nuclear weapon in a matter of months, they said. The Israelis informed the Americans that they would strike Iranian targets in the early morning. Within hours, Iran struck back, killing three civilians in central Israel. But soon Israel managed to establish supremacy over Iran&rsquo;s airspace. &ldquo;In two days, we&rsquo;ve eliminated a third of their arsenal,&rdquo; says Mascha Michelson, an IDF spokesperson.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump officials say ideally Israel would force Tehran to return to the negotiating table and accept a permanent end to their nuclear program. Some of Trump&rsquo;s allies, including Stephen Bannon and Tucker Carlson, fear that Israel will drag the U.S. military into the conflict.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s endgame remains unknown. Netanyahu has said that his goal is not regime change but that it could happen. Even the Prime Minister&rsquo;s aides aren&rsquo;t sure what the final outcome will be, but they are preparing for more war. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s been a number of surprises that we pulled off,&rdquo; says one of the officials. &ldquo;There are probably some more surprises that we have up our sleeve.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Either way, it appears Netanyahu has succeeded in winning Trump over to his view of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear ambitions. When asked on June 17 about Gabbard&rsquo;s testimony, Trump responded, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t care what she said. I think they were very close.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295726</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Iran Became Isolated in the Middle East</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295480/iran-isolation-middle-east-strategy-failure/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295480/iran-isolation-middle-east-strategy-failure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lina Khatib]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Decades of proxy warfare and regional ambition have left Iran diplomatically alone—just as it faces a new conflict with Israel.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295480"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295480/iran-isolation-middle-east-strategy-failure/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2158978868.jpg" alt="TOPSHOT-IRAN-VOTE"/>



<p>It is a perilous moment for Iran. Israel has <a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" >gained control</a> of the skies. Much of the regime&rsquo;s top military command has been <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/13/middleeast/israel-iran-strikes-military-deaths-intl-hnk"  target="_blank">taken out</a>, to say nothing of the <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/middle-east/20250615-israel-and-iran-trade-strikes-for-a-third-day-as-hundreds-reported-dead"  target="_blank">civilian toll</a>. U.S. President Donald Trump is now <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/00996449-94bf-48d5-ad8c-21eef78a91f4"  target="_blank">calling</a> for an &ldquo;unconditional surrender.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Islamic Republic hopes it can convince the Gulf Arab states to tell the U.S. to pressure Israel to end its military campaign. But it is a lost cause. The regime has no true friends in the region&mdash;and it has itself to blame.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>For almost five decades, the ayatollahs have pursued an expansionist policy of &ldquo;exporting the revolution&rdquo; and &ldquo;forward defense.&rdquo; But what Iran thought was a winning strategy to consolidate long-term leadership in the Middle East has backfired.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s rise was based on exploiting issues like the Palestine question and the marginalization of Lebanon&rsquo;s Shi&lsquo;ites. Iran&rsquo;s model presented Tehran as a mentor and patron, incubating armed groups under the pretext of fighting just causes. In reality, Iran&rsquo;s proxies relied on the same oppressive behavior as that of the Tehran regime.</p>



<p>For years, Iran&rsquo;s strategy appeared to be working. Iran-backed groups became the strongest actors in their countries. The seeming success of Lebanese Hezbollah&mdash;the first proxy Iran nurtured&mdash;became a template for others in the Middle East.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" >A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</a></em></p>



<p>But the expansion of proxies created vulnerabilities for Iran and its assets. With no domestic space for critique, and the suppression of outside opponents, there were no checks on the regime&rsquo;s behavior. Tehran grew blind to its brittleness, believing that it could outmaneuver the U.S., Israel, the Arab countries, and the international community. This included negotiating an international nuclear deal while it was <a href="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" >enriching uranium</a> beyond the level necessary for civilian use and thinking it could withstand the consequences of <a href="https://time.com/6321849/israel-attack/" >Hamas&rsquo; Oct. 7, 2023 attack on Israel</a>.</p>



<p>Blindness also led Tehran to overestimate its friendship with Russia and China. Tehran saw Moscow as an ally when it intervened to <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-34416519"  target="_blank">prop up Syria&rsquo;s Assad regime</a> in 2015. But Russia saw instead an opportunity to grow its influence in that country, consolidate its <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c14nk475nd5o"  target="_blank">military presence on the Mediterranean</a>, and stand up to the West. Iran and China, for their part, struck a <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/3/27/iran-and-china-sign-25-year-cooperation-agreement-in-tehran"  target="_blank">25-year cooperation deal in 2021</a>. But what Tehran viewed as rising global sway, China saw as a limited economic pact. Beijing subsequently stalled the agreement&rsquo;s delivery.</p>



<p>Today, neither Russia nor China will come to Iran&rsquo;s rescue. Beijing has always avoided getting involved in Middle East conflicts, and remains focused on its Indo-Pacific backyard. Moscow is bogged down in Ukraine and is prioritizing the yearslong conflict there, which has only escalated in recent months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nor will Iran&rsquo;s proxies save it. Israel has <a href="https://time.com/7049289/hezbollah-israel-war/" >decapitated Hezbollah&rsquo;s leadership</a> and destroyed much of its missile arsenal, and the group would lose much of its remaining domestic support if it drags Lebanon into another war. The scale of the Houthis&rsquo; remaining arsenal in Yemen remains a mystery, following a monthslong campaign of U.S. airstrikes, but they are constrained by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/trump-says-us-will-stop-bombing-houthis-after-agreement-struck-2025-05-06/"  target="_blank">de-escalation deals</a> with Washington and Riyadh. Most of the Iran-backed Iraqi factions are also choosing self-preservation over involvement in an unwinnable battle with Israel and the U.S. Meanwhile, Syria has turned from a fertile ground to a hostile one for Iran and its assets, after the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/syria-rebels-celebrate-captured-homs-set-sights-damascus-2024-12-07/"  target="_blank">Assad regime was toppled</a> in December.</p>



<p>Israel has framed its war on Iran as a boost to regional and global stability. Both the U.S. and Israel want the mission achieved. And while the Arab Gulf states have pursued <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/20/world/middleeast/israel-saudi-arabia-iran-gulf.html"  target="_blank">rapprochement in recent years</a> with Iran, and are <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/13/middle-east-nations-call-for-urgent-de-escalation-after-israel-strikes-on-iran"  target="_blank">calling for de-escalation</a>, that is largely a symbolic gesture. They will ultimately not stand in the way of a new Middle East and a weakened Iran.</p>



<p>The regime, it seems, may be taking its last breaths, and has no one to turn to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295480/iran-isolation-middle-east-strategy-failure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A New Middle East Is Unfolding Before Our Eyes</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karl Vick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iran has spent most of this century as the region’s rising power.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295798"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/new-middle-east-israel-iran.jpg" alt=""/>



<p>It might be difficult to discern through the black clouds billowing from bomb craters in Tehran, but Iran has spent most of the 21st century as the region&rsquo;s rising power.</p>



<p>Until recently, things had really been going its way. In Iraq, the U.S. toppled Saddam Hussein, then departed, having turned Iran&rsquo;s largest and most dangerous neighbor from an enemy to a vassal even before Tehran&rsquo;s militias rescued Baghdad from ISIS, and then stayed. The forces Iran sent to Syria did double duty, rescuing the Assad regime while opening an arms pipeline to Hezbollah, the Iran-backed militia fighting beside them. Based in Lebanon, Hezbollah was the crown jewel in the &ldquo;Axis of Resistance&rdquo; that Iran had arrayed against Israel. </p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>And for more than 80 years, opposition to Israel had defined the Middle East.</p>



<p>For the Islamic Republic of Iran, it still does. Removal of the Jewish state from &ldquo;Islamic lands&rdquo; is core to the ideology of the 1979 Islamic Revolution, which casts Iran in the unlikely role of leader of the Muslim world. America is the Great Satan, but for Iran&rsquo;s proxies in Baghdad, Lebanon, and Yemen, Israel is the target. So on the eve of Oct. 7, 2023, the leaders of Hamas, the only prominent Palestinian node in the axis, had reason to assume that after breaching Israeli defenses on the Gaza Strip and pouring into Israel by the thousands, they would not be fighting alone for long. </p>



<p>But the axis of resistance barely resisted at all. Hezbollah launched a few missiles a day toward Israel when the &ldquo;Zionist entity&rdquo; was most vulnerable. Iran&rsquo;s leaders had scanned the battlefield, and, seeing an opponent backed not only by U.S. arms and intelligence, but also a nuclear arsenal, remembered why they were investing in one of their own: survival. In the words of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, creator of the theocratic system that governs Iran, &ldquo;The preservation of the system is the highest priority.&rdquo; Solidarity with the Palestinians was laudable, but there&rsquo;s also such a thing as self-interest. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/TIM250707_Cover-IsraelIran_FINAL.jpg" alt="The New Middle East Time Magazine cover" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>The problem, for both Iran and the Palestinian cause, is that the rest of the Middle East had already come to the same conclusion. During the two decades Iran was extending its military reach in the name of the Palestinians, the wealthy kingdoms of the Persian Gulf had been making common cause with the Jewish state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is, most of the Arab world had made some accommodation or other with Israel. Egypt and Jordan, which share borders with Israel, signed peace treaties with it after suffering repeated military defeats at its hands. The Gulf states aligned with Israel in large part out of a shared enmity for Iran. As home to Islam&rsquo;s dominant Sunni branch, the kingdoms know Iran not only as radical, but as the nominal leaders of the minority Shi&lsquo;ite branch, and thus a rival. Saudi Arabia, custodian of Islam&rsquo;s holy sites, has its own claim to leadership of the world&rsquo;s Muslims.</p>



<p>As autocratic states, the Gulf kingdoms were also eager clients for an Israeli tech sector that had grown out of its military. Surveillance, not least of millions of Palestinians under occupation (and obliged to use Israeli phone systems), generated startups like the spyware firm NSO Group, which soon found clients in the Arab regimes. One, the United Arab Emirates, was the first nation to cement diplomatic ties with Israel under the Abraham Accords, the signal diplomatic achievement of the first Trump Administration. Three other Arab states followed, and the Saudis keep signaling their intention to do the same once the situation in Gaza permits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Gaza churns on, a war Israel had not expected, and has no plan to win, because at bottom it&rsquo;s not a military affair. The Palestinian question&mdash;What to do about the people who claim the same land Jewish Israelis do?&mdash;will still be waiting when the shooting stops. The war on Iran, by contrast, is one Israel spent years planning for, and opened with the playbook of deception, decapitation, and precision strikes on missile sites that decimated Hezbollah in the space of a month last September, freeing Israelis from the dread of the militia&rsquo;s 100,000 missiles, and exposing Iran to the Israeli offensive that began June 13. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/7295726/netanyahu-trump-israel-iran-nuclear-strikes/" >How Netanyahu Pushed Trump Toward War</a></em></p>



<p>That day, a shepherd posted cell phone footage of an Israeli C-130 low in the sky over Syria, sheep bells clanking over the roar of the engines. The Assad family had fled the country months earlier, helpless to keep rebels out of Damascus without Hezbollah. Iran sent a plane to evacuate its generals to Tehran. There, the question is how Israel will choose to define victory. Regime change did not go so well in Iraq. And the stated goal of demolishing Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities appears <a href="https://time.com/7295632/israel-strikes-iran-nuclear-site-program/" >impossible without U.S. airstrikes</a>.</p>



<p>That decision <a href="https://time.com/7295729/trump-middle-east-war-iran-risk/" >rests with Donald Trump</a>. His choice may alter the region in unforeseen ways. But by reaching past the Palestinians to embrace Israel, as well as the sheiks of the Gulf, the U.S. President already has described the contours of its new, more transactional reality. In 1945, the mere prospect of an Israeli state inspired a boycott by every Arab one, in the name of the Palestinians. Eighty years later, an Arab nation can declare outrage that 55,000 have been killed in Gaza, then dispatch jets to intercept Iranian missiles aimed at Tel Aviv, joining Israeli warplanes in the skies over a new Middle East.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295798/new-middle-east-time-cover/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295798</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thailand’s Government Seems on the Verge of Collapse—Again</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295978/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-government-collapse-coup-cambodia-economy-democracy-analysis/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295978/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-government-collapse-coup-cambodia-economy-democracy-analysis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether or not the military intervenes, Thailand’s government seems on the verge of collapse, again.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295978"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295978/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-government-collapse-coup-cambodia-economy-democracy-analysis/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/thailand-military-coup.jpg" alt="THAILAND-POLITICS"/>



<p>Domestic regime change is no stranger to Thailand, which has had at least 12 successful <a href="https://time.com/105781/thailand-history-of-military-coups/" >coups</a> and 31 Prime Ministers since the founding of its current constitutional monarchy in 1932&mdash;itself the product of a coup.</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s for that reason that Prime Minister <a href="https://time.com/7023533/paetongtarn-shinawatra/" >Paetongtarn Shinawatra</a>, who took over after her fellow Pheu Thai party predecessor <a href="https://time.com/6900104/srettha-thavisin-thailand-interview-takeaways/" >Srettha Thavisin</a> was <a href="https://time.com/7011229/thailand-democracy-srettha-prime-minister-constitutional-court-progressive-movement-analysis/" >ousted</a> from power last year, has sought to insulate the government against military takeovers, which have typically occurred in coordination with conservative, royalist elites. It&rsquo;s likely, however, that she&rsquo;s failed.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Amid an escalating crisis sparked by <a href="https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/" >border tensions with neighbor Cambodia</a>, experts and observers of Thai politics tell TIME that Paetongtarn is all but certain to be deposed within months, if not imminently. She would follow in the path of her father, divisive but influential Thai power broker and former Prime Minister <a href="https://time.com/6307052/thaksin-shinawatra-return-from-exile-establishment-democracy/" >Thaksin Shinawatra</a>, as well as her aunt, former Prime Minister Yingluck Shinawatra, who were both forced out of office early in 2006 and 2014, respectively.</p>



<p>Whether by coup or political maneuvering, how exactly Paetongtarn may leave remains to be seen. But Thailand&rsquo;s increasingly likely change in leadership&mdash;and the uncertainty that inevitably will follow&mdash;comes at a trying time of both <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/business/economy/40051054"  target="_blank">economic headwinds</a> and <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/business/general/3008099/thailand-faces-hit-from-us-china-trade-war"  target="_blank">geopolitical challenges</a>, threatening to throw the country into further instability.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How we got here</h2>



<p>Srettha&mdash;and by extension Paetongtarn&mdash;only <a href="https://time.com/6307115/thailand-prime-minister-srettha-thavisin-pheu-thai/" >attained the premiership through a faustian bargain</a> after <a href="https://time.com/6279758/thailand-elections-move-forward-party-pheu-thai/" >2023&rsquo;s election</a> saw the <a href="https://time.com/6310002/pita-limjaroenrat-thailand-move-forward-interview-profile/" >progressive, pro-reform Move Forward party</a> receive the most votes but just shy of the majority needed to form the government. Pheu Thai, a populist party that placed second and was initially seen to be more aligned with Move Forward, partnered instead with conservative minority parties, including some of the pro-military forces it had campaigned against, to form a coalition of unlikely allies.</p>



<p>Now, that coalition is <a href="https://eastasiaforum.org/2025/06/15/thailands-grand-political-compromise-cracks-under-pressure/"  target="_blank">splintering apart</a>.</p>



<p>The government that was formed on a shaky foundation started showing cracks last December, when Pheu Thai lawmakers tried to pass <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Politics/Turbulent-Thailand/Thailand-anti-coup-bill-creates-strains-in-ruling-coalition"  target="_blank">anti-coup legislation</a> that was opposed by other members of its coalition.</p>



<p>On the 11th anniversary of the nation&rsquo;s 2014 coup last month, Deputy Prime Minister and Defense Minister Phumtham Wechayachai <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/politics/40050304"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters that Thailand had made democratic progress since then, but he couldn&rsquo;t &ldquo;rule it out&rdquo; that there would be &ldquo;no more coups.&rdquo;</p>



<p>A border dispute with Cambodia just days later significantly raised the possibility that the next coup could come quite soon.</p>



<p>On May 28, a <a href="https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/" >longstanding row</a> between Cambodia and Thailand was reignited after an early morning clash in the so-called Emerald Triangle that left a Cambodian soldier dead. The incident has inflamed nationalist sentiment on both sides of the border, and some have speculated&mdash;without evidence&mdash;that it may have been a &ldquo;<a href="https://thediplomat.com/2025/06/is-thailand-on-the-cusp-of-another-military-coup/"  target="_blank">calculated provocation by hardline elements within the military</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Since then, the two countries&rsquo; Prime Ministers, Thailand&rsquo;s Paetongtarn and Cambodia&rsquo;s Hun Manet, have engaged in diplomatic back-and-forths, but have generally tried to keep the peace. The Royal Thai Army, however, said it was on high alert, announcing that it was ready for a &ldquo;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thai-military-prepared-high-level-operation-if-cambodia-border-row-escalates-2025-06-06/"  target="_blank">high-level military operation</a> &hellip;  to defend the country&#8217;s sovereignty to the fullest extent if the situation is called for.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Amid allegations from some critics that she was already &ldquo;<a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/asean/40051272"  target="_blank">too soft</a>&rdquo; on Cambodia in the dispute given a longstanding friendship between her father Thaksin and Hun Manet&rsquo;s father, former Cambodia Prime Minister Hun Sen, Paetongtarn came under intense scrutiny following the leak on Wednesday of part of a <a href="https://www.thairath.co.th/news/politic/2865274"  target="_blank">phone call</a> with Hun Sen, in which she called him &ldquo;Uncle&rdquo; and promised to &ldquo;take care&rdquo; of his concerns, even referring to a prominent Thai army commander as being part of &ldquo;the opposite side.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Despite the commander in question <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/general/40051416"  target="_blank">saying he didn&rsquo;t mind</a>, the call immediately ignited controversy and <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c70rwjl99rzo"  target="_blank">calls for Paetongtarn&rsquo;s resignation</a>, which she has refused. Paetongtarn defended the call as a &ldquo;negotiation technique&rdquo; but apologized for the &ldquo;public resentment&rdquo; it caused.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/paetongtarn-shinawatra.jpg" alt="THAILAND-POLITICS" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Hun Sen admitted to recording the call and said that he shared it with around 80 people. He also released the full audio, which <a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=1063810361787069"  target="_blank">ran for more than 17 minutes</a>, on Facebook, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hunsencambodia/posts/pfbid02hR1cvjjU2mYyqi2FH5DtTTzjzzbbBeKhDvvEHAmuaiu8V2U1xYY46hSs3FYzaAhZl"  target="_blank">explaining</a> that he believed recording was necessary &ldquo;in order to avoid any misunderstanding or misrepresentation in official matters.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The Thai foreign ministry <a href="https://thailand.prd.go.th/en/content/category/detail/id/48/iid/399120"  target="_blank">criticized</a> Cambodia, saying the release of the call undermined neighborly &ldquo;trust and respect&rdquo; as well as &ldquo;good faith&rdquo; efforts to resolve the border dispute peacefully.</p>



<p>Since the call, Pheu Thai&rsquo;s governing coalition lost its second biggest member: the conservative Bhumjaithai party, which announced that the call was to blame, though tensions had been building between its leader, former Prime Minister candidate <a href="https://time.com/6264782/anutin-charnvirakul-thailand-prime-minister-election-interview/" >Anutin Charnvirakul</a>, and Paetongtarn over a <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/politics/3051757/fight-for-control-of-interior-ministry-heats-up"  target="_blank">fight for control of the influential Interior Ministry</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Bhumjaithai will work with all Thai people to support the army and officials who safeguard the sovereignty, territorial integrity, and interests of Thailand in all ways,&rdquo; Bhumjaithai <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/politics/3052625/bhumjaithai-quits-thai-coalition-over-phone-call-furore"  target="_blank">said</a> in a statement.</p>



<p>Amid concerns of a looming coup, the Thai army chief <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/general/40051447"  target="_blank">urged</a> the Thai public on Thursday to trust the military to uphold the democratic system. Paetongtarn, during her hasty call-apology press conference, also aimed to quell rumors of a power struggle. &ldquo;The government and armed forces are united, so I call on the people to have unity with the government,&rdquo; she <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/asean/40051451"  target="_blank">said</a>. &ldquo;We should not fight among ourselves.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Still, Natthaphong Ruengpanyawut, the leader of the opposition People&rsquo;s Party that grew out of the dissolved Move Forward party, called on Paetongtarn to return &ldquo;<a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/politics/40051418"  target="_blank">the mandate to the people</a>&rdquo; by dissolving parliament, which would lead to a snap election. (Barring an early dissolution, the next Thai general election wouldn&rsquo;t need to be called until 2027.)</p>



<p>&ldquo;This will prevent certain groups from exploiting Paetongtarn&rsquo;s mistake and inciting an incident that could harm our democracy,&rdquo; Natthaphong said.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What could come next</h2>



<p>&ldquo;History is repeating itself,&rdquo; Napon Jatusripitak, visiting fellow and acting coordinator of the Thailand Studies Programme at the ISEAS-Yusof Ishak Institute in Singapore, tells TIME.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Shinawatra dynasty, Napon says, &ldquo;had other ways to play this out,&rdquo; but &ldquo;they are shooting themselves in the foot here by making it easy for conservative hardliners to label them as betraying the country, selling the country out for their own family&rsquo;s private benefit.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Royalist and conservative factions already had deep-seated mistrust of Paetongtarn because of her father Thaksin, who is widely seen as pulling the strings behind the scenes.</p>



<p>Mark S. Cogan, associate professor of peace and conflict studies at Kansai Gaidai University, described the Cambodia border crisis as &ldquo;icing on top of this cake,&rdquo; as the Paetongtarn government was already losing public confidence for failing to effectuate its populist campaign promises, including revitalizing the economy with a &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7203306/thailand-government-soft-power-moo-deng-lisa-economy/" >soft power</a>&rdquo; push.</p>



<p>Distrust of the Shinawatras, Pheu Thai&rsquo;s failure to deliver material improvements to people&rsquo;s lives, and the Cambodia border crisis created the &ldquo;perfect storm to rally opposition,&rdquo; says Napon.</p>



<p>The army may not even need to get involved to remove Paetongtarn, says Termsak Chalermpalanupap, a visiting senior fellow at the ISEAS-Yusof Ishak Institute. With Bhumjaithai&rsquo;s defection to the opposition, all that&rsquo;s likely needed is the resignation of another medium-sized party from the coalition government, such as the United Thai Nation Party, an ultra-conservative pro-military party.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It may be &ldquo;too soon&rdquo; to call for the dissolution of parliament, says Termsak, as the last general elections happened so recently. &ldquo;There is still a possibility that some caretaker Prime Minister can step in and then try to settle the border issue first.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But so far, as Paetongtarn has rebuffed calls to resign, her removal may have to be orchestrated by the courts, similar to <a href="https://time.com/90445/after-six-months-of-fighting-thai-pm-yingluck-is-finally-ousted-by-court/" >her aunt Yingluck</a> and <a href="https://time.com/7010847/thailand-srettha-thavisin-prime-minister-removed-constitutional-court-ethics-violation/" >her predecessor Srettha</a>.</p>



<p>Paetongtarn&rsquo;s call with Hun Sen has already prompted ethics complaints. On Thursday, a Thai Senate committee <a href="https://x.com/KhaosodEnglish/status/1935560795972317384"  target="_blank">said</a> it will petition the Conservative Court and the National Anti-Corruption Commission to remove Paetongtarn for her &ldquo;alleged mishandling of Thai-Cambodia border disputes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Cogan believes it will be &ldquo;very difficult [for Paetongtarn] to recover&rdquo; from the call scandal. Instead, Pheu Thai would be wise, he says, to try &ldquo;managing the decline&rdquo; and &ldquo;salvaging what&rsquo;s left&rdquo; of the party&rsquo;s domestic agenda.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There is no good time for regime change,&rdquo; Cogan says, explaining that a change in leadership threatens the continuity of both domestic and international policies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&ldquo;Geopolitically, we are dealing with a new series of flash points,&rdquo; says Napon. &ldquo;It comes at a time when we haven&rsquo;t finalized any negotiations in tariffs with the Trump Administration.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The World Bank lowered <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/business/economy/40051094"  target="_blank">the economic growth prospects</a> for the Southeast Asian country, and Thailand&rsquo;s economy is expected to take another hit when U.S. President Donald Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;Liberation Day&rdquo; tariffs&mdash;at a rate of 36% for Thailand&mdash;are set to go back into effect after a temporary global reduction ends in July.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Napon adds that it would be &ldquo;highly disastrous&rdquo; for Thailand to undergo a regime change that&rsquo;s military-led. Thailand&rsquo;s past military interventions have seen massive democratic crackdowns&mdash;including restrictions on freedom of assembly and rampant use of <a href="https://time.com/6296556/thailand-lese-majeste-reform-teen-crop-top/" ><em>lese majeste</em></a> laws to silence critics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While the last Thai election brought hopes of a trend toward democracy, Napon warns that if the military returns to power, &ldquo;there may not be a quick reversal to [a] democratic regime.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295978/thailand-paetongtarn-shinawatra-government-collapse-coup-cambodia-economy-democracy-analysis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295978</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Know About New Social Media Screening Rules for Student Visas</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295949/international-student-visas-colleges-universities-social-media-state-department-trump/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295949/international-student-visas-colleges-universities-social-media-state-department-trump/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Applicants will be required to make their social media profiles “public” and will be screened for “hostile attitudes” toward the U.S., new State Department guidance says.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295949"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295949/international-student-visas-colleges-universities-social-media-state-department-trump/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/student-social-media.jpg" alt="A mobile phone in the hands of a girl."/>



<p>Prospective students applying for U.S. student visas must now unlock their social media accounts for government review, the State Department <a href="https://www.state.gov/releases/office-of-the-spokesperson/2025/06/announcement-of-expanded-screening-and-vetting-for-visa-applicants/"  target="_blank">said</a> Wednesday.</p>



<p>The notice instructs applicants for F, M, and J visas to change their social media profile privacy settings to &ldquo;public.&rdquo; A separate cable, obtained by multiple news outlets, directed embassies and consulates to vet applicants for &ldquo;hostile attitudes towards our citizens, culture, government, institutions, or founding principles,&rdquo; while visa appointments, which had been <a href="https://time.com/7289060/us-student-visa-interviews-paused-embassies-trump-social-media-vetting/" >suspended in May</a>, are allowed to resume. The guidance comes amid the Trump Administration&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7288422/harvard-university-international-students-trump/" >crackdown on universities</a>, including by targeting <a href="https://time.com/7289945/us-china-trump-rubio-international-student-visa-restrictions-trade-negotiations/" >international students</a>.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>&ldquo;A U.S. visa is a privilege, not a right,&rdquo; the announcement said, echoing a refrain that&rsquo;s become common among the Trump Administration. &ldquo;Every visa adjudication is a national security decision. The United States must be vigilant during the visa issuance process to ensure that those applying for admission into the United States do not intend to harm Americans and our national interests, and that all applicants credibly establish their eligibility for the visa sought, including that they intend to engage in activities consistent with the terms for their admission.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the new guidance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Visa process reopened</h2>



<p>Weeks after embassies were told to stop all new student visa appointments, they are now allowed to resume. Fanta Aw, CEO of NAFSA: Association of International Educators, said in a <a href="https://www.nafsa.org/about/about-nafsa/pause-international-student-visa-interviews-misguided-and-self-defeating"  target="_blank">statement</a> at the time that the pause&mdash;and more stringent checks&mdash;would cause &ldquo;unnecessary delays, fuels uncertainty, and damages our reputation as a welcoming destination for global talent.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The cable noted that increased vetting may be a strain on consulates, and said consular officers &ldquo;should consider overall scheduling volume and the resource demands of appropriate vetting&rdquo; such as by scheduling fewer appointments, the <em>Washington Post </em><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/06/18/student-visas-social-media-vetting-state-department/"  target="_blank">reported</a>.</p>



<p>The State Department told embassies to prioritize students going to colleges where international students make up less than 15% of the student body, per the cable, which was first <a href="https://www.thefp.com/p/exclusive-student-visa-applicants-social-media-check"  target="_blank">reported</a> by the Free Press. An Associated Press analysis from 2023 <a href="https://apnews.com/article/student-visas-trump-social-media-6632a2c585245edcd6a63594345dd8c7"  target="_blank">found</a> that international students comprise more than 15% of the total student body at around 200 universities across the country, including all eight Ivy League colleges, and more than 15% of the undergraduate student body at around 100 universities.</p>



<p>Trump previously <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aGu2ANZmWFE"  target="_blank">said</a> Harvard should cap its foreign enrollment at 15%. The Trump Administration has <a href="https://time.com/7291333/harvard-university-trump-international-students-visa-suspension-sevp/" >targeted international students</a> at the elite university in a punitive move over the school&rsquo;s refusal to sufficiently capitulate to a list of demands. International students currently make up more than a quarter of Harvard&rsquo;s student body.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Expanded scrutiny of social media</h2>



<p>Applicants for student and exchange visas will now have their &ldquo;entire online presence&rdquo; vetted, per the cable reportedly said. If students refuse to change their accounts to &ldquo;public&rdquo; and &ldquo;limited access to, or visibility of, online presence could be construed as an effort to evade or hide certain activity.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Specifically, consulates are instructed to &ldquo;identify applicants who bear hostile attitudes towards our citizens, culture, government, institutions, or founding principles; who advocate for, aid, or support designated terrorists and other threats to U.S. national security; or who perpetrate unlawful antisemitic harassment or violence.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The guidance did not specify what exactly would constitute &ldquo;hostile attitudes.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Consulates are required to implement the new procedures within five business days, but the new criteria applies to both new applicants as well as to cases currently in progress&mdash;students who are awaiting their interviews, have been interviewed but who have not yet been approved, and those whose interviews have been waived.</p>



<p>&ldquo;During the vetting, you simply are looking for any potentially derogatory information about the applicant,&rdquo; the cable said, but gave as an example: &ldquo;You might discover on social media that an applicant endorsed Hamas or its activities.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;For applicants who demonstrate a history of political activism, especially when it is associated with violence or with the views and activities described above, you must consider the likelihood they would continue such activity in the United States and, if so, whether such activity is consistent with the nonimmigrant visa classification they seek,&rdquo; the cable said, as <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/06/18/politics/us-embassies-vet-student-visa-applications"  target="_blank">reported</a> by CNN. &ldquo;As Secretary Rubio has said, we do not seek to import activists who will disrupt and undermine scholarly activity at U.S. universities.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, students&rsquo; &ldquo;online presence&rdquo; will go beyond their social media activity, Politico <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/18/social-media-screening-student-visas-00413160"  target="_blank">reported</a>, and includes information from online databases like LexisNexis.</p>



<p>Whether or not an applicant&rsquo;s activity amounts to a threat is at the discretion of consular officers, according to the cable, adding that &ldquo;you must consider whether they undermine the applicant&rsquo;s credibility or suggest that the applicant will not respect the terms of his admission to the United States.&rdquo; Officers are instructed to take &ldquo;detailed case notes&rdquo; including screenshots for additional review.</p>



<p>The cable notes that student visa applicants warrant particularly strict vetting because &ldquo;the FBI has long warned that foreign powers seek access to American higher education institutions to, among other things, steal technical information, exploit U.S. research and development, and spread false information for political or other reasons.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Critics, like Aw, have said increased vetting should be &ldquo;applied uniformly&mdash;not selectively to students who have long contributed to American classrooms, communities, and cutting-edge research.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Higher education experts <a href="https://time.com/7289060/us-student-visa-interviews-paused-embassies-trump-social-media-vetting/" >previously told TIME</a> that more rigorous scrutiny of students&rsquo; social media, in addition to punitive policies toward students that participated in pro-Palestinian activism, could have a chilling effect on academic freedom&mdash;something U.S. universities had previously developed a strong global reputation for.</p>



<p>Lili Yang, an associate professor specializing in higher education at the University of Hong Kong, said that Trump&rsquo;s crackdown will lead to a tremendously negative impact on free speech on campus and the U.S.&rsquo;s reputation [as] a place for free expression.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295949/international-student-visas-colleges-universities-social-media-state-department-trump/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295949</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
