<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>VMware Security Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 22:12:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">240671509</site>	<item>
		<title>VMware and Pwn2Own 2025 &#8211; Berlin</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/05/vmware-and-pwn2own-2025-berlin.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Praveen Singh and Monty Ijzerman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 09:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[VMware Security Response Center]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png 611w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?resize=600,339 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>Greetings from the Broadcom PSIRT Team &#8211; VCF Division. Pwn2Own 2025 has been wrapped-up and we have witnessed successful exploitation of some of the very well-known products. Broadcom VMware products have been a part of Pwn2Own since 2016. Similar to last year, VMware ESXi – Type 1 and VMware Workstation – Type 2 Hypervisors were &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/05/vmware-and-pwn2own-2025-berlin.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/05/vmware-and-pwn2own-2025-berlin.html">VMware and Pwn2Own 2025 &#8211; Berlin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png 611w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/05/Screenshot-2025-05-20-at-3.19.18 PM.png?resize=600,339 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p>Greetings from the Broadcom PSIRT Team &#8211; VCF Division.</p>
<p>Pwn2Own 2025 has been wrapped-up and we have witnessed successful exploitation of some of the very well-known products. Broadcom VMware products have been a part of Pwn2Own since 2016. Similar to last year, VMware ESXi – Type 1 and VMware Workstation – Type 2 Hypervisors were the targets in the virtualization category with a prize money of $180,000 and $80,000 respectively.</p>
<p>We have seen three successful attempts on our products in this year&#8217;s contest.</p>
<p>On day 2 &#8211; May 16, 2025, Nguyen Hoang Thach of STARLabs SG successfully exploited VMware ESXi. This is the first time VMware ESXi was exploited in Pwn2Own hacking event.</p>
<p>On Day 3 &#8211; May 17, 2025, Corentin BAYET of Reverse Tactics successfully exploited ESXi by chaining two vulnerabilities. One of vulnerabilities used in the exploit was a collision as it was already known. Later that day, Thomas Bouzerar and Etienne Helluy-Lafont from Synacktiv managed to successfully exploit Workstation.</p>
<p>We are actively working on the remediation and we plan to publish a VMware Security Advisory to provide information on updates for the affected products.</p>
<p>We would like to thank Zero Day Initiative (ZDI) for allowing us to participate. In addition, we would like to thank teams from STAR Labs SG, Reverse Tactics, and Synacktiv for working with us to address the reported issues.</p>
<p>If you want to be informed on VMware Security Advisories (VMSAs), please sign up <a href="https://www.broadcom.com/support/vmware-security-advisories">here</a> for new and updated information.</p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/05/vmware-and-pwn2own-2025-berlin.html">VMware and Pwn2Own 2025 &#8211; Berlin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VMware vDefend: Accelerate Enterprise’s Zero Trust Private Cloud Journey with Micro-segmentation and NDR Innovations</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/03/vdefend-microsegmentation.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prashant Gandhi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCF Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workload Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lateral Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micro-segmentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zero-trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="171" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg 700w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?resize=300,171 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?resize=600,343 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>New enhancements include: Micro-segmentation Assessment, Air-gapped NDR, and Scale-out Data Lake Platform (Security Services Platform 5.0) For decades, enterprises have relied on perimeter defenses to protect their private cloud assets from external threats. Yet, in this era of ransomware, protecting only the perimeter has proven to be insufficient. Traditionally, only a handful of &#8220;crown jewel&#8221; &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/03/vdefend-microsegmentation.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/03/vdefend-microsegmentation.html">VMware vDefend: Accelerate Enterprise’s Zero Trust Private Cloud Journey with Micro-segmentation and NDR Innovations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="171" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg 700w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?resize=300,171 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Getty-2149012097.jpg?resize=600,343 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">New enhancements include: Micro-segmentation Assessment, Air-gapped NDR, and Scale-out Data Lake Platform (Security Services Platform 5.0)</span></i></p>
<p>For decades, enterprises have relied on perimeter defenses to protect their private cloud assets from external threats. Yet, in this era of ransomware, protecting only the perimeter has proven to be insufficient. Traditionally, only a handful of &#8220;crown jewel&#8221; applications were protected inside the private cloud. East-west traffic being ~4X more than north-south traffic, extending perimeter defenses internally proved neither scalable nor economically feasible. As a result, large portions of the private cloud remained vulnerable, enabling attackers to breach weakly protected non-critical workloads and laterally move to compromise high-value assets – crown jewels – ultimately causing significant damage.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/cloud-infrastructure/vdefend-distributed-firewall">VMware vDefend</a> is a software-defined, hypervisor-integrated security solution architected to comprehensively protect every VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF) private cloud workload – including both critical and non-critical workloads. We are excited to announce new vDefend capabilities that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expand the enterprise’s micro-segmentation scope with planning and assessment,</li>
<li>Seamlessly scale lateral security across application environments,</li>
<li>Simplify lifecycle management and operations, and</li>
<li>Deploy threat detection in regulated environments with air-gapped NDR</li>
</ul>
<p>These capabilities are designed to accelerate the implementation of zero-trust lateral security in the VCF private cloud. They are especially critical in brownfield environments, which are poorly segmented, and application communication patterns are primarily unknown. Additionally, SE Labs (a leading cyber security test lab) has provided independent validation of vDefend’s real-world effectiveness.</p>
<p>Here are the key highlights:</p>
<p>Kickstarting Micro-segmentation Assessment and Planning</p>
<ul>
<li>Security Segmentation Report &#8211; Part of our Security Intelligence tool for lateral security visibility and threat analytics, the security segmentation report provides security teams and compliance officers with a clear assessment of the current segmentation health (via segmentation score), identifies gaps and offers actionable next steps to improve the segmentation posture. This is the magic bullet that enables enterprises to rapidly and comprehensively roll out zero-trust lateral security to combat ransomware.</li>
<li>Lateral Security for VCF validated solutions guide &#8211; A must-have, verified technical reference for quickly deploying VMware vDefend Zero Trust lateral security in VCF private clouds.</li>
</ul>
<p>Streamlining Security Operations</p>
<ul>
<li>Security Services Platform &#8211; A self-contained, simplified platform that hosts Security Intelligence and advanced threat prevention features. It also provides a scale-out architecture to address the growing analytics and security demands of large VCF deployments.</li>
<li>Micro-segmentation-as-Code &#8211; Automates policy deployment with the applications, accelerating secure application rollouts.</li>
<li>Network Detection and Response (NDR) for Air-Gapped Environments &#8211; Enables real-time threat detection and response in classified or high-security deployments without requiring external connectivity.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem;">Third-party Validation</span></p>
<ul>
<li>SE Labs Test Validation Report for <a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/cloud-infrastructure/vdefend-advanced-threat-prevention">VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention</a> (ATP) – Awarded a highly coveted AAA rating in a rigorous multi-stage attack test against the most sophisticated real-world threats.</li>
</ul>
<p>Business Value &#8211; Analyst Insights from Customer Interviews</p>
<ul>
<li>Forrester Total Economic Impact (TEI) – Found that customers using VMware vDefend reduced cyber breach risk by 40%, improved security operations team productivity by 25%, avoided 10% cyber insurance premium increases, and realized 116% ROI.</li>
</ul>
<h2>An Easy Button For Robust Private Cloud Security</h2>
<h3>Introducing the Security Segmentation Report with Security Intelligence</h3>
<p>Today, we&#8217;re excited to announce the launch of the <strong>Security</strong> <strong>Segmentation Report</strong>, a powerful new Security Intelligence tool of vDefend for real-time assessment of the segmentation posture of the VCF private cloud. By analyzing network flow data alongside existing distributed firewall security rules, this assessment delivers a clear picture of your current micro-segmentation posture, pinpointing gaps caused by insecure network protocols and inappropriate application communication, measuring progress with a security segmentation score, offering actionable recommendations, and helping you stay ahead of potential breaches.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Automated Segmentation Assessment:</strong> Gathers up to 30 days of network flow data to uncover potential security gaps and deliver timely, data-driven insights related to application communication.</li>
<li><strong>Security Segmentation Score:</strong> Evaluate your network flows and the distributed firewall rules to identify gaps in micro-segmentation and provide actionable next steps, enabling you to track progress toward a fully segmented private cloud.</li>
<li><strong>Actionable Recommendations: </strong>Highlights areas for improvement and provides specific, easy-to-implement policy recommendations for the roll-out of zero trust lateral security.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/security_seg_report_31732f.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84275 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/security_seg_report_31732f.jpg?w=753" alt="" width="628" height="446" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/security_seg_report_31732f.jpg 753w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/security_seg_report_31732f.jpg?resize=300,213 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/security_seg_report_31732f.jpg?resize=600,426 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Figure 1 &#8211; Numerical score quantifies your current segmentation posture</em></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-1-commchain-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84277 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-1-commchain-2.jpg?w=685" alt="" width="619" height="420" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-1-commchain-2.jpg 685w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-1-commchain-2.jpg?resize=300,204 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-1-commchain-2.jpg?resize=600,407 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 619px) 100vw, 619px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Figure 2 &#8211; Visualize only the workloads that are potentially exposed and understand their communication</em></p>
<h3>VMware vDefend Design Guide for Securing VCF Private Cloud</h3>
<p>After the Security Segmentation Report uncovers potential risks and areas for improvement, the next step is putting those recommendations into action—quickly and confidently. That’s where the<a href="https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-cis/vcf/vvs/1-0/lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend.html"> lateral security for the VCF-validated solutions guide</a> comes in. This thoroughly vetted resource provides a step-by-step blueprint for deploying Zero Trust lateral security with VMware vDefend in VCF, ensuring best practices are consistently applied across your entire environment. By following its verified configurations and guidelines, security and IT teams can streamline setup, reduce guesswork, and accelerate the path to a cyber-resilient private cloud. Whether you’re new to security or a seasoned veteran, the VMware Validated Solutions guide makes it easier than ever to transform your security plans into a tangible zero-trust lateral security strategy.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #0f4761;">Simplifying Security Operations</span></h2>
<p>In today’s fast-paced private cloud security landscape, smaller teams need to do more with limited resources. Our new features enable enterprises to activate advanced threat detection and prevention swiftly.</p>
<h3>Security Services Platform with Next-generation Architecture</h3>
<p>Security Services Platform (SSP) is a self-contained, scale-out platform that makes deployment of Security Intelligence and advanced threat prevention tools, such as NDR and Malware Prevention (for blocking malicious files), quick and easy.</p>
<p>Its<a href="https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-security-load-balancing/vdefend/security-services-platform/5-0/release-notes/security-services-platform-50-release-notes.html"> latest 5.0 release</a> offers a simplified network design, a tailored user profile for security admins, and easier workflows for configuration and deployment.</p>
<ul>
<li>Simple OVA Deployment – makes adoption fast and hassle-free, letting teams quickly roll out Security Intelligence and advanced threat prevention capabilities.</li>
<li>Scale-out Architecture &#8211; ensures that visibility and threat prevention automatically extend to workloads of large-scale VCF deployments</li>
<li>Enterprise-Ready Backup &amp; Restore – Built-in, streamlined processes ensure your security infrastructure can quickly recover, helping maintain business continuity and compliance.</li>
<li>Independent Upgrades and Enhanced Interoperability – Upgrades are decoupled from other platform components, simplifying the update cycle while ensuring broader compatibility with VCF.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84289 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png?w=987" alt="" width="769" height="394" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png 987w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png?resize=300,153 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png?resize=768,393 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/March_announce_image_ssp_block_v2.png?resize=600,307 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px" /></a></p>
<h3>Micro-segmentation as Code–Lateral Security at the Speed of Apps</h3>
<p>Most security gaps arise when applications are deployed first and then protected retroactively—a time-consuming approach that can leave workloads exposed to attackers for an extended period. VMware vDefend plug-n-play integrations with VCF address this issue by allowing you to define and apply security policies at the same time applications are spun up. Through a simple “as code” model, you can ensure that every new workload is protected from day one, eliminating the waiting period often associated with deploying workloads first and layering on security later.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Declarative Model &#8211; </strong>Allows operators to specify the full intent of an application security policy; vDefend then converts this intent into a working configuration, simplifying policy creation and implementation.</li>
<li><strong>Automate Security with Tag-Based Policies &#8211; </strong>Define policies by application tags (e.g., dev, prod, test) for dynamic Zero Trust enforcement. As workloads are created or re-tagged, vDefend automatically applies the right policies—no manual reconfiguration needed.</li>
<li><strong>Expand with Scripting &#8211; </strong>Modern-day applications grow and shrink depending on demand.  With automation, customers can auto-scale security to ensure that applications stay safe and secure.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84265 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg?w=785" alt="" width="601" height="436" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg 785w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg?resize=300,217 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg?resize=768,557 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/Fig-3-microseg_as_code.jpg?resize=600,435 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Figure 3 &#8211; Declarative payload using Postman to create a policy with an API call</em></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">NDR Enhancement for Air-Gapped Environments</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware vDefend NDR now supports mechanisms for organizations to securely update threat intelligence in standalone operations without external network access. This ensures that all detection, correlation, and response activities are executed with higher fidelity entirely within the closed network, leveraging both internally and externally sourced threat intelligence and providing an additional layer of protection against targeted attacks in sensitive or classified environments. This approach uses local storage and processing, ensuring real-time analysis and threat response while mitigating the risks associated with external connectivity, making it a unique solution for high-security, regulatory-sensitive, and isolated networks.</span></p>
<p><b>Enhanced Security: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operates effectively in environments without external connectivity, minimizing exposure to external threats and attack surfaces.</span></p>
<p><b>Operational Flexibility: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enables deployment in sensitive, high-security environments like critical infrastructure or classified systems without compromising NDR capabilities.</span></p>
<p><b>Regulatory Compliance: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supports industries requiring strict data isolation, such as government, healthcare, and finance, ensuring adherence to compliance standards.</span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #0f4761;">3<sup>rd</sup> Party Validation &#8211; Test Labs and Analysts</span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">SE Labs’ AAA Rating for vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SE Labs Ltd. recently put vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention under the microscope, taking it through its rigorous tests to determine just how well it would perform in specific threat detection scenarios. SE Labs’ methodology is to test full chains of attack, including complex, multi-staged ransomware threats, using a variety of tools and techniques employed by Advanced Persistent Threat actors in the wild.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/APT_Award_singleimage.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84263 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/APT_Award_singleimage.png?w=642" alt="" width="613" height="359" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/APT_Award_singleimage.png 642w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/APT_Award_singleimage.png?resize=300,176 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/03/APT_Award_singleimage.png?resize=600,351 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 613px) 100vw, 613px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The test report results are a glowing AAA rating for vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention, which detected the most sophisticated threats with the highest accuracy. You can find the full report </span><a href="https://selabs.uk/reports/reports-advanced-security-test-report-vmware-vdefend-advanced-threat-prevention-ndr-protection-2025-q1/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forrester Total Economic Impact (TEI) Report – 116% ROI for vDefend</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a Total Economic Impact (TEI) study commissioned by Broadcom, Forrester Consulting interviewed customers using VMware vDefend and combined the results to form a single composite organization. Their analysis revealed that organizations using vDefend:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reduced their cyber breach risk by 40%, </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improved security operations team productivity by 25%, and </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoided 10% cyber insurance premium increases</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These organizations also saved on capital expenditures by eliminating the need for costly hardware, thanks to vDefend’s software-defined distributed firewall and dynamic threat protection. Additionally, the composite organization realized a 116% ROI. You can find the full study </span><a href="https://www.broadcom.com/company/industry-analyst-report/forrester-consulting-the-total-economic-impact-of-broadcom-vmware-vdefend"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about vDefend by registering for our upcoming webinar series or watching them on-demand from our library </span><a href="https://go-vmware.broadcom.com/vDefend-Webinar-Series"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/03/vdefend-microsegmentation.html">VMware vDefend: Accelerate Enterprise’s Zero Trust Private Cloud Journey with Micro-segmentation and NDR Innovations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SE Labs awards VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention &#8220;AAA&#8221; Rating!</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/se-labs-awards-vmware-vdefend-atp-aaa-rating.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stijn Vanveerdeghem]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="250" height="207" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/SELabs_newimage_small.jpg?w=250" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" /></div>
<p>Complex, multi-staged ransomware attacks are top of mind for organizations across all industries. VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention has won the AAA award from SE labs in the Advanced Security test, confirming its excellent capabilities in detecting these advanced threats. We are very happy to announce that SE Labs has awarded VMware vDefend Advanced Threat &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/se-labs-awards-vmware-vdefend-atp-aaa-rating.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/se-labs-awards-vmware-vdefend-atp-aaa-rating.html">SE Labs awards VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention &#8220;AAA&#8221; Rating!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="250" height="207" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/SELabs_newimage_small.jpg?w=250" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" /></div><p style="text-align: center;"><em>Complex, multi-staged ransomware attacks are top of mind for organizations across all industries. </em><br /><em>VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention has won the AAA award from SE labs in the Advanced Security test, confirming its excellent capabilities in detecting these advanced threats.</em></p>
<p>We are very happy to announce that SE Labs has awarded VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention (ATP) the <strong>AAA</strong> rating in Advanced Security testing.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84228 alignleft" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa.png" alt="" width="169" height="311" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa.png 183w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa.png?resize=163,300 163w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" /></a></p>
<p>According to the report, &#8220;<em>VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention was tested against a range of hacking attacks designed to compromise systems and penetrate target networks in the same way as criminals and other attackers breach systems and networks. VMware vDefend ATP posted excellent results, detecting every targeted attack</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>The solution was put through a series of real-world attack scenarios aligned with Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) groups like Wizard Spider, Sandworm and Dragonfly/Dragonfly 2.0.</p>
<p>The fact that SE labs awarded vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention with it&#8217;s best possible AAA rating in this real world test, illustrates the strength of the real-world detection and correlation capabilities of the solution. </p>
<p><span style="font-family: Metropolis-Medium, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 1.125rem;">Real-World Protection against fully featured attacks </span></p>
<p data-v-5bdddea5=""><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attackers often move from one system to another searching for the most valuable assets. The distributed nature of VMware vDefend, with detection and prevention controls applied at the network interface of every workload enables organizations to spot and stop attackers wherever and whenever they may act, without needing to deploy sensors or re-architecting the network. Along with the AAA rating, VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention achieved an impressive 97% Total Accuracy Rating in the SE Labs test, detecting every targeted attack and tracking almost all hostile activities that occurred during the attacks.</span></p>
<p data-v-5bdddea5=""><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone  wp-image-84229" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png" alt="" width="635" height="199" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png 2484w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=300,94 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=768,241 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=1024,321 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=1536,482 1536w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=2048,642 2048w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/aaa2.png?resize=600,188 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 635px) 100vw, 635px" /></a></p>
<p data-v-5bdddea5=""><span style="font-weight: 400;">SE Labs adopted a rigorous testing methodology by executing comprehensive attacks that closely replicated the tactics employed by real-world cybercriminals. The testing process utilized a diverse array of tools and techniques to breach target systems, simulating complete attack chains to assess the product’s effectiveness. Each phase of the attack, from initial compromise to potential data theft or system disruption, was meticulously executed and monitored to ensure thorough evaluation. SE Labs references the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework to showcase how the various TTPs (Tactics, Techniques and Procedures) leverage in each attack map to the vDefend controls. </span></p>
<p>VMware vDefend is uniquely capable of protecting against complex multi-staged attacks through:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Prevention of Lateral movement</strong>: <span style="font-weight: 400;">By segmenting the network into smaller zones without network changes or hair-pinning, vDefend Firewall minimizes the attack surface and prevents attackers from moving laterally within the environment.</span></li>
<li><strong>Elimination of Visibility gaps</strong>: VMware vDefend Security Intelligence along with the rest of the vDefend stack is fully integrated with VMware Cloud Foundation and provides complete East-to-West visibility across workloads, applications and network traffic without the need to deploy any sensors or taps.</li>
<li><strong>Detecting Threats Everywhere</strong>: VMware vDefend ATP leverages behavioral analytics as well as signature-based detection to detect known and unknown attack techniques, wherever these may occur. Controls are applied in the &#8220;Goldilocks zone&#8221;, directly at the network interface of a workload, providing network-architecture independent protection with rich context and without needing &#8220;yet another&#8221; endpoint agent.</li>
<li><strong>Powered by AI</strong>: <span style="font-weight: 400;">During SE Labs&#8217; testing, the VMware vDefend platform achieved a very high degree of accuracy with virtually no false positives, reducing alert-overhead. Furthermore, vDefend ATP leverages AI and ML to correlate individual signals from IDPS, Malware Detection and Anomaly detection into prioritized and actionable campaigns, making it far easier for security teams to focus on the incidents that matter and ignore the noise.  With Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend, we provide infrastructure and security teams with a Gen-AI powered co-pilot to further accelerate the time-to-insight and resolution. </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-family: Metropolis-Medium, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 1.125rem;">Learn More</span></p>
<p data-v-5bdddea5="">Please find the full report <a href="https://selabs.uk/reports/reports-advanced-security-test-report-vmware-vdefend-advanced-threat-prevention-ndr-protection-2025-q1/">here</a>. </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to learn more about how vDefend achieved the AAA-rating from SE labs, please join the founder and CEO of SE labs &#8211; </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/spgedwards"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Simon Edwards</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and us on March 20th at 10:00 AM PST for our vDefend Webinar &#8220;</span><b>A Look Inside VMware vDefend’s Test Against Full-Featured Attacks by SE labs®</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8221; : </span><a href="https://go-vmware.broadcom.com/vDefend-Webinar-Series"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://go-vmware.broadcom.com/vDefend-Webinar-Series</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additional VMware vDefend ATP information can be found <a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/cloud-infrastructure/vdefend-advanced-threat-prevention">here</a>.</span></p>
<p data-v-5bdddea5=""> </p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/se-labs-awards-vmware-vdefend-atp-aaa-rating.html">SE Labs awards VMware vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention &#8220;AAA&#8221; Rating!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend Validated Solution</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/introducing-lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend-validate-solution.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikodim Nikodimov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 09:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCF Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workload Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vDefend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware cloud foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="150" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png 1280w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=768,384 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=1024,512 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=600,300 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>At Broadcom, we are committed to providing cutting-edge security solutions to empower VMware Cloud Foundation customers with cyber-resilient private cloud. We are excited to announce the general availability of Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend validated solution. New to VMware Validated Solutions? VMware Validated Solutions is a vetted portfolio of technical validated solutions &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/introducing-lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend-validate-solution.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/introducing-lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend-validate-solution.html">Introducing Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend Validated Solution</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="150" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png 1280w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=768,384 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=1024,512 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/sec-shield-3-whtbg.png?resize=600,300 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p>At Broadcom, we are committed to providing cutting-edge security solutions to empower VMware Cloud Foundation customers with cyber-resilient private cloud.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>We are excited to announce the general availability of Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend validated solution.</strong></em></p>
<h2>New to VMware Validated Solutions?</h2>
<p><a href="https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-cis/vcf/vvs/1-0.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">VMware Validated Solutions</a> is a vetted portfolio of technical validated solutions designed to help customers build secure, high-performing, resilient, and efficient infrastructure for their applications and workloads deployed on VMware Cloud Foundation. The VMware Validated Solutions offer a systematic method for achieving quick and efficient deployment, encompassing planning and preparation, design decision-making, implementation, operational guidance, and solution interoperability. Furthermore, many of our solutions can automate a significant portion of the deployment process.</p>
<h2>About the Solution</h2>
<p>Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend is a well-architected, modular solution that guides the design, implementation, and operation of VMware vDefend to protect the VMware Cloud Foundation management components and workloads.</p>
<p>Establishing a secure infrastructure is essential for guaranteeing that customers&#8217; private cloud workloads are safeguarded from the ground up. Addressing this security paradigm can be overwhelming for administrators without specialized expertise. The complexity of setting up and overseeing secure environments is considerable, often necessitating a thorough, extensive understanding of the infrastructure and applications’ specific network communication.</p>
<p>Using Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend, organizations can effectively address these challenges and confidently protect their private clouds and workloads through validated configurations and tailored recommendations.</p>
<h2>What is covered?</h2>
<p>The Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend validated solution builds upon the Broadcom best design practices and principles for utilizing VMware vDefend security products and features in VMware Cloud Foundation environments.</p>
<p>The solution details the design decisions and the automated steps on securing the VMware Cloud Foundation management domain components, as well as streamlined guidelines for architecting and implementing macro and micro-segmentation to protect the customer workload that runs in the workload domains. It directs the effective deployment of the NSX Application Platform, detailing important considerations for sizing and scaling to ensure optimal performance. The solution also guides the use of Security Intelligence to automate and enhance the vDefend protection capabilities and features, providing highly repeatable processes that can be adapted for all VMware Cloud Foundation environments and workloads.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-84215 size-large" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?w=1024" alt="" width="1024" height="510" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png 2359w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=300,149 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=768,382 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=1024,510 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=1536,764 1536w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=2048,1019 2048w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/02/Logical-Design-of-Lateral-Security-for-VMware-Cloud-Foundation-with-VMware-vDefend.png?resize=600,299 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h2>Getting Started</h2>
<p>Ready to deep-dive and discover the full potential of VMware vDefend? You can access this VMware Validated Solution at: <a href="https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-cis/vcf/vvs/1-0/lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-cis/vcf/vvs/1-0/lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend.html</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techdocs.broadcom.com/us/en/vmware-cis/vcf/vvs/1-0/lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-84178 size-medium" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2025/01/VMware-Validated-Solutions-vDefend-275x300.png" alt="" width="275" height="300" /></a></p>
<h2>Summary</h2>
<p>VMware vDefend is a foundational element of VMware Cloud Foundation, providing state-of-the-art capabilities for zero-trust lateral security. It is the only security solution providing granular, micro-segmentation protection for the VMware Cloud Foundation management components.</p>
<p>Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation is an enterprise-ready solution to equip customers with a quick and efficient way to design, plan, and deploy VMware vDefend security to protect VMware Cloud Foundation infrastructure and workloads.</p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2025/02/introducing-lateral-security-for-vmware-cloud-foundation-with-vmware-vdefend-validate-solution.html">Introducing Lateral Security for VMware Cloud Foundation with VMware vDefend Validated Solution</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84173</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Started with VMware vDefend Automation: Part 1</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/12/getting-started-with-vmware-vdefend-automation-part-1.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Hrycaj]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="300" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png 1080w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=1024,1024 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=360,360 360w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>Introduction VMware vDefend objects can be created in both the UI and API. The vDefend API can be interacted with using tools like Postman, cURL, and Terraform along with scripting languages like Python and Golang. In this guide, we will be using Postman. The API documentation can be found here and has all the information &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/12/getting-started-with-vmware-vdefend-automation-part-1.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/12/getting-started-with-vmware-vdefend-automation-part-1.html">Getting Started with VMware vDefend Automation: Part 1</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="300" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png 1080w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=1024,1024 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/automation_blog-image.png?resize=360,360 360w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><h1>Introduction</h1>
<p>VMware vDefend objects can be created in both the UI and API. The vDefend API can be interacted with using tools like Postman, cURL, and Terraform along with scripting languages like Python and Golang. In this guide, we will be using Postman. The API documentation can be found <a href="https://developer.broadcom.com/xapis/nsx-t-data-center-rest-api/latest/">here</a> and has all the information you need to perform CRUD actions against the NSX Manager. In this article, we will be focusing on the absolute basics of how to use the NSX Policy API to gather information.</p>
<p>https://developer.broadcom.com/xapis/nsx-t-data-center-rest-api/latest/</p>
<h2>Building the URL:</h2>
<p>All queries to the NSX Manager will start with what protocol we want to use and the FQDN/IP Address of the NSX Manager. Let&#8217;s assume our NSX Manager IP was 192.168.1.10. Whether it be using a scripting language like Python or using tools like Postman or cURL, we will query it like this:</p>
<p>https://10.10.1.105</p>
<p>When you want to gather information from NSX, we need to query it using a URI containing the object we want information about. For example, if we want to gather information about groups, we would use the following URI</p>
<p>/policy/api/v1/infra/domains/{domain-id}/groups</p>
<p>{domain-id} will be default when working with the global NSX Manager context.  So, the URI will look like this:</p>
<p>/policy/api/v1/infra/domains/default/groups</p>
<p>If we put the two parts above together, we will have the following:</p>
<p>https://10.10.1.105/policy/api/v1/infra/domains/default/groups</p>
<p>We need to couple this with a method like GET which will retrieve information based on the URL provided above.  In order to complete the get request we also need to couple this with authentication.  There are a few ways we can authenticate against the NSX Manager, but for this introduction, we will use the username and password of an admin account.</p>
<h2>Postman</h2>
<p>For Postman, we will configure Basic Authentication:</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Basic-Auth-Screen.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84161" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Basic-Auth-Screen-1024x454.png" alt="" width="1024" height="454" /></a></p>
<p>In the picture above, I have set environment variables for username and password.  I encourage you to do the same with Postman.  For details on how to do this, please refer to the Postman documentation.</p>
<p>Now that we have authentication information set, we can prep for the call.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Get-Groups-Call-with-Params-Tab.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84160" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Get-Groups-Call-with-Params-Tab-1024x299.png" alt="" width="1024" height="299" /></a></p>
<p>With a GET call, we do not have to send any payload or body with the call.  We are getting information from the NSX Manager and expecting a payload in the response.</p>
<p>Now that we have all of our information set, we will execute the call in Postman.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Get-Groups-Result.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84159" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Get-Groups-Result-1024x641.png" alt="" width="1024" height="641" /></a></p>
<p>As we can see from the picture, we got a 200 status code which means it was successful.  For more information about status codes, please see the option content at the end of this article explaining return codes and their meaning.</p>
<p>As a quick reminder, groups are objects that contain a collection of one or more static or dynamic members, such as IP addresses or VMs. Groups are used in the source, destination or “Applied To” field of firewall rules.</p>
<p>We can see we received a payload containing information about all the groups configured in the NSX Manager.  We get information like:</p>
<p>&#8211; _revision</p>
<p>&#8211; ID</p>
<p>&#8211; display_name</p>
<p>&#8211; description</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Each group will have all the properties of the group in a JSON format.  These things can later be modified with PUT, POST, and PATCH commands as well.  For now, we will continue to focus on GET.  Let&#8217;s say we want to get information about a singular group.  All we have to do, per the API documentation, is include a name of a group in the URI.  So let&#8217;s look for a group that we know already exists called &#8220;Windows&#8221;</p>
<p>https://10.10.1.105/policy/api/v1/infra/domains/default/groups/Windows</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Windows-Group.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84158" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Windows-Group-1024x658.png" alt="" width="1024" height="658" /></a></p>
<p>As we can see, we only received the Windows group information as opposed to the call we did earlier where we got all of the groups in the NSX Manager.  The URL above required us to query the group by the ID.  There are two ways we could get that information.  One way is querying for all of the groups like we did above and getting the ID from the result, or we can use the UI to get the path of the object like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Copy-Path-to-Clipboard.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84162" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/12/Copy-Path-to-Clipboard-1024x477.png" alt="" width="1024" height="477" /></a></p>
<p>/infra/domains/default/groups/Windows</p>
<p>Notice how the path matches what we had above after the /policy/api/v1/ part of the URI.</p>
<p>When writing code in python, GoLang, or any other scripting language, we would use the same logic to make calls against the NSX Manager.  We will show real examples in the next blog post.</p>
<p>To learn more about automation, be sure to check out the following:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vmware.com/explore/video-library/video/6360758101112">Deep Dive into VMware vDefend Automation</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z8pp06bMELE">Let’s Talk Automation! Livestream episode</a></p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/12/getting-started-with-vmware-vdefend-automation-part-1.html">Getting Started with VMware vDefend Automation: Part 1</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend: Turbocharge Threat Defense with GenAI-Driven Intelligence</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/11/intelligent-assist-for-vdefend.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prashant Gandhi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advanced Threat Prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GenAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vDefend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="150" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg 700w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?resize=600,300 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>VMware vDefend’s GenAI co-pilot innovation speeds up ransomware threat defense with context-driven explainability of the attack chain, correlated threat campaign insights, and guided remediation. There&#8217;s a lot of euphoria around generative AI/GenAI today, not just among enterprises but also among threat actors wanting to cast a wider net for ransom. As these technologies evolve, they &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/11/intelligent-assist-for-vdefend.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/11/intelligent-assist-for-vdefend.html">Introducing Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend: Turbocharge Threat Defense with GenAI-Driven Intelligence</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="150" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg 700w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/11/199589491_xl.jpg?resize=600,300 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware vDefend’s GenAI co-pilot innovation speeds up ransomware threat defense with context-driven explainability of the attack chain, correlated threat campaign insights, and guided remediation.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There&#8217;s a lot of euphoria around generative AI/GenAI today, not just among enterprises but also among threat actors wanting to cast a wider net for ransom. As these technologies evolve, they will be more deeply embedded into security workflows, helping enterprises stay ahead of emerging threats and enabling defenders to be more effective than ever. VMware vDefend has long been at the forefront of the AI/ML innovation journey, which includes the use of AI for micro-segmentation rule recommendation and applying ML to traffic flows and workload contexts to deliver granular insights. We have now embarked on the logical but important next step with GenAI and Large Language Models (LLMs) to further enable customers to protect their crown jewels. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past year, our team has been hard at work on an initiative known as Project Cypress. The result is Intelligent Assist for vDefend, powered by GenAI and LLM. This new capability simplifies the way virtualization, network security, and SOC teams understand detailed, contextual information about active threats and their impact. With just a few clicks, teams can initiate remediation, streamlining processes that once required complex workflows across multiple-point products. By democratizing threat response, Intelligent Assist for vDefend enables security and infrastructure teams to operate far more collaboratively to defend against ransomware attacks and make a greater impact.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decoding the Complexity of Security Threats and Alerts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prior to the advent of Gen AI, correlating actions across campaigns or investigating the relationships between threats and alerts was a manual, time-consuming process. Attempts to integrate multiple-point solutions often introduced more complexity, increasing the risk of errors and visibility gaps.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All too often, critical context around an event—such as what occurred before and after—was missed. While there are numerous systems to score the severity or impact of vulnerabilities, they lack the ability to communicate this information in clear, natural language across teams, making it challenging to assess the true scope of threat campaigns. Sharing Indicators of Compromise (IoCs) for threat hunting has also been historically difficult for similar reasons.</span></p>
<p>Generative AI makes security operations faster and smoother. GenAI-powered tools significantly accelerate the ability of security teams to sift through large volumes of alerts, which would otherwise be overwhelming due to the high number of threats. GenAI can save hours—or even days—of manual efforts by intelligently prioritizing and correlating these alerts for appropriate remediation. This increase in speed translates directly to enhanced threat defense posture.</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Introducing Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At its core, Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend is an interactive chatbot powered by a Large Language Model (LLM) integrated directly into the vDefend user interface (UI). This chatbot explains detection events in plain English, helping security teams grasp the full impact of threats while enhancing collaboration across the organization. It helps security teams grasp the full impact of threats while enhancing collaboration across the organization. This not only lowers the false positive rate but also accelerates the remediation process. With an easy-to-use natural language interface, analysts can ask specific questions to gain deeper contextual insights whenever needed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Key features of Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend include its ability to explain threats in plain English, as well as its automated response and remediation capabilities. The platform is purposefully designed to offer a simple and intuitive user experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s dive into these features.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explainability</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider a typical ransomware scenario involving data exfiltration via tools like dnscat, which creates an encrypted Command-and-Control (C&amp;C) over the DNS protocol. With our comprehensive set of IDS signatures, vDefend detects this malicious activity and generates a high-impact detection event. Intelligent Assist provides additional context for the SOC operator, revealing that other events suggest Darkside ransomware was the initial attack vector. Moreover, it confirms that the impact is significant but currently contained to a specific workload. With this information in hand, the SOC team can confidently conclude that the event is a true positive, prompting immediate action.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-24-at-10.07.37-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-84141" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-24-at-10.07.37-AM-1024x818.png" alt="" width="1024" height="818" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Intelligent_Assist_Blog2.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-84140 aligncenter" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Intelligent_Assist_Blog2-703x1024.png" alt="" width="703" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Intelligent Assist’s ability to explain threats and events in plain English allows security, network and virtualization teams to immediately assess the scope and impact of individual threats. By automatically identifying related events and displaying Indicators of Compromise (IoCs), it eliminates visibility gaps across the security stack and accelerates time-to-insight far beyond what was previously possible.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automatic Response and Remediation</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once an event is verified as a true positive, rapid and effective remediation is crucial. This is where Intelligent Assist steps in again, taking automatic, immediate remediation actions while you continue gathering information and conducting forensic analyses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depending on your risk tolerance and the potential impact on legitimate traffic and business productivity, you can choose between a targeted or comprehensive response:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Targeted response:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This approach focuses on narrow, specific remediation actions to minimize business disruption. However, this &#8216;scalpel-like&#8217; strategy carries the risk of not fully containing the attack.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Comprehensive response:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Broader in scope, this &#8216;hammer&#8217; approach is more likely to prevent lateral threat movement but poses a higher risk of disrupting normal business operations.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whenever Intelligent Assist identifies an attack campaign, it recommends an appropriate response strategy. In the example below, involving an in-progress ransomware attack, Intelligent Assist has recommended a comprehensive remediation policy. While Intelligent Assist automates policy creation, it is not meant to be a fully autonomous system. The security team still has the final say—Intelligent Assist generates the policy, but it’s not enforced until reviewed and activated by a security expert. In this case, the recommended policy blocks all outbound DNS communication from the impacted workload to prevent further propagation of the threat.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-84135" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png" alt="" width="916" height="525" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png 916w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png?resize=300,172 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png?resize=768,440 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/Cypress_blog_image3.png?resize=600,344 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 916px) 100vw, 916px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seamless and Intuitive User Experience</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When designing Intelligent Assist, we focused on making the end-user experience as seamless and intuitive as possible. Features like chat export allow users to easily save and share relevant insights from conversations with other teams, while built-in feedback mechanisms ensure the system&#8217;s responses improve over time. Intelligent Assist also recommends queries, helping even the least experienced users unlock its full potential. The administrative dashboard is built to simplify user management, and multi-user session support, along with workflow management tools, enhances collaboration among various teams. Deploying Intelligent Assist is effortless. The solution leverages a secure Chrome browser extension, providing a direct communication channel. Simply download the extension, and you&#8217;re ready to go.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Try Intelligent Assist Today</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ready to take off with our threat defense co-pilot? You can find Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend Chrome extension <strong><a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/intelligent-assist-for-vm/ocancapkkpbfdfjbkindbaljgkhgkdpf">here</a>.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To learn more about Intelligent Assist, watch the VMware Explore Las Vegas 2024 technical breakout session </span><strong><a href="https://www.vmware.com/explore/video-library/video/6360758102112">here.</a></strong></p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/11/intelligent-assist-for-vdefend.html">Introducing Intelligent Assist for VMware vDefend: Turbocharge Threat Defense with GenAI-Driven Intelligence</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secure VCF Management Workload Domain with VMware vDefend</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/secure-vcf-management-workload-domain-with-vmware-vdefend.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikodim Nikodimov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 19:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCF Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[segmentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vDefend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workload management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84094</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="210" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg 1600w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=1024,717 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=600,420 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF) seamlessly integrates on-premises virtual infrastructure with the agility of the public cloud. This empowers customers to establish their own private cloud within a secure and controlled data center environment, delivering scalability, rapid innovation, and effective cost management. Security is a crucial consideration for any cloud environment. Organizations should design and implement &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/secure-vcf-management-workload-domain-with-vmware-vdefend.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/secure-vcf-management-workload-domain-with-vmware-vdefend.html">Secure VCF Management Workload Domain with VMware vDefend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="210" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg 1600w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=768,538 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=1024,717 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=1536,1075 1536w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2023/08/150DPIx-AdobeStock_87909563.jpg?resize=600,420 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF) seamlessly integrates on-premises virtual infrastructure with the agility of the public cloud. This empowers customers to establish their own private cloud within a secure and controlled data center environment, delivering scalability, rapid innovation, and effective cost management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Security is a crucial consideration for any cloud environment. Organizations should design and implement their VCF private cloud infrastructure using a zero-trust security approach to mitigate potential malicious activity.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use case</span></h2>
<p>Building a secure VCF private cloud infrastructure is the foundation for protecting organizations&#8217; applications that run on top of it. The Management workload domain is a critical element of the VCF stack, hosting the resources that power VCF and ensure continuous operations. It is essential that the VCF workload and its management components be equally protected at the required level to prevent potential network intrusion activities and misuse and to establish a secure VCF operation.</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solution</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware vDefend is the VCF integrated security solution that solves this matter through a distributed, scale-out architecture. The vDefend Distributed Firewall (DFW) is uniquely positioned outside the guest operating system but within the host itself, allowing it to protect the VCF private cloud in a way other solutions cannot. It provides a stateful L2-L7 firewall that is transparently applied to the workload&#8217;s network interface. This allows customers to implement any level of segmentation without redesigning the data center network infrastructure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VCF 5.2 (NSX 4.2) introduced new capabilities for customers to secure VCF workloads regardless of the network backing (NSX VLAN and Overlay segments, and vSphere VLAN distributed port groups &#8211; DVPGs). This new capability simplifies VCF customers&#8217; security journey by allowing them to enforce security without the need for workload migration from vSphere virtual distributed switch (VDS) networking backing to NSX segments. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notably, this also provides a simple, built-in approach to securing the VCF management components (SDDC Manager, vCenter Servers, NSX Managers, etc.) connected to vSphere DVPG.</span></p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-84095" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/VCF-Mgmt-WLD-NSX-on-DVPGs-1024x692.png" alt="" width="694" height="469" /></h2>
<h2></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To empower  VCF consumers with technical guidance on that matter, Broadcom&#8217;s Application Networking and Security (ANS) Division has published the &#8220;</span><a href="https://community.broadcom.com/HigherLogic/System/DownloadDocumentFile.ashx?DocumentFileKey=d617ff32-eff2-ba15-eca8-0a820b779bb9&amp;forceDialog=0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secure VCF Management Workload Domain with VMware vDefend</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8221; white paper. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The document directs VCF architects, infrastructure, and security administrators through the steps to implement vDefend Distributed Firewall (DFW) and protect the VCF Management domain components. It includes examples of security policies, recommendations, and implementation workflows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Check out this brief demo to learn how to use VMware vDefend DFW to protect the VCF Management workload domain.</span></p>
<div class="embed embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9"><script ot_flaged="1">appendContentOneTrust("4:1","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"How to Secure your VCF Management Domain using VMware vDefend Firewall\" width=\"500\" height=\"281\" src=\"https://www.youtube.com/embed/WWJw31jHjsc?feature=oembed\" frameborder=\"0\" allow=\"accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share\" referrerpolicy=\"strict-origin-when-cross-origin\" allowfullscreen ot_flaged=\"1\"></iframe>","content");</script></div>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WWJw31jHjsc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WWJw31jHjsc</a></p>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<h2>Summary</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware vDefend is a foundational element of NSX, providing cutting-edge capabilities for zero-trust lateral security. The vDefend Firewall delivers distributed, software-defined protection at the scale to ensure that VCF private cloud infrastructures and applications are safeguarded. vDefend is seamlessly integrated into VCF and is available immediately for consumption, thus making it the perfect choice for customers to protect their private cloud.</span></p>
<h2>References</h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://community.broadcom.com/HigherLogic/System/DownloadDocumentFile.ashx?DocumentFileKey=d617ff32-eff2-ba15-eca8-0a820b779bb9&amp;forceDialog=0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secure VCF Management Workload Domain with VMware vDefend &#8211; White Paper</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://community.broadcom.com/applications-networking-security/home"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VMware vDefend Community</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://github.com/vmware-nsx/vcf-mgmt-wld-security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Terraform config files GitHub repository</a></li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/secure-vcf-management-workload-domain-with-vmware-vdefend.html">Secure VCF Management Workload Domain with VMware vDefend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84094</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VMware vDefend: Latest Enhancements in Advanced Threat Prevention</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/vmware-vdefend-latest-enhancements-in-advanced-threat-prevention.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prashant Gandhi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Threat Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FS-ISAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-ISAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICS-CERT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vDefend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="162" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png 410w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png?resize=300,162 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>The latest enhancements to the VMware vDefend portfolio include custom IDS/IPS signature options tailored for industry-specific attacks and a malware analysis test drive for advanced malware analysis.  In today&#8217;s evolving threat landscape, digital enterprises face sophisticated, laterally mobile cyberattacks within their private cloud environments. Traditional perimeter defenses are simply insufficient to secure east-west application traffic. &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/vmware-vdefend-latest-enhancements-in-advanced-threat-prevention.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/vmware-vdefend-latest-enhancements-in-advanced-threat-prevention.html">VMware vDefend: Latest Enhancements in Advanced Threat Prevention</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="162" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png 410w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2022/05/Threat-Analysis-Unit_410x222.png?resize=300,162 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest enhancements to the VMware vDefend portfolio include custom IDS/IPS signature options tailored for industry-specific attacks and a malware analysis test drive for advanced malware analysis. </span></i></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In today&#8217;s evolving threat landscape, digital enterprises face sophisticated, laterally mobile cyberattacks within their private cloud environments. Traditional perimeter defenses are simply insufficient to secure east-west application traffic. Vulnerabilities such as Log4j and advanced malware such as Emotet serve as a wake-up call for all IT organizations. An effective security solution requires (1) comprehensive threat defense (including IDS/IPS, malware prevention, and network detection &amp; response), (2) micro-segmentation to ensure zero trust for applications and restrict lateral movement of threats, and (3) operating at large scale and performance to protect all applications. VMware vDefend has provided these advanced security capabilities with the </span><a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/cloud-infrastructure/vdefend-distributed-firewall"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Distributed Firewall</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/cloud-infrastructure/vdefend-advanced-threat-prevention"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Advanced Threat Prevention</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> portfolio to protect VCF private cloud application traffic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are excited to unveil new vDefend Advanced Threat Prevention enhancements with the VCF 5.2.1 release: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>IDS/IPS Custom Signature Support:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> For our distributed and hypervisor-integrated IDS/IPS offering, customers can now import their own custom IDS/IPS signatures or those sourced from third-party threat feeds, enabling tailored defenses against industry-specific attacks.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><b>Malware Analysis Test Drive:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This capability allows customers to upload artifacts (files/URLs) for in-depth analysis, providing crucial insights into highly evasive malware and zero-day threats. </span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Distributed IDS/IPS Enhancement – Custom IDS/IPS Signature Support</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">vDefend’s custom signature capabilities offer three key benefits: tailored defenses for applications, the ability to integrate third-party threat intelligence, and streamlined operational management of custom signatures. These features help enterprises stay ahead of evolving threats by customizing detection for their unique environments, incorporating industry-specific threat feeds, and simplifying signature lifecycle management. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Custom signatures allow businesses to protect critical applications with tailored defenses. With vDefend&#8217;s distributed IDS/IPS, organizations can create and deploy custom signatures or import existing sets (Figure 1), providing comprehensive monitoring for specialized applications. Security teams can capture (Figure 2) and analyze real-time traffic, and the insights can be used to generate these signatures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By integrating industry-specific intelligence from platforms like ICS-CERT for critical infrastructure/Industrial Control Systems (ICS) or from Information Sharing and Analysis Centers (ISACs), such as FS-ISAC for financial services or H-ISAC for healthcare, customers can protect against targeted threats like attacks on SCADA systems, transaction fraud or breaches of personal health information (PHI). Additionally, the ability to consume non-industry-specific threat intelligence or threat-sharing platforms like MISP (Malware Information Sharing Platform), which offer early indicators of emerging threats, can help customers to &#8220;virtually patch&#8221; vulnerabilities by deploying customized signatures before official updates are released. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operationally, vDefend simplifies custom signature management with tools for lifecycle control, ensuring accuracy and performance. Logs for custom signatures (Figure 3) integrate into the product UI and can be exported to SIEM, while PCAP collection enables precise packet analysis, further enhancing detection and response.</span></p>
<p><figure id="attachment_84083" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-84083" style="width: 850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure1_IDS_IPS_sig_screenshot.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84083" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure1_IDS_IPS_sig_screenshot-1024x337.png" alt="" width="850" height="280" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-84083" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Figure 1. Custom IDS Signature Management</em></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_84082" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-84082" style="width: 850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure-2-PCAP_screenshot.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84082" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure-2-PCAP_screenshot-1024x281.png" alt="" width="850" height="233" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-84082" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Figure 2. Packet Capture Files &#8211; View and Download</em></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_84084" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-84084" style="width: 850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure3_IDPS-event.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-84084" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/10/421blog_figure3_IDPS-event-1024x282.png" alt="" width="850" height="234" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-84084" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Figure 3. IDPS Event generated from a Custom Signature</em></figcaption></figure></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><br style="font-weight: 400;" /><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malware Analysis Test Drive</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For vDefend Distributed Firewall users, the malware analysis test drive provides limited-time access to advanced malware analysis, allowing customers to upload artifacts (files and URLs) for detailed examination without impacting production systems. Security analysts, who are constantly seeking out new malware—sometimes even scouring the dark web for emerging threats—can use this feature to test malware samples in a secure sandbox environment. This allows them to understand the behavior of new and evasive threats, including zero-day exploits. The resulting reports provide deep visibility into how malware interacts with the CPU, memory, and network. With this powerful functionality, organizations can better understand the behavior of emerging threats and strengthen their defenses.</span></p>
<h2><br style="font-weight: 400;" /><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s Next?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we push the boundaries of cybersecurity innovation for lateral (east-west) traffic, vDefend remains at the forefront of defending against advanced threats with its multi-layer defense-in-depth distributed security approach. The fact that vDefend is plug-and-play (fully integrated) with VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF) private cloud, enables customers to deploy vDefend at speed and operate it at scale. Afterall, if lateral security roll-out is slow or it is not applicable to all workloads, the enterprise is really not secure. With vDefend, we are innovating across all aspects of lateral security.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Join us at VMware Explore Barcelona (November 4-7, 2024) to dive deeper into our latest innovations. Don’t miss out—</span><a href="https://www.vmware.com/explore/eu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">register today!</span></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br style="font-weight: 400;" /><br style="font-weight: 400;" /></span></em></p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/10/vmware-vdefend-latest-enhancements-in-advanced-threat-prevention.html">VMware vDefend: Latest Enhancements in Advanced Threat Prevention</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84078</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VMware vDefend Security Sessions at VMware Explore Barcelona 2024</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/09/vmware-vdefend-security-sessions-at-vmware-explore-barcelona-2024.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bhanu Vemula]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 18:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Threat Intelligence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png 1280w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=1024,576 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=600,338 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>VMware Explore Barcelona 2024 preparations are underway, and we couldn’t be more excited!  Mark your calendars for this year’s European event at Fira Gran Via in Barcelona from 4 – 7 November. The content catalog and session scheduling tool are now available, waiting for you to choose your favorites. In today’s ever-evolving cybersecurity arena, vDefend &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/09/vmware-vdefend-security-sessions-at-vmware-explore-barcelona-2024.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/09/vmware-vdefend-security-sessions-at-vmware-explore-barcelona-2024.html">VMware vDefend Security Sessions at VMware Explore Barcelona 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png 1280w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=1024,576 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/09/Explore_Blog1_graphic.png?resize=600,338 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p><a href="https://www.vmware.com/explore/eu?utm_source=sma&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=vmx24"><strong>VMware Explore</strong></a> Barcelona 2024 preparations are underway, and we couldn’t be more excited!  Mark your calendars for this year’s European event at Fira Gran Via in Barcelona from 4 – 7 November. The content catalog and session scheduling tool are now available, waiting for you to choose your favorites.</p>
<p>In today’s ever-evolving cybersecurity arena, vDefend is at the forefront of protecting your private cloud from ransomware and other threats with advanced security capabilities such as distributed firewall, gateway firewall, advanced threat prevention, security intelligence, and more. There are so many sessions to choose from – our featured session with Application Networking and Security General Manager Umesh Mahajan, breakouts, tutorials, hands-on labs, and an opportunity to meet the experts.</p>
<h2>Featured Session</h2>
<h3>Ransomware Prevention and Cloud-Speed Application Delivery: Innovations in vDefend and Avi [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1237">ANSP1237BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Distributed, software-defined security and load balancing are critical to rapidly deploy applications and defend against malware and ransomware in a secure and resilient VCF private cloud. VMware vDefend and Avi Load Balancer are plug-and-play network services for VCF, delivering operational simplicity with unmatched visibility and application analytics to cloud and security admins. VMware vDefend protects your applications and data from unrelenting ransomware attacks and accelerates your journey to Zero Trust with multi-layer, defense-in-depth security. GenAI co-pilot with vDefend revolutionizes threat detection and transforms SOC operations by alleviating alert fatigue. Avi Load Balancer ensures app delivery at cloud speed with an elastic load balancer, container ingress, and web application firewall. Join this session to learn about new innovations and strategic directions for vDefend and Avi to drastically buy-down cyber risk and accelerate application delivery.</p>
<p>Umesh Mahajan, VP &amp; GM, Application Networking and Security, Broadcom<br />
Stijn Vanveerdeghem, Senior Manager, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h2>Breakout Sessions</h2>
<h3>The Conman of the Digital Era: Ransomware [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1237">ANSB1217BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Ransomware, the modern-day conman, is a boardroom conversation. Protecting your business from the conman is everyone&#8217;s responsibility—not just your security team—because the conman doesn’t just knock on your security team’s door; he knocks on your door, too. The conman&#8217;s attacks are notoriously hard to detect because they are surprisingly simple yet unsuspecting. With access to ChatGPT, the conman is more powerful than ever. The purpose of this session is to teach you how the conman thinks and what you can do about it. This session will dissect a ransomware attack from the conman’s perspective, using VMware vDefend to illuminate strategies to thwart these threats before they cause harm. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned security professional or an IT enthusiast, this session will equip you with the knowledge to combat the conman of the digital age.</p>
<p>Prashant Gandhi, Head of Products, Broadcom<br />
Srinivas Nimmagadda, Director, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Reveal Your Application Flows with Security Intelligence [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1167">ANSB1167BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Security Intelligence reveals your network traffic flows in a matter of minutes. Without the need for installing agents, deploying a TAP, or making any network configuration change, you get immediate deep visibility on your network flows, and you can review your security posture. In this session, you will see how Security Intelligence avoids any blind spot and provides layer-7 information and OS processes context. We will show you how to leverage clustering, labels or filters in the graphical user interface so you can manage your flows view at scale. Finally, we will demonstrate how Security Intelligence can analyze traffic patterns and detect suspicious network activity, which is a key element for network detection and response.</p>
<p>Antoine Deleporte, Technical Product Manager, Broadcom<br />
Catherine Fan, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Demystifying Distributed Security in VMware Cloud Foundation [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?search=1015&amp;int_cid=vmwx_exploreblog&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW">ANSB1015BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>People&#8217;s Choice Winner!</p>
<p>VMware vDefend Distributed Firewall (DFW), Distributed Intrusion Detection System (DIDS), and Distributed Intrusion Protection System (DIPS) provide security services in the kernel through processing of rules and signatures intrinsically within the virtual networking infrastructure. Great, so how does it work? We show the inner workings of the distributed services from an architectural standpoint, but more importantly, the best implementation techniques, as well as troubleshooting tools for examining the effectiveness of the strategy deployed. We show how to simplify the configuration of the centrally managed protection mechanisms and greatly reduce the time and effort needed to put a tight security policy in place.</p>
<p>Tim Burkard, Staff Technical Learning Engineer, Broadcom<br />
Chris McCain, Director, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Bootstrapping Segmentation and Zero-Trust in your VMware Cloud Foundation Private Cloud [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1214">ANSB1214BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Micro-segmentation is an essential Zero Trust technique for preventing the lateral movement of malware and ransomware. Security teams are often stymied when they attempt to micro-segment large-scale, diverse, and sprawling private cloud environments. In this session, we&#8217;ll show how you can successfully micro-segment large, complex, and sprawling private clouds quickly and effectively using Security Intelligence.</p>
<p>Kausum Kumar, Product Management, Broadcom<br />
Ranga Rajagopalan, CTO &#8211; ANS Division, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Uncover Threats and Stop Ransomware with VMware vDefend [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1216">ANSB1216BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Almost half of all breaches today involve threat actors taking advantage of the high degree of freedom of movement within internal enterprise networks to gain access to your most valuable assets. Traditional security solutions have left organizations in the dark about what happens within their virtualized environments, enabling attackers to lurk within for months before being discovered. Lack of visibility, limited automation, operational silos, and security policies that are decoupled from the assets being protected have led to operational inefficiencies and unmitigated risks. Join us in this session to learn about how the VMware Firewall and Advanced Threat Prevention enable you to turn on the lights in your data centers and beyond and stop unauthorized lateral movement in its tracks.</p>
<p>Stijn Vanveerdeghem, Senior Manager, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Deep Dive into VMware vDefend Automation [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1169">ANSB1169BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>When building new applications on-premises, developers want to use automation to control the infrastructure. With VMware vDefend, you can use automation to deploy your security policy and your workloads. As new workloads are created, policy is automatically applied and cleaned up when removed from the environment. Greenfield deployments can instantly be secured using the VMware vDefend toolkit. In this session, we look at ways to automate VMware vDefend using many different frameworks. Automation can give you quick results and simplify operationalizing your on-premises cloud.</p>
<p>Srinivas Nimmagadda, Director, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom<br />
Antoine Deleporte, Technical Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Security Reference Design for VMware Cloud Foundation [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1235">ANSB1235BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Attend this session to learn how to design security for VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF) management and workload domains. This session will include best practices for segmentation using VMware vDefend Distributed Firewall, policy management across multiple VCF instances, IDS/IPS, and threat prevention design best practices.</p>
<p>Nikodim Nikodimov, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Elevate Your Threat Investigation Workflow with the GenAI Security Intelligent Assist [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*jcum6s*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MjcuMC4wLjA.&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1189">ANSB1189BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>Security operators are tasked with investigating and responding to security incidents. With limited information and assistance, key tasks—such as triaging, contextualizing, and responding to incidents in a timely manner—place a burden on resources and sometimes results in suboptimal outcomes. The Intelligent Assist security assistant is designed to address these challenges by leveraging GenAI and machine learning. This demo-based session will cover how Intelligent Assist enables chatbot-enabled explainability of threat detection events on the VMware vDefend Distributed Firewall, and remediation through automatic policy creation.</p>
<p>Bopaiah Puliyanda, Senior Manager, Technology Product Mgr, Broadcom<br />
Ranga Rajagopalan, CTO &#8211; ANS Division, Broadcom</p>
<h3>Container Security – Policy Management for Kubernetes Workloads [<a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW&amp;search=1572">ANSB1572BCN</a>]</h3>
<p>This session gives a quick overview of the overall container security portfolio. It covers design recommendations with zero trust security policy for your container workloads running on VMware Cloud Foundation and upstream Kubernetes. This session also provides guidelines for designing policies that span across both Virtual Machine workloads and Container workloads.</p>
<p>Madhukar Krishnarao, Sr Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<h2>Tutorial</h2>
<p>With the growing landscape of malicious threat actors and the continued sophistication of attacks, security cannot be relegated to one group within the IT organization. Every part of the IT structure must adopt a security mindset. From architects to developers, security must be top of mind and built into all parts of the enterprise architecture. This session will showcase how to use the VMware vDefend Firewall to quickly and easily buy down risk against common attack methods and tools to create a more secure private cloud with VMware Cloud Foundation. This session will allow attendees to better understand the anatomy of an attack and why vDefend Firewall is a powerful tool for mitigating the standard practices of today&#8217;s attack chain. The session will include demos that show how easy it can be to protect your private cloud.</p>
<p>Chris McCain, Technology Product Management, Broadcom<br />
Stijn Vanveerdeghem, Senior Manager, Technology Product Manager, Broadcom</p>
<p><a href="https://myevents.vmware.com/widget/vmware/explore2024bcn/1726092693551001mwvT"><strong>These sessions</strong></a> allow attendees to learn directly from top experts, advance their professional development, and accelerate their progress toward Zero Trust.</p>
<p>Join us by <a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/reg/form/contactInfo?_gl=1*ggu5n8*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MzkuMC4wLjA.">registering</a> and <a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024bcn/content/page/catalog?_gl=1*15x7ji2*_ga*MTk0NDQ4MDM1Ni4xNzI2NTMxMDQz*_ga_8VJHMNGE3E*MTcyNzIwMzkxMi4xMi4xLjE3MjcyMDU2MzkuMC4wLjA.">reserving your seat</a> at these incredible sessions. We look forward to seeing you!</p><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/09/vmware-vdefend-security-sessions-at-vmware-explore-barcelona-2024.html">VMware vDefend Security Sessions at VMware Explore Barcelona 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VMware vDefend Innovations: Elevating Enterprise Lateral Threat Defense for the GenAI Era</title>
		<link>https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/08/vmware-vdefend-innovations-elevating-enterprise-lateral-threat-defense-for-genai-era.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prashant Gandhi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Threat Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workload Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall rule analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GenAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[threat assessment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blogs.vmware.com/security/?p=84014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png 1276w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=768,433 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=1024,578 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=600,339 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<p>Highlights: Innovations focus on GenAI assist for threat defense; greater performance, assessment and deployment flexibility for malware and ransomware prevention; VCF 9 integrations and Zero trust lateral security enhancements We are in an early stage of a thrilling journey with generative AI (GenAI) and large language models (LLMs).  There is tremendous excitement in regards to &#8230; <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/08/vmware-vdefend-innovations-elevating-enterprise-lateral-threat-defense-for-genai-era.html">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/08/vmware-vdefend-innovations-elevating-enterprise-lateral-threat-defense-for-genai-era.html">VMware vDefend Innovations: Elevating Enterprise Lateral Threat Defense for the GenAI Era</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="169" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?w=300" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 10px;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png 1276w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=768,433 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=1024,578 1024w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Explore.png?resize=600,339 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div><p style="text-align: center;"><em>Highlights:</em> Innovations focus on GenAI assist for threat defense; greater performance, assessment and deployment flexibility for malware and ransomware prevention; VCF 9 integrations and Zero trust lateral security enhancements</p>
<p>We are in an early stage of a thrilling journey with generative AI (GenAI) and large language models (LLMs).  There is tremendous excitement in regards to the benefits GenAI/LLMs can offer, especially in enterprise security. Sadly, the same technologies are being utilized by attackers to probe for weaknesses in enterprise defenses to get to the crown jewels (critical enterprise data). This is enabling attackers to launch increasingly faster and more complex attacks. The traditional approach—providing strong protection for crown jewels (business-critical apps) and basic protection for all other workloads—has been proven radically ineffective. This has become a boon for attackers, who can easily infiltrate non-critical workloads and move laterally toward critical assets.</p>
<p>To meet this challenge, enterprises must quickly adopt multi-layered defensive strategies emphasizing zero trust for application access and strict adherence to the principle of least privilege. Often overwhelmed by managing multiple disparate point products, security teams yearn for a comprehensive full-stack, hypervisor-integrated solution that offers <em>visibility</em>, <em>segmentation</em>, and <em>threat defense</em> and is easy to deploy and operate. A lateral security solution must be deployed at speed, operate at scale, diagnose quickly in case of a security incident, and reduce the overall cost of ownership.</p>
<p>At Explore Las Vegas 2024, we are highlighting our next chapter of innovations for the GenAI era:</p>
<ul>
<li>Project Cypress: GenAI-based intelligent assist for threat defense for alert triaging, contextualize insights into threat campaigns and remediation recommendations</li>
<li>Malware and Ransomware Prevention enhancements:
<ul>
<li>Distributed IDS/IPS: 2X – 3X performance increase (ideal for AI/ML workloads), and support for multi-site (multi-instance) VCF with centralized management (delivering consistent enterprise-wide security posture)</li>
<li>Malware Prevention: Support both file-based and file-less (in-memory) malware prevention as well as on-prem deployment for regulated organizations with air-gapped environments.</li>
<li>Rapid Threat Assessment: Comprehensive east-west threat assessment and reporting without the need to install agents.</li>
<li>Bare metal workload support: Enhanced threat detection and prevention support for bare metal workloads for unified security across physical and virtual environments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>VCF 9 Integrations
<ul>
<li>VCF Import: Simplify the integration of existing security configurations into VCF 9</li>
<li>Native VPC Integration: Integrate security workflows with VPC functionality, enabling firewall admins to define and delegate security policies to app owners for self-service operations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Zero Trust Lateral Security Enhancements
<ul>
<li>Firewall Rule Impact Analysis: Advanced rules analysis provides immediate visibility into how security policies impact workloads. Eliminate ineffective and redundant rules to ensure optimized security effectiveness.</li>
<li>Geo IP filtering: Uniquely manage and secure traffic by allowing or blocking connections to a specific geographic location directly at the T0 gateway firewall, enabling precise control over global traffic flows.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2>Project Cypress: GenAI Co-pilot for Threat Defense</h2>
<p>Security teams struggle with high false positive rates and the complexity of threat triage workflows. It hasn’t been simple to correlate actions across campaigns or to determine which alerts are related to the same threat. Project Cypress, powered by GenAI and LLM, can change the game, making it faster to understand the true scope and impact of threats and remediate high-impact events with just a few clicks. Security analysts can interact with vDefend through an easy-to-understand natural language interface. They can see which alerts are related to one another at a glance, ask questions to gain additional context, and get recommendations for effective remediation steps. The GenAI copilot eliminates false positives, reduces the number of alerts by ~10X, gives security teams greater situational awareness across their environment, and speeds up remediation.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-84037" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg" alt="" width="816" height="275" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg 816w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg?resize=300,101 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg?resize=768,259 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/cypress_blog_image0823.jpg?resize=600,202 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 816px) 100vw, 816px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Malware and Ransomware Prevention Enhancements</h2>
<h3>Industry-leading malware detection capabilities deployable on-premises for highly regulated industries</h3>
<p>Thorough file analysis is essential for detecting and blocking file-based threats. The VMware hypervisor can act as a sensor, intercepting files locally before they’re written to disk and extracting them for analysis through the Guest Introspection functionality. VMware vDefend’s comprehensive detection pipeline performs static file analysis as well as advanced dynamic analytic techniques such as memory analysis, ML-based behavioral analysis, and code gene analysis to identify and block malicious files. Formerly available only in our cloud sandbox environment, these analytic activities can now be conducted on-premises, meeting regulatory requirements that mandate air-gapped VCF deployments since no data is sent outside of the organization’s environment for analysis.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-84034" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg" alt="" width="797" height="423" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg 797w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg?resize=768,408 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/Onprem_blogimage_0823.jpg?resize=600,318 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 797px) 100vw, 797px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Centralized global management of IDS/IPS policies and signatures across multi-instance VCF deployments</h3>
<p>Customers with large, multi-instance (federated) environments require consistent, organization-wide IDS/IPS security policy and signature management. Planned centralized policy management capabilities make it possible to deliver global IDS/IPS security policies across distributed VCF deployments. Support for multiple IDS/IPS signature bundle assignments allows customers to apply specific signature bundles where needed across their VCF deployments, and an air-gapped mode enables delivery of IDS/IPS signature bundles to Local Managers even when internet connectivity and compliance restrictions are in place. Together, these capabilities ensure consistent threat prevention policies across multi-instance VCF deployments and simplify operations with all IDS/IPS events made visible within a single management console (Global Manager).</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-84043" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png" alt="" width="804" height="442" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png 804w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png?resize=300,165 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png?resize=768,422 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/hypervisor_blog.png?resize=600,330 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 804px) 100vw, 804px" /></a></p>
<h3>Security Intelligence: Rapid Threat Assessment</h3>
<p>Security operations teams need to understand the current state of their environment so that they can quickly take action to evict any malicious actors that might be lurking around. Installing agents or additional tools takes time and effort, impacting performance and end-user experience. VMware vDefend now enables security teams to use the VMware hypervisor as a threat sensor, so they can perform a comprehensive east-west threat assessment by leveraging a solution that is already in place. Threat profiling can be completed with just a few clicks, and because vDefend is integrated with VCF, security teams can immediately act upon the findings. Security Intelligence for vDefend leverages AI and machine learning (ML) to create security rules and policy recommendations based on the threat assessment, and vDefend Distributed Firewall can implement these rules and policies immediately. Not only can security operations teams better understand their current security posture by conducting this assessment, but also can readily deploy advanced controls to block any future lateral movement of threats.</p>
<h2>VCF 9 Integrations</h2>
<h3>vDefend: Integration with Native VPC</h3>
<p>VMware vDefend will integrate with VCF 9 native VPC to allow security administrators to set information security standards that will be consistently enforced across their VPC and delegate controls to individual application teams for self-service. vDefend gives administrators more granular control over threat prevention so that policies can be applied to individual applications. Security Groups can designate VPC-level policies, and logs can be generated at a per-VPC level.</p>
<h2>Zero Trust Lateral Security Enhancements</h2>
<h3>Distributed Firewall: Enhanced Firewall Rule Analysis</h3>
<p>Visibility into how security policies impact business operations is critical for security operations teams, but stakeholders also need to understand whether their policies are effective. Planned enhancements to the Security Intelligence rule recommendation engine will enable users to rapidly identify and eliminate rules that do not improve security effectiveness. Dynamic policy analysis will allow organizations to reduce their attack surface by weeding out overly permissive, ineffective, and redundant rules. Conflict and overlap analysis will enable the simplification and consolidation of policies, while predictive impact analysis helps teams understand the impact that security policies would have on business operations before they’re put into place. These capabilities allow customers to design and deploy simple but highly effective security policies and update them at application deployment speed in real-time. Ongoing health monitoring immediately alerts if newly deployed applications require changes to the security policy environment.</p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-84038" src="https://blogs.vmware.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg" alt="" width="798" height="348" srcset="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg 798w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg?resize=300,131 300w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg?resize=768,335 768w, https://blogs.vmware.com/security/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2024/08/rule_analysis_0823.jpg?resize=600,262 600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 798px) 100vw, 798px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This comprehensive set of innovations further strengthens VMware vDefend multi-layer zero trust lateral security to protect your VCF Private Cloud.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer &#8211; Statements regarding plans, directions, and intent are subject to change or withdrawal without notice at the sole discretion of VMware.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vmware.com/explore/us">Join us</a> at Explore 2024 Las Vegas to learn about our innovations and strategy in our Application Networking and Security Division.</p>
<ul>
<li>Keynote session, <a href="https://event.vmware.com/flow/vmware/explore2024lv/content/page/catalog?search=2267&amp;tab.contentcatalogtabs=1627421929827001vRXW">Innovations in Ransomware Prevention and Cloud-Speed Application Delivery with vDefend and Avi</a></li>
<li><a href="https://myevents.vmware.com/widget/vmware/explore2024lv/1721177261882001CqR1">Curated list of sessions on VMware vDefend at Explore</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Read our prior blogs, whitepapers and business value study on VMware vDefend.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/05/vmware-vdefend-defending-corporate-crown-jewels-against-unrelenting-cyber-attacks.html">VMware vDefend – Defending Corporate Crown Jewels Against Unrelenting Cyber Attacks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/06/vmware-vdefend-lateral-security-new-innovations.html">VMware vDefend Lateral Security: New Innovations to Strengthen Enterprise Ransomware Defense</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.vmware.com/docs/vmware-secure-private-cloud-with-vmware-vdefend">Secure your Private Cloud with VMware vDefend</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.vmware.com/docs/vmware-business-value-networking-lateral-security-vcf">Customer Business Value Study of VMware vDefend</a></li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security/2024/08/vmware-vdefend-innovations-elevating-enterprise-lateral-threat-defense-for-genai-era.html">VMware vDefend Innovations: Elevating Enterprise Lateral Threat Defense for the GenAI Era</a> appeared first on <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/security">VMware Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">84014</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
