<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>World &#8211; TIME</title>
	<atom:link href="https://time.com/world/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://time.com</link>
	<description>Current &#38; Breaking News &#124; National &#38; World Updates</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 17:50:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">228315549</site>	<item>
		<title>Even as They Are Driven Into Bomb Shelters, Many Ordinary Israelis Support the Attack on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294940/israel-iran-attack-support-netanyahu/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294940/israel-iran-attack-support-netanyahu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Orly Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 16:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many Israelis were surprised by the Iran attack but, even from shelters, many still support it.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294940"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294940/israel-iran-attack-support-netanyahu/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Israel-iran-trump-005.jpg" alt="Israelis take shelter in an underground station as they anticipate another missile attack by Iran on June, 17 2025."/>



<p><a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >Israel</a> has taken on the eerie quiet of a ghost town. Shops are closed, streets nearly empty. The occasional car races to its destination.</p>



<p>In the supermarkets, many shelves are empty, usually of basic necessities: No bread, no milk, no eggs, no diapers and no bottled water for what may be extended stays in bomb shelters. Israelis have stocked up not knowing what their government is planning and how this will unfold.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>Israel&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sudden attack</a> on <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >Iran</a> that began at 3 a.m. on June 13, Friday, didn&rsquo;t catch only the Iranians by surprise. No one in Israel expected a full-scale assault&mdash;not before the end of the school year; before <a href="https://time.com/7276739/trump-iran-diplomacy-oman/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">talks</a> on Iran&#8217;s nuclear program ended between the U.S. and Iran; or before the<em> </em>controversially lavish, <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/planned-wedding-of-pms-son-canceled-amid-conflict-with-iran/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">wedding </a>of Avner Netanyahu, the son of Prime Minister Benjamin <a href="https://time.com/7294186/israel-warns-tehran-will-burn-deadly-strikes-traded-nuclear-program/" >Netanyahu</a>, set to take place three days later. </p>



<p>When the sirens first went off in towns and cities across the country very early Friday morning, many people stayed in bed, knowing that <a href="https://time.com/7049499/oct-7-anniversary-israel-hamas-hezbollah-iran-future/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">earlier campaigns</a> had wiped out the rocket capabilities of <a href="https://time.com/tag/israel-hamas-war/" >Hamas</a> in the Gaza Strip on Israel&#8217;s western flank, and <a href="https://time.com/7049289/hezbollah-israel-war/" >Hezbollah</a>, on its northern border. An impending attack wasn&rsquo;t on their radar. </p>



<p>&ldquo;I was preparing food for the Sabbath on Friday morning, kubbeh and borekas, and I turned on the radio and was shocked,&rdquo; said Rivka Benayim, a cashier at a supermarket in Jerusalem. Her store had no baby wipes, fresh chicken or tomatoes and very little milk. &ldquo;I had no idea we were at war with Iran.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Israelis now realize&nbsp;that a tit-for-tat with Iran is nothing like a barrage of rockets from Palestinian militants in the Gaza, or from Hezbollah fighters in southern Lebanon. The reach and destructive power of Iran&#8217;s missiles has made everyone feel vulnerable.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Hamas fired&nbsp;rockets made out of traffic sign poles,&rdquo; said Shlomo Alkobi, 25, an employee at a cellphone company service center, at work in a job classified by the Isareli government as essential. &ldquo;Those are like kindergarten games compared to Iran&rsquo;s ballistic missiles.&rdquo;</p>



<p>So it is that, since the first barrages landed, even more Israelis than usual have been heeding the Home Front Command&rsquo;s alerts that flash on their cellphone screens, TV sets and radio programs when the missiles get close, often accompanied by a frightening screeching alarm.</p>



<p>In Israel, there are three types of &#8220;safe space.&#8221; Any apartment building constructed after1992 has a reinforced room, or <em>mamad</em>, in each apartment (a requirement put in place after Saddam Hussein&#8217;s Iraq <a href="https://time.com/archive/6716979/the-dangerous-dinosaur/" >launched Scud</a> missiles toward it during the First Gulf War). <a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" >Older buildings</a> may have a shared bomb shelter under ground. For people who find themselves driving when the sirens sound, or on foot, or in a building with no reinforced space, the only option is to run to a public shelters that dot populated areas around the country.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Israel-iran-trump-007.jpg" alt="TEL AVIV, ISRAEL - JUNE 18: Israel's 'Iron Dome' air defense system responds to incoming Iranian ballistic missiles as seen from Tel Aviv, Israel on June 18, 2025. (Photo by Mostafa Alkharouf/Anadolu via Getty Images)" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>During a Hamas missile barrage, an elderly relative of mine would settle for sitting on the steps in the stairwell of his second-floor apartment in Bat Yam, a coastal suburb of Tel Aviv. But with the Iranian salvos, he has been making his way down to the building&rsquo;s first-floor bomb shelter a couple times a day and waiting with the rest of the tenants for the all clear. His first time down there, he was appalled to discover it was filled with a thick layer of dust, and the clutter of bicycles and a baby carriage.</p>



<p>On the second night, his focus was elsewhere. An Iranian missile struck<a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/body-recovered-from-rubble-of-bat-yam-building-hit-by-iranian-missile-bringing-death-toll-to-seven/"  target="_blank"> an apartment building</a> 500 meters away from his. Five people were killed.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We could feel the shock waves underground,&rdquo; he said.</p>



<p>Many Israelis are shocked by the level of destruction. While Israel&#8217;s military does not reveal damage to its installations, it encourages people to film damage to civilian areas. Israeli reporters say they have never seen such devastation, at least in person; the results of their military&#8217;s work in Gaza appears on TV.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/" ><em>Lawmakers Seek to Limit Trump From Dragging U.S. Into Israel-Iran War</em></a></p>



<p>Some communities are entirely unprotected. The desert villages of Bedouin Israelis lack shelters because the government refuses to recognize their settlements. Residents have been entirely exposed; some have taken cover under highway bridges. </p>



<p>Many villages of Israeli citizens who are Palestinian (who account for 20 percent of the country&#8217;s population) also lack shelters. But in those that do have them, the assumption that they would not be targeted by Iranian missiles has been enough to keep some from seeking whatever shelter might be available.</p>



<p>The illusion shattered Saturday night, when a missile that appeared bound for the northern city of Haifa struck a villa in nearby Tamra, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/06/16/middleeast/israel-iran-tamra-shelters-latam-hnk-intl"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">killing four women</a> from the Khatib family. Locals point to video taken from their rooftops and say the missile fell after an Iron Dome anti-missile battery tried to intercept it, changing its trajectory. The victims had a safe room built in their home, but had not entered it. </p>



<p>Israel has long claimed that it avoids civilian casualties, while accusing Iran of intentionally targeting noncombatants. But Israeli strikes on Iran, which began with precise strikes on leading regime figures, have also killed scores of civilians. A human rights group <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-iran-war-latest-06-15-2025-291df01b03179cd414db21ca33791b39"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">put the total at</a> 406 through June 15.<br><br>Iran may also be targeting senior security figures in Israeli residential buildings. Over the last year, Israel&rsquo;s internal security agency, Shin Bet, has uncovered <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-jews-who-spied-iran-biggest-infiltration-decades-2024-12-11/"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">nearly 30 cases of espionage and subversion by Israelis,</a> mostly Jews, recruited to work for Iran. In some cases, Tehran sought to gather information on former senior officials in the security establishment, including their home address and daily routines.  </p>



<p>In Rishon L&rsquo;Tzion, south of Tel Aviv, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx270vklvv7o"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">an Iranian missile</a> struck near the former home of a former high ranking security official early Saturday, June 14. Asked if he believed he might have been the target, he told <a href="https://www.maariv.co.il/news/military/article-1205347"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"><em>Maariv</em></a> newspaper that if he was, the Iranians &ldquo;haven&rsquo;t updated their lists since 2007.&rdquo; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Israel-iran-trump-006.jpg" alt="A billboard bearing a picture of U.S. President Donald Trump accompanied by a message, is deployed in central Tel Aviv on June 18, 2025." alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Israel&#8217;s death toll<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-iran-attack-strikes-news-06-16-25-intl-hnk"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"> reached 24</a> in four nights&mdash;far less than in Iran, with more than <a href="https://time.com/7294722/iran-israel-war-trump-strike/" >220 killed</a>&mdash;and a fraction of the number of Palestinians killed in an average day in <a href="https://time.com/7286958/israel-gaza-aid-babies-netanyahu-airstrikes/" >Gaza</a>. Yet for Israelis, it&#8217;s a jarring loss. In the 17 years between 2004 to 2021, only <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palestinian_rocket_attacks_on_Israel"  target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">32 civilians were killed inside Israel</a> by rockets out of Gaza. </p>



<p>Even so, many here are excited by the attack on Iran. Israelis are expecting nothing less than regime change. Religious Jews were filmed dancing in celebration in an underground parking lot where they took cover during an air raid siren.</p>



<p>&ldquo;They have been threatening to destroy us for years,&rdquo; said Alkobi, the cell phone merchant. &ldquo;We are removing the threat. I want to annihilate them. Assassinate the whole regime.&rdquo; </p>



<p>Ayala Hasson, an anchor on Israel&#8217;s national television, called it a &lsquo;dramatic historic day&rsquo; and had difficulty suppressing her smile. On the radio, an Israeli news reporter thanked a pilot for his service before interviewing him.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" ><em>Air Supremacy Over Tehran Gives Israel a Decisive Edge&mdash;And Raises New Risks</em></a></p>



<p>But not all Israelis are cheering. Some expressed wariness of how the new war would end. Others remained focused on the one it interrupted. </p>



<p>&ldquo;They no longer open every TV program with a mention of the number of hostages and the days in captivity,&rdquo; Dani Elgarat, whose brother Itsik died in capativity, wrote on X. </p>



<p>&ldquo;There is no discussion in the studios about the kidnapped people&hellip;From today, we are counting barrages, missiles, and deaths, not hostages. Netanyahu reset the war clock, and erased the calendar of desolation. Don&#8217;t forget, echo, keep counting, don&#8217;t be silent until they return.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294940/israel-iran-attack-support-netanyahu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294940</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran&#8217;s Supreme Leader Calls Out Trump, Threatens &#8216;Irreparable Damage&#8217; If U.S. Joins Israeli Conflict </title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Any U.S. military intervention will undoubtedly be accompanied by irreparable damage,” Khamenei warned.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295471"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220030759.jpg" alt="Iranian Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei addresses the nation"/>



<p>Iran&rsquo;s Ayatollah Ali <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2025/06/18/3337849/ayatollah-khamenei-warns-us-to-avoid-military-engagement-against-iran"  target="_blank">Khamenei issued a grave warning to the U.S</a>. on Wednesday, telling the country it would suffer &ldquo;irreparable damage&rdquo; if it engages in military action against Iran amid its <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" >conflict with Israel</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The Americans should know that any U.S. military intervention will undoubtedly be accompanied by irreparable damage,&rdquo; Khamenei said in a televised address. &ldquo;The U.S. entering in this matter [war] is 100% to its own detriment. The damage it will suffer will be far greater than any harm that Iran may encounter.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>His statement was also <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935301111050641472"  target="_blank">shared online</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It was already suspected that the U.S. was involved in the malicious move carried out by the Zionist regime, but considering their recent remarks, this suspicion is growing stronger day by day,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935307441836523917"  target="_blank">Khamenei said</a>.</p>



<p>Calling out President Donald Trump directly, the Supreme Leader added: &ldquo;The U.S. President threatens us. With his absurd rhetoric, he demands that the Iranian people surrender to him. They should make threats against those who are afraid of being threatened. The Iranian nation isn&rsquo;t frightened by such threats.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump issued a series of cryptic responses following Khamenei&#8217;s highly-publicized address.</p>



<p>When asked if the U.S. is &ldquo;moving closer&rdquo; to striking Iranian nuclear facilities, <a href="https://x.com/SkyNews/status/1935338300396408951"  target="_blank">Trump offered a non-committal</a>: &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it, nobody knows what I&#8217;m going to do&hellip; I can tell you this. Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble. They want to negotiate. I said, &lsquo;Why didn&rsquo;t you negotiate with me before? All this death and destruction.&#8217;&rdquo; </p>



<p>On the subject of whether he gave Iran an ultimatum, the President said: &#8220;You could say so. Maybe you could call it the ultimate ultimatum.&#8221;</p>



<p>Responding to Khamenei&rsquo;s assertion that Iran will never surrender, Trump said &ldquo;good luck&rdquo; to the country, adding that his patience with Iran has &ldquo;already run out&mdash;that&rsquo;s why we&rsquo;re doing what we&rsquo;re doing.&rdquo; He did not elaborate on what he meant by this.</p>



<p>Amid the back-and-forth, <a href="https://x.com/Iran_UN/status/1935346753202471083"  target="_blank">Iran&#8217;s mission to the United Nations in New York said</a> that &rdquo;no Iranian official has <em>ever </em>asked to grovel at the gates of the White House.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;The only thing more despicable than his lies is his cowardly threat to &lsquo;take out&rsquo; Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader,&rdquo; the statement read, speaking of Trump. &ldquo;Iran does NOT negotiate under duress, shall NOT accept peace under duress, and certainly NOT with a has-been warmonger clinging to relevance. Iran shall respond to any threat with a counter-threat, and to any action with reciprocal measures.&rdquo; </p>



<p>The response directly refers to the very public warning that Trump issued against Khamenei on Tuesday.</p>



<p> &ldquo;We know exactly where the so-called &#8216;Supreme Leader&#8217; is hiding. He is an easy target, but is safe there. We are not going to take him out (kill!), at least not for now,&rdquo; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">Trump said via social media</a>. &ldquo;But we don&rsquo;t want missiles shot at civilians, or American soldiers. Our patience is wearing thin.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump added what appeared to be a direct instruction to Iran, saying: &ldquo;UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER!&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>:<em><a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" > Air Supremacy Over Tehran Gives Israel a Decisive Edge&mdash;And Raises New Risks</a></em></p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-israel-iran-war.jpg" alt="G7 summit" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>This latest back-and-forth between Trump and Iran comes amid questions surrounding the<a href="https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/?utm_source=beehiiv&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=newsletter-the-brief&amp;_bhlid=112adf0e154bbf16d4c911b2dd81d8d2484df397" > U.S. response</a> to the escalating conflict in the Middle East and whether or not the U.S. will become involved.</p>



<p>Trump notably spoke out after Israel&rsquo;s early strikes on Iran&mdash;launched against the country&#8217;s nuclear and military targets on June 13&mdash;<a href="https://time.com/7293906/trump-warning-iran-israel-strikes-death-destruction/" >to say that the U.S. had not taken part.</a></p>



<p>But on Tuesday, Trump sparked renewed questions over the U.S.&rsquo; possible involvement.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We now have complete and total control of the skies over Iran. Iran had good sky trackers and other defensive equipment, and plenty of it, but it doesn&rsquo;t compare to American made, conceived, and manufactured &lsquo;stuff.&rsquo; Nobody does it better than the good ol&rsquo; USA,&rdquo; <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699514822488706"  target="_blank">Trump said</a>.</p>



<p>Joining Khamenei in his condemnation of any potential U.S. involvement, Iran&rsquo;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson Esmail Baghaei warned that &ldquo;American intervention would be a recipe for an all-out war in the region.&#8221;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We have very good relations with Arab countries, and they are very cognizant of the fact that Israel has been trying to drag others into the war,&rdquo; said Baghaei, <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/18/iran-warns-us-intervention-in-conflict-with-israel-risks-all-out-war"  target="_blank">in an interview</a> with Al Jazeera on Wednesday. &ldquo;We are sure our Arab countries hosting U.S. bases would not allow their territory to be used against their Muslim neighbours.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="https://time.com/7294819/the-future-of-iran/" ><em>The Future of Iran Belongs Only to its People</em></a></p>



<p>Ahead of this commentary directed at Iran, <a href="https://time.com/7294722/iran-israel-war-trump-strike/" >Trump told reporters</a> aboard Air Force One on Tuesday that he is looking for a &ldquo;real end&rdquo; to the conflict between the two countries, something &ldquo;better than a cease-fire.&rdquo;</p>



<p>With tensions between Israel, Iran, and now the U.S., reaching what many fear is an all-time high, the road to an immediate end to the conflict is becoming significantly more problematic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295471</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Iran Is Urging Residents to Delete WhatsApp Amid Israel Conflict—and WhatsApp&#8217;s Response</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295424/iran-urges-residents-delete-whatsapp-israel-privacy/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295424/iran-urges-residents-delete-whatsapp-israel-privacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Callum Sutherland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 11:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A WhatsApp spokesperson told TIME that the messaging platform is concerned about the reports coming from Iranian state television.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295424"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295424/iran-urges-residents-delete-whatsapp-israel-privacy/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2183307378.jpg" alt="Social Media App Photo Illustration"/>



<p>Amid the escalating <a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" >active conflict between Israel and Iran</a>, the latter has delivered yet another directive to its residents, this time involving the popular messaging platform WhatsApp.</p>



<p>Iran instructed its population, via state television, to delete WhatsApp on account of safety and privacy concerns. </p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the country-wide directive.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why has Iran instructed its residents to delete WhatsApp?</strong></h2>



<p>Iranian state television urged residents on Tuesday afternoon to delete WhatsApp from their smartphones, on account of concerns the messaging platform is gathering user information to share with Israel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s understood that residents were encouraged to refrain from using other &ldquo;location-based applications,&rdquo; also.</p>



<p>The television report did not offer any evidence to support the privacy-related claims.</p>



<p>The claim also comes as Iran is reportedly experiencing a &ldquo;near-total national Internet blackout,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/netblocks/status/1935338921006641377"  target="_blank">according to NetBlock</a>, an organization that monitors internet governance globally.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The incident follows a series of earlier partial disruptions and comes amid escalating military tensions with Israel after days of back-and-forth missile strikes,&rdquo; the organization said on Wednesday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How has WhatsApp responded to the claims?</strong></h2>



<p>A WhatsApp spokesperson told TIME on Wednesday morning that the Meta-owned messaging platform is concerned about the reports coming from Iranian state television.</p>



<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re concerned these false reports will be an excuse for our services to be blocked at a time when people need them the most,&rdquo; the emailed statement read. &ldquo;All of the messages you send to family and friends on WhatsApp are end-to-end encrypted. We do not track your precise location, we don&rsquo;t keep logs of who everyone is messaging, and we do not track the personal messages people are sending one another. We do not provide bulk information to any government.&rdquo;</p>



<p>WhatsApp&#8217;s publicly-shared information <a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/820124435853543/?locale=en_US"  target="_blank">purports that its </a> &ldquo;end-to-end encryption&rdquo; effectively &ldquo;locks&rdquo; chats between individuals, and that no one, including WhatsApp, can access those messages.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" >Air Supremacy Over Tehran Gives Israel a Decisive Edge&mdash;And Raises New Risks</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Has Iran issued warnings or taken action over WhatsApp before?</strong></h2>



<p>A number of social media and messaging apps are banned or heavily restricted in Iran, including Instagram, Telegram, and X, but millions of Iranians still access the sites via VPNs.</p>



<p>In 2022, WhatsApp and Google Play were banned by the Iranian government <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2025/6/18/meta-concerned-iran-could-ban-whatsapp-after-snooping-claims#:~:text=Iran%20added%20WhatsApp%20and%20Instagram,promised%20by%20President%20Masoud%20Pezeshkian."  target="_blank">during nationwide protests</a> after the death of <a href="https://time.com/6216024/iran-protests-islamic-republic-response/" >22-year-old Mahsa Amini</a> in police custody. Iran <a href="https://president.ir/en/156166"  target="_blank">restored access</a> to WhatsApp and Google Play in December 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <em><a href="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" >What To Know About Iran&rsquo;s Nuclear Program After Israel&rsquo;s Strikes</a></em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Wider privacy concerns about WhatsApp messaging</strong></h2>



<p>While no evidence has been provided by Iran regarding its recent instruction to its residents, there have long been privacy concerns surrounding WhatsApp.</p>



<p>In January, Meta alleged that journalists and other WhatsApp users had been targeted by spyware from Paragon Solutions, an Israeli spyware maker.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/metas-whatsapp-says-israeli-spyware-company-paragon-targeted-scores-users-2025-01-31/"  target="_blank">A WhatsApp official said</a> that at least 90 users were targeted in over two dozen countries by a &ldquo;zero-click hack,&rdquo; which uses a malicious electronic document to compromise an account without any interaction from the user themselves.</p>



<p>It was not clear who was behind the incident or which of Paragon&rsquo;s clients may have ordered the attack.</p>



<p>In May, the NSO Group&mdash;the Israeli firm which developed the Pegasus spyware&mdash;was ordered to pay WhatsApp $167m over a hacking campaign that targeted 1,400 users in 2019. <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/05/winning-the-fight-against-spyware-merchant-nso/"  target="_blank">Meta called the settlement</a> &ldquo;an important step forward for privacy and security as the first victory against the development and use of illegal spyware that threatens the safety and privacy of everyone.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Meta claimed that WhatsApp was not the only target of the attacks, and that Pegasus &#8220;has had many other spyware installation methods to exploit other companies&rsquo; technologies to manipulate people&rsquo;s devices into downloading malicious code and compromising their phones.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295424/iran-urges-residents-delete-whatsapp-israel-privacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Zealand Becomes Latest Government to Approve ‘Shrooms’ for Medicinal Use</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295413/psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-hallucinogen-new-zealand-approved-medicinal-therapeutic-depression/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295413/psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-hallucinogen-new-zealand-approved-medicinal-therapeutic-depression/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Zealand is the latest government to approve the therapeutic use of psilocybin, a known hallucinogen.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295413"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/7295413/psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-hallucinogen-new-zealand-approved-medicinal-therapeutic-depression/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/magic-mushrooms-shrooms-medicinal-use.jpg" alt="Psilocybin Mushrooms Increasingly Sought For Therapeutic Purposes"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 18, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the Israel and Iran conflict, a case that could upend social media, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>51001c1f-ad86-4ceb-b10b-d17b768f72d6</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>51001c1f-ad86-4ceb-b10b-d17b768f72d6</code></p></div>



[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]

<p>Psilocybin&mdash;a notorious hallucinogen found in &ldquo;<a href="https://time.com/7032706/are-mushroom-edibles-safe-legal/" >magic mushrooms</a>&rdquo;&mdash;is a federally controlled substance that the U.S. deems to have &ldquo;no currently accepted medical use&rdquo; and &ldquo;a high potential for abuse.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But not everyone agrees with that assessment: New Zealand on Wednesday became the latest country to approve the use of the substance for therapeutic purposes.</p>



<p>David Seymour, New Zealand&rsquo;s Associate Minister for Health, told reporters that <a href="https://www.beehive.govt.nz/release/government-expands-access-melatonin-and-psilocybin"  target="_blank">the new policy</a>, which allows a single approved psychiatrist to prescribe psilocybin to patients with treatment-resistant depression, represents a &ldquo;<a href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/564504/melatonin-to-be-sold-over-the-counter-psilocybin-to-be-prescribed"  target="_blank">real breakthrough</a>.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Seymour said that the psychiatrist, <a href="https://www.nzherald.co.nz/nz/meet-the-one-psychiatrist-approved-to-prescribe-magic-mushrooms-in-new-zealand/GIM2JVVV2FEKTCYFAKVNX2P7WY/"  target="_blank">identified as Cameron Lacey</a>, a <a href="https://www.otago.ac.nz/healthsciences/expertise/profile?id=586"  target="_blank">professor at the University of Otago</a>, &ldquo;has previously prescribed psilocybin in clinical trials and will operate under strict reporting and record-keeping requirements.&rdquo; Seymour added that he is hoping more psychiatrists will apply for clearance to prescribe the drug to patients, though he clarified that the drug remains &ldquo;unapproved medicine.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time as the psilocybin policy change was announced, New Zealand announced plans to loosen restrictions on melatonin, which is used to treat insomnia and is sold over the counter in many other places. As Seymour promised to expand access to treatments like melatonin and psilocybin, no specific date was set for when they will be available across the country.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where is the use of psilocybin for medicinal purposes legal?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>New Zealand is not alone in permitting the medicinal use of the drug.</p>



<p>Australia, in July 2023, <a href="https://www.tga.gov.au/news/media-releases/change-classification-psilocybin-and-mdma-enable-prescribing-authorised-psychiatrists"  target="_blank">authorized</a> specific psychiatrists to prescribe it for the treatment of certain mental health conditions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Switzerland, using LSD, MDMA, and psilocybin in medicine <a href="https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/multinational-companies/switzerland-is-home-to-europes-only-psychedelics-treatment/89195943"  target="_blank">has been legal</a> since 2014, for both research and treatment of mental health conditions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while the substance is generally illegal in Canada, regulated <a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/services/substance-use/controlled-illegal-drugs/magic-mushrooms.html"  target="_blank">medical use</a> is allowed under strict conditions.</p>



<p>Even some states in the U.S. have allowed some degree of use.</p>



<p>Oregon became the first state to legalize psilocybin&rsquo;s therapeutic use in 2020, though some cities have banned the drug. Still, in the state, access to the drug remains restricted: it may only be administered in a <a href="https://www.oregon.gov/oha/PH/PREVENTIONWELLNESS/Documents/OPS-Fact-Sheet.pdf"  target="_blank">licensed psilocybin service center</a>, and an administration session can cost up to $2,000, according to the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/oregon-psilocybin-psychedelic-mushrooms-ban-9c73a25986171b41bb162100d54d2217"  target="_blank">Associated Press</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Colorado also <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/colorado-veterans-and-conservatives-clash-over-psychedelic-therapy"  target="_blank">legalized</a> the regulated use of psilocybin for medical use in a ballot measure in 2022, with the first licenses for dispensing it issued <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Health/colorado-psychedelic-mushroom-experiment-arrived/story?id=120109227"  target="_blank">earlier this year.</a> And in April, New Mexico <a href="https://www.nmlegis.gov/Sessions/25%20Regular/bills/senate/SB0219.HTML"  target="_blank">legalized</a> psilocybin&rsquo;s use in approved settings to treat certain medical conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Laws on the regulated medical use of psilocybin are also making their way through state legislatures like <a href="https://www.revisor.mn.gov/bills/bill.php?b=House&amp;f=HF2906&amp;ssn=0&amp;y=2025"  target="_blank">Minnesota</a> and <a href="https://malegislature.gov/Bills/194/HD3368"  target="_blank">Massachusetts</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.beehive.govt.nz/release/government-expands-access-melatonin-and-psilocybin"  target="_blank">Said</a> Seymour in announcing New Zealand&rsquo;s rationale for changing its tune on the drug: &ldquo;If a doctor believes psilocybin can help, they should have the tools to try.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295413/psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-hallucinogen-new-zealand-approved-medicinal-therapeutic-depression/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295413</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Considers U.S. Attack on Iran, Demands ‘Unconditional Surrender’</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. President is reportedly weighing whether to launch a military strike, threatening Iran’s leader: “Our patience is wearing thin.”]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295400"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-israel-iran-war.jpg" alt="G7 summit"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 18, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the Israel and Iran conflict, a case that could upend social media, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>51001c1f-ad86-4ceb-b10b-d17b768f72d6</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>51001c1f-ad86-4ceb-b10b-d17b768f72d6</code></p></div>



<p>The Israel-Iran war, which is now in its sixth day and has already killed hundreds in Iran and dozens in Israel, could soon enter a perilous new phase should the U.S. join the fight.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>According to recent reports, Donald Trump is actively weighing with his national security team whether to order U.S. strikes on Iran, as the President has publicly toughened his language about the conflict in a series of posts on his platform Truth Social.</p>



<p>In the initial days after Israel <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >launched</a> its attack on Iran last Friday, the U.S. repeatedly disclaimed <a href="https://time.com/7294500/israel-attack-iran-us-involvement-trump-netanyahu-khamenei/" >involvement</a>. But as Iran vowed to <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >retaliate</a> against both Israel and the U.S., Israel&rsquo;s primary arms supplier, Trump&rsquo;s tone shifted. On Saturday, he <a href="https://time.com/7294360/trump-warns-iran-bloody-conflict-israel-death-toll-rises/" >warned</a>: &ldquo;If we are attacked in any way, shape, or form by Iran, the full strength and might of the U.S. Armed Forces will come down on you at levels never seen before.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Still, at that time, Trump reiterated a preference for diplomacy that had long been a feature of his political campaigns, in which he rallied against past interventionist U.S. administrations and promised during his second-term <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/remarks/2025/01/the-inaugural-address/"  target="_blank">inaugural address</a> to &ldquo;stop all wars.&rdquo;</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=TBYdgfpz]</div>



<p>&ldquo;We can easily get a deal done between Iran and Israel, and end this bloody conflict,&rdquo; his <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114685507052179501"  target="_blank">post</a> on Saturday ended.</p>



<p>However, as Trump abruptly left the G7 summit early on Monday night to focus on the Middle East, he clarified that he was no longer interested in making nice with Iran.</p>



<p>&ldquo;They should have done the deal. I told them, &lsquo;Do the deal,&rsquo;&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/videos/2025-06-17/trump-not-too-much-in-the-mood-to-negotiate-with-iran-video"  target="_blank">told</a> reporters on his return to the White House from the summit, in apparent reference to negotiations with Iran over <a href="https://time.com/7294133/iran-israel-nuclear-program-attack/" >its nuclear program</a> that were underway but disrupted by Israel&rsquo;s attack. &ldquo;So I don&rsquo;t know. I&rsquo;m not too much in the mood to negotiate.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump had <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114695407357588413"  target="_blank">posted</a> earlier Monday: &ldquo;Iran should have signed the &lsquo;deal&rsquo; I told them to sign. What a shame, and waste of human life. Simply stated, IRAN CAN NOT HAVE A NUCLEAR WEAPON. I said it over and over again! Everyone should immediately evacuate Tehran!&rdquo;</p>



<p>On Tuesday morning, he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114696999897040583"  target="_blank">posted</a> that French President Emanuel Macron was &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; to suggest that Trump was heading back to Washington to work on a ceasefire between Israel and Iran. &ldquo;He has no idea why I am now on my way to Washington, but it certainly has nothing to do with a Cease Fire. Much bigger than that.&rdquo; In a follow-up <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114697964891587065"  target="_blank">post</a>, Trump added: &ldquo;I have not reached out to Iran for &lsquo;Peace Talks&rsquo; in any way, shape, or form.&rdquo;</p>



<p>By Tuesday afternoon, Trump made his desire clear. &ldquo;UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER!&rdquo; he <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699621000737127"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Truth Social after a series of posts in which he hailed American military superiority, <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699514822488706"  target="_blank">claiming</a> &ldquo;complete and total control of the skies over Iran,&rdquo; and he appeared to threaten Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, claiming to know where he is hiding and <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">warning</a>: &ldquo;He is an easy target, but is safe there &#8211; We are not going to take him out (kill!), at least not for now. But we don&rsquo;t want missiles shot at civilians, or American soldiers. Our patience is wearing thin.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Khamenei <a href="https://time.com/7295471/iran-supreme-leader-khamenei-warning-trump-united-states/" >responded</a> on Wednesday: &ldquo;The US President threatens us. With his absurd rhetoric, he demands that the Iranian people surrender to him. They should make threats against those who are afraid of being threatened. The Iranian nation isn&rsquo;t frightened by such threats,&rdquo; he <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935296111444472296"  target="_blank">said</a>.</p>



<p>&ldquo;It isn&rsquo;t wise to tell the Iranian nation to surrender. What should the Iranian nation surrender to? We will never surrender in response to the attacks of anyone. This is the logic of the Iranian nation. This is the spirit of the Iranian nation,&rdquo; Khamenei <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935298684729872552"  target="_blank">added</a>, before <a href="https://x.com/khamenei_ir/status/1935301111050641472"  target="_blank">ending</a> with a threat: &ldquo;The US entering in this matter [war] is 100% to its own detriment. The damage it will suffer will be far greater than any harm that Iran may encounter.&rdquo; </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump considers military intervention</h2>



<p>While the U.S. has officially maintained that it was not involved in Israel&rsquo;s initial attack on Iran beyond being informed by Israel ahead of the strike, the <em>New York Times</em> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/us/politics/trump-iran-israel-nuclear-talks.html"  target="_blank">reported</a> this week that the U.S. offered Israel as-yet-undisclosed intelligence support&mdash;and that Trump is seriously considering a more serious escalation.</p>



<p>The White House&rsquo;s official position&mdash;as warships, aircraft, and personnel have been <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/06/16/us-military-israel-iran/"  target="_blank">moved</a> to the Middle East in recent days&mdash;is that U.S. forces are only mobilizing in the region for &ldquo;<a href="https://x.com/SecDef/status/1934726498725810271"  target="_blank">defensive</a>&rdquo; purposes. But officials have told multiple news outlets, including the <em>Times</em>, <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-considers-joining-israel-iran-strikes-nuclear-facilities-fordo/"  target="_blank">CBS</a>, and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/17/trump-iran-israel-khamenei.html"  target="_blank">NBC</a>, that Trump is considering acting first, rather than waiting to see if Iran will attack.</p>



<p>The potential next courses of action Trump could take, according to the <em>Times</em>, range from sending American aircraft to help refuel Israeli combat jets to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/us/politics/trump-iran-diplomacy-conflict.html"  target="_blank">striking Iran&rsquo;s underground nuclear facility at Fordow</a> with so-called bunker buster bombs that the U.S. has but Israel doesn&rsquo;t. Trump has <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/us/politics/trump-iran-israel-nuclear-talks.html"  target="_blank">reportedly</a> told confidants in private conversations that he is now leaning towards the latter. According to the <em>Times</em>, Trump earlier this year authorized U.S. Central Command to coordinate with Israel on refining and developing Pentagon plans for how to take out Iran&rsquo;s nuclear sites.</p>



<p>Another potential course of action could be a strike to kill Khamenei, as Trump warned on Truth Social. The latter is a plan that was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/trump-vetoed-an-israeli-plan-kill-irans-supreme-leader-us-officials-say-2025-06-15/"  target="_blank">reportedly</a> proposed by Israel over the weekend and rejected by Trump who was worried then that it would escalate the conflict and destabilize the region.</p>



<p>As Trump claimed Tuesday to know Khamenei&rsquo;s location, Iranian state television urged people to remove the popular encrypted-messaging app <a href="https://time.com/7295424/iran-urges-residents-delete-whatsapp-israel-privacy/" >WhatsApp</a> from their phones, alleging that the Meta-owned platform shared user information with Israel. WhatsApp said in a statement that it is &ldquo;concerned these false reports will be an excuse for our services to be blocked at a time when people need them the most&rdquo; and that WhatsApp does not provide &ldquo;bulk information to any government&rdquo; nor track users&rsquo; precise locations or personal messages.</p>



<p>Of course, the U.S. could also be dragged into greater military intervention if attacked, and Iran is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/us/politics/iran-israel-us-bases.html"  target="_blank">reportedly</a> preparing missiles for a potential retaliatory strike on U.S. bases in the Middle East in case of further U.S. military engagement in the war<em>.</em></p>



<p>Even before Trump ramped up his threats, Iran&rsquo;s foreign ministry said in a <a href="https://x.com/IrnaEnglish/status/1933371705486950552"  target="_blank">statement</a> after Israel&rsquo;s first attack that the strike &ldquo;could not have been carried out without coordination with and approval of the United States&rdquo; and that the U.S. would be &ldquo;held responsible&rdquo; for its support of Israel. Iran&rsquo;s Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/15/solid-evidence-iran-says-us-bears-responsibility-for-israels-aggression"  target="_blank">said</a> Sunday after further attacks were traded between Israel and Iran that Iran had &ldquo;well-documented and solid evidence&rdquo; of U.S. assistance to Israel.</p>



<p>U.S. intelligence earlier this year had concluded that Iran was not building a nuclear weapon and that Khamenei had not reauthorized the country&rsquo;s suspended nuclear weapons program, according to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/gabbard-trump-intelligence-iran-nuclear-program-51c8d85d536f8628870c110ac05bb518"  target="_blank">testimony</a> in March by Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard and <a href="https://www.dni.gov/files/ODNI/documents/assessments/ODNI-Unclassified-Irans-Nuclear-Weapons-Capability-and-Terrorism-Monitoring-Act-of-2022-202411.pdf"  target="_blank">intelligence reports</a> made public in November. But Trump <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/17/trump-gabbard-iran-nuclear-weapon-testimony"  target="_blank">dismissed</a> Gabbard&rsquo;s testimony this week, telling reporters aboard Air Force One on his way back from the G7 summit: &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t care what she said. I think they were very close to having them.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Analysts have <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/iran-to-double-down-on-nuclear-programme-after-israeli-strikes-analysts"  target="_blank">noted</a> that Israel&rsquo;s attacks may change Iran&rsquo;s outlook on its nuclear program and could actually incentivize the country to try to develop a nuclear weapon. Rosemary Kelanic, director of the Middle East program at Defense Priorities, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/17/us/politics/iran-israel-us-bases.html"  target="_blank">told</a> the <em>Times</em> that the incentive would &ldquo;multiply dramatically if the United States joins the war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>A number of lawmakers <a href="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" >across both parties</a> have <a href="https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/" >expressed concern</a> about Trump authorizing military action without a congressionally-approved declaration of war.</p>



<p>Vice President J.D. Vance <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1934996183702704404"  target="_blank">posted on X</a> Tuesday that Trump &ldquo;may decide he needs to take further action to end Iranian enrichment. That decision ultimately belongs to the president.&rdquo; And Trump himself <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114698784693311065"  target="_blank">shared a message</a> from U.S. Ambassador to Israel Mike Huckabee that compared the choice before Trump to former President Harry Truman&rsquo;s in 1945, when he <a href="https://www.trumanlibrary.gov/education/presidential-inquiries/decision-drop-atomic-bomb"  target="_blank">decided</a> to drop atomic bombs on Japan. &ldquo;I trust your instincts,&rdquo; the message from Huckabee said. &ldquo;No president in my lifetime has been in a position like yours.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Trump <a href="https://x.com/JenGriffinFNC/status/1935342579320590634"  target="_blank">reiterated</a> his call for Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;unconditional surrender&rdquo; on Wednesday, <a href="https://x.com/JenniferJJacobs/status/1935338106732888459"  target="_blank">adding</a> when asked about U.S. involvement in striking Iran: &ldquo;I may do it, I may not do it. I mean, nobody knows what I&rsquo;m going to do. I can tell you this, that Iran&rsquo;s got a lot of trouble.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295400/trump-us-iran-israel-war-khamenei-strike-fordow-unconditional-surrender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295400</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 5 Groups Hoping to Sway Trump on Iran</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Philip Elliott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 20:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7295241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he threatens Iran's supreme leader, Trump's base finds itself on new ground]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7295241"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2220537500.jpg" alt="G7 Leaders' Summit"/>



<p><em>This article is part of The D.C. Brief, TIME&rsquo;s politics newsletter. Sign up </em><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><em>here</em></a><em> to get stories like this sent to your inbox.</em></p>



<p>The Constitution is pretty clear about the powers bestowed upon Presidents: they can negotiate treaties, command the military, stack a Cabinet and the courts, issue pardons and commutations. But the true superpowers of the presidency are more nebulous, but just as significant. Presidents can rally world-weary Americans to coalesce on foreign policy. They can rally America-weary countries to Washington&rsquo;s causes. They can exploit the instinctive respect for the presidency at moments of crisis.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>But for any of those softer powers to work, the White House has to have credibility. And, at the moment, President Donald Trump is at a pronounced disadvantage as he faces a Middle East in crisis. It isn&#8217;t just that he is coming off a weekend in which he provoked one of the largest single-day <a href="https://time.com/7294323/trumps-military-parade-took-over-washington-as-anti-trump-no-kings-protests-dominated-everywhere-else/" >protests</a> in U.S. history as he threw an underwhelming, but expensive, <a href="https://time.com/7294323/trumps-military-parade-took-over-washington-as-anti-trump-no-kings-protests-dominated-everywhere-else/" >military parade</a>. Trump could more easily dismiss his many detractors if his base were with him as solidly as it was just a few weeks ago. But the political movement that fueled his most unlikely return to power is threatening to now crack.</p>



<p>&#8220;We now have complete and total control of the skies over Iran,&#8221; Trump <a href="https://trumpstruth.org/statuses/31531"  target="_blank">posted</a> on Tuesday, making clear the U.S. and Israel were now in lockstep on the Israeli military operation that the U.S. didn&#8217;t initially back. &#8220;Nobody does it better than the good ol&rsquo; USA,&#8221; he added. </p>



<p>It was the latest diplomatic swerve from Trump, who has responded in recent days to Israel&#8217;s offensive by veering to nearly every possible position&mdash;from a hands-off approach to pressing for a diplomatic off-ramp to claiming total ownership of Israel&#8217;s barrage and threatening Iran&rsquo;s annihilation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ever one for theatrics, Trump this week even urged millions of Iranians to evacuate their capital ahead of suggested wasteland strikes. His Vice President, J.D. Vance, on Tuesday seemed to hint at further escalation&mdash;even as the architects of the MAGA movement he is <a href="https://time.com/7024414/jd-vance-2024-interview/" >usually more aligned</a> with are pushing Republicans to climb down from scorched-earth rhetoric.</p>



<p>There remains a window for this moment to deliver a clear political victory for Trump. Iran clearly wants to de-escalate its hot war with Israel, which is now in its fifth day and ostensibly over a nuclear program Israel sees as an existential threat. Israel pushed pause on plans to assassinate Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader after U.S. officials&mdash;including Trump&mdash;called it too outrageous. A return to a deal with Iran to put limits on its nuclear programs could give Trump diplomatic cache he has sought in that region since his first foreign trip as President in 2017. And nothing would shut down his haters faster than an objective win for U.S. interests.</p>



<p>But the political realities Trump finds himself navigating are different from the ones he has dispensed with in the past. As he pushes for Iran&rsquo;s surrender, here are the specific factions that are trying to guide his next steps.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump and the GOP Traditionalists</h2>



<p>Trump ran in 2024 on rich promises of fast ends to conflicts in the Middle East and Ukraine, pledging peace deals were on the horizon if only he could get back into the White House. As he railed against his predecessors&rsquo; meddling into international affairs and flex of American might, the GOP traditionalists largely bit their tongues. After all, the alternative of Joe Biden and later Kamala Harris was still seen to them as less desirable than Trump&mdash;who proved pretty pliable on the global stage during his first term.</p>



<p>But it&rsquo;s an unbendable fact in GOP orthodoxy that the United States stands linked with Israel. As Washington&rsquo;s strongest ally in the region, support for Israel has been a cornerstone of U.S. policy since modern Israel&rsquo;s founding. To the dismay of critics of Israeli&rsquo;s governments over the years, that has sometimes been mistaken for a blank check. But the Establishment-minded Republicans are not going to be quiet if Trump is seen even hinting at a split with Benjamin Netanyahu&rsquo;s government.</p>



<p>That said, those same Republicans are keeping a close eye on signals coming from the White House. It&rsquo;s no secret that Trump and Netanyahu do not have a terrific relationship. (Though Netanyahu hasn&rsquo;t <a href="https://time.com/7207325/gaza-ceasefire-trump-biden/" >exactly been besties</a> with any of his U.S. counterparts, dating back to Bill Clinton.) Yet for the moment, the GOP&rsquo;s hawks are trying to signal optimism. &ldquo;The Iranians are about to get their asses kicked,&rdquo; Fox host Mark Levin said this weekend.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump and the MAGA Isolationists</h2>



<p>The core of Trump&rsquo;s MAGA base is far more distressed. Trump came to power by openly dinging internationalism from administrations of both parties. He vowed to retreat from foreign entanglements that began decades ago, wind down interventions that left Americans Googling for maps an ocean away, and double-down on a domestic agenda that better served his base. It was a clear play to a constituency that was unhappy with a creeping American reach.</p>



<p>Trump on Tuesday was testing the limits of that cohort&rsquo;s support, as he posted on social media that he knew where Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader was bunkering down and threatened his life unless Iran agreed to &ldquo;UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER.&rdquo; &ldquo;We are not going to take him out (kill!), at least not for now,&rdquo; Trump posted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This puts in motion a slow-rolling collision with Trump&rsquo;s base of supporters who thought they were walking away from other people&rsquo;s problems. Former Fox host <a href="https://time.com/6080432/tucker-carlson-profile/" >Tucker Carlson</a>, MAGA evangelist <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-maga-iran-israel-2085940"  target="_blank">Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene</a>, and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/video/sen-rand-paul-says-it-s-not-the-u-s-s-job-to-be-involved-in-israel-iran-conflict-full-interview-241621061772?playlist=mmlsnnd_bestofnbc-nnd"  target="_blank">Sen. Rand Paul</a> have all spoken out against unequivocal support for Israel&rsquo;s actions. Rep. Tom Massie, a Republican who has bucked Trump with glee, on Tuesday <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/17/congress/thomas-massie-iran-resolution-war-powers-00410454"  target="_blank">introduced</a> a resolution that would block military escalation from the U.S. side.</p>



<p>After promising an end to entanglements that have bedeviled Trump&rsquo;s predecessors, Trump now seems on the cusp of joining the fray in a region where 40,000 Americans are deployed and there are scant off-ramps.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-1242271351.jpg" alt="GOLF: JUL 31 LIV Golf Invitational Series Bedminster" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump and the Pro-Israel Activists</h2>



<p>How the country feels about Israel belies party labels, even as Republicans are often the most vocally supportive. Trump owned the pro-Israel space in his campaigns. While Americans are pretty evenly split on the three-way question of whether U.S. support for Israel is just right, too weak, or too strong, there was a clear imbalance on how those camps voted last year. Trump carried 4 in 5 of those seeking more backing for Israel, according to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2024/exit-polls/national-results/general/president/0"  target="_blank">exit polls</a>. (Vice President Kamala Harris, by contrast, carried two-thirds of the share who thought Washington was too pro-Israel.)</p>



<p>Trump clearly owes this constituency a chit. The pro-Israel lobby in Washington is highly organized to the point of sparking conspiracy theories. The clout is real and the consequences are significant. It reaches across the aisle, which is why even some of the most reliably liberal lawmakers still make the hike to AIPAC&rsquo;s policy conferences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump has mastered the pander here. Despite his deep, deep antipathy toward Netanyahu, Trump understands the transactional nature of his relationship with those voters who prioritize Israel&rsquo;s future over any domestic U.S. priorities. Given that constituency&rsquo;s heft on the Hill, Trump gets that falling short with them could complicate everything else on his agenda, from tax cuts to immigration enforcement to crypto regulation to his beloved tariffs.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump and the Christian Right</h2>



<p>There is some overlap with the pro-Israel cohort here, but for very different reasons. The Christian Right has a long-seeded allegiance with those who want U.S. support of Israel to be absolute. Trump carried Evangelicals and born-again Christians last year, again, by a 4-to-1 margin, according to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2024/exit-polls/national-results/general/president/0"  target="_blank">exit polls</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For many on the Christian Right, Israel&rsquo;s survival is a necessary component to Jesus&rsquo; return to the physical earth. In some readings of the Bible, a modern state of Israel is destined and will be where Jesus makes his second coming as prophesied in the so-called End Times. For many on the Christian Right, anything but fealty to Israel is an affront to their faith.</p>



<p>The overlap between Trump&rsquo;s isolationist base and his Israel-at-all-cost Evangelicals seems destined for a conflict, one with deep contradictions that has zero apparent resolution. The balancing act is not one that comes naturally to Trump, but he has time and time again proven capable of digging himself out of seemingly impossible dead ends.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump and the Democrats</h2>



<p>Democrats have so far been measured in their response to the current strikes into Iran. No fans of a nuclear Iran, Democrats recall the landmark deal the Obama Administration negotiated with Tehran that Trump quickly abandoned in his first term. But Democrats also have pointed memories of how Netanyahu all but campaigned against Obama&rsquo;s re-election in 2012 in favor of Mitt Romney, a former colleague. And the long-festering frustrations with Netanyahu&rsquo;s administration cannot be overstated, even among Israel&rsquo;s strongest defenders in the Democratic caucus.</p>



<p>The opposition party is far from united in how they want to see the U.S. engage in the Middle East in this moment. Some voices, such as Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders, have urged <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/06/17/politics/trump-iran-israel-conflict-g7"  target="_blank">restraint</a> against rushing to defer to Israel&rsquo;s efforts&mdash;putting leading leftists in an odd confluence with folks like Carlson and former Trump counselor Steve Bannon. Others, like Senate Democratic Leader Chuck Schumer, are mostly staying away from a bill Sanders has sponsored that would block funding for military force against Iran&mdash;despite the fact that Schumer sponsored similar legislation in 2020. Democrats are carefully watching where public opinion heads in the quick-moving situation or what might be done to curb Trump.</p>



<p>While the Jewish vote was just 2% of the total electorate last year, it was pretty unified for Democrats; 78% of Jewish voters backed Harris, according to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2024/exit-polls/national-results/general/president/0"  target="_blank">exit polls</a>. Trump is no fool when it comes to optimism that Democrats would be natural allies here. But even his allies make for unsteady partners. Ultimately, Trump will need to figure out how to cobble together a coalition that permits him to execute a choice that he alone can make.</p>



<p><em>Make sense of what matters in Washington. </em><a href="https://cloud.newsletters.time.com/signup?nln=dc-brief&amp;source=dc_onsite" ><em>Sign up for the D.C. Brief newsletter</em></a><em>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7295241</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thailand and Cambodia’s Friendship Falters as Border Clash Escalates: What to Know</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad de Guzman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A deadly border skirmish has revived grievances between the once-friendly Southeast Asian neighbors.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294994"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/cambodia-thailand-border.jpg" alt="CAMBODIA-THAILAND-BORDER-TEMPLE"/>



<p>Both Cambodia and Thailand have been <a href="https://www.phnompenhpost.com/business/cambodia-voted-worlds-friendliest-country-rough-guides-reader-poll"  target="_blank">rated</a> among the friendliest nations in the world, and just five years ago, the Southeast Asian neighbors thought their friendship with each other could never be broken. &ldquo;As we share a long border, we both know that we have to live and grow together,&rdquo; Thailand&rsquo;s then-Ambassador to Cambodia Panyarak Poolthup <a href="https://www.phnompenhpost.com/national/thailand-cambodia-two-kingdoms-friendship-standing-test-time"  target="_blank">told</a> Cambodia&rsquo;s then-Prime Minister Hun Sen. &ldquo;The political will is always there to resolve any issues that may arise.&rdquo;</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>But in recent weeks, bilateral relations have sunk to a dangerous new low, threatening to reignite a historic rivalry that had seemed to be a relic of the past.</p>



<p>Following weeks of standoff, including Cambodia invoking the language of &ldquo;war,&rdquo; since a Cambodian soldier was killed in a clash along the border last month, Thai Prime Minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra issued her strongest rebuke yet, signaling resolution likely remains distant.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Thailand is united. We will not tolerate maltreatment, accusations or threats from any party. Our country also has dignity. Our country is also strong,&rdquo; Paetongtarn <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3050711/strident-pm-declares-thailand-will-defend-its-sovereignty"  target="_blank">said</a>, in response to Cambodia retaliating with cross-border embargoes and taking the dispute to the International Court of Justice, which Thailand does <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/blogs/news/asean/40051314"  target="_blank">not recognize</a> the jurisdiction of.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about the conflict&mdash;and its potential consequences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What has happened in recent weeks?</h2>



<p>The reescalation of conflict was sparked on May 28, when a Cambodian soldier was killed in an early morning clash between both nations&rsquo; troops, in an area called the Emerald Triangle&mdash;the shared border between Thailand, Cambodia, and Laos. The area remains disputed as both Thailand and Cambodia lay claims to parts of the region.</p>



<p>Both sides argued that the other was the aggressor: Cambodia&rsquo;s Ministry of National Defense <a href="https://mod.gov.kh/contents/uploads/2025/05/IMG_20250528_0001.pdf"  target="_blank">said</a> the Thai army opened fire on a trench that had been a Cambodian army base, leading to the death of the soldier, while Thailand&rsquo;s army <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3036327/thai-cambodian-soldiers-in-brief-clash-no-casualties"  target="_blank">claimed</a> that its soldiers responded only after the Cambodian forces &ldquo;started using weapons&rdquo; during a misunderstanding in the disputed area.</p>



<p>Hun Sen, who relinquished the Cambodian premiership to his son in 2023 but became the Senate President and remains the effective country leader, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hunsencambodia/posts/1321171426031308?ref=embed_post"  target="_blank">reacted</a> to the skirmish, saying that he supports the &ldquo;decision to send troops and heavy weapons to the border to prepare for a counterattack in case of a further invasion.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We hate war, but we are compelled to wage it when facing foreign aggression,&rdquo; Hun Sen said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As members of the regional bloc Association of Southeast Asian Nations, Cambodia and Thailand are expected to resolve disputes peacefully, per the <a href="https://asean.org/wp-content/uploads/images/archive/publications/ASEAN-Charter.pdf"  target="_blank">ASEAN charter</a>. While both countries <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/7/thailand-and-cambodia-reinforce-troops-along-disputed-border-thai-minister"  target="_blank">initially beefed up</a> military presence on their respective sides of the border, on June 8, they appeared to attempt a deescalation by sending their troops back to military positions that were agreed upon last year. Paetongtarn, in a <a href="https://x.com/ingshin/status/1931685763273605120"  target="_blank">statement,</a> said the countries agreed &ldquo;to jointly adjust military forces at points of conflict to reduce the atmosphere of confrontation.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But the dispute escalated through punitive tit-for-tat policies seemingly designed to appease fomenting nationalistic sentiment on their respective sides of the border.</p>



<p>The Thai army <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3044047/thai-army-takes-control-of-border-checkpoints"  target="_blank">took control</a> of border checkpoints and Bangkok <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/asean/40051025"  target="_blank">threatened</a> to cut electricity and the internet to Cambodia. Cambodia <a href="https://apnews.com/article/border-internet-tv-movie-ban-1d554bda4b59aa89b79f02ad2913acc7"  target="_blank">responded</a> by banning Thai media like TV and movies, and disconnecting cross-border internet links to Thailand. On June 17, Cambodia banned <a href="https://www.facebook.com/PhnomPenhPost/posts/pfbid02RfFS8YaxganZLn795wngg7tRZPivYd2FsNvPzmmxAEZEU8XjFjjTnMVzpuuii8rcl"  target="_blank">Thailand&rsquo;s export of produce into the country</a>. Thailand, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3051507/army-prohibits-thais-crossing-border-to-work-in-poipet-bars-casinos"  target="_blank">barred</a> Thais from crossing the border to work in casinos and other entertainment venues in Cambodia&rsquo;s Poipet. </p>



<p>Further inflaming tensions, Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manet announced on Facebook on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=pfbid026SS4TiFZtKibtNmYqZVooHPDBU6nzzdSrjE9omBTjGoXZTyqmNGWKZj3DZLNWHEkl&amp;id=100069511484329&amp;__cft__[0]=AZWvdc4SnFJC9ooA8PqkAcYKSSvjMZU99szxLKfB5UlqIVeOg7NyS-9CpyXbDM-zU0X-YvO2U3wS_ZsR1rcsqISDhrIBJuRnJL2vlPyU_v7WbelOI7ENQlQmWY7GboZIun2GWrnbUw2XU1bxRfC-6B7X5ldaweHMxG03ozp5kHehqea7r63XdXYULOPq5q6YrQxO-iEunOg0fmU6IUywp-Za&amp;__tn__=%2CO%2CP-R"  target="_blank">June 16</a> that Cambodia sent an official letter to the International Court of Justice to help find a solution to the border development issues. &ldquo;Cambodia chooses international law and peace,&rdquo; he said the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=pfbid0K3AAGz5m3BSJhbtYW7CQ4vak3L63GzPmQsKEvENzChD4HoRAvrFz7PeDFisuyuvkl&amp;id=100069511484329&amp;__cft__[0]=AZWAlvkGWwDvwZKKMid4dcJLGsyBv0u5Sj4-xTTdpfaQvIx7MOBNniUWeThVLSyS5__XB71NvOWpXPVx8p3QmnETi72L0diGS2PYvn90DlfwxQBhEecyxTYmL0iFPu4dmEVd3MIBX-mTlXDECAtzNzbBtqimo4b8oW1g1hfVISlpQ4NW0-e2WwYuCTvUCItEecaKPusk_mZSbFVsTM9iUZwP&amp;__tn__=%2CO%2CP-R"  target="_blank">day before</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thailand&rsquo;s foreign ministry has <a href="https://www.mfa.go.th/en/content/thai-position-response-to-cambodia-icj-en?cate=5d5bcb4e15e39c306000683c"  target="_blank">ruled out</a> an intervention from the ICJ and made clear its preference for bilateral talks, arguing that &ldquo;a third party may not always be conducive to the preservation of amicable relations among States, particularly in sensitive matters involving complex historical, territorial, or political dimensions.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the historic context?</h2>



<p>Cambodia and Thailand share an 817-km. land border, but that border was largely mapped by French colonizers while they occupied Cambodia from 1863 to 1953. A 1907 map was based on an agreement to follow a natural watershed line between Thailand and Cambodia. But Thailand later contested the map over the fact that it placed the 11th-century Preah Vihear Temple in the D&acirc;ngr&ecirc;k Mountains within Cambodian territory.</p>



<p>The dispute, as well as <a href="https://www.nationthailand.com/news/asean/40051324"  target="_blank">historical differences</a> in cartographic methods, led to areas around the border that both countries lay claim to.</p>



<p>There have been attempts to clarify demarcations. Cambodia brought Thailand to the International Court of Justice in 1959 over the temple dispute, and in 1962 the court <a href="https://www.icj-cij.org/sites/default/files/case-related/45/4873.pdf"  target="_blank">ruled</a> in Phnom Penh&rsquo;s favor, saying that Preah Vihear falls in Cambodian territory. Thailand recognized this at the time but argued that the surrounding frontiers were still disputed, which further complicated the borderlines.</p>



<p>Tensions flared in 2008 when Cambodia sought a UNESCO world-heritage status for the Preah Vihear Temple. After the temple received the recognition in July, military clashes between Cambodian and Thai troops <a href="https://time.com/archive/6944665/thai-cambodian-border-spat-heats-up/" >erupted</a> near the border area.</p>



<p>These clashes lasted for years, coming to a head in <a href="https://time.com/archive/6957211/deadly-clashes-as-thai-cambodian-temple-tensions-reignite/" >2011</a>, after displacing 36,000 at the height of the conflict in <a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/cambodia/cambodia-thailand-36000-displaced-deadly-border-clashes"  target="_blank">April that year</a>. Around this time, Cambodia took to the ICJ again to interpret its earlier 1962 ruling, and the court affirmed its previous decision two years later.</p>



<p>Thailand has pushed for a more bilateral approach, with a Joint Boundary Commission (JBC) established in 2000 to help resolve border disputes. Cambodia has engaged with Thailand through the JBC, but these meetings&mdash;the latest of which was scheduled on June 14 in Phnom Penh&mdash;tend to produce <a href="https://www.bangkokpost.com/thailand/general/3050052/no-conclusions-from-thai-cambodian-joint-boundary-meeting"  target="_blank">no significant results</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What could come next?</h2>



<p>Resolving the border dispute quickly seems unlikely.</p>



<p>Complicating matters is the relationship between the two countries&rsquo; current leaders&mdash;and their fathers. Paetongtarn&rsquo;s father former Thai Prime Minister Thaksin Shinawatra and Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manet&rsquo;s father Hun Sen have a public friendship, with Hun Sen even providing refuge to Thaksin in Cambodia and naming him as an <a href="https://time.com/archive/6948517/latest-pawn-in-the-thai-cambodian-spat-thaksin/" >honorary economic adviser</a> after Thaksin was ousted in a coup in 2006.</p>



<p>The relationship between the two has caused concern about how the border dispute will be resolved, particularly for Thailand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When Paetongtarn was asked about whether she&rsquo;s becoming &ldquo;too soft&rdquo; on Cambodia because of the relationship, she <a href="https://www.khaosodenglish.com/politics/2025/06/05/thailand-cambodia-border-tensions-rise-with-nationalism/"  target="_blank">responded</a>: &ldquo;Even though our two families are friends, it doesn&rsquo;t mean we would allow the country to lose its interests &hellip; if a friend asks for your house, no friend would just give it away.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Paetongtarn&rsquo;s comments come as the Royal Thai Army said it was ready for a &ldquo;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thai-military-prepared-high-level-operation-if-cambodia-border-row-escalates-2025-06-06/"  target="_blank">high-level operation</a>&rdquo; if necessary to address the situation at the border. Paetongtarn has reiterated calls for a peaceful resolution to the dispute, but being at odds with the Army has echoes of previous government downfalls: both her father Thaksin and aunt Yingluck Shinawatra, another former Prime Minister, were ousted following nationalists groups&rsquo; revival of border issues.</p>



<p>In an analysis for Asian current affairs magazine <a href="https://thediplomat.com/2025/06/is-thailand-on-the-cusp-of-another-military-coup/"  target="_blank"><em>The Diplomat</em></a>, Royal University of Phnom Penh&rsquo;s Center for Southeast Asian Studies researcher Rath Pichanvorlak warned that the Thai military &ldquo;could allow border tensions to escalate, inflaming nationalist sentiment,&rdquo; to justify another coup.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294994/thailand-cambodia-border-dispute-hun-sen-thaksin-paetongtarn-history-explainer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Air Supremacy Over Tehran Gives Israel a Decisive Edge—And Raises New Risks</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nik Popli]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said Monday that it can now fly over Tehran without facing major resistance.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294919"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2219726680.jpg" alt="Israel Launches Strikes Against Iran"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 17, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the rise of political violence in the U.S., Israel and Iran, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>d172b396-a05f-49a8-91f4-5e9ecff5874e</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>34e224e1-2194-42f7-a6bb-b33a19e61436</code></p></div>

[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]



<p>Just four days into its <a href="https://time.com/7294609/iran-israel-war-pictures-strike/" >ferocious air campaign</a>, Israel appears to have gained a decisive edge in its escalating conflict with Iran: aerial supremacy over Iran.</p>



<p>The Israeli military said Monday that it can now fly over the country&#8217;s capital, Tehran, without facing major resistance after crippling Iran&rsquo;s air defenses in recent strikes, enabling Israel to hit an expanding range of targets with relative ease. </p>



<p>Such control over Iran&rsquo;s skies, military analysts say, is not just a tactical advantage&mdash;it&rsquo;s a strategic turning point. Air supremacy gives Israel the freedom to escalate its bombing campaign, look for additional targets, and possibly redraw the rules of deterrence in a region where missile salvos and proxy wars have long defined the limits of conflict.</p>



<p>Soon after declaring control of Tehran&rsquo;s skies, Israel warned residents and workers in the capital to evacuate, and later appeared to strike the headquarters of Iran&rsquo;s state television broadcaster while anchors were live on air. It was a symbolically potent moment: a demonstration not just of reach, but of psychological dominance.</p>



<p>Israel&rsquo;s aerial ascendancy is not free of risks. Backed into a corner, the Iranian regime may consider its survival at stake and could take more extreme measures. Iran has limited tools given the setbacks it has suffered over the last two years, but it still has terrorist proxies around the world and has attempted assassinations of major figures in the past. It might also try to sprint for a nuclear weapon in one of its remaining underground facilities.</p>



<p>The Israeli offensive&mdash;codenamed Operation Rising Lion&mdash;<a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >was launched Friday </a>after the IAEA concluded that Iran had moved closer to the threshold of producing a nuclear weapon. Since then, Israel has carried out one of the <a href="https://time.com/7293839/iran-retaliation-israel-attack-what-to-know/" >most intense and far-reaching air operations</a> in its history, targeting nuclear sites, missile launchers, airports, and senior figures in Iran&rsquo;s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</p>



<p>Prime Minister <a href="https://time.com/7294186/israel-warns-tehran-will-burn-deadly-strikes-traded-nuclear-program/" >Benjamin Netanyahu</a> has said the strikes will continue until both Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities and missile stockpiles are destroyed. U.S. President <a href="https://time.com/7294722/iran-israel-war-trump-strike/" >Donald Trump</a> on Tuesday morning backed Israel&#8217;s declaration that Tehran has lost control of Iran&rsquo;s airspace: &ldquo;We now have complete and total control of the skies over Iran,&rdquo; Trump <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699514822488706"  target="_blank">posted on Truth Social</a>. &ldquo;Iran had good sky trackers and other defensive equipment, and plenty of it, but it doesn&rsquo;t compare to American made, conceived, and manufactured &lsquo;stuff.&rsquo;  Nobody does it better than the good ol&rsquo; USA.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7293886/iranian-generals-scientists-targets-killed-by-israeli-strikes/" ><em>Here Are the Top Iranian Generals and Scientists Targeted and Killed by Israeli Strikes&mdash;and What We Know About Them</em></a></p>



<p>But while the air campaign has given Israel the upper hand militarily, it has also hardened diplomatic dead-ends. Richard Nephew, the former Deputy Special Envoy for Iran under the Biden Administration, says that reviving nuclear negotiations with Iran is now &ldquo;infinitely harder than it used to be&rdquo; because the U.S. has shown it can withdraw from an agreement at any time and is unable to control its ally in Israel. &ldquo;The idea of finding a sustainable, permanent deal here has taken a big hit as a result of Israeli military action,&rdquo; he says, adding that Trump&#8217;s 2018 withdrawal from the original nuclear agreement was the catalyst for the current crisis. &ldquo;We had a nuclear deal that was working. His own administration was saying it was working.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Now, with Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program damaged but not destroyed, and its retaliatory missile strikes continuing, military analysts say Israel may double down on the advantage its air superiority provides: more strikes, more decapitation efforts, and potentially even covert ground operations&mdash;backed by an air force that now roams Iranian skies largely unchallenged.</p>



<p>Here&rsquo;s what to know about Israel&rsquo;s air supremacy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What does it mean to have air supremacy?</h2>



<p>Air supremacy is the most complete form of aerial dominance a military can achieve. It means an air force can strike targets across a country at will, without major opposition from enemy aircraft or air defenses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For Israel to claim this over Iran just days after the strikes began is an impressive military accomplishment, says Michael Knights, the Bernstein Senior Fellow at The Washington Institute who specializes in Middle Eastern security. &ldquo;It&#8217;s exceptional to get this level of freedom. I&rsquo;m quite surprised that they&rsquo;ve managed it,&rdquo; he says, noting that not even the U.S. had been able to establish air superiority over the Houthis despite spending around $1 billion on the effort, losing over 20 major drone systems in the process.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Air superiority gives you a real edge when it comes to keeping the enemy stationary or watching whenever they try to move,&rdquo; Knights says, suggesting that Israel may use it to track key targets like nuclear facilities or where certain Iranian leaders live. The air advantage also allows Israel to bomb &ldquo;around the clock instead of just at night&rdquo; without real fear of being shot down, he adds.</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7293976/israel-iran-attack-war-hezbollah/" ><em>Israel Gets the War It Wanted</em></a></p>



<p>Israel began the war using its most advanced stealth aircraft, the F-35, enhanced with intelligence-gathering modifications to fly deep into Iranian territory and strike Iran&rsquo;s air defense radar installations and surface-to-air missile batteries. After suppressing most of Iran&rsquo;s air defenses, Israel sent older fighter jets, including F-15s and F-16s, to join the operation and began dropping JDAMs and SPICE bombs&mdash;relatively inexpensive compared to missiles&mdash;on an expanding list of military sites, some of them within the heart of Tehran.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/israel-iran-conflict-2025-05.jpg" alt="Israel Iran Conflict" alignment="center"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>Unlike Russia, which has failed to achieve similar air dominance in Ukraine after more than three years of war, Israel has accomplished it in a matter of days. Analysts credit superior training, tighter integration with intelligence and cyber operations, and the element of surprise.</p>



<p>&ldquo;The two previous Israeli retaliatory operations in 2024 taught them that they could operate within Iranian airspace relatively freely,&rdquo; Knights says. &ldquo;First you take out its command and control, its communications, radar&hellip;and pretty soon you can operate drones in daylight over Tehran.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How much damage can Israel do from the air?</h2>



<p>With aerial supremacy, Israel&rsquo;s destructive potential has increased exponentially. Without needing to rely on costly long-range missiles, Israeli jets can now fly directly over Iranian targets, drop cheaper precision bombs, and strike with greater frequency.</p>



<p>Knights says that the Israeli military will likely try to destroy the entire Iranian Navy and Iran&rsquo;s weapon storage facilities, military and civilian fuel storage sites, and national security buildings. But he notes that Israel will not be able to strike some of Iran&rsquo;s major uranium enrichment sites, like Fordow, a nuclear facility that is buried deep within a mountain and is considered nearly impervious to conventional airstrikes. &ldquo;They don&rsquo;t have bunker busters that are good enough,&rdquo; he says. </p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7294791/iran-state-tv-israel-strike/" ><em>Watch The Moment Israel Strikes Iranian State Television During Live Broadcast</em></a></p>



<p>Israeli officials have said its military has prepared at least two weeks of strikes, though that could <a href="https://time.com/7294360/trump-warns-iran-bloody-conflict-israel-death-toll-rises/" >change if the U.S. increases its involvement.</a> The U.S. military has already helped shoot down Iranian missiles fired at Israel, and Trump appears to want a full surrender from Iran rather than a ceasefire.</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">social media post</a> on Tuesday morning, Trump said the U.S. knows the location of Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei but doesn&rsquo;t want him killed &ldquo;for now.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;We know exactly where the so-called &lsquo;Supreme Leader&rdquo; is hiding,&rdquo; Trump wrote. &ldquo;He is an easy target, but is safe there&mdash;We are not going to take him out (kill!), at least not for now. But we don&rsquo;t want missiles shot at civilians, or American soldiers. Our patience is wearing thin.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;UNCONDITIONAL SURRENDER!&rdquo; Trump wrote in a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699621000737127"  target="_blank">follow up post</a>.</p>



<p>Trump&rsquo;s latest comments were likely welcomed by the Israelis, who &ldquo;were quite concerned about what kind of deal Donald Trump was going to make&rdquo; with the Iranians, Nephew says. That prompted them to &ldquo;act now, as opposed to waiting to see what else would come from the negotiating process.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/7294500/israel-attack-iran-us-involvement-trump-netanyahu-khamenei/" ><em>How Involved Was the U.S. in Israel&rsquo;s Attack on Iran?</em></a></p>



<p>Already, Israel has destroyed more than 120 surface-to-surface missile launchers&mdash;roughly a third of Iran&rsquo;s total&mdash;along with two F-14 aircraft, dozens of command centers, and critical infrastructure supporting Iran&rsquo;s nuclear and ballistic missile programs. The strike on Mashhad airport, 1,400 miles from Israel, was the longest-range attack in the campaign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran is depleting its stockpiles of missiles and drones in repeated attempts to retaliate. Iran&#8217;s ambassador to the United Nations, Amir Saeid Iravani, said that more than 220 civilians in Iran have been killed since the start of Israel&#8217;s offensive, including 20 children, while more than 1,000 people have been injured. The Israeli prime minister&#8217;s office says that at least 24 people have been killed by Iran&#8217;s retaliatory strikes against Israel, and nearly 600 injured.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Iran has turned out to be much weaker than we had assumed, and yet it&rsquo;s still standing,&rdquo; says Alex Vatanka, a Senior Fellow at the Middle East Institute who specializes in Iranian security affairs. He adds that the Iranians know the U.S. is the only country that can stop Israel from attacking, and that Iran&rsquo;s leaders are asking for talks to resume as long as the U.S. doesn&rsquo;t join the attack. &ldquo;Israel definitely cannot stay in this fight for the long haul without the U.S.,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;But Netanyahu is saying to Trump, please let me finish the job.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294919/israel-air-supremacy-tehran-iran/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294919</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lawmakers Seek to Limit Trump From Dragging U.S. Into Israel-Iran War</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Jeyaretnam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether the U.S. gets more involved than it already is, some members of Congress from both parties argue, should not be up to the President.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294985"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/trump-military.jpg" alt="Washington DC Celebrates Army's 250th Anniversary With Parade And Festivities"/>



<div class="brief-podcast-player"><h3 class="podcast-title">The Brief June 17, 2025</h3><h4>Updates on the rise of political violence in the U.S., Israel and Iran, and more</h4><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Short Length: <code>d172b396-a05f-49a8-91f4-5e9ecff5874e</code></p><p>Podcast ID &#8211; Long Length: <code>34e224e1-2194-42f7-a6bb-b33a19e61436</code></p></div>



[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]

<p>As the war between Israel and Iran rages on, it is unclear whether the Trump Administration is preparing to intervene militarily.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On <a href="https://time.com/7294722/iran-israel-war-trump-strike/" >Monday</a>, U.S. forces were sent to the Middle East, ostensibly for &ldquo;defensive&rdquo; purposes, as Donald Trump left the G7 summit early and warned Tehran to evacuate. On Tuesday, Trump insisted he was not interested in a ceasefire, called for Iran&rsquo;s &ldquo;unconditional surrender,&rdquo; and warned Iran&rsquo;s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei that &ldquo;our patience is wearing thin.&rdquo;</p>



<p>But whether the U.S. gets more involved <a href="https://time.com/7294500/israel-attack-iran-us-involvement-trump-netanyahu-khamenei/" >than it already is</a>, some members of Congress from both parties argue, is not a decision that should be up to the President.</p>



<p>Reps. Thomas Massie (R-Ky.) and Ro Khanna (D-Calif.) introduced a war powers <a href="https://massie.house.gov/uploadedfiles/iranwpr.pdf"  target="_blank">resolution</a> on Tuesday that asserts the requirement of Congress&rsquo; approval if Trump wants to commit armed forces to military action in the region.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is not our war. But if it were, Congress must decide such matters according to our Constitution,&rdquo; Massie <a href="https://x.com/RepThomasMassie/status/1934749340813476204"  target="_blank">posted</a> on X on Monday night.</p>



<p>Outspoken progressive Reps. <a href="https://x.com/AOC/status/1934791134049341538"  target="_blank">Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez</a> (D-N.Y.) and <a href="https://x.com/IlhanMN/status/1934975318005305657"  target="_blank">Ilhan Omar</a> (D-Minn.), replied &ldquo;Signing on&rdquo; to Massie&rsquo;s post. They and 12 other Democrats are cosponsoring the bill, <a href="https://massie.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=395731"  target="_blank">according</a> to Massie&rsquo;s office.</p>



<p>Sen. Tim Kaine (D-Va.) introduced a companion <a href="https://www.kaine.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/iran_war_powers_resolution.pdf"  target="_blank">war powers resolution</a> in the upper chamber on Monday that would terminate the unauthorized use of U.S. armed forces against Iran, given that there has not been a declaration of war, which only Congress can issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>War powers resolutions are &ldquo;privileged,&rdquo; meaning that the House and Senate are required to promptly debate and vote on the resolutions.</p>



<p>&ldquo;I am deeply concerned that the recent escalation of hostilities between Israel and Iran could quickly pull the United States into another endless conflict,&rdquo; Kaine said in a <a href="https://www.kaine.senate.gov/press-releases/kaine-announces-the-filing-of-a-war-powers-resolution-to-prevent-war-with-iran"  target="_blank">statement</a>. &ldquo;This resolution will ensure that if we decide to place our nation&rsquo;s men and women in uniform into harm&rsquo;s way, we will have a debate and vote on it in Congress.&rdquo;</p>



<div class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-video-jw">[video id=KBP7sVeC autostart="viewable"]</div>



<p>These are also not the first proposals by lawmakers seeking to limit U.S. military engagement in the conflict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-Vt.) also introduced a separate <a href="https://www.sanders.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/DAV25B57.pdf"  target="_blank">bill</a>, cosponsored by Sens. Elizabeth Warren (D-Mass.) and Chris Van Hollen (D-Md.), on Monday that would prohibit the use of federal funds for &ldquo;any use of military force in or against Iran&rdquo; without congressional approval, with the exception of self-defense.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Another war in the Middle East could cost countless lives, waste trillions more dollars and lead to even more deaths, more conflict, and more displacement,&rdquo; Sanders said in a <a href="https://www.sanders.senate.gov/press-releases/news-sanders-introduces-no-war-against-iran-act/"  target="_blank">statement</a>. &ldquo;I will do everything that I can as a Senator to defend the Constitution and prevent the US from being drawn into another war.&rdquo;</p>



<p>While the measures seeking to constrain Trump are unlikely to pass in the Republican-majority House or Senate, proponents have said that they want to force lawmakers to show where they stand on an issue where the public has been very clear. According to a <a href="https://criticalissues.umd.edu/sites/criticalissues.umd.edu/files/Questionnaire_May2025.pdf"  target="_blank">University of Maryland poll in May</a>, before Israel <a href="https://time.com/7293795/israel-strikes-iran-attack-what-to-know/" >launched its strikes against Iran last Friday</a>, only 14% of U.S. respondents across political parties supported &ldquo;Military action in attempt to destroy Iran&rsquo;s nuclear program.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s time for every member to go on record,&rdquo; Khanna <a href="https://x.com/RoKhanna/status/1934782903935697058"  target="_blank">posted</a>. &ldquo;Are you with the neocons who led us into Iraq or do you stand with the American people?&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What the Constitution says</h2>



<p>War powers are <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/war_powers"  target="_blank">divided</a> between Congress and the President, according to the Constitution. While the President is named the Commander in Chief of the Army and Navy, only Congress has the authority to decide whether the U.S. should go to war&mdash;either a total war or more limited uses of force. The President retains inherent defensive powers to use military force without congressional authorization if the U.S. is attacked, but congressional approval is still needed for a prolonged war.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.nixonlibrary.gov/news/war-powers-resolution-1973"  target="_blank">War Powers Resolution of 1973</a> provided further guidance on the President&rsquo;s war powers, including that the President must have congressional approval for the use of force abroad except for certain circumstances like safely removing troops or rescuing Americans overseas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nevertheless, the executive branch has expanded its view of the President&rsquo;s defensive war powers, most notably with its interpretations of the 2001 and 2002 Authorizations of Use of Military Force (AUMF). Congress passed the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/107/plaws/publ40/PLAW-107publ40.pdf?ref=hir.harvard.edu"  target="_blank">2001 AUMF</a> after the September 11 attacks to allow the use of force against entities that &ldquo;planned, authorized, committed, or aided&rdquo; in the attacks or &ldquo;harbored such organizations or persons.&rdquo; The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/107th-congress/house-joint-resolution/114/text?ref=hir.harvard.edu"  target="_blank">2002 AUMF</a> authorized military action against Saddam Hussein&rsquo;s Iraq government &ldquo;to defend the national security of the United States against the continuing threat posed by Iraq&rdquo; and was used to justify the 2003 invasion of Iraq.</p>



<p>But the authorizations have been <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/blog/what-the-aumf-is-and-why-you-should-care-2018/"  target="_blank">criticized</a> for effectively giving Presidents a &ldquo;<a href="https://www.fcnl.org/sites/default/files/2024-09/UncheckedWar.AUMFLimits.pdf"  target="_blank">blank check</a>&rdquo; to direct military actions without congressional approval <a href="https://hir.harvard.edu/runaway-authorization-tower-22/"  target="_blank">far beyond</a> their original intended scope. When Trump in his first term authorized the killing of Iranian general Qasem Soleimani, Defense Department general counsel explained at the time that it distilled the President&rsquo;s constitutional and statutory authority to direct military action into a broad <a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/Speeches/Speech/Article/2181868/dod-general-counsel-remarks-at-byu-law-school/"  target="_blank">two-part test</a>: first, &ldquo;whether the President could reasonably determine that the action serves important national interests,&rdquo; and second, whether the military action does not necessarily &ldquo;bring the nation into the kind of protracted conflict that would rise to the level of a &lsquo;war.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>



<p>There have been multiple <a href="https://missouriindependent.com/2024/03/22/the-u-s-senate-repealed-iraq-war-authorizations-a-year-ago-in-the-house-theyre-frozen/"  target="_blank">unsuccessful efforts</a> by both parties to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/17/1007363054/congress-is-poised-to-take-back-some-of-its-war-powers-from-the-president"  target="_blank">repeal</a> the 2001 and 2002 AUMFs, including by Kaine in 2023 with the <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/republican-senators-oppose-iraq-war-aumf-repeal-2023-3"  target="_blank">support</a> of then-Sen. J.D. Vance (R-Ohio), who <a href="https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/2270101/aumf-mirage-republicans-still-hawkish-on-war-powers-despite-support-for-repeal/"  target="_blank">said at the time</a>: &ldquo;I think the fact that you have a lot of Republicans who are very skeptical of continuing to provide a blank check here I think is a good sign.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Vance, now Vice President, appears to have changed his position, <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1934996183702704404"  target="_blank">posting</a> on X on Tuesday that Trump &ldquo;may decide he needs to take further action to end Iranian enrichment. That decision ultimately belongs to the president.&rdquo;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Party splits</h2>



<p>Conflict with Iran has divided <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/house/5350106-israel-iran-conflict-democrats/"  target="_blank">Democrats</a> and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/israel-iran-conflict-splits-maga-leaving-trump-navigate-rcna212786"  target="_blank">Republicans</a>&mdash;not along party lines but within them.</p>



<p>While some &ldquo;America First&rdquo; voices have <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/13/the-intra-gop-fight-over-israels-strikes-on-iran"  target="_blank">rallied against</a> direct U.S. involvement, Trump&rsquo;s MAGA camp also includes war hawks like Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-S.C.), who has <a href="https://x.com/LindseyGrahamSC/status/1933569381881053429"  target="_blank">said</a> on X that, if negotiations fail, the U.S. should &ldquo;go all-in to help Israel finish the job.&rdquo;</p>



<p>&ldquo;If diplomacy is not successful, and we are left with the option of force, I would urge President Trump to go all in to make sure that, when this operation is over, there&rsquo;s nothing left standing in Iran regarding their nuclear program,&rdquo; Graham <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/senators-richard-blumenthal-connecticut-lindsey-graham-south-carolina-face-the-nation-transcript-06-15-2025/"  target="_blank">said</a> on CBS on Sunday. &ldquo;If that means providing bombs, provide bombs. &hellip; If it means flying with Israel, fly with Israel.&rdquo;</p>



<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/7295241/trump-iran-israel-tucker-carlson/" ><em>Why Trump&rsquo;s MAGA Base Is Splintering Over Iran and Israel</em></a></p>



<p>Nine lawmakers led by Rep. Josh Gottheimer (D-N.J.), a pro-Israel Democrat, signed onto a <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25976120-gottheimer-bacon-letter-trump-iran/"  target="_blank">letter</a> imploring Trump to apply &ldquo;crushing diplomatic pressure in addition to Israel&rsquo;s military pressure&rdquo; on Iran towards zero nuclear enrichment.</p>



<p>Trump, who also faces <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/06/14/israel-iran-war-us-nuclear-program-trump"  target="_blank">pressure from Israel</a> to join the war, has for days urged finding a diplomatic solution to the conflict but signaled a potential shift to a more offensive stance on Tuesday, posting on Truth Social that he has &ldquo;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/114697964891587065"  target="_blank">not reached out to Iran for &lsquo;peace talks&rsquo; in any way, shape, or form</a>&rdquo; and that the U.S. knows where Khamenei is but won&rsquo;t &ldquo;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114699610769479275"  target="_blank">take him out (kill!), at least not for now.</a>&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294985/iran-israel-trump-us-war-powers-congress-massie-khanna-kaine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294985</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Wants Rare Earths. But Challenging China’s Dominance Will Take More Than Tariffs</title>
		<link>https://time.com/7294964/us-rare-earths-minerals-china-dominance-trump-tariffs/</link>
					<comments>https://time.com/7294964/us-rare-earths-minerals-china-dominance-trump-tariffs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News desk edits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=7294964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How America and its allies can break free of Chinese dependency is a geopolitical priority with sweeping ramifications but no easy answer.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-7294964"></div></div>
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/7294964/us-rare-earths-minerals-china-dominance-trump-tariffs/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>

<img decoding="async" class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-featured-media" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-1148483593.jpg" alt="Inside The Mountain Pass Mine As Rare Earths Face Trade War Threats"/>



<p>When, in December 1953, <em>Dragnet</em> became the first American television show to broadcast in color, few fans knew they had a dusty nook on the California-Nevada border to thank for bringing it to polychromatic life. But every early cathode-ray tube color television owed its screen&rsquo;s red hue to europium, a rare earth element excavated and processed exclusively at the Mountain Pass Mine in San Bernardino County.</p>
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]




<p>From the 1950s to the 1980s, Mountain Pass produced practically all known quantities of europium, as well as over 90% across the spectrum of rare earth minerals worldwide. Back then, of course, uses were limited: apart from europium adding vibrancy to L.A. cop procedurals, cerium was used as a glass polishing agent, while lanthanum was&mdash;and still is&mdash;crucial for oil cracking, or turning crude into gasoline and other lighter fuels.</p>



<p>Today, however, the picture is very different. Rare earth materials are vital for myriad industries, from advanced weaponry to wind turbines and robotics. But far from the U.S. having a monopoly on production, now some 96% of rare earth minerals are sourced from China, propelling these arcane materials into center stage in the escalating trade war between the world&rsquo;s top two economies.</p>



<p>In response to President Donald Trump imposing tariffs of 145% on Chinese goods, as well as curbing the sale of strategic U.S. technology including semiconductor chips, China hit back by restricting the export of rare earth elements. Auto <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-rare-earth-export-curbs-risk-halting-german-car-production-lobby-group-2025-06-03/"  target="_blank">manufacturers</a> across the U.S., Japan, South Korea, Germany and India have warned the shortages may <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-curbs-exports-strategic-minerals-2025-02-04/#:~:text=German%20automakers%20became,factories%20could%20close."  target="_blank">force factories</a> to halt production.</p>



<p>The spat prompted Trump to hit out at China for reneging on a nascent trade deal between the superpowers. Then, last week, Trump <a href="https://time.com/7292207/us-china-trade-war-trump-tariffs-timeline/" >revealed</a> a &ldquo;framework&rdquo; struck in London that supposedly will ease U.S. access to China&rsquo;s rare earth minerals and magnets in exchange for setting tariffs on Chinese exports at 55% and a relaxing of <a href="https://time.com/7289945/us-china-trump-rubio-international-student-visa-restrictions-trade-negotiations/" >curbs on Chinese students&rsquo; access</a> to U.S. colleges. &ldquo;Full magnets, and any necessary rare earths, will be supplied, up front, by China,&rdquo; Trump posted on Truth Social.</p>



<p>But reports from Washington suggest that the deal will expire in just six months, and with U.S.-China relations continuing to spiral, how America and its allies can break itself free of its Chinese rare earth dependency is a geopolitical priority. While it&rsquo;s a question with sweeping economic ramifications, it&rsquo;s also one with no easy answer.</p>



<p>&ldquo;Everybody wants to just snap their fingers and start producing heavy rare earth elements,&rdquo; says Mark Smith, CEO of rare earths firm NioCorp, who has worked in the industry for almost four decades. &ldquo;But it&rsquo;s a very long, hard process. And the longer we wait, the further China gets ahead.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>China has bet on rare earths for a long time. Back in 1992, reformist leader Deng Xiaoping declared: &ldquo;The Middle East has oil, China has rare earths.&rdquo;</p>



<p>China accompanied this strategic focus with billions of dollars of investment in mines and processing facilities to monopolize the market. Just like countless strategic industries, China wielded huge state subsidies, and little concern for environmental or safety standards, to produce rare earths at a fraction of the cost of Western competitors.</p>



<p>As a result, in 1998, Mountain Pass&rsquo; separation plant ceased producing refined rare earth compounds. Four years later, a toxic waste spill led the mine to close altogether, and intense Chinese competition impelled the decision not to reopen.</p>



<p>At the same time, uses of rare earths were just ramping up. Today, yttrium is used in lighting and flat screens; ytterbium in cancer treatments and earthquake monitoring; erbium in lasers and fiberoptic cables. But particularly important are permanent rare earth magnets, which account for a quarter of total rare earths consumption and are a vital component in actuators, or devices that turn a control signal into mechanical motion. These could be robot arms on assembly lines, the fins of a ballistic missile or stealth bomber, or any of the multiple motors of an electric vehicle.</p>



<p>But it&rsquo;s not just EVs that rely on actuators and, by extension, permanent rare earth magnets. Conventional internal combustion engine vehicles are also heavily reliant on these materials. That is how, in 2010, China managed to bring Japan&rsquo;s auto industry to the brink of collapse by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/23/business/global/23rare.html"  target="_blank">halting</a> exports of rare earth materials amid a territorial spat in the East China Sea.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-104550998.jpg" alt="Pentagon Losing Control of Bombs to China's Monopoly" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>In the following year, prices of rare earths <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/12/japan-rare-earths-huge-deposit-of-metals-found-in-pacific.html#:~:text=As%20a%20major%20electronics%20manufacturer,sources%2C%20according%20to%20the%20Journal."  target="_blank">soared</a> by 10 times and the incident served as a wake-up call that was only partly heeded. Japan invested in alternative sources, particularly in Australia, though remains heavily dependent on Chinese supplies. That September, the U.S. House passed the Rare Earths and Critical Materials Revitalization Act to subsidize the revival of the American rare earths industry, including reopening Mountain Pass, which resumed production in 2012 only to fall into bankruptcy three years later. Today, under the new ownership of MP Materials, it remains the only functioning American rare earth mine.</p>



<p>Crucially, however, not all rare earths are created equal. What are termed rare earths are in fact a &ldquo;basket&rdquo; of 17 elements with overlapping but ultimately unique properties. Regarding permanent rare earth magnets for actuators, the most common element is neodymium, which can be sourced from Mountain Pass. The problem is that for actuators to work at high temperatures&mdash;like those found under a car&rsquo;s hood&mdash;the neodymium needs to be mixed with either dysprosium or terbium, distinct rare earth minerals which are not significantly present in the Mountain Pass ore body.</p>



<p>In fact, China controls practically 100% of global supply of dysprosium and terbium and added both to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-hits-back-us-tariffs-with-rare-earth-export-controls-2025-04-04/"  target="_blank">export controls</a> on April 4. Tellingly, Beijing didn&rsquo;t bother restricting sales of neodymium, cognizant of alternative sources&mdash;and the fact they are largely useless without their heat-resistant siblings.</p>



<p>So where can American firms source dysprosium and terbium&mdash;and fast?</p>



<hr/>



<p>At the Lynas rare earth mine in Mount Weld, Western Australia, yellow diggers scoop the tawny earth and dump it into soot-stained trucks. Following on-site concentration, the semi-refined ore is then taken on a four-hour drive to processing facilities in nearby Kalgoorlie, or loaded on ships to Malaysia, where in the seaside town of Kuantan Lynas operates the world&rsquo;s largest rare earth processing plant. Crucially, in May the Kuantan plant produced its first batch of dysprosium and is expecting its first terbium this month.</p>



<p>&ldquo;This is an exciting achievement for Lynas and for manufacturers keen to secure a resilient supply of separated rare earths products,&rdquo; Amanda Lacaze, CEO and managing director of Lynas Rare Earths, tells TIME. &ldquo;We have stated our intention to meet the needs of the U.S. Defense Industrial Base on a priority basis.&rdquo;</p>



<p>It&rsquo;s a great start, but given the insatiable global appetite for rare earths, many more sources will ultimately be needed. And other options are years from fruition.</p>



<p>It was with great fanfare that Trump <a href="https://time.com/7282110/ukraine-minerals-deal/" >signed</a> a deal with Ukraine in March that ostensibly handed half the war-torn nation&rsquo;s future oil, gas, and mineral wealth&mdash;including rare earths&mdash;to the U.S. The only problem is that Ukraine may have abundant reserves of lithium and titanium, but it <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-rare-earth-minerals"  target="_blank">doesn&rsquo;t actually have rare earths</a> in any sizable deposits worthy of exploitation.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2207178869.jpg" alt="Mount Karachun Near The City Of Sloviansk In Donetsk Oblast" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>What about Greenland? Trump has repeatedly touted buying or even invading the semi-autonomous Danish province, citing its mineral wealth. In March, Vice President J.D. Vance led a U.S. delegation including National Security Adviser Michael Waltz and Energy Secretary Chris Wright to Greenland. But while Greenland does boast 18% of the world&rsquo;s total rare earth reserves, accessing them is extremely problematic, owing to freezing temperatures and a thick layer of silica. Chinese, American, and European prospectors have spent decades trying to figure out how to extract these resources without any success. Today, Greenland has no functioning rare earth mines.</p>



<p>Other options are more feasible. Brazil has the world&rsquo;s third largest reserves of rare earths and is aggressively exploring this space, while Saudi Arabia also boasts significant deposits and signed a cooperation agreement with the U.S. on critical minerals during Trump&rsquo;s visit in May. MP Materials and Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s national mining company, Maaden, also <a href="https://investors.mpmaterials.com/investor-news/news-details/2025/Maaden-and-MP-Materials-Collaborate-to-Establish-Full-Value-Chain-for-Rare-Earth-Magnetics/default.aspx"  target="_blank">signed</a> a MoU to collaborate on establishing a rare earth supply chain in the Gulf state.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Japan&rsquo;s state-owned energy firm JOGMEC and gas firm Iwatani have <a href="https://www.mining.com/web/japans-jogmec-iwatani-to-invest-120-million-in-french-rare-earths-project/#:~:text=The%20$1.83%20billion%20all%2Dstock,Equinox%20from%20the%20current%20seven."  target="_blank">unveiled</a> plans to invest up to $120 million in a French rare earths refining project.</p>



<p>And with Africa boasting four of the top 10 nations for rare earth exploration last year&mdash;namely South Africa, Namibia, Uganda, and Malawi&mdash;the continent stands to play a huge role in future supply chains.</p>



<p>But there are also options closer to home. Other than Mountain Pass, Lynas has <a href="https://lynasrareearths.com/u-s-dod-strengthens-support-for-lynas-u-s-facility/"  target="_blank">secured</a> $258 million from the U.S. Department of Defense to build a heavy rare earth refinement facility in Seadrift, Texas. &ldquo;The U.S. facility has been designed with the capability to process feedstock from other sources as and when they become available and are qualified,&rdquo; says Lacaze.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, NioCorp has the permits to build a rare earth processing facility at its Elk Creek Mine in Nebraska and is currently waiting on a $780 million financing agreement with the U.S. Export&ndash;Import Bank for the $1.2 billion project, which will take around three years to get online. Smith, the NioCorp CEO, says he is currently 2.5 steps through a four-step approval process, which if greenlighted will provide up to 1,500 jobs during construction followed by a 450-strong full-time crew. Although Smith predicts Elk Creek could service all Department of Defense dysprosium and terbium needs, he&rsquo;s under no illusions about the scale of the challenge.</p>



<p>&ldquo;One thing absolutely for sure is that NioCorp, by itself, is not the whole answer to the problem,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;So we&rsquo;re rooting for anybody to be an additional part of the solution. We need to put all the parts together to really be formidable against China.&rdquo;</p>



<hr/>



<p>Unfortunately, simply seeding projects in friendly countries doesn&rsquo;t solve the problem. For one, China controls the separation and refining equipment market and placed export controls on those technologies in December 2023. Today, the rare earth refining industry is scrambling to reverse engineer Chinese technologies or innovate entirely new ones.</p>



<p>There is also the matter of expertise. Refining rare earths is &ldquo;a whole new art unto itself,&rdquo; says Smith. Heavy rare earth elements are extremely close to each other in terms of their atomic weights, making the process to separate each from the other at sufficient purity levels for commercial or military applications extremely taxing.</p>



<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s chemical engineering involved, there&rsquo;s physics, there&rsquo;s kinetics,&rdquo; says Smith. &ldquo;It takes a whole bunch of knowhow, practice, and art to get heavy rare earths into their final purified oxide form. As well as a big investment.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The cash injections needed keep on growing. Lynas&rsquo;s Texas project, for one, is currently stalled as the firm seeks more government funding on top of the nine figures already pledged. &ldquo;Following design changes to accommodate local permitting, additional CAPEX will be required, and Lynas is in discussion with the U.S. government with respect to this funding,&rdquo; says Lacaze.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gutenberg-custom-blocks-inline-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-1148483614.jpg" alt="Inside The Mountain Pass Mine As Rare Earths Face Trade War Threats" alignment="original-size-image"/><p class="article_header"></p><p class="article_subheading"></p><p class="article_text"></p></figure>



<p>But even if all these new rare earth projects are realized across the globe, challenging Chinese dominance must still overcome its toughest obstacle: price.</p>



<p>China has spent decades building out massive capacity for rare earth minerals, so all other competitors operate at a huge disadvantage. &ldquo;The inside China price is used by outside China customers as a benchmark,&rdquo; says Lacaze. &ldquo;We have not observed any intent from the majority of non-Chinese consumers to pay a significant premium to the inside China price.&rdquo;</p>



<p>Moreover, China&rsquo;s massive processing capacity means it just opens the spigot whenever a potential competitor emerges to price them out of the market. The Chinese state has no problem eating any short-term losses to maintain key strategic levers over the global economy. It&rsquo;s a similar dynamic for many different minerals, including cobalt, nickel, and titanium. Today, neodymium oxide costs less than $60 per kilogram&mdash;around half its 2023 cost&mdash;and is <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/450152/global-reo-neodymium-oxide-price-forecast/"  target="_blank">forecast</a> to get even cheaper.</p>



<p>&ldquo;One of the biggest challenges we face is that rare earth prices are very low,&rdquo; says Gracelin Baskaran, director of the Critical Minerals Security Program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies. &ldquo;And a lot of that has been achieved through market manipulation by China increasing and increasing production.&rdquo;</p>



<p>The cost issue looks frankly impossible to solve. Other than technical challenges, refining rare earth minerals uses a huge amount of water. Back when China was first ramping up its rare earth industry, wastewater was just discharged into the nearest river, although environmental standards have tightened considerably in recent years. In the U.S. or other developed economies, wastewater must be evaporated in huge kilns to isolate and dispose of pollutants&mdash;though this is a very energy intensive and thus costly process. &ldquo;And it&rsquo;s not something that China has to do,&rdquo; shrugs Smith.</p>



<p>So, the big question is how American&mdash;or Saudi or African&mdash;rare earths can survive in such a cost-competitive marketplace. Various mechanisms have been considered: One is a <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/contractfordifferences.asp"  target="_blank">Contract for Difference</a> model, which is common in agriculture and says that if prices fall below a certain point the government will pay the difference. Another option is having the government serve as an <a href="https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/what-is-an-offtake-agreement/"  target="_blank">Offtaker of Last Resort</a>, agreeing to buy minerals at a certain price if nobody wants them on the open market.</p>



<p>However, &ldquo;in the U.S., at least in an era of <a href="https://time.com/7222251/doge-musk-federal-workers-government/" >DOGE</a>, putting in an indefinite OPEX subsidy is quite politically unpalatable,&rdquo; says Baskaran. &ldquo;But it is what China will do, so how do we compete against a country that&rsquo;s willing to inject fiscal support at any part of the supply chain to retain their dominance?&rdquo;</p>



<p>Another potential solution is one very close to Trump&rsquo;s heart: tariffs. By hiking levies on Chinese rare earths, the U.S. could strongarm firms to source from preferred friendly nations. But this essentially shifts the cost burden from government to businesses, undermining their global competitiveness with unknown ramifications down the line.</p>



<p>For Smith, tariffs are merely a stop-gap solution. &ldquo;The answer cannot be for President Trump to issue a tariff,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;We need to be competitive with or without tariffs by increasing our technology, improving our processes, using more robotics. But we must have a legitimate business at the end of the day.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://api.time.com/7294964/us-rare-earths-minerals-china-dominance-trump-tariffs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7294964</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
