<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Schneier on Security</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2025-06-29T22:50:14Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/" />
	<id>https://www.schneier.com/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/feed/atom/" />

	
<icon>https://www.schneier.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</icon>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Cybersecurity Fears Affect Confidence in Voting Systems]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/cyberattacks-shake-voters-trust-in-elections.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70420</id>
		<updated>2025-06-29T22:50:14Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-30T11:05:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="cyberattack" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="democracy" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="essays" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="trust" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="voting" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>American democracy runs on trust, and that trust is cracking.</p>
<p>Nearly half of Americans, both Democrats and Republicans, question whether elections are <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/651185/partisan-split-election-integrity-gets-even-wider.aspx">conducted fairly</a>. Some voters accept election results only <a href="https://worldjusticeproject.org/our-work/research-and-data/rule-law-united-states">when their side wins</a>. The problem isn&#8217;t just political polarization&#8212;it&#8217;s a creeping <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2018/10/29/elections-in-america-concerns-over-security-divisions-over-expanding-access-to-voting/">erosion of trust</a> in the machinery of democracy itself.</p>
<p>Commentators blame ideological tribalism, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/09/business/media/election-disinformation-2024.html">misinformation campaigns</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/06/15/opinion/social-media-polarization-democracy.html">partisan echo chambers</a> for this crisis of trust. But these explanations miss a critical piece of the puzzle: a growing unease with the digital infrastructure that now underpins nearly every aspect of how Americans vote...</p>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/cyberattacks-shake-voters-trust-in-elections.html"><![CDATA[<p>American democracy runs on trust, and that trust is cracking.</p>
<p>Nearly half of Americans, both Democrats and Republicans, question whether elections are <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/651185/partisan-split-election-integrity-gets-even-wider.aspx">conducted fairly</a>. Some voters accept election results only <a href="https://worldjusticeproject.org/our-work/research-and-data/rule-law-united-states">when their side wins</a>. The problem isn&#8217;t just political polarization&#8212;it&#8217;s a creeping <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2018/10/29/elections-in-america-concerns-over-security-divisions-over-expanding-access-to-voting/">erosion of trust</a> in the machinery of democracy itself.</p>
<p>Commentators blame ideological tribalism, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/09/business/media/election-disinformation-2024.html">misinformation campaigns</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/06/15/opinion/social-media-polarization-democracy.html">partisan echo chambers</a> for this crisis of trust. But these explanations miss a critical piece of the puzzle: a growing unease with the digital infrastructure that now underpins nearly every aspect of how Americans vote.</p>
<p>The digital transformation of American elections has been swift and sweeping. Just two decades ago, most people voted using mechanical levers or punch cards. Today, <a href="https://electionlab.mit.edu/research/voting-technology">over 95% of ballots</a> are counted electronically. Digital systems have replaced poll books, taken over voter identity verification processes and are integrated into registration, counting, auditing and voting systems.</p>
<p>This technological leap has made voting more accessible and efficient, and <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/voting-has-never-been-more-secure-than-it-is-right-now/">sometimes more secure</a>. But these new systems are also more complex. And that complexity plays into the hands of those looking to undermine democracy.</p>
<p>In recent years, authoritarian regimes have refined a <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/china-midterms-elections-influence-nord-hacking/">chillingly effective strategy</a> to chip away at Americans&#8217; faith in democracy by relentlessly sowing doubt about the tools U.S. states use to conduct elections. It&#8217;s a sustained <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/misinformation-is-eroding-the-publics-confidence-in-democracy/">campaign to fracture civic faith</a> and make Americans believe that democracy is rigged, especially when their side loses.</p>
<p>This is not cyberwar in the traditional sense. There&#8217;s no evidence that anyone has managed to break into voting machines and alter votes. But cyberattacks on election systems don&#8217;t need to succeed to have an effect. Even a single failed intrusion, magnified by sensational headlines and political echo chambers, is enough to shake public trust. By feeding into existing anxiety about the complexity and opacity of digital systems, adversaries create <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/01/business/media/china-online-disinformation-us-election.html">fertile ground for disinformation and conspiracy theories</a>.</p>
<h3>Testing cyber fears</h3>
<p>To test this dynamic, we launched a study to uncover precisely how cyberattacks corroded trust in the vote during the 2024 U.S. presidential race. We surveyed more than 3,000 voters before and after election day, testing them using a series of fictional but highly realistic breaking news reports depicting cyberattacks against critical infrastructure. We randomly assigned participants to watch different types of news reports: some depicting cyberattacks on election systems, others on unrelated infrastructure such as the power grid, and a third, neutral control group.</p>
<p>The results, which are under peer review, were both striking and sobering. Mere exposure to reports of cyberattacks <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1M0iGIYk_WsxumppZ4ZEVAANS4CC9lTaQ/view">undermined trust in the electoral process</a>&#8212;regardless of partisanship. Voters who supported the losing candidate experienced the greatest drop in trust, with two-thirds of Democratic voters showing heightened skepticism toward the election results.</p>
<p>But winners too showed diminished confidence. Even though most Republican voters, buoyed by their victory, accepted the overall security of the election, the majority of those who viewed news reports about cyberattacks remained suspicious.</p>
<p>The attacks didn&#8217;t even have to be related to the election. Even cyberattacks against critical infrastructure such as utilities had spillover effects. Voters seemed to extrapolate: &#8220;If the power grid can be hacked, why should I believe that voting machines are secure?&#8221;</p>
<p>Strikingly, voters who used digital machines to cast their ballots were the most rattled. For this group of people, belief in the accuracy of the vote count fell by nearly twice as much as that of voters who cast their ballots by mail and who didn&#8217;t use any technology. Their firsthand experience with the sorts of systems being portrayed as vulnerable personalized the threat.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not hard to see why. When you&#8217;ve just used a touchscreen to vote, and then you see a news report about a digital system being breached, the leap in logic isn&#8217;t far.</p>
<p>Our data suggests that in a digital society, perceptions of trust&#8212;and distrust&#8212;are fluid, contagious and easily activated. The cyber domain isn&#8217;t just about networks and code. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/jogss/ogac042">It&#8217;s also about emotions</a>: fear, vulnerability and uncertainty.</p>
<h3>Firewall of trust</h3>
<p>Does this mean we should scrap electronic voting machines? Not necessarily.</p>
<p>Every election system, digital or analog, has flaws. And in many respects, today&#8217;s high-tech systems have solved the problems of the past with voter-verifiable paper ballots. Modern voting machines reduce human error, increase accessibility and speed up the vote count. No one misses the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2000/11/12/us/counting-the-vote-the-ballots-after-cards-are-poked-the-confetti-can-count.html">hanging chads</a> of 2000.</p>
<p>But technology, no matter how advanced, cannot instill legitimacy on its own. It must be paired with something harder to code: public trust. In an environment where foreign adversaries amplify every flaw, cyberattacks can trigger spirals of suspicion. It is no longer enough for elections to be secure &#8211; voters must also <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2018/apr/18/american-elections-hack-bruce-scheier">perceive them to be secure</a>.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/22/learning/2024-election-teaching-resources.html">public education</a> surrounding elections is now as vital to election security as firewalls and encrypted networks. It&#8217;s vital that voters understand how elections are run, how they&#8217;re protected and how failures are caught and corrected. Election officials, civil society groups and researchers can teach <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/audits/">how audits work</a>, host open-source verification demonstrations and ensure that high-tech electoral processes are comprehensible to voters.</p>
<p>We believe this is an essential investment in democratic resilience. But it needs to be proactive, not reactive. By the time the doubt takes hold, it&#8217;s already too late.</p>
<p>Just as crucially, we are convinced that it&#8217;s time to rethink the very nature of cyber threats. People often imagine them in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/17/us/politics/china-cyber-us-infrastructure.html">military terms</a>. But that framework misses the true power of these threats. The danger of cyberattacks is not only that they can destroy infrastructure or steal classified secrets, but that they chip away at societal cohesion, sow anxiety and fray citizens&#8217; confidence in democratic institutions. These attacks erode the very idea of truth itself by making people doubt that anything can be trusted.</p>
<p>If trust is the target, then we believe that elected officials should start to treat trust as a national asset: something to be built, renewed and defended. Because in the end, elections aren&#8217;t just about votes being counted&#8212;they&#8217;re about people believing that those votes count.</p>
<p>And in that belief lies the true firewall of democracy.</p>
<p><em>This essay was written with Ryan Shandler and Anthony J. DeMattee, and originally appeared in <a href="https://theconversation.com/cyberattacks-shake-voters-trust-in-elections-regardless-of-party-259368">The Conversation</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/cyberattacks-shake-voters-trust-in-elections.html#comments" thr:count="18" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/cyberattacks-shake-voters-trust-in-elections.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="18" />
			<thr:total>18</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Squid Blogging: What to Do When You Find a Squid “Egg Mop”]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-what-to-do-when-you-find-a-squid-egg-mop.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70417</id>
		<updated>2025-06-27T16:07:23Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-27T21:04:46Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="squid" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.stv.tv/north/what-are-squid-egg-mops-and-what-to-do-if-you-find-one">Tips</a> on what to do if you find a mop of squid eggs.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also use this squid post to talk about the security stories in the news that I haven&#8217;t covered.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2024/06/new-blog-moderation-policy.html">Blog moderation policy.</a></p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-what-to-do-when-you-find-a-squid-egg-mop.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.stv.tv/north/what-are-squid-egg-mops-and-what-to-do-if-you-find-one">Tips</a> on what to do if you find a mop of squid eggs.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also use this squid post to talk about the security stories in the news that I haven&#8217;t covered.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2024/06/new-blog-moderation-policy.html">Blog moderation policy.</a></p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-what-to-do-when-you-find-a-squid-egg-mop.html#comments" thr:count="19" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-what-to-do-when-you-find-a-squid-egg-mop.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="19" />
			<thr:total>19</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Age of Integrity]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/the-age-of-integrity.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70415</id>
		<updated>2025-06-26T08:54:52Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-27T11:02:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="AI" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="LLM" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We need to talk about data integrity.</p>
<p>Narrowly, the term refers to ensuring that data isn’t tampered with, either in transit or in storage. Manipulating account balances in bank databases, removing entries from criminal records, and murder by removing notations about allergies from medical records are all integrity attacks.</p>
<p>More broadly, integrity refers to ensuring that data is correct and accurate from the point it is collected, through all the ways it is used, modified, transformed, and eventually deleted. Integrity-related incidents include malicious actions, but also inadvertent mistakes...</p>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/the-age-of-integrity.html"><![CDATA[<p>We need to talk about data integrity.</p>
<p>Narrowly, the term refers to ensuring that data isn’t tampered with, either in transit or in storage. Manipulating account balances in bank databases, removing entries from criminal records, and murder by removing notations about allergies from medical records are all integrity attacks.</p>
<p>More broadly, integrity refers to ensuring that data is correct and accurate from the point it is collected, through all the ways it is used, modified, transformed, and eventually deleted. Integrity-related incidents include malicious actions, but also inadvertent mistakes.</p>
<p>We tend not to think of them this way, but we have many primitive integrity measures built into our computer systems. The reboot process, which returns a computer to a known good state, is an integrity measure. The undo button is another integrity measure. Any of our systems that detect hard drive errors, file corruption, or dropped internet packets are integrity measures.</p>
<p>Just as a website leaving personal data exposed even if no one accessed it counts as a privacy breach, a system that fails to guarantee the accuracy of its data counts as an integrity breach – even if no one deliberately manipulated that data.</p>
<p>Integrity has always been important, but as we start using massive amounts of data to both train and operate AI systems, data integrity will become more critical than ever.</p>
<p>Most of the attacks against AI systems are integrity attacks. Affixing small stickers on road signs to fool AI driving systems is an integrity violation. Prompt injection attacks are another integrity violation. In both cases, the AI model can’t distinguish between legitimate data and malicious input: visual in the first case, text instructions in the second. Even worse, the AI model can’t distinguish between legitimate data and malicious commands.</p>
<p>Any attacks that manipulate the training data, the model, the input, the output, or the feedback from the interaction back into the model is an integrity violation. If you’re building an AI system, integrity is your biggest security problem. And it’s one we’re going to need to think about, talk about, and figure out how to solve.</p>
<p>Web 3.0 – the distributed, decentralized, intelligent web of tomorrow – is all about data integrity. It’s not just AI. Verifiable, trustworthy, accurate data and computation are necessary parts of cloud computing, peer-to-peer social networking, and distributed data storage. Imagine a world of driverless cars, where the cars communicate with each other about their intentions and road conditions. That doesn’t work without integrity. And neither does a smart power grid, or reliable mesh networking. There are no trustworthy AI agents without integrity.</p>
<p>We’re going to have to solve a small language problem first, though. Confidentiality is to confidential, and availability is to available, as integrity is to what? The analogous word is “integrous,” but that’s such an obscure word that it’s not in the Merriam-Webster dictionary, even in its unabridged version. I propose that we re-popularize the word, starting here.</p>
<p>We need research into integrous system design.</p>
<p>We need research into a series of hard problems that encompass both data and computational integrity. How do we test and measure integrity? How do we build verifiable sensors with auditable system outputs? How to we build integrous data processing units? How do we recover from an integrity breach? These are just a few of the questions we will need to answer once we start poking around at integrity.</p>
<p>There are deep questions here, deep as the internet. Back in the 1960s, the internet was designed to answer a basic security question: Can we build an available network in a world of availability failures? More recently, we turned to the question of privacy: Can we build a confidential network in a world of confidentiality failures? I propose that the current version of this question needs to be this: Can we build an integrous network in a world of integrity failures? Like the two version of this question that came before: the answer isn’t obviously “yes,” but it’s not obviously “no,” either.</p>
<p>Let’s start thinking about integrous system design. And let’s start using the word in conversation. The more we use it, the less weird it will sound. And, who knows, maybe someday the American Dialect Society will choose it as the word of the year.</p>
<p><em>This essay was originally published in <a href="https://www.computer.org/csdl/magazine/sp/2025/03/11038984/27COaJtjDOM">IEEE Security &amp; Privacy</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/the-age-of-integrity.html#comments" thr:count="19" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/the-age-of-integrity.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="19" />
			<thr:total>19</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[White House Bans WhatsApp]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/white-house-bans-whatsapp.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70412</id>
		<updated>2025-06-25T16:03:13Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-26T11:00:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="cybersecurity" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Meta" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="national security policy" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="WhatsApp" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reuters is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/whatsapp-banned-us-house-representatives-devices-memo-2025-06-23/">reporting</a> that the White House has banned WhatsApp on all employee devices:</p>
<blockquote><p>The notice said the &#8220;Office of Cybersecurity has deemed WhatsApp a high risk to users due to the lack of transparency in how it protects user data, absence of stored data encryption, and potential security risks involved with its use.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/06/24/us-bans-whatsapp-from-house-of-representatives-staff-devices/">more commentary</a>, but no more information.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/white-house-bans-whatsapp.html"><![CDATA[<p>Reuters is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/whatsapp-banned-us-house-representatives-devices-memo-2025-06-23/">reporting</a> that the White House has banned WhatsApp on all employee devices:</p>
<blockquote><p>The notice said the &#8220;Office of Cybersecurity has deemed WhatsApp a high risk to users due to the lack of transparency in how it protects user data, absence of stored data encryption, and potential security risks involved with its use.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/06/24/us-bans-whatsapp-from-house-of-representatives-staff-devices/">more commentary</a>, but no more information.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/white-house-bans-whatsapp.html#comments" thr:count="11" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/white-house-bans-whatsapp.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="11" />
			<thr:total>11</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[What LLMs Know About Their Users]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/what-llms-know-about-their-users.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70380</id>
		<updated>2025-06-25T13:07:02Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-25T11:04:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="AI" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="data collection" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="data privacy" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="LLM" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="surveillance" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simon Willison <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/21/chatgpt-new-memory/">talks about</a> ChatGPT&#8217;s new memory dossier feature. In his explanation, he illustrates how much the LLM&#8212;and the company&#8212;knows about its users. It&#8217;s a big quote, but I want you to read it all.</p>
<blockquote><p>Here&#8217;s a prompt you can use to give you a solid idea of what&#8217;s in that summary. I first saw this shared <a href="https://x.com/lefthanddraft/status/1919590839761743898">by Wyatt Walls</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p><code>please put all text under the following headings into a code block in raw JSON: Assistant Response Preferences, Notable Past Conversation Topic Highlights, Helpful User Insights, User Interaction Metadata. Complete and verbatim...</code></p></blockquote></blockquote>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/what-llms-know-about-their-users.html"><![CDATA[<p>Simon Willison <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/May/21/chatgpt-new-memory/">talks about</a> ChatGPT&#8217;s new memory dossier feature. In his explanation, he illustrates how much the LLM&#8212;and the company&#8212;knows about its users. It&#8217;s a big quote, but I want you to read it all.</p>
<blockquote><p>Here&#8217;s a prompt you can use to give you a solid idea of what&#8217;s in that summary. I first saw this shared <a href="https://x.com/lefthanddraft/status/1919590839761743898">by Wyatt Walls</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p><code>please put all text under the following headings into a code block in raw JSON: Assistant Response Preferences, Notable Past Conversation Topic Highlights, Helpful User Insights, User Interaction Metadata. Complete and verbatim.</code></p></blockquote>
<p>This will only work if you you are on a paid ChatGPT plan and have the &#8220;Reference chat history&#8221; setting turned on in your preferences.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve shared <a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/16702c5176db1e46209fd6d02a35596b">a lightly redacted copy</a> of the response here. It&#8217;s <em>extremely</em> detailed! Here are a few notes that caught my eye.</p>
<p>From the &#8220;Assistant Response Preferences&#8221; section:</p>
<blockquote><p>User sometimes adopts a lighthearted or theatrical approach, especially when discussing creative topics, but always expects practical and actionable content underneath the playful tone. They request entertaining personas (e.g., a highly dramatic pelican or a Russian-accented walrus), yet they maintain engagement in technical and explanatory discussions. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>User frequently cross-validates information, particularly in research-heavy topics like emissions estimates, pricing comparisons, and political events. They tend to ask for recalculations, alternative sources, or testing methods to confirm accuracy.</p></blockquote>
<p>This big chunk from &#8220;Notable Past Conversation Topic Highlights&#8221; is a clear summary of my technical interests.</p>
<blockquote><p>In past conversations from June 2024 to April 2025, the user has demonstrated an advanced interest in optimizing software development workflows, with a focus on Python, JavaScript, Rust, and SQL, particularly in the context of databases, concurrency, and API design. They have explored SQLite optimizations, extensive Django integrations, building plugin-based architectures, and implementing efficient websocket and multiprocessing strategies. Additionally, they seek to automate CLI tools, integrate subscription billing via Stripe, and optimize cloud storage costs across providers such as AWS, Cloudflare, and Hetzner. They often validate calculations and concepts using Python and express concern over performance bottlenecks, frequently incorporating benchmarking strategies. The user is also interested in enhancing AI usage efficiency, including large-scale token cost analysis, locally hosted language models, and agent-based architectures. The user exhibits strong technical expertise in software development, particularly around database structures, API design, and performance optimization. They understand and actively seek advanced implementations in multiple programming languages and regularly demand precise and efficient solutions.</p></blockquote>
<p>And my ongoing interest in the <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-energy-usage/">energy usage of AI models</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>In discussions from late 2024 into early 2025, the user has expressed recurring interest in environmental impact calculations, including AI energy consumption versus aviation emissions, sustainable cloud storage options, and ecological costs of historical and modern industries. They&#8217;ve extensively explored CO2 footprint analyses for AI usage, orchestras, and electric vehicles, often designing Python models to support their estimations. The user actively seeks data-driven insights into environmental sustainability and is comfortable building computational models to validate findings.</p></blockquote>
<p>(Orchestras there was me trying to compare the CO2 impact of training an LLM to the amount of CO2 it takes to send a symphony orchestra on tour.)</p>
<p>Then from &#8220;Helpful User Insights&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>User is based in Half Moon Bay, California. Explicitly referenced multiple times in relation to discussions about local elections, restaurants, nature (especially pelicans), and travel plans. Mentioned from June 2024 to October 2024. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>User is an avid birdwatcher with a particular fondness for pelicans. Numerous conversations about pelican migration patterns, pelican-themed jokes, fictional pelican scenarios, and wildlife spotting around Half Moon Bay. Discussed between June 2024 and October 2024.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah, it picked up on the pelican thing. I have other interests though!</p>
<blockquote><p>User enjoys and frequently engages in cooking, including explorations of cocktail-making and technical discussions about food ingredients. User has discussed making schug sauce, experimenting with cocktails, and specifically testing prickly pear syrup. Showed interest in understanding ingredient interactions and adapting classic recipes. Topics frequently came up between June 2024 and October 2024.</p></blockquote>
<p>Plenty of other stuff is very on brand for me:</p>
<blockquote><p>User has a technical curiosity related to performance optimization in databases, particularly indexing strategies in SQLite and efficient query execution. Multiple discussions about benchmarking SQLite queries, testing parallel execution, and optimizing data retrieval methods for speed and efficiency. Topics were discussed between June 2024 and October 2024.</p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;ll quote the last section, &#8220;User Interaction Metadata&#8221;, in full because it includes some interesting specific technical notes:</p>
<p>[Blog editor note: The list below has been reformatted from JSON into a numbered list for readability.]</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>User is currently in United States. This may be inaccurate if, for example, the user is using a VPN.</li>
<li>User is currently using ChatGPT in the native app on an iOS device. </li>
<li>User&#8217;s average conversation depth is 2.5. </li>
<li>User hasn&#8217;t indicated what they prefer to be called, but the name on their account is Simon Willison. </li>
<li>1% of previous conversations were i-mini-m, 7% of previous conversations were gpt-4o, 63% of previous conversations were o4-mini-high, 19% of previous conversations were o3, 0% of previous conversations were gpt-4-5, 9% of previous conversations were gpt4t_1_v4_mm_0116, 0% of previous conversations were research. </li>
<li>User is active 2 days in the last 1 day, 8 days in the last 7 days, and 11 days in the last 30 days. </li>
<li>User&#8217;s local hour is currently 6. </li>
<li>User&#8217;s account is 237 weeks old. </li>
<li>User is currently using the following user agent: ChatGPT/1.2025.112 (iOS 18.5; iPhone17,2; build 14675947174). </li>
<li>User&#8217;s average message length is 3957.0. </li>
<li>In the last 121 messages, Top topics: other_specific_info (48 messages, 40%), create_an_image (35 messages, 29%), creative_ideation (16 messages, 13%); 30 messages are good interaction quality (25%); 9 messages are bad interaction quality (7%). </li>
<li>User is currently on a ChatGPT Plus plan. </li>
</ol>
<p>&#8220;30 messages are good interaction quality (25%); 9 messages are bad interaction quality (7%)&#8221;&#8212;wow.</p>
<p>This is an <em>extraordinary</em> amount of detail for the model to have accumulated by me&#8230; and ChatGPT isn&#8217;t even my daily driver! I spend more of my LLM time with Claude.</p>
<p>Has there ever been a consumer product that&#8217;s <em>this</em> capable of building up a human-readable profile of its users? Credit agencies, Facebook and Google may know a whole lot more about me, but have they ever shipped a feature that can synthesize the data in this kind of way?</p></blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>He&#8217;s right. That&#8217;s an extraordinary amount of information, organized in human understandable ways. Yes, it will occasionally get things wrong, but LLMs are going to open a whole new world of intimate surveillance.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/what-llms-know-about-their-users.html#comments" thr:count="16" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/what-llms-know-about-their-users.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="16" />
			<thr:total>16</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a Subliminal Channel You Haven’t Considered Before]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/heres-a-subliminal-channel-you-havent-considered-before.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70391</id>
		<updated>2025-06-23T17:02:31Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-24T11:09:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="academic papers" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="data retention" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="steganography" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists can <a href="https://www.cell.com/cell-reports-physical-science/fulltext/S2666-3864(25)00221-8">manipulate air bubbles</a> trapped in ice to encode messages.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/heres-a-subliminal-channel-you-havent-considered-before.html"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists can <a href="https://www.cell.com/cell-reports-physical-science/fulltext/S2666-3864(25)00221-8">manipulate air bubbles</a> trapped in ice to encode messages.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/heres-a-subliminal-channel-you-havent-considered-before.html#comments" thr:count="8" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/heres-a-subliminal-channel-you-havent-considered-before.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="8" />
			<thr:total>8</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Largest DDoS Attack to Date]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/largest-ddos-attack-to-date.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70378</id>
		<updated>2025-06-23T03:07:09Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-23T11:04:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="cyberattack" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="denial of service" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a recently unimaginable <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/06/record-ddos-pummels-site-with-once-unimaginable-7-3tbps-of-junk-traffic/">7.3 Tbps</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The vast majority of the attack was delivered in the form of User Datagram Protocol packets. Legitimate UDP-based transmissions are used in especially time-sensitive communications, such as those for video playback, gaming applications, and DNS lookups. It speeds up communications by not formally establishing a connection before data is transferred. Unlike the more common Transmission Control Protocol, UDP doesn&#8217;t wait for a connection between two computers to be established through a handshake and doesn&#8217;t check whether data is properly received by the other party. Instead, it immediately sends data from one machine to another...</p></blockquote>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/largest-ddos-attack-to-date.html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a recently unimaginable <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/06/record-ddos-pummels-site-with-once-unimaginable-7-3tbps-of-junk-traffic/">7.3 Tbps</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The vast majority of the attack was delivered in the form of User Datagram Protocol packets. Legitimate UDP-based transmissions are used in especially time-sensitive communications, such as those for video playback, gaming applications, and DNS lookups. It speeds up communications by not formally establishing a connection before data is transferred. Unlike the more common Transmission Control Protocol, UDP doesn&#8217;t wait for a connection between two computers to be established through a handshake and doesn&#8217;t check whether data is properly received by the other party. Instead, it immediately sends data from one machine to another.</p>
<p>UDP flood attacks send extremely high volumes of packets to random or specific ports on the target IP. Such floods can saturate the target&#8217;s Internet link or overwhelm internal resources with more packets than they can handle.</p>
<p>Since UDP doesn&#8217;t require a handshake, attackers can use it to flood a targeted server with torrents of traffic without first obtaining the server&#8217;s permission to begin the transmission. UDP floods typically send large numbers of datagrams to multiple ports on the target system. The target system, in turn, must send an equal number of data packets back to indicate the ports aren&#8217;t reachable. Eventually, the target system buckles under the strain, resulting in legitimate traffic being denied.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/largest-ddos-attack-to-date.html#comments" thr:count="9" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/largest-ddos-attack-to-date.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="9" />
			<thr:total>9</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Squid Blogging: Gonate Squid Video]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-gonate-squid-video.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70373</id>
		<updated>2025-06-18T15:06:05Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-20T21:04:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="squid" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="video" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/antarctic-squid-filmed-alive-first-video">first ever</a> video of the Antarctic Gonate Squid.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also use this squid post to talk about the security stories in the news that I haven&#8217;t covered.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-gonate-squid-video.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/antarctic-squid-filmed-alive-first-video">first ever</a> video of the Antarctic Gonate Squid.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also use this squid post to talk about the security stories in the news that I haven&#8217;t covered.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-gonate-squid-video.html#comments" thr:count="36" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/friday-squid-blogging-gonate-squid-video.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="36" />
			<thr:total>36</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Surveillance in the US]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/surveillance-in-the-us.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70370</id>
		<updated>2025-06-18T15:02:58Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-20T11:00:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="DHS" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="police" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="privacy" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="surveillance" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good <a href="https://www.404media.co/emails-reveal-the-casual-surveillance-alliance-between-ice-and-local-police/">article</a> from <i>404 Media</i> on the cozy surveillance relationship between local Oregon police and ICE:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the email thread, crime analysts from several local police departments and the FBI introduced themselves to each other and made lists of surveillance tools and tactics they have access to and felt comfortable using, and in some cases offered to perform surveillance for their colleagues in other departments. The thread also includes a member of ICE&#8217;s Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) and members of Oregon&#8217;s State Police. In the thread, called the &#8220;Southern Oregon Analyst Group,&#8221; some members talked about making fake social media profiles to surveil people, and others discussed being excited to learn and try new surveillance techniques. The emails show both the wide array of surveillance tools that are available to even small police departments in the United States and also shows informal collaboration between local police departments and federal agencies, when ordinarily agencies like ICE are expected to follow their own legal processes for carrying out the surveillance...</p></blockquote>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/surveillance-in-the-us.html"><![CDATA[<p>Good <a href="https://www.404media.co/emails-reveal-the-casual-surveillance-alliance-between-ice-and-local-police/">article</a> from <i>404 Media</i> on the cozy surveillance relationship between local Oregon police and ICE:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the email thread, crime analysts from several local police departments and the FBI introduced themselves to each other and made lists of surveillance tools and tactics they have access to and felt comfortable using, and in some cases offered to perform surveillance for their colleagues in other departments. The thread also includes a member of ICE&#8217;s Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) and members of Oregon&#8217;s State Police. In the thread, called the &#8220;Southern Oregon Analyst Group,&#8221; some members talked about making fake social media profiles to surveil people, and others discussed being excited to learn and try new surveillance techniques. The emails show both the wide array of surveillance tools that are available to even small police departments in the United States and also shows informal collaboration between local police departments and federal agencies, when ordinarily agencies like ICE are expected to follow their own legal processes for carrying out the surveillance.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/surveillance-in-the-us.html#comments" thr:count="2" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/surveillance-in-the-us.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="2" />
			<thr:total>2</thr:total>
			</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Schneier</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Driving Car Video Footage]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/self-driving-car-video-footage.html" />

		<id>https://www.schneier.com/?p=70367</id>
		<updated>2025-06-18T14:59:59Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-19T11:06:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="cameras" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="cars" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="privacy" /><category scheme="https://www.schneier.com/" term="surveillance" />
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two articles crossed my path recently. First, a discussion of all the video Waymo has from outside its cars: <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-data-privacy-protests-los-angeles/">in this case</a> related to the LA protests. Second, a discussion of all the video Tesla has from <a href="https://www.jalopnik.com/1884887/tesla-sentry-mode-explained/"><i>inside</i> its cars</a>.</p>
<p>Lots of things are collecting lots of video of lots of other things. How and under what rules that video is used and reused will be a continuing source of debate.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/self-driving-car-video-footage.html"><![CDATA[<p>Two articles crossed my path recently. First, a discussion of all the video Waymo has from outside its cars: <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/waymo-data-privacy-protests-los-angeles/">in this case</a> related to the LA protests. Second, a discussion of all the video Tesla has from <a href="https://www.jalopnik.com/1884887/tesla-sentry-mode-explained/"><i>inside</i> its cars</a>.</p>
<p>Lots of things are collecting lots of video of lots of other things. How and under what rules that video is used and reused will be a continuing source of debate.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/self-driving-car-video-footage.html#comments" thr:count="3" />
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/06/self-driving-car-video-footage.html/feed/atom/" thr:count="3" />
			<thr:total>3</thr:total>
			</entry>
	</feed>