<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Logs>
  <feed>{"?xml":{"@version":"1.0","@encoding":"utf-8"},"rss":{"@xmlns:dc":"http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/","@xmlns:content":"http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/","@version":"2.0","channel":{"title":"(ISC)² Blog","link":["https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/",{"@xmlns:atom10":"http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom","@rel":"self","@href":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/rss.xml","@type":"application/rss+xml"}],"description":"Voice of the Certified Cybersecurity Professional","language":"en-US","lastBuildDate":"Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0400","generator":"http://www.typepad.com/","docs":"http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification","item":[{"title":"Push Notification Is More Secure Than SMS 2FA, So Why the Reluctance to Enable It?","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/push-notification-is-more-secure-than-sms-2fa-so-why-the-reluctance-to-enable-it.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/push-notification-is-more-secure-than-sms-2fa-so-why-the-reluctance-to-enable-it.html"},"description":"Forget SMS 2FA authentication – Twitter and others are making it less attractive by either charging for it or phasing it out altogether. But there’s a better alternative if only tech companies were willing to invest. By John E. Dunn Mention Twitter and two factor authentication (2FA) in the same breath right now and security watchers will immediately think about a puzzling announcement the company made less than two months ago. The gist was that anyone using or adding SMS 2FA to their account would have to buy a subscription to Twitter Blue for $8 per month to continue to...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a3960200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Forget SMS 2FA authentication – Twitter and others are making it less attractive by either charging for it or phasing it out altogether. But there’s a better alternative if only tech companies were willing to invest.&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By John E. Dunn&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a3970200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"JD_2FAopinion\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a3970200b img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a3970200b-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"JD_2FAopinion\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mention Twitter and two factor authentication (2FA) in the same breath right now and security watchers will immediately think about a puzzling &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2023/an-update-on-two-factor-authentication-using-sms-on-twitter\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;announcement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; the company made less than two months ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The gist was that anyone using or adding SMS 2FA to their account would have to buy a subscription to Twitter Blue for $8 per month to continue to use the feature. Charitably, this was probably intended as a nudge to make people upgrade to more secure options such as authentication apps or hardware tokens, which remain free of charge. More likely, people pointed out, its effect will be to encourage some users to stop using 2FA altogether.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Arguably frustrating for some given the extra step and the delay it creates when logging in, yet for all its failings, SMS 2FA has always had one big feature going for it - it is incredibly easy to use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Alternative Authentication&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;It’s true that putting a paywall between users and this simplicity is bothersome. Users could use an authentication app instead but that means downloading it, enrolling the app to Twitter, unlocking the app each time with a PIN or fingerprint, switching between apps to get a six-digit code before entering it at each login.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Or they could buy a FIDO U2F token. They’re easier to use – a simple finger press - but they cost around $30 each, still need to be enrolled, and let’s not forget that you need a second one as a backup in case you lose the other one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;This is the tension that has thwarted 2FA take-up among consumers from the start. You can have more security, but it’ll probably be less convenient. If you make it too easy – sending one-time passcodes via SMS – hackers will find ways around this using SIM jacking, man-in-the middle attacks, or bogus account resets.&amp;#0160; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The massive irony of this debate is that almost nobody uses Twitter 2FA in the first place. According to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://transparency.twitter.com/en/reports/account-security.html#2021-jul-dec\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;its own figures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; from 2021, the percentage of users with at least one 2FA method turned on is a ridiculously low 2.6%. At Google, take-up is better at 10% but that still means 90% have it turned off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Frankly, for Twitter, as for so many other big web sites and services, the much-ballyhooed era of 2FA security has been an illusion all along. Most big web platforms turned 2FA on around 2013 and the only people using it a decade later seem to be corporates and expert users.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The push alternative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Frustratingly, a possible way out of this 2FA impasse already exists in the form of push notification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The technology is already widely adopted for business MFA and is simple to use. Users download an app and enroll their phones. Each time they log on from then on, a message pops up on their device asking them to authenticate their login with a yes/no.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The advantage is that the user can authenticate with a single tap, backed by a conventional authentication code in situations where network communication is a problem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Admittedly, there are downsides. Push requires companies such as Google, Apple, Microsoft, or a third-party security vendor to act as a notification gateway. There have also been attacks on push notifications such as MFA fatigue which bombard users with rogue push requests until they agree to one to make them stop coming.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A lot of these issues can be addressed through tweaks such as Microsoft’s number matching push system, or by rate limiting the number of push notifications that can be sent. Push notification apps also now give users more information about requests such as their geo-location and the device they were made from.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;But push notifications have one more trick up their sleeve that deserves to make them every security manager’s best friend.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The whole reason 2FA is needed in the first place is that password credentials are incredibly prone to compromise. Once an attacker has these, organizations and individuals become vulnerable to an attempted bypass or social engineering attack at some point.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Credential compromise is dangerous because admins have no way of knowing it has happened. They know the problem is likely but not when or against whom it will occur. It follows then that rogue notifications are a warning that something is wrong. If your users have been bombarded with multiple push notifications that weren’t from them that’s telling admins to change that user’s credentials immediately.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;As long as admins remember to give their users a channel for reporting suspicious push requests, it’s like having a free password compromise alerting system built into authentication.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Will Twitter, or any other consumer social networking site adopt push? That seems highly unlikely. Setting up push notification would cost money at a company that seems happier cutting costs at the moment. However, as the industry embarks on the long and probably slow journey towards a password-less future, we could do a lot worse than giving push notifications a closer look. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":["IT Security","Operations Security"],"dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"LATEST CYBERTHREATS AND ADVISORIES - APRIL 7, 2023","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-april-7-2023.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-april-7-2023.html"},"description":"The U.S. government takes down another dark web forum, Western Digital suffers a cyberattack and the fastest acting ransomware to date. Here are the latest threats and advisories for the week of April 7, 2023. By John Weiler Threat Advisories and Alerts Websites Built with Elementor Pro and WooCommerce under Attack Millions of WordPress websites using the popular Elementor Pro website builder and the WooCommerce plugin have been exposed to a serious security vulnerability. The flaw, which affects Elementor Pro versions 3.11.6 and earlier, allows malicious actors to change the default user privileges to include administrator access. The vulnerability was...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a393c200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"4.7 Threats\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a393c200b img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a393c200b-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"4.7 Threats\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517a3937200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The U.S. government takes down another dark web forum, Western Digital suffers a cyberattack and the fastest acting ransomware to date. Here are the latest threats and advisories for the week of April 7, 2023.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By John Weiler&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p aria-level=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 14pt;\"&gt;Threat Advisories and Alerts&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.csa.gov.sg/alerts-advisories/alerts/2023/al-2023-041\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Websites Built with Elementor Pro and WooCommerce under Attack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Millions of WordPress websites using the popular Elementor Pro website builder and the WooCommerce plugin have been exposed to a serious security vulnerability. The flaw, which affects Elementor Pro versions 3.11.6 and earlier, allows malicious actors to change the default user privileges to include administrator access. The vulnerability was patched in a March 22 update, but the number of reported incidents indicates that most website administrators have yet to install it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/rorschach-spread-commercial/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Rorschach Ransomware: One of the Fastest and Most Sophisticated Strains Yet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Cybersecurity researchers have found a new ransomware strain called Rorschach that is extraordinarily sophisticated and faster at encrypting data than any other documented strain. Once a system is infected, Rorschach works to replicate itself across a network and cover its tracks. It also employs several situational features that the ransomware controller can use to alter its trajectory. In one controlled test, LockBit ransomware encrypted a drive in seven minutes, while Rorschach encrypted the same drive in four and a half minutes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p aria-level=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 14pt;\"&gt;Emerging Threats and Research&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/04/fbi-seizes-bot-shop-genesis-market-amid-arrests-targeting-operators-suppliers/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Dozens Arrested as FBI Targets Genesis Market Cybercrime Forum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has taken down yet another illicit invitation-only marketplace popular among cybercriminals. Just two weeks after &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-march-24-2023.html\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;seizing the infamous Breached hacking forum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;, the FBI has commandeered domains associated with Genesis Market, which peddled stolen usernames, passwords and other private data. The sting was named Operation Cookie Monster and also involved the arrest of several dozen U.S.-based and international website administrators and contributors.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/security-breach-strikes-western-digital\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Western Digital&amp;#39;s My Cloud Service Goes Down after Security Breach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Western Digital, the California-based hard drive and flash storage maker, has announced that it was breached by an unauthorized party. The network security incident was first discovered on March 26 and announced earlier this week. The investigation is still in its early stages. As such, Western Digital has yet to divulge any details on what data or systems threat actors were able to access. One likely candidate is My Cloud, the company’s cloud-linked, network-attached storage (NAS) service. It suffered a significant outage after the announcement of the cyberattack.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/capita-cyberattack-disrupted-access-to-its-microsoft-office-365-apps/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;U.K. Outsourcing Giant Hit by Cyberattack That Downs Microsoft 365&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A prominent business process outsourcing firm in the U.K. revealed that a cyberattack disrupted access to its Microsoft Office 365 applications. More than 50,000 specialists and contractors work for Capita, which provides services to the U.K.’s National Health Service, the government’s military infrastructure, London’s public transport network and more. Capita first described the outage on March 31 as an ‘IT issue’ but later admitted it was the result of a cyberattack. The firm claims that, as of yet, there is no evidence of cybercriminals gaining access to customer, supplier or staff data.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.theregister.com/2023/04/04/siri_alexa_cortana_google_nuit/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Vulnerabilities in Smart Speakers Could Enable Remote Access&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A team of information security researchers have demonstrated the viability of what they’re calling a Near-Ultrasound Inaudible Trojan (NUIT). This novel cyberattack involves threat actors creating and broadcasting inaudible sounds that grant remote access and control to Apple&amp;#39;s Siri, Amazon&amp;#39;s Alexa, Microsoft&amp;#39;s Cortana and Google&amp;#39;s Assistant. Researchers are concerned that cybercriminals could embed sound bites into YouTube videos, music playlists or other trusted audio sources, thereby issuing silent commands to security systems, financial applications and private databases.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;To stay updated on the latest cybersecurity threats and advisories, look for weekly updates on the (ISC)² blog. Please share other alerts and threat discoveries you’ve encountered and join the conversation on the (ISC)² Community &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/Industry-News/bd-p/industry-news\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Industry News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; board.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":["Network Security","Operations Security"],"dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Fri, 07 Apr 2023 08:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"(ISC)² Supports Cyber Newcomers","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/isc2-supports-cyber-newcomers.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/isc2-supports-cyber-newcomers.html"},"description":"With more than 14,000 new Certified in Cybersecurity members joining (ISC)² last year and an additional 180,000+ Candidates gearing up to earn their first certification, (ISC)² will be supporting these cyber newcomers every step of the way. Recently, the Center for Cyber Safety and Education held its first Birds of a Feather: Newbies in Cyber webinar to promote an open dialogue and space for those leaning toward a career in cybersecurity, career changers and anyone interested in joining the field with questions. Within this conversation, we heard many of the questions and concerns that have been echoed across our social...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517966e3200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"Data-Techs-Servers-Getty-1347880353\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7517966e3200b img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517966e3200b-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"Data-Techs-Servers-Getty-1347880353\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;With &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;more than 14,000 new Certified in Cybersecurity members &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;joining &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)²&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; last year and an additional 180,000+ Candidates gearing up to earn their first certification, (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;ISC)² will be supporting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; these cyber newcomers every step of the way. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Recently, the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Center for Cyber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt; Safety and Education&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; held its first &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/birds\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Birds of a Feather&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/birds\"&gt;: Newbies in Cyber&lt;/a&gt; webinar to promote an open dialogue and space for those leaning toward a career in cybersecurity, career changers and anyone interested in joining the field with questions. Within this conversation, we heard many of the questions and concerns that have been echoed across our social channels and in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² Community as well. Please see below for some helpful guidance and resources for those looking to step into a cybersecurity career.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What can I do to find a job in cybersecurity without experience?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Build Your Cyber Network &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;There are a few ways to build up your cybersecurity community. Start on social, see who in your existing circle works in the field that you could reach out to or make a post showing your interest along with your training goals. Check out the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² Community&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt; - not only does this site offer many engagement opportunities, but there this a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/Cybersecurity-Job-Openings/bd-p/Cybersecurity-Jobs\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;job board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/Career-Discussions/bd-p/Career\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;career discussions section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;, opportunity to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/Career-Discussions/Cybersecurity-Mentorship-Connect-With-Mentors-amp-Mentees/m-p/54387\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;connect with a mentor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt; and more. When you are ready to step out from behind the keyboard, find and join your local &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/Chapters\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² Chapter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;. While some groups do hold virtual meetings as well, this is a great way to get to know your local cyber community. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Working Your Way in the Door&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Research companies that you are interested in working for and find a position that fits your current skillset. Use your position to progress into cyber while you continue your cyber education while working for your dream company. Be sure to find out more about their cybersecurity team and be vocal about your interest and active training to transition. According to the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org//-/media/ISC2/Research/2022/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Hiring-Managers-Guide.ashx\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Hiring Managers Report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;, internal recruitment was found to be utilized for filling entry- and junior-level cybersecurity roles by 18% of hiring managers surveyed. It’s worth noting that this number varies widely by organization size. Those with fewer than 100 people cited 46% of these hires were internal and in workplaces with 5,000+ employees, internal recruitment was 34% of position fills. Dig deeper into &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org//-/media/ISC2/Research/2022/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Hiring-Managers-Guide.ashx\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;this report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; to find the departments with the most transferable skills, the top skills cyber recruiters are looking for and more. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The More Traditional Route&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Most Human Resources departments do still seek to fill their entry-level cybersecurity roles via staffing and recruitment agencies and from applications submitted to them directly. Be sure you are highlighting your transferable skills in your resume and don’t be shy to include in-progress trainings. This shows your initiative. Keep in mind the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org//-/media/ISC2/Research/2022/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Hiring-Managers-Guide.ashx\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;top five personality attributes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; cybersecurity recruiters seek are problem solving, creativity, analytical thinking, desire to learn and critical thinking. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are cyber entry-level job titles to look out for and what tasks are they generally expected to perform?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Entry-level cybersecurity job roles include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;table aria-rowcount=\"1\" data-tablelook=\"1696\" data-tablestyle=\"MsoTableGrid\"&gt;\r\n&lt;tbody&gt;\r\n&lt;tr aria-rowindex=\"1\"&gt;\r\n&lt;td data-celllook=\"4369\"&gt;\r\n&lt;ul&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"1\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Security analyst&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"2\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Security specialist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"3\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Security architect&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"4\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Security auditor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"5\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Forensic specialist/analyst&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#0160;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;/ul&gt;\r\n&lt;/td&gt;\r\n&lt;td data-celllook=\"4369\"&gt;\r\n&lt;ul&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"1\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Junior penetration tester&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"2\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Security engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"3\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;IT auditor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"4\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;IT security manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"5\" data-font=\"Symbol\" data-leveltext=\"\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559683&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Symbol&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"4\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Systems administrator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;/ul&gt;\r\n&lt;/td&gt;\r\n&lt;/tr&gt;\r\n&lt;/tbody&gt;\r\n&lt;/table&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org//-/media/ISC2/Research/2022/ISC2-Cybersecurity-Hiring-Managers-Guide.ashx\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;top five tasks for entry-level staff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; are alert and threat monitoring, documenting processes and procedures, using scripting languages, incident response and reporting. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are there any free training opportunities or scholarships to help grow the cyber workforce?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Yes, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² offers free training and a free exam for those interested in earning the entry-level Certified in Cybersecurity certification via the One Million in Cyber initiative. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/1mcc\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Visit this page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt; for more information on how to participate and to see all of the steps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;The Center for Cyber Safety and Education, the charitable arm of (ISC)², encourages and supports students pursuing a degree with a focus on cybersecurity, information assurance, or a similar field. These scholarships support students globally on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;&amp;#0160;their path to long-term career success. See the open applications available now at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/scholarships\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/scholarships&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What events or opportunities are coming up for cyber newcomers? &lt;/em&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Monday, March 13 - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.iamcybersafe.org/s/newbies\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Birds of a Feather: Newbies in Cyber&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; (Webinar)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;This virtual conversation allows newcomers to the cybersecurity field to come together and share ideas or ask questions. We welcome any newcomers to the cybersecurity field, whether still trying to get your foot in the door or have just started your career. This will be an open forum conversation to encourage honest, open dialog to discuss your experience in starting your career in cyber. Let&amp;#39;s chat!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Wednesday, April 19 - &lt;a href=\"https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/19929/579127\"&gt;(ISC)² Guide to Membership&lt;/a&gt; (Webinar)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Join the (ISC)² membership team LIVE to learn about YOUR membership. Get an overview of how to navigate your member account, details on how to maintain your certification and advice on how to make the most of your membership. Whether you&amp;#39;re a newly certified member or have held the CISSP for years, join (ISC)² to hear all about what is new for members.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Friday, May 5 - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.brighttalk.com/webcast/13159/577265\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;CC EXAM READY: Ask the Experts Before You Sit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; (Webinar)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Join us for this live Q&amp;amp;A where our panel of experts will answer &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;your questions about CC before you sit for the exam. We’ll go over certification requirements, the domains, self-study resources, training options and more to help you build confidence so you’re ready on exam day. You’ll also learn about career opportunities in cybersecurity, available training tools, what to expect on exam day and much more!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;For more on how to find your way into a cyber career, visit the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/Cybersecurity-Careers/How-to-Get-a-Cybersecurity-Job\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;guide to the evolving cybersecurity recruitment landscape&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":"Cybersecurity Workforce","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Wed, 05 Apr 2023 08:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"CYBERSECURITY INDUSTRY NEWS REVIEW - APRIL 4, 2023","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/cybersecurity-industry-news-review-april-4-2023.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/cybersecurity-industry-news-review-april-4-2023.html"},"description":"UK government potentially skimps on senior cyber role salary as the NCSC calls for more investment in people, Microsoft talks up the potential for ChatGPT and the US moves to ban spyware. By Joe Fay U.K. Treasury Tries to Drive Down Inflation with Paltry Cybersecurity Salary The U.K.’s Treasury department is looking for an “experienced” Head of Cyber Security willing to work for £55,500. The successful candidate will be “working at the heart of Government in a time of momentous change and offering a level of exposure and challenge that is hard to find anywhere else”. Amongst other things, they...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=\"TextRun Highlight MacChromeBold SCXW238894165 BCX0\" data-contrast=\"auto\" lang=\"EN\" xml:lang=\"EN\"&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW238894165 BCX0\"&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519e1900200c-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"Joe fay - ISC2 - wir 3 4 23 iStock-905221388\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7519e1900200c img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519e1900200c-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"Joe fay - ISC2 - wir 3 4 23 iStock-905221388\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;UK government potentially skimps on senior cyber role salary as the NCSC calls for more investment in people, Microsoft talks up the potential for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW238894165 BCX0\"&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW238894165 BCX0\"&gt; and the US moves to ban spyware.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"EOP SCXW238894165 BCX0\" data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=\"TextRun Highlight MacChromeBold SCXW157371754 BCX0\" data-contrast=\"auto\" lang=\"EN\" xml:lang=\"EN\"&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW157371754 BCX0\"&gt;By Joe Fay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"EOP SCXW157371754 BCX0\" data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.civilservicejobs.service.gov.uk/csr/index.cgi?SID=c2VhcmNoc29ydD1jbG9zaW5nJnBhZ2VjbGFzcz1Kb2JzJm93bmVyPTUwNzAwMDAmdXNlcnNlYXJjaGNvbnRleHQ9Mjk3ODgxMjkmcGFnZWFjdGlvbj12aWV3dmFjYnlqb2JsaXN0JmpvYmxpc3Rfdmlld192YWM9MTg0NjE5OSZvd25lcnR5cGU9ZmFpciZzZWFyY2hwYWdlPTE5\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;U.K. Treasury Tries to Drive Down Inflation with Paltry Cybersecurity Salary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.K.’s Treasury department is looking for an “experienced” Head of Cyber Security willing to work for £55,500. The successful candidate will be “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;working at the heart of Government in a time of momentous change and offering a level of exposure and challenge that is hard to find anywhere else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;”. Amongst other things, they will supervise specialist security processes and the provision of device security throughout the organization. Commentators have lambasted the proposed salary, saying that at the very least it is around £100,000 short. On the other hand, a closer read of the advert reveals the role involves managing “two cyber apprentices”. So, perhaps it’s actually a case of an over-inflated job title and unduly-enthusiastic description, rather than an under-inflated pay packet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/board-toolkit\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;NCSC Advises Business Chiefs to Get a Grip on Cyber Security&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.K. Treasury’s bargain basement ad came as its fellow government agency, the National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC), urged boards to “get to grips” with cyber risks and start investing in people. The call came as it launche&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;d a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Cyber Security Board Toolkit to hel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;p leaders have “essential discussions” about cyber security with their organizations’ technical experts and key stakeholders. The toolkit includes documentation, podcasts and videos, including “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;an account of a ransomware attack on an industrial business from the eyes of its C-level team&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;”. Amongst other things, the kit advises boards on the importance of an established and experienced workforce and encourages them to invest in their people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2023/mar/30/vulkan-files-leak-reveals-putins-global-and-domestic-cyberwarfare-tactics\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Whistleblower Lays Bare Russia’s Vulkan Hacking and Misinformation Operation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A massive data leak has apparently exposed the workings of t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;he&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;St Petersburg-based NTC Vulkan. The Guardian newspaper reports that the “cybersecurity consulta&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;ncy” is intimately connected to Russia’s domestic spy agency, the FSB, foreign intelligence organization the SVR, as well as the military intelligence arms GOU and GRU. Documents detail the organization’s tooling and its involvement in attacks on national infrastructure, disinformation, and malware attacks, including NotPetya. The documents were released by a whistleblower angered by the war in Ukraine. The Guardian said Western intelligence agencies said the files appear to be authentic and added that the Kremlin did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://news.microsoft.com/2023/03/28/with-security-copilot-microsoft-brings-the-power-of-ai-to-cyberdefense/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Microsoft Launches Security Copilot – Your ChatGPT-Powered Wingman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Microsoft ha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;released Security Copilot, which &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;it says will integrate “advanced OpenAI” models into its security tooling to help cyber security teams make sense of a deluge of information. In other words, ChatGPT will be supporting cyber defenders even as threat actors use the generative AI tech to finesse their own code and phishing lures. Microsoft said Copilot will&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; “simplify complexity and amplify the capabilities of security teams by summarizing and making sense of threat intelligence, helping defenders see through the noise of web traffic and identify malicious activity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;” And, it added, it will help address cyber skills shortages. The technology will initially be available as a private preview.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/joint-statement-strategic-dialogue-cybersecurity-civil-society-under-threat-transnational-repression\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Governments Pledge to Protect Civil Society In Cyberspace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A group of democratic governments have committed to a joint statement on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Cybersecurity of Civil Society Under Threat of Transnational Repression. The text recognize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;s the importance of civil rights and free speech, and the role of dissidents, journalists, human rights advocates and others, while noting “authoritarian governments” use of cyber means” to target them. The governments of Australia, Canada, Denmark, Estonia, France, Japan, New Zealand, Norway, the U.K., and the U.S. have all committed to “identifying actions” they can take to defend these groups and have launched a forum to share information and find ways to collaborate on and advance “cybersecurity for civil society around the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2023/03/27/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-prohibit-u-s-government-use-of-commercial-spyware-that-poses-risks-to-national-security/#:~:text=Today%2C%20President%20Biden%20signed%20an,rights%20abuses%20around%20the%20world.\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;White House Prohibits Spyware – At Least For Other Countries’ Spies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;U.S. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;President Biden has signed an executive order limit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;ing the use of “commercial spyware” by the U.S. government. A statement on the order noted that such tooling was used by repressive governments, while “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Democratic governments also have confronted revelations that actors within their systems have used commercial spyware to target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; citizens”. The order will prohibit “operational” use of such tools by the U.S. government. A closer reading of the order doesn’t seem to completely rule out U.S. use of such tools. Rather, the aim seems to be preventing commercial variants falling into the hands of hostile nations who will use them to silence critics and attack the U.S.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:240,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":["Cybersecurity Workforce","Network Security","Operations Security"],"dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Tue, 04 Apr 2023 07:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"New adaptive platform customizes online certification training for a personalized experience","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/new-adaptive-platform-customizes-online-certification-training.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/04/new-adaptive-platform-customizes-online-certification-training.html"},"description":"We all learn differently. And we all have different schedules and needs when it comes to certification training. In the past, finding the time to train has been limiting for some. Enter adaptive online training, a new and innovative way to prep for certification that uses artificial intelligence (AI) to tailor the learning journey to each individual’s needs. It provides a non-linear, personalized learning experience that works well for busy professionals who want to upskill without having to rely on traditional linear learning models, which can be restrictive about time and pace. How it works (ISC)² is leading the way...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d6216200c-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"Blog-Banner_230x150\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d6216200c img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d6216200c-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"Blog-Banner_230x150\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We all learn differently. And we all have different schedules and needs when it comes to certification training. In the past, finding the time to train has been limiting for some.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;Enter adaptive online training, a new and innovative way to prep for certification that uses artificial intelligence (AI) to tailor the learning journey to each individual’s needs. It provides a non-linear, personalized learning experience that works well for busy professionals who want to upskill without having to rely on traditional linear learning models, which can be restrictive about time and pace.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;(ISC)² is leading the way in rolling out this flexible learning option for certification training. Official (ISC)² Online Training uses AI-led adaptive learning to provide individualized learning paths based on prior knowledge, learning speed and confidence levels. Learners answer questions using sliders to rate their level of confidence, which helps to detect knowledge gaps while building self-awareness regarding competency. Analytics provide a complete overview of learning progress and performance. The platform also identifies specific areas that require further study so that you’re better prepared on exam day.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;The training features interactive, engaging courses designed for professionals of different experience levels, taking into consideration their time and expertise. For example, highly experienced professionals may not need to cover every domain with the same level of detail as someone less experienced. One of the benefits of the adaptive self-paced training is that learners can direct their experience or rely on the AI to guide them through it. In contrast, traditional linear training requires learners to complete each module, even if they don’t need further study in certain areas.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;The new training also offers a robust search capability that enables learners to find the content they need, when they need it. It includes an analytics dashboard to track progress and see concept-by-concept performance changes over time. Easy and accessible email support is available for those who require additional assistance.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=\"font-size: 12pt;\"&gt;Education guarantee&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;For learners who don’t pass the exam on their first attempt, (ISC)² offers an education guarantee. Learners can access the same training again at no cost to them within one year from the end of the initial training. The education guarantee covers the cost of the second course.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;AI-driven adaptive learning is a game-changer for certification training. It provides a personalized learning experience tailored to the individual learner’s needs, enabling them to upskill faster and smarter.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/Training/Online-Self-Paced\"&gt;(ISC)² Official Training.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":"Cybersecurity Training","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Mon, 03 Apr 2023 08:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"CISA Moving Further Towards Pre-Emptive Stance with Ransomware Attack Alert System","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/cisa-moving-further-towards-pre-emptive-stance-with-ransomware-attack-alert-system.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/cisa-moving-further-towards-pre-emptive-stance-with-ransomware-attack-alert-system.html"},"description":"In the latest of several recent announcements, the U.S. body responsible for cybersecurity is making a clear shift towards pre-emptive over reactionary reporting, alerting and advice for organizations. By John E. Dunn A defining characteristic of ransomware attacks is the element of surprise. By the time the victim receives the ransom note, it is usually already too late to contain an incident. The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has announced a new pilot project, the Pre-Ransomware Notification Initiative, which it hopes will be able to notify more victims before this happens. The premise is that attackers often linger...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517968b1200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"JD_ransomware_CISA\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7517968b1200b img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7517968b1200b-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"JD_ransomware_CISA\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In the latest of several recent announcements, the U.S. body responsible for cybersecurity is making a clear shift towards pre-emptive over reactionary reporting, alerting and advice for organizations.&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By John E. Dunn&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A defining characteristic of ransomware attacks is the element of surprise. By the time the victim receives the ransom note, it is usually already too late to contain an incident.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/resources-tools/resources/ransomware-vulnerability-warning-pilot-rvwp-fact-sheet\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;announced&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; a new pilot project, the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/getting-ahead-ransomware-epidemic-cisas-pre-ransomware-notifications-help-organizations-stop-attacks\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Pre-Ransomware Notification Initiative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;, which it hopes will be able to notify more victims before this happens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The premise is that attackers often linger inside networks for some time before striking. This offers a window of opportunity, according to CISA:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;“These early warnings can enable victims to safely evict the ransomware actors from their networks before the actors have a chance to encrypt and hold critical data and systems at ransom.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Getting ahead of ransomware sounds like a tall order but CISA said it had already helped 60 organizations since the beginning of 2023 across sectors including energy, healthcare, water treatment and education.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The Source of the Intelligence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The announcement doesn’t say where the Pre-Ransomware Notification Initiative gets its intelligence from but some of it is probably fed from the also recently announced Ransomware Vulnerability Warning Pilot (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/stopransomware/Ransomware-Vulnerability-Warning-Pilot\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;RVWP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;).&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The rest is based on risk-assessing vulnerabilities using tools that scan critical infrastructure for vulnerabilities that might be exploited by ransomware.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;“Once CISA identifies these affected systems, our regional cybersecurity personnel notify system owners of their security vulnerabilities, thus enabling timely mitigation before damaging intrusions occur,” said CISA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;It’s not clear how much is preemptive defense based on intelligence about a compromise in progress and how much is just risk-based guesswork.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The RVWP itself was established in response to the Cyber Incident Reporting for Critical Infrastructure Act of 2022 (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/topics/cyber-threats-and-advisories/information-sharing/cyber-incident-reporting-critical-infrastructure-act-2022-circia\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;CIRCIA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;), part of a remarkable flurry of executive orders relating to cybersecurity signed into law by the Biden administration.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A workable idea?&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The assumption of an early warning is that there is time for one to be given. This has a lot to do with the fact that the groups who initially compromise networks are not always the ones who execute the later attack. Instead, they sell on their access to specialists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The handover between one group and another can extend to weeks or months, at least in some cases. That, presumably, gives something like the Pre-Ransomware Notification Initiative time to warn victims if they uncover evidence of the earlier incursion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Equally, not all ransomware attacks take their time. Some strike within days. Nevertheless, helping 60 organizations in less than three months is an encouraging start.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;There are limitations in scope. The initiative is aimed at critical infrastructure, for instance, and is not designed to help the SMEs outside these sectors, for instance.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Both the Pre-Ransomware Notification Initiative and the RVWP are part of CISA’s larger &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.cisa.gov/stopransomware/stopransomware\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Stop Ransomware&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; campaign which offers organizations the ability to report incidents and receive ransomware alerts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":"Ransomware","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Fri, 31 Mar 2023 12:01:00 -0400"},{"title":"Latest Cyberthreats and Advisories - March 31, 2023","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-march-31-2023.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-march-31-2023.html"},"description":"By John Weiler Microsoft patches the “aCropalypse” vulnerability, ChatGPT leaks users’ billing information and the Latitude Financial breach expands to 14 million records. Here are the latest threats and advisories for the week of March 31, 2023. Threat Advisories and Alerts FBI Alerts U.S. Companies of Email Scam Targeting Commercial Goods The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has warned companies of a new type of business email compromise (BEC) fraud. Threat actors are impersonating known and reputable U.S.-based companies by spoofing email domains and display names of employees to place large orders for material goods without paying upfront. When...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=\"TextRun SCXW55798302 BCX0\" data-contrast=\"auto\" lang=\"EN\" xml:lang=\"EN\"&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW55798302 BCX0\"&gt;By John &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW55798302 BCX0\"&gt;Weiler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"EOP SCXW55798302 BCX0\" data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=\"EOP SCXW55798302 BCX0\" data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&lt;span class=\"TextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\" data-contrast=\"auto\" lang=\"EN\" xml:lang=\"EN\"&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt;Microsoft patches the “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt;aCropalypse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt;” vulnerability, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt; leaks users’ billing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt;information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW223354796 BCX0\"&gt; and the Latitude Financial breach expands to 14 million records. Here are the latest threats and advisories for the week of March 31, 2023. &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b685307baf200d-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"3.31.23 Cyber threats\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b685307baf200d img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b685307baf200d-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"3.31.23 Cyber threats\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p aria-level=\"2\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threat Advisories and Alerts&amp;#0160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2023/03/27/bec-scammers-physical-goods/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;FBI Alerts U.S. Companies of Email Scam Targeting Commercial Goods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) has warned companies of a new type of business email compromise (BEC) fraud. Threat actors are impersonating known and reputable U.S.-based companies by spoofing email domains and display names of employees to place large orders for material goods without paying upfront. When vendors try to collect payment, they find that the purchaser was an impersonator using fake credentials or credit references.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://thehackernews.com/2023/03/microsoft-issues-patch-for-acropalypse.html\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Windows Users Urged to Update Snipping Tool to Avoid “aCropalypse”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;An emergency update from Microsoft addresses a vulnerability in its Windows 10 app Snip &amp;amp; Sketch and its Windows 11 Snipping Tool. Referred to as ‘aCropalypse’, the vulnerability allows bad actors to potentially view sensitive information contained within sections of a screenshot that have been cropped out. Although the attack requires several variables outside of the control of a cybercriminal to align, it puts screenshots of bank statements, login credentials and health records at significant risk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.bitdefender.com/blog/hotforsecurity/uk-police-reveal-they-are-running-fake-ddos-for-hire-sites-to-collect-details-on-cybercriminals/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;U.K. Authorities Use Decoy Sites to Gather Data on Cybercriminals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The U.K.&amp;#39;s National Crime Agency (NCA) announced that it has been running several fake websites purporting to sell Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) services. When visitors to the site attempt to sign up for the service and provide details of their request, their submissions actually go to the NCA for analysis. Data is shared with international law enforcement and has led to several arrests.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p aria-level=\"2\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emerging Threats and Research&amp;#0160;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2023/03/27/chatgpt-data-leak/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Billing Information and Chat History Revealed in ChatGPT Breach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;For approximately nine hours, 1.2% of all ChatGPT users were shown someone else’s billing information on the ‘Manage Subscription’ page. Breached data fields included chat histories, first and last names, billing addresses, credit card types, credit card expiration dates and the last four digits of credit cards. OpenAI confirmed that a vulnerability in one of its open-source libraries was responsible for the breach and has fixed the issue.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://cyberscoop.com/breachforums-arrest-cybercrime-underground/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;FBI Gains Access to Breachforums Database&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Baphomet’s hunch was right. The fears of the remaining Breached hacking forum admin, who &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-march-24-2023.html\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;shut down the notorious cybercrime meeting ground&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; last week, have come true. The U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) announced it has complete access to a SQL database that tracked user histories on the site. Experts believe that details contained within the database will bolster efforts to bring down other forums and dark web marketplaces. The forum’s founder, Conor Brian Fitzpatrick, has been arrested and charged with the theft and sale of sensitive personal data belonging to U.S. citizens, as well as foreign companies, organizations and government agencies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://informationsecuritybuzz.com/customer-details-latitude-financial/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Latitude Financial Data Breach Affects 14 Million Customer Records&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;As predicted, the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/latest-cyberthreats-and-advisories-march-24-2023.html\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;recent breach of Australia’s Latitude Financial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; just got a whole lot worse. The consumer lending company has now confirmed the theft of 14 million records containing personal data on Australian and New Zealander loan applicants. Malicious actors breached systems containing customers’ driver’s license information, passport numbers, addresses, phone numbers and dates of birth. Latitude Financial promises to pay document replacement fees and credit monitoring for those affected by the breach.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/emotet-malware-distributed-as-fake-w-9-tax-forms-from-the-irs/\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Emotet Malware: Stealing Tax Data with Phishing Emails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;A new phishing campaign employing the Emotet malware is masquerading as U.S. W-9 tax forms attached to emails claiming to come from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and business partners. When opened, the Microsoft OneNote document initiates a VBScript that installs the Emotet malware to remain open without the user’s knowledge. The program steals victims&amp;#39; email records to target friends and colleagues and may eventually act as a back door for other malware campaigns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:276}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;To stay updated on the latest cybersecurity threats and advisories, look for weekly updates on the (ISC)² blog. Please share other alerts and threat discoveries you’ve encountered and join the conversation on the (ISC)² Community &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/Industry-News/bd-p/industry-news\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Industry News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; board.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"New CISSP Exam Registration Process for 2023","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/new-cissp-exam-registration-process-for-2023.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/new-cissp-exam-registration-process-for-2023.html"},"description":"Looking to earn your (ISC)² CISSP certification? Make sure you follow these updated steps to register for your exam. Here is how you can register for the CISSP exam: Log in to your account at www.isc2.org and visit the Register for Your Certification Exam If you don’t have an (ISC)² account, you’ll need to create one before you register for your CISSP exam. We recommend signing up as an (ISC)² Candidate so you can take advantage of discounted CISSP training and other benefits. You’ll then visit https://my.isc2.org/s/ISC2-Pearson to fill out your Exam Account Information form. Once completed, review for accuracy...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;Looking to earn your (ISC)² CISSP certification? Make sure you follow these updated steps to register for your exam. &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b751791575200b-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"CISSP-logo-square\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b751791575200b img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b751791575200b-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"CISSP-logo-square\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;Here is how you can register for the CISSP exam:&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;ol&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;Log in to your account at www.isc2.org and visit the &lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/Register-for-Exam\"&gt;Register for Your Certification Exam&lt;/a&gt; If you don’t have an (ISC)² account, you’ll need to &lt;a href=\"https://my.isc2.org/s/login/SelfRegister?ec=302&amp;amp;startURL=%2Fs%2FISC2-Pearson\"&gt;create one&lt;/a&gt; before you register for your CISSP exam. &lt;em&gt;We recommend signing up as an (ISC)² Candidate so you can take advantage of discounted CISSP training and other benefits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;You’ll then visit &lt;a href=\"https://my.isc2.org/s/ISC2-Pearson\"&gt;https://my.isc2.org/s/ISC2-Pearson&lt;/a&gt; to fill out your Exam Account Information form. Once completed, review for accuracy to ensure it matches your required identification that you’ll provide at your test center.&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;Submit the form and then you’ll be transferred to the Pearson VUE website to schedule your exam.\r\n&lt;ol&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;Click View Exams and select your (ISC)² exam of choice, such as CISSP.&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;Select your language, CISSP in English (Computerized Adaptive Test) or CISSP in Chinese, Korean, German, Japanese, Spanish and review the &lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/Exams/Before-Your-Exam\"&gt;Exam Policies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li&gt;Choose your test center location and schedule your exam.&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;/ol&gt;\r\n&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;/ol&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in another (ISC)² certification, read the blog &lt;a href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/update-new-process-for-isc2-exam-registration.html\"&gt;Update – New Process for (ISC)² Exam Registration&lt;/a&gt; for all exams.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;Always use the same email and login to access your accounts with (ISC)² and Pearson VUE. Having multiple accounts may cause delays in receiving exam results and could result in a ban from (ISC)² exams.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;Connect with others preparing to take the CISSP Exam on the &lt;a href=\"https://community.isc2.org/t5/CISSP-Study-Group/gh-p/CISSP_Study_Group_Hub\"&gt;(ISC)² CISSP Study Group&lt;/a&gt; on the Community.&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;If you need account assistance, please contact our customer support team via phone, email or live chat at &lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/contact-us\"&gt;https://www.isc2.org/contact-us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;","category":"Cybersecurity Certifications","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Thu, 30 Mar 2023 08:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"Analysis: Hackers Exploit Zero-Day to Siphon $1.5 Million From Bitcoin ATMs","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/analysis-hackers-exploit-zero-day-to-siphon-15-million-from-bitcoin-atms.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/analysis-hackers-exploit-zero-day-to-siphon-15-million-from-bitcoin-atms.html"},"description":"Anxiety about the security of hot wallets grows as General Bytes customers are hit by a zero-day flaw in the company’s Bitcoin ATMs. By John E. Dunn It’s fair to say that crypto has an image problem. What it didn’t need was a Bitcoin ATM (BATM) hack to generate even more bad publicity. Unfortunately, that’s exactly what happened on March 17-18, according to General Bytes, one of the best-known makers of BATMs on the market. Hackers exploited a zero-day flaw in a video interface that’s part of the General Bytes CAS server platform to steal 56 Bitcoins (worth $1.5 million)...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d5f0b200c-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"JD-generalbytes\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d5f0b200c img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d5f0b200c-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"JD-generalbytes\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b7519d5eeb200c-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anxiety about the security of hot wallets grows as General Bytes customers are hit by a zero-day flaw in the company’s Bitcoin ATMs.&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By John E. Dunn&amp;#0160;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;It’s fair to say that crypto has an image problem. What it didn’t need was a Bitcoin ATM (BATM) hack to generate even more bad publicity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Unfortunately, that’s exactly what happened on March 17-18, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://generalbytes.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/ESD/pages/2885222430/Security+Incident+March+17-18th+2023\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;according to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; General Bytes, one of the best-known makers of BATMs on the market.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Hackers exploited a zero-day flaw in a video interface that’s part of the General Bytes CAS server platform to steal 56 Bitcoins (worth $1.5 million) and a small volume of Ethereum from customers running the BATMs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The attacker first identified BATMs running vulnerable CAS servers and the General Bytes Cloud service by scanning the IP address space of recommended service provider DigitalOcean on ports 7777 or 443.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The attacker uploaded a Java application that created a new default admin user to execute the compromise. This gave the attacker:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;ul&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"0\" data-font=\"Calibri\" data-leveltext=\"-\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335551671&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Access the database.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"0\" data-font=\"Calibri\" data-leveltext=\"-\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335551671&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The ability to read and decrypt API keys.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"0\" data-font=\"Calibri\" data-leveltext=\"-\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335551671&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Access and send funds from ‘hot’ (online) wallets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"0\" data-font=\"Calibri\" data-leveltext=\"-\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335551671&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The ability to download usernames, password hashes, turn off 2FA authentication.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;li aria-setsize=\"-1\" data-aria-level=\"1\" data-aria-posinset=\"0\" data-font=\"Calibri\" data-leveltext=\"-\" data-list-defn-props=\"{&amp;quot;335551671&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335552541&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559684&amp;quot;:-2,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:720,&amp;quot;335559991&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;469769226&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469769242&amp;quot;:[8226],&amp;quot;469777803&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777804&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;469777815&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;hybridMultilevel&amp;quot;}\" data-listid=\"2\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Access to logs, including where customers had scanned their private key at a BATM.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;\r\n&lt;/ul&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;It’s not clear how many customers have been affected by the attack, but presumably General Bytes will be liable for some or all of the missing funds. However, given the unregulated space that cryptocurrency is, even that is uncertain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;How has the company responded?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;General Bytes released a patch within 15 hours, instructions on how customers can assess whether their BATM was breached, plus mitigations to secure the terminal.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;According to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://coinatmradar.com/manufacturer/5/general-bytes-bitcoin-atm-producer/\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;one map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;, there appear to be around 10,000 General Bytes BATMs worldwide, predominantly in the U.S.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Meanwhile, the company said it is closing its cloud service, which means all customers will have to manage their BATMs as standalone devices.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;General Bytes BATMs were hit by a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://generalbytes.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/ESD/pages/2785509377/Security+Incident+August+18th+2022\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;separate zero-day flaw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; last August that resulted in undisclosed losses. This week the company said that it has conducted “multiple” security audits since 2021, none of which turned up the latest vulnerability which has been present since version 20210401.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;An On-Going Challenge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;Concern about the vulnerability of BATMs has been growing for some time. In 2021, researchers uncovered &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://blog.kraken.com/post/11263/kraken-security-labs-identifies-vulnerabilities-in-commonly-used-bitcoin-atm/\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;a nest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt; of security issues in one of General Bytes’ BATMs, the BATMtwo (GBBATM2):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;“Our team found that a large number of ATMs are configured with the same default admin QR code, allowing anyone with this QR code to walk up to an ATM and compromise it. Our team also found a lack of secure boot mechanisms, as well as critical vulnerabilities in the ATM management system,” said Kraken Security Labs at the time.&amp;#0160;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"auto\"&gt;The bigger issue in play here is how it can ever be possible to secure hot wallets. This is a fundamental issue with BATMs, which require an online connection for real-time transactions to take place.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","category":["IT Security","Malware"],"dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Wed, 29 Mar 2023 07:00:00 -0400"},{"title":"Member Feedback on (ISC)² 2023 Bylaws Requested by April 7","link":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/member-feedback-on-isc2-2023-bylaws-requested-by-april-7.html","guid":{"@isPermaLink":"true","#text":"https://blog.isc2.org/isc2_blog/2023/03/member-feedback-on-isc2-2023-bylaws-requested-by-april-7.html"},"description":"Today, all members should’ve received an email with a link to a survey inviting feedback on the (ISC)² 2023 Bylaws which closes on April 7, 2023. The URL starts with https://schlesinger.focusvision.com/. We encourage all members to read the bylaws located on the (ISC)² Governance webpage. The (ISC)² Bylaws set forth the rules concerning the operation of our association and actions of our members. It guides how our Board of Directors and staff manage our nonprofit corporation. The (ISC)² Amended and Restated Bylaws establish fundamental principles about key governance policies, members’ rights and Board operations. As (ISC)² begins the 2023 Bylaws...","content:encoded":"&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Today, all members should’ve received an email with a link to a survey inviting feedback on the (ISC)² 2023 Bylaws which closes on April 7, 2023.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;The URL starts with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;https://schlesinger.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;focusvision&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;.com/. &lt;a class=\"asset-img-link\" href=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b6852ffca1200d-pi\" style=\"float: right;\"&gt;&lt;img alt=\"CPE Credit\" class=\"asset  asset-image at-xid-6a00e54f109b67883402b6852ffca1200d img-responsive\" src=\"https://blog.isc2.org/.a/6a00e54f109b67883402b6852ffca1200d-320wi\" style=\"margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;\" title=\"CPE Credit\" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;We encourage all members to read the bylaws located on the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/About/Governance\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² Governance webpage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;. The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/-/media/Files/Amended-and-Restated-Bylaws.ashx\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;(ISC)² Bylaws&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt; set forth the rules concerning the operation of our association and actions of our members. It guides how our Board of Directors and staff manage our nonprofit corporation. The (ISC)² Amended and Restated Bylaws establish fundamental principles about key governance policies, members’ rights and Board operations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;As (ISC)² begins the 2023 Bylaws review process, the Board of Directors are looking for feedback from the membership. This will allow members to provide input and help shape the future of the association and its governance process. As the cybersecurity industry changes and the organization evolves and grows, this process provides an opportunity to allow (ISC)² to grow, adapt and continue to support all members.&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;To learn more about what is new about the bylaws review process and meet some of the 2023 (ISC)² Bylaws Committee, we recorded a webinar with Board of Directors member and Bylaws Committee Chair Lisa Young, CISSP, as she guides viewers through this year’s process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\r\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Watch the webinar: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.isc2.org/en/News-and-Events/Webinars/ThinkTank?commid=576902\"&gt;&lt;span data-contrast=\"none\"&gt;Get Involved – Meet the 2023 (ISC)² Bylaws Committee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-ccp-props=\"{&amp;quot;134233117&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;134233118&amp;quot;:false,&amp;quot;201341983&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335551550&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335551620&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;335559685&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559737&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559738&amp;quot;:0,&amp;quot;335559739&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;335559740&amp;quot;:259}\"&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;","dc:creator":"(ISC)² Management","pubDate":"Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:03:04 -0400"}]}}/* ph=1 */}</feed>
</Logs>