<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Logs>
  <feed>{"?xml":{"@version":"1.0","@encoding":"UTF-8"},"rss":{"@version":"2.0","@xmlns:content":"http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/","@xmlns:wfw":"http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/","@xmlns:dc":"http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/","@xmlns:atom":"http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom","@xmlns:sy":"http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/","@xmlns:slash":"http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/","channel":{"title":"360Quadrants","atom:link":{"@href":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/feed/","@rel":"self","@type":"application/rss+xml"},"link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog","description":"Official Blog","lastBuildDate":"\n\tTue, 13 Sep 2022 05:42:18 +0000\t","language":"en-US","sy:updatePeriod":"\n\thourly\t","sy:updateFrequency":"\n\t1\t","generator":"https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.13","image":{"url":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/KBVrKl-_400x400-150x150.png","title":"360Quadrants","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog","width":"32","height":"32"},"item":[{"title":"Top Automotive Cybersecurity companies in North America","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-automotive-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-automotive-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/#respond","pubDate":"Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:26:48 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"360Quadrants"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Automotive Cyber security"},{"#cdata-section":"automotive cybersecurity"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity vendors"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2944"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity vendors specializing in Automotive It is now more important than ever to protect road cars from cyber-threats. The electronic control unit (ECU), which provides important communication and essential capabilities for operating, monitoring, and customising vehicle subsystems, is one of the main attack vectors. The complexity of vehicle functions is increasing the requirements for information [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-automotive-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Automotive Cybersecurity companies in North America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity vendors specializing in Automotive &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It is now more important than\never to protect road cars from cyber-threats. The electronic control unit\n(ECU), which provides important communication and essential capabilities for\noperating, monitoring, and customising vehicle subsystems, is one of the main\nattack vectors. The complexity of vehicle functions is increasing the\nrequirements for information security in the car. In addition to safeguarding\ninternal vehicle data, the vehicle&amp;#8217;s connections to the outside world must be\nprotected from illegal access.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;For the car sector, cybersecurity is a difficult problem to solve now and in the future. In the coming decade, automakers and suppliers will have to put in a lot of work to comply with cybersecurity regulations and standards. In the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/automotive-industry\"&gt;automobile cybersecurity sector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, there are just a few software vendors. The following is a quick rundown of ten firms:&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Automotive Cybersecurity Companies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/automotive.png\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2945\"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Aptiv&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Plymouth, Michigan&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Aptiv is a multinational\ntechnology business that creates solutions that make mobility safer, greener,\nand more connected. Aptiv creates self-driving vehicle software and computing\nplatforms. The cybersecurity technologies developed by the corporation secure\neverything from a car&amp;#8217;s infotainment system to its wiring.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Aptiv&amp;#8217;s self-driving cars were\nthe first to be tested in Singapore, and the company expects to have them\ncompletely operational by 2022. Aptiv has already offered over 100,000 robotaxi\ntrips to passengers in Las Vegas, in conjunction with the ride-hailing service\nLyft, and wants to expand its service over the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Britive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Los Angeles, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Britive is a cloud-native security\nproduct that provides API-Location Integrations and application access\nmanagement. With a dynamic and intelligent privileged access administration\nsolution for multi-cloud settings, the Britive platform supports teams across\ncloud infrastructure, DevOps, and security activities. Its software is used by\nenterprises in a variety of industries, including automotive, to secure cloud\ndata and manage user permission.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Britive platform enables\nbusinesses to deploy cloud security best practises such as just-in-time (JIT)\naccess and zero standing privileges (ZSP) to avoid security breaches and\noperational disruptions while enhancing efficiency and user productivity.\nBritive enables the rapid detection of privileged access blind spots such as\n&amp;#8220;overprivileged&amp;#8221; users (human or machine IDs) and proposes the\nnecessary changes. Britive enables continual management and control for cloud\napplications and platforms through continuous scanning and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Toyota was able to reduce the\nsetup of user authorisation and role-based action control privileges for Toyota\nuser accounts from three days to 30 seconds utilising Britive platform\ntechnology, according to a 2021 Britive blog article.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. CENTRI Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Seattle, Washington&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;For the Internet of Things, CENTRI\nprovides superior data security. Its software-only solution enables IoT\nprofessionals, developers, and device makers to swiftly get to market with\npurpose-built IoT security, safeguarding data from creation to consumption.\nWith heavyweight industry-standard encryption and compression packed into a\nlightweight tiny footprint appropriate for low-power IoT endpoint devices,\nCENTRI helps you to mitigate today&amp;#8217;s data transfer threats in a standards-based\nnetwork infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Centri develops &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity solutions&lt;/a&gt; for IoT-enabled automotive devices. The Centri IoTAS is a chip and mobile software that protects automobile sensors as well as data that aids automobiles in learning crucial driver navigation preferences such as best routes and addresses.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;To protect IoT-enabled autotech\ndevices, the IoTAS platform does not require an internet connection. Instead,\nit uses identity management technology to connect to all trustworthy devices,\nwhich uses about 40% less bandwidth than BLE and TLS.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Dellfer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: San Mateo, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Dellfer is a cybersecurity firm\nspecialising on autotech software coding. People who create and install linked\ndevices are given more power by the company. It gives DevOps the tools they\nneed to add endpoint protection during the factory build process. The secured\ndevices send forensic data to a cloud server in the field, allowing SecOps to\ntrack thwarted cyber-attacks and system health.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Embedded code from the company\naids IoT-enabled cars in combating cyber-attacks throughout the vehicle&amp;#8217;s\nsystem. To update important fixes, you do not require an Internet connection.\nInstead, the organisation enforces security by deploying code execution\npathways during runtime.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Dellfer teamed up with DENSO, the\nworld&amp;#8217;s second-largest mobility provider, to help put Dellfer&amp;#8217;s IoT\ncybersecurity tools in a larger number of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Harman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Stamford, Connecticut&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Harman, Location Stamford,\nConnecticut, creates connected products and solutions for automakers,\nconsumers, and businesses around the world, including linked automotive\nsystems, audio and video devices, enterprise automation solutions, and Internet\nof Things services. HARMAN audio and linked car solutions are installed in more\nthan 50 million cars on the road today. Their software services link,\nintegrate, and secure billions of mobile devices and systems across all\nplatforms, from work and home to car and mobile. Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.\nacquired HARMAN as a wholly owned subsidiary in March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Harman SHIELD, developed in\ncollaboration with IBM, secures crucial entry points of a car&amp;#8217;s network against\nhackers. It also does a threat analysis on a regular basis to determine which\npoints are the most vulnerable at any time.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;At the 2019 CES conference in Las\nVegas, Harman unveiled the Ignite 3.0, an automotive-based assistant for cars.\nThe company&amp;#8217;s SHIELD cybersecurity infrastructure backs up the technology.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Intertrust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Sunnyvale, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Intertrust Technologies is a\nsoftware firm situated in Silicon Valley that focuses on trustworthy computing\nproducts and services. Intertrust has grown to become a leading provider of\ntrusted distributed computing, based on a history of innovation and significant\ncontributions to the fields of computer security and digital trust.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Intertrust creates technologies\nthat allow drivers customise their cybersecurity requirements and overall\nexperience. Tools that safeguard a vehicle&amp;#8217;s infotainment centre, prevent\nunauthorised entry, and prevent the collection of personal data are among the\ncompany&amp;#8217;s offerings.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;WhiteCryption, one of\nIntertrust&amp;#8217;s key software products, speeds up and secures material transmission\nto drivers. Personagraph, another programme, encrypts a driver&amp;#8217;s personal\ninformation.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. NVIDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Santa Clara, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The GPU was invented by NVIDIA in\n1999, and it drove the expansion of the PC gaming sector while also redefining\ncurrent computer graphics and revolutionising parallel computing. GPU deep\nlearning has lately sparked modern AI, the next phase of computing, with the\nGPU serving as the brain of computers, robotics, and self-driving cars that can\nsense and interpret the world. NVIDIA is rapidly being referred to as &amp;#8220;the\nAI computing firm.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;To operate and defend\nself-driving automobiles, NVIDIA uses AI-powered data processors and\nsemiconductors. Autonomous vehicles can securely learn and relay driving data\nthanks to the company&amp;#8217;s software and cloud-based technology.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Tesla, Mercedes-Benz, Audi,\nToyota, Volkswagen, and others have employed NVIDIA deep learning algorithms to\npower and protect self-driving vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Ixia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Calabasas, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Customers may connect and safeguard their networks with Keysight Network Visibility Security, previously Ixia. From the hardware level through all layers of the OSI stack, Keysight offers a complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/automotive-industry\"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Automotive Cybersecurity solution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Automated end-to-end device security testing covers all access interfaces on a platform, allowing you to find and patch vulnerabilities faster, allowing you to get to market faster. Keysight&amp;#8217;s application and threat intelligence (ATI) database is a subscription-based solution that allows you to test your devices for known vulnerabilities and integrate your own threat database.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Keysight Automotive\nCybersecurity Penetration Test Platform is a scalable platform that allows you\nto validate the cyber-attack resistance of your ECU/TCU, subcomponents, and\nfull car. The Penetration Test Solution is built on the UXM platform from\nKeysight, Ixia Security expertise, and the PathWave Lab Operations platform\nfrom Keysight for test case management and regression testing.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Arxan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Bethesda, Maryland&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Arxan is a division of\nDigital.ai, the industry&amp;#8217;s first integrated value stream management, software\ndelivery, and application security company, which was founded in 2001. Arxan\noffers RASP-based security solutions for mobile devices, PCs, servers, and\nembedded systems, including the Internet of Things. Code obfuscation,\npre-damage, encryption, string encryption, symbol stripping, and renaming are\nall used to protect apps from being compromised. Arxan&amp;#8217;s patented guarding\ntechnology defends applications against assaults, detects attacks at run-time,\nand deters attacks to halt hackers, provide alarms, or fix, making clients&amp;#8217;\napplications genuinely resilient.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Arxan presently protects over 500\nmillion devices in a variety of industries, including financial services,\nautomotive (connected autos), healthcare (connected medical devices), digital\nmedia, gaming, high tech/independent software vendors (ISVs), and others.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. VisualThreat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Founded Year 2013&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location Santa Clara, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;VisualThreat is a connected\nautomobile security company that provides vehicle firewall and over-the-air\n(OTA) ECU update solutions. It provides end-to-end connected-car security\nsolutions to reduce cyber-attack penetration.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;OEMs and tier providers can use\nVisualThreat&amp;#8217;s connected car security technology to incorporate and strengthen\nsecurity functionalities in telematics devices, TSP cloud platforms, and\nautomotive apps. To fight against cyber-attacks, the solution uses a vehicle\ncybersecurity protection framework that includes (FUSE) &amp;#8211; Firewall, Umbrella\npolicy, Security Over the Air (SOTA), and Event Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Car design security testing,\nfirewall, and security OTA as custom SDK &amp;amp; API, automotive mobile app\nsecurity, monitoring dashboard, and anti-fraud of automobiles are among the\ncompany&amp;#8217;s services.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-automotive-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Automotive Cybersecurity companies in North America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-automotive-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Top Cybersecurity vendors for Cars","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors-for-cars/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors-for-cars/#respond","pubDate":"Fri, 15 Jul 2022 10:30:44 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"automotive cybersecurity"},{"#cdata-section":"cybersecurity platform"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity software"},{"#cdata-section":"cybersecurity solutions"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2937"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity procedures used to defend automobiles from bad actors are becoming smarter as the automotive sector grows smarter. Automotive cybersecurity protects the new generation of intelligent cars&amp;#8217; communication networks, electronic systems, software, and data. Long thought to be a thing of the future, self-driving smart vehicles are now a growing industry with a slew [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors-for-cars/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity vendors for Cars&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;The\ncybersecurity procedures used to defend automobiles from bad actors are\nbecoming smarter as the automotive sector grows smarter. &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;Automotive\ncybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; protects the new generation of intelligent cars&amp;#8217; communication\nnetworks, electronic systems, software, and data.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Long thought to\nbe a thing of the future, self-driving smart vehicles are now a growing\nindustry with a slew of firms fighting for a piece of the self-driving pie.\nSo-called &amp;#8220;autotech&amp;#8221; companies, which operate at the confluence of\nautomotive and IoT, are developing the next generation of intelligent vehicles\nwhile also working to address a critical issue: automotive cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\ntools&lt;/a&gt; that defend the new wave of autotech are only as good as the\ncybersecurity technologies that protect it. These ten businesses are working to\nimprove future transportation. The list demonstrates that Israel is the\nindustry leader in vehicle cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Cybersecurity vendors for Cars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;table class=\"wp-block-table\"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Vendor&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Argus Cyber Security&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Tel Aviv, Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;GuardKnox&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Ramla,\n  Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Thales&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Paris, France\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Upstream Security&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Herzliya,\n  Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Cognomotiv&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Menlo Park, California, United States\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Karamba Security&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Hod\n  Hasharon, Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;Regulus Cyber&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Haifa, Hefa, Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;EUROCYBCAR&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Basque,\n  Spain\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;SafeRide Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  &lt;strong&gt;C2A Security&lt;/strong&gt;\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;\n  Jerusalem,\n  Israel\n  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Argus\nCyber Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Tel\nAviv, Israel&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Argus, the\nworld&amp;#8217;s leading provider of automotive cyber security solutions and services,\nprotects connected automobiles and commercial vehicles from cyber-attacks with\ncomprehensive and proven solutions and services. Argus blends novel security\nmethodologies and proven computer networking ability with a strong grasp of\nautomotive best practises, based on decades of expertise in both cyber security\nand the automotive industry. Automobile manufacturers, Tier 1 suppliers, fleet\noperators, and aftermarket connectivity providers are among the company&amp;#8217;s\nclients. Argus was founded in 2013 in Tel Aviv, Israel, and has operations in\nMichigan, Silicon Valley, Stuttgart, and Tokyo. Elektrobit&amp;#8217;s Argus division is\na prominent producer of automotive software solutions and services.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Argus equips\ncommercial smart vehicles with anti-cyber-attack solutions such as connection\nand in-car network protection, which cover everything from the vehicle&amp;#8217;s\ninfotainment system to the software and hardware communication networks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Continental, a\nmanufacturer of car parts, has begun integrating Argus&amp;#8217; cybersecurity solutions\ninto all its connected vehicle electronics.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. GuardKnox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Ramla,\nIsrael&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;GuardKnox, which\nwas founded in 2016, is the automobile industry&amp;#8217;s first Cybertech Tier\nprovider, allowing OEMs, Tier 1 suppliers, and the aftermarket to expand\nfreely. GuardKnox is headquartered in Israel, with offices in Stuttgart,\nGermany, and Detroit, Michigan. GuardKnox provides the ability, technologies,\nand solutions that enable the automotive industry to deliver new vehicle\ncapabilities on a budget that is both affordable and evolutionary.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;GuardKnox\ndevelops autonomous vehicle code architecture that controls everything from\ngeneral vehicle systems (including sensors) to technologies that improve the\nuser experience (infotainment systems, centre consoles and more).&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;GuardKnox was\nhired by Porsche to address cybersecurity in its new vehicle line. The new\ntechnology, according to the German automaker, will protect against hacking\nthreats and serve as a foundation for &amp;#8220;real-time vehicle\npersonalization.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Thales&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Paris,\nFrance&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Thales is a\nworldwide high-tech leader that invests in digital and &amp;#8220;deep tech&amp;#8221;\nbreakthroughs such as connectivity, big data, artificial intelligence,\ncybersecurity, and quantum technology to create a future that is critical to\nsociety&amp;#8217;s growth. By putting humans at the centre of the decision-making\nprocess, the company helps its customers – businesses, organisations, and\nnations – in the defence, aeronautics, space, transportation, and digital\nidentity and security markets fulfil their important tasks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Thales delivers\nIoT hardware, software, devices, and vehicles with electrical system\nengineering services. Its services for the transportation and automotive\nindustries place a strong emphasis on cybersecurity and compliance with data\nregulations.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Thales announced\na cooperation with Gireve in 2021, a firm designed to connect European electric\ntransport operators. The &amp;#8220;Plug &amp;amp; Charge&amp;#8221; technology, which was\ndeveloped collaboratively, allows drivers to charge their electric vehicle at\nany participating suitable charging station and be automatically billed through\na secure card-free transaction.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Upstream\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Herzliya,\nIsrael&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Upstream\nSecurity was established in Israel in 2017. The business offers cloud-based\nautomobile cybersecurity solutions. Upstream provides a cloud-based\ncybersecurity and data analytics platform that protects connected car fleets by\nutilizing big data analytics and machine learning algorithms to monitor and\ndetect threats in real time. Using existing automotive data flows, Upstream&amp;#8217;s\nC4 platform combines machine learning, data standardization, and digital twin\ntechnologies to detect anomalies in real time.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Upstream is the\nindustry leader in centralized SaaS-based cybersecurity and security operations\ncentres. Upstream focuses on connected car security services that include\nbuilt-in cybersecurity as part of the vehicle&amp;#8217;s linked systems. Upstream It\nalso caters to linked fleets in the rental car and haulage industries.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Cognomotiv\n&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Menlo\nPark, California, United States&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cognomotiv,\nwhich was founded in 2016, provides onboard cybersecurity for self-driving and\nsemi-autonomous vehicles. The automotive and transportation industries rely on\nCognomotiv&amp;#8217;s real-time services to ensure safety and security.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cognomotiv is a\nprovider of cloud-AI-based automotive solutions. It does a non-intrusive system\ndiagnosis and makes recommendations for system improvement. The module works in\nconjunction with the existing system to give solutions for vehicle fleets and\nlogistics. It offers services such as real-time vehicle health analysis, insights\nand recommendations for existing and future system concerns, cybersecurity, and\nmore. The module can also be found in connected, semi-autonomous, and fully\nautonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cognomotiv&amp;#8217;s\nsolution protects OEMs, tier-1 automotive suppliers, fleet operators, and\nindividual vehicle owners from cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Karamba\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Hod\nHasharon, Israel&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Karamba Security\nwas established in the year 2015. Device security solutions for IoT\napplications are provided by Karamba. It offers &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\nsolutions&lt;/a&gt; for connected gadgets and self-driving cars. Its approach\nprotects an automobile&amp;#8217;s externally connected controllers from hackers. To keep\nthe car safe and prevent attacks from ever accessing the car&amp;#8217;s Controller Area\nNetwork, only valid code and valid behaviours are permitted to run on the\ncontrollers. Rather of identifying assaults that have already entered the\nvehicle&amp;#8217;s internal network, it concentrates on detecting and preventing attacks\nfrom entering the CAN Bus.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Its embedded &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\nsoftware&lt;/a&gt; is utilised in automotive ECUs, IoT devices, Industry 4.0\ncontrollers, enterprise edge devices, and other linked devices. Carwall, the\ncompany&amp;#8217;s strategy to securing ECUs, hardens them by developing an ECU-specific\ncode based on factory settings. This ECU code is compared to the original OEM\nsettings on a regular basis. The Karamba software can shut down external\nattacks if ECU settings are illegally altered. Carwall is an effective way for\ndetecting security issues and provides a bespoke solution for ECUs. Carwall is\nalso independent of MCUs and operating systems, supporting Linux, QNX, and\nAUTOSAR.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Other linked\ndevices are protected with a solution called XGuard. It now supports seven MPU\narchitectures and 12 operating systems and is OS and MPU agnostic. Karamba is\nan industry leader in the field of IoT device cybersecurity. Karamba had\nagreements in place to secure 12 million IoT devices by the end of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Regulus\nCyber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Haifa,\nHefa, Israel&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Regulus Cyber is\nanother Israeli cybersecurity business that was founded in 2016. Regulus was\nthe first company to offer sensor security solutions for ADAS and self-driving\ncars. It is focusing on data protection for three main sensors: GPS, radar, and\nlidar.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Regulus provides\nsoftware-only security for GNSS vulnerabilities, including an\n&amp;#8220;anti-virus&amp;#8221; for Global Navigation Satellite Systems. Similar to a\nGPS Firewall, the programme ensures position and time fidelity under a variety\nof attack surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Spoofing or\nillegal signals masquerading as valid GPS signals, as well as jamming or\nattacks that limit the sensors&amp;#8217; capacity to accept input signals, are all\nprotected by the Regulus Pyramid GNSS. The Pyramid GNSS system may also protect\na car GPS receiver from spoofing.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Harman became a\nRegulus customer in April 2020 and would utilise the technology in its\ncybersecurity product, Harman Shield.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. EUROCYBCAR\n&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Basque,\nSpain&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;EUROCYBCAR is a\nSpanish firm that conducts technical assessments to verify the security of\nconnected vehicles. The company assesses a vehicle&amp;#8217;s cybersecurity by examining\nits privacy policies for drivers and passengers, as well as physical safety\nprecautions. EUROCYBCAR also offers several different cybersecurity testing for\nthe automotive industry, ranging from individual vehicles to fleet management\nsystems and mobility apps. EUROCYBCAR conducts a test to determine whether\nautomobiles equipped with applications are cyber secure. It also aids in the\ndefence of automobiles from cyber-attacks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;EUROCYBCAR\ncreated the first European testing procedure based on two metrics to validate\nthe level of vehicle cybersecurity. On the one hand, how it safeguards the\nprivacy of data from people who travel by automobile &amp;#8211; as well as those who\nmake the car. The level of protection and vulnerability of a vehicle&amp;#8217;s systems\nagainst possible cyberattacks -physically or remotely- that are intended to be\nused as an access door for reaching the devices that affect driving -brakes,\ndirection, motor &amp;#8211; and whose malicious handling could cause an accident that\njeopardises the lives of the occupants.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. SafeRide\nTechnologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in: Tel\nAviv-Yafo, Israel&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The vSentry &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity platform&lt;/a&gt; from SafeRide combines embedded client software with cloud services, as well as a security operations centre. It&amp;#8217;s a connected and autonomous vehicle cybersecurity platform with multiple layers. For linked ECUs, VSentry Core is a cybersecurity software suite. It&amp;#8217;s made for Linux-based ECUs including infotainment systems, telematics, and networked gateways. The vSentry Edge AI version is an Intrusion Detection and Prevention Software for central and zonal gateway modules, as well as IDPS for automotive Ethernet. The AI version is a cloud-based fleet cybersecurity solution.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;For OEMs, Tier 1\nsuppliers, telematics providers, and fleets, SafeRide also offers vInsight, an\nAI-based Vehicle Health Management platform.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. C2A\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based in:\nJerusalem, Israel&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;C2A Security is\nan automotive cybersecurity lifecycle management platform that was founded in\n2016. The perimeter cybersecurity protection, in-vehicle network security, and\nembedded runtime protection are all C2A products. A Cybersecurity Management\nSystem is provided by C2A Security (CSMS). C2A released AutoSec, a suite of\ncybersecurity products, in October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Original\nequipment manufacturers (OEMs), tier-1 suppliers, and the entire automotive\nsupply chain benefit from AutoSec&amp;#8217;s full-spectrum visibility and security. It\nalso improves supply chain communication, automates threat modelling and\ndetection, and minimises vulnerability reaction time. The platform quickly\nintegrates security policy updates into embedded systems and controls risks\nthroughout vehicle lifecycles thanks to its flexible and open ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The new ISO/SAE\n21434 standard, as well as the new UNECE WP.29 rule, are both met by AutoSec.\nIn April 2020, C2A became an AUTOSAR development partner.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connected Car Cybersecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;A connected car\nis one that can communicate with other systems outside of the vehicle in both\ndirections (LAN). This enables the car to exchange internet connection and, as\na result, data with other devices both inside and outside the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Connected\nvehicles, in conjunction with other upcoming vehicular technologies such as\nautomated driving, electric automobiles, and shared mobility, are helping to\ncreate a new type of future mobility: autonomous, connected, electric, and\nshared vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;A vehicle can\nconnect to its surroundings and communicate with them in three ways:&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(V2I) Vehicle\nto Infrastructure Connectivity:&lt;/strong&gt; This technology collects\ndata from the vehicle and gives the driver with information on the\ninfrastructure. Information concerning safety, mobility, or environmental\nconditions is communicated using V2I technology.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(V2V) Vehicle\nto Vehicle connectivity&lt;/strong&gt;: This technology uses a\nwireless exchange of data to relay information about the speed and location of\nnearby vehicles. The goal is to reduce traffic congestion, avoid accidents, and\nhave a positive impact on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(V2C) Vehicle\nto Cloud Connectivity&lt;/strong&gt;: This technology communicates\nwith a cloud system information about and for vehicle applications. This\nenables the car to access data from other cloud-connected industries, such as\nenergy, transit, and smart homes, which all make use of IoT.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;While linked\ncars provide consumers with numerous benefits, manufacturers and suppliers must\nevaluate what connected cars represent for consumer privacy and security. As\nmore connected automobiles hit the road, malevolent hackers will be able to\nexploit software flaws via cellular networks, Wi-Fi, and hard-line connections.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Hackers&amp;#8217; ability\nto get illegal remote access to the vehicle network and undermine vital safety\nsystems puts not just users&amp;#8217; personal information at danger, but also their\nphysical safety.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vehicle manufacturers\nmust implement a cybersecurity strategy that covers not only visible\nvulnerabilities in their vehicles&amp;#8217; software, but also hidden vulnerabilities\npresented by open source [or third-party] components.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors-for-cars/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity vendors for Cars&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors-for-cars/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Which region has the cheapest EV charging prices in America?","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/which-region-has-the-cheapest-ev-charging-prices-in-america/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/which-region-has-the-cheapest-ev-charging-prices-in-america/#respond","pubDate":"Wed, 29 Jun 2022 06:07:01 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"360Quadrants"},{"#cdata-section":"ELECTRIC VEHICLE MARKET"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging station"},{"#cdata-section":"charging cost for electric cars"},{"#cdata-section":"Charging System"},{"#cdata-section":"cheapest EV charging"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging companies"},{"#cdata-section":"ev charging station business"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging stations"},{"#cdata-section":"free EV charging"},{"#cdata-section":"type of charging port"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2927"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;As evident, the US is one of the major contributors to EV sales globally and is growing linearly in the EV market since 2015. However, not all states share an equal distribution of technology. As per the data given by National Renewable Energy Laboratory (last updated June 2021), California has the maximum number of EVs, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/which-region-has-the-cheapest-ev-charging-prices-in-america/\"&gt;Which region has the cheapest EV charging prices in America?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;div class=\"wptb-table-container wptb-table-2925\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-table-container-matrix\"&gt;&lt;table class=\"wptb-preview-table wptb-element-main-table_setting-2925\" data-reconstraction=\"1\" style=\"border: 3px solid rgb(77, 108, 155);\" data-wptb-table-tds-sum-max-width=\"44\" data-wptb-cells-width-auto-count=\"1\" data-wptb-table-alignment=\"center\" data-wptb-header-background-color=\"#ffffff\" data-wptb-even-row-background-color=\"#0d5933\" data-table-columns=\"0\" data-wptb-td-width-auto=\"10\"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\" style=\"background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 2px; padding: 14px; border-color: rgb(77, 108, 155); border-style: none;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-2\" style=\"font-size: 20px; color: rgb(0, 112, 108);\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p class=\"\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-1\" style=\"color: rgb(0, 0, 0); font-size: 15px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Florida and Texas can be predicted as the cheapest charging regions across the US&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; A massive amount of DC Fast charger installation is still a long way&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; California to dominate the US EVCS market with the maximum number of private and public charging ports&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; CCS connector will support the higher adoption of EVs globally&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Level 2 chargers to dominate the US EVCS market&lt;br&gt;·&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Federal Bill to accelerate the EVCS infrastructure in the US&lt;/div&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"mix-blend-mode: darken; position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"mix-blend-mode: darken; position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;grammarly-extension data-grammarly-shadow-root=\"true\" style=\"mix-blend-mode: darken; position: absolute; top: -1px; left: -1px; pointer-events: none; z-index: auto;\" class=\"cGcvT\"&gt;&lt;/grammarly-extension&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\nAs evident,\nthe US is one of the major contributors to EV sales globally and is growing linearly\nin the EV market since 2015. However, not all states share an equal\ndistribution of technology. As per the data given by National Renewable Energy\nLaboratory (last updated June 2021), &lt;strong&gt;California has the maximum number of\nEVs, contributing to 42% of the total nationwide&lt;/strong&gt;. While Florida has the\nsecond-highest number of EVs followed by Texas, Washington, New York City, New\nJersey, and Arizona. It was noted that California has a total of 42,550 public\nand private EVSE ports and Florida has 7,393 charging ports. From the data\navailable, the year 2021 showed a rapid increase in the number of charging stations\nwhich grew by 55%. Many US states have laws and incentives related to the use\nof electric vehicles which makes the EV adoption rate to be completely\ndifferent across all the 50 states.\n\n\n\n&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Cheapest-EV-charging.jpg\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2928\"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: From Left to Right – Number of Level 1 Chargers, Level 2 Chargers, and DC Fast Chargers&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It is well known that even though the\ncountry is governed by federal law, the states are responsible for their own\ngoverning and decisions, which also include decisions pertaining to the expansion\nof the charging vehicle infrastructure. It is evident that not all the states\nare well equipped with charging facilities. Some states like California and\nFlorida have adopted EV technology and have set net-zero emissions goals for\n2025, while the other states have not expanded in the technology as the sales\nfor ICE vehicles have been dominant over the electric vehicles and hence taking\nthe slower route for the EVCS deployment.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;With the new EV infrastructure bill passed by the American government, the US is expected to have around 15 million electric vehicles by 2030. This huge increase is fueled by the decarbonization and net-zero emissions target of the government. Several prominent companies such as Tesla, Electrify America, and ChargePoint are also aggressively making moves to expand their &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;charging infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; across American states. These initiatives involve the deployment of more Level 2 chargers as compared to the DC fast chargers along with other charging infrastructure and software upgrades. However, merely adding a large number of Level 2 chargers instead of Level 3 DC fast chargers will not be a correct pathway to achieving net-zero emissions.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;Different levels of EV Charging&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;There are three types of charging levels,\nnamely Level 1, Level 2, and Level 3based on the output power levels. A vast\nmajority of the charging stations across the country are Level 2 chargers,\naccounting for 80% of total chargers. While Level 1 and Level 3 comprise 5% and\n15% of the total chargers respectively. The primary reason for such a\ndistribution is the low power level of Level 1 chargers and high pricing of the\nDC fast chargers, due to which the EV users are more deviated to using the\nLevel 2 chargers. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;As per Alternative Fuels Data Center, there\nare currently 43,163 Level 2 chargers and 6,286 DC fast chargers, and only 285\nLevel 1 chargers. Most of the EVs across the US are compatible to charge with\nLevel 1 and Level 2 charging equipment. To address the rapid charging needs of\nthe EVs for long runs most EV manufacturers now ensure to make it compatible\nwith the CCS connectors which allow the EV charging to be compatible with all\nlevels of charging. The Tesla vehicles come with a J1772 adapter, which allows\nthem to use non-Tesla charging equipment spread across the US. It additionally\nprovides an adapter for its users to connect with the CHAdeMO adapter. These\ncharging levels can be explained as below:&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1 Chargers:&lt;/strong&gt; This charging is typically used at homes where 120V AC outlets are\navailable. Since most of the EVs come with a portable Level 1 cord set,\ntherefore no additional equipment is required and can be installed easily. It\nusually takes 8 hours of charging at 120 V to work for about 40 miles of\nelectric range for a mid-sized electric vehicle. These chargers have a minimum\npricing structure and usually come along with the EV.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2 Chargers:&lt;/strong&gt; It is the most common type of charging observed in residential\nbuildings. It offers charging through a 240 V or 208 V AC outlet and can\noperate at up to 80 amps and 19.2 kW. The level 2 chargers need a constant dedicated\n40-Amp circuit to work in accordance with the National Electric Code\nrequirements in Article 625. However, most of the residential equipment\noperates at lower power ratings, therefore many of these units operate at up to\n30 Amps, delivering 7.2 kW of power while charging the vehicle overnight. These\nLevel 2 chargers are easy to use and can be installed at home and have a\nreasonable pricing structure when compared to the DC chargers. They are also a\npreferred choice for workplaces, shopping malls, public charging places, etc. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3 Chargers:&lt;/strong&gt; DC fast chargers also called Level 3 chargers operate at high power\nvalues such as 250 kW and above. These chargers are mostly found in the heavy\ntraffic corridors at installed stations. There are three types of DC fast\ncharging systems based on the type of charging port on the vehicle namely, SAE\nCombined Charging System (CCS), CHAdeMO, and Tesla. The CCS connectors used are\nunique in the application as they can be used for all three types of charging\nlevels, the only difference is DC fast charging connectors have two additional\nbottom pins. The only setback with the DC fast chargers is the high installation\nand maintenance costs, which hinders its expansion.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;Miles per hour of charging time&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The charging time for an EV can be as long\nas 8 to 12 hours and as short as 15 to 30 mins only depending on the type of\ncharger used. A typical electric car has a 60-kWh battery that can be charged\nfrom zero to 100% within a duration of 8 hours using the 6.6 kW charging power\nor can be charged under 30 mins by using a rapid DC fast charger. These DC fast\nchargers are the fastest way to add up to 60 to 200 miles of range by mere\ncharging the EV for 30 mins or less.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Level 1 chargers are very slow, adding nearly 5 miles of range per hour as compared to the Level 2 chargers which can add up to 25 miles of range per hour, therefore the EV drivers tend more towards using the Level 2 charging. For the DC fast charging, although it can speed up the charging process and can add up several miles, not all the EVs are compatible with such high-power values and therefore the chargers are less in number, comprising only 15% of the total public charging ports across the US.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n&lt;div class=\"wptb-table-container wptb-table-2926\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-table-container-matrix\"&gt;&lt;table class=\"wptb-preview-table wptb-element-main-table_setting-2926\" data-reconstraction=\"0\" style=\"border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; border-image: initial;\" data-wptb-table-tds-sum-max-width=\"650\" data-wptb-cells-width-auto-count=\"5\" data-wptb-fixed-width-size=\"0\" data-table-columns=\"4\"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-1\" style=\"font-size: 20px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type of Charger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-2\" style=\"font-size: 20px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miles per Hour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-3\" style=\"font-size: 20px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p class=\"\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Needs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-5\" style=\"font-size: 20px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feasible Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-4\" style=\"font-size: 20px;\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connectors Compatible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-6\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 1 (&amp;gt;2% of total public chargers across the US)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-7\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Approximately 5 miles of range per 1 hour of charging*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-8\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;120-volt AC outlet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-9\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Home&lt;br&gt;Workplace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-10\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;J1772&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-11\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 2 (80% of total public chargers across the US)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-12\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Approximately 25 miles of range per 1 hour of charging†&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-13\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;240 volts and 40 amps continuous load&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-14\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Home&lt;br&gt;Workplace&lt;br&gt;Public Charging Stations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-15\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;J1772&lt;br&gt;Tesla connector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-16\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 3 (15% of total public chargers across the US)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-17\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;Approximately 100 to 200+ miles of range per 30 minutes of charging‡&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-18\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Voltage and current rating vary according to the CPOs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-19\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public Charging Stations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-20\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"mce-edit-focus\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;CCS&lt;br&gt;CHAdeMO &lt;br&gt;Tesla connector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=\"wptb-row\"&gt;&lt;td class=\"wptb-cell\" style=\"border-width: 1px;\" data-wptb-css-td-auto-width=\"true\" colspan=\"5\" rowspan=\"1\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"wptb-text-container wptb-ph-element wptb-element-text-21\"&gt;&lt;div class=\"\" style=\"position: relative;\"&gt;&lt;p&gt;*- Assumes 1.9 kW charging power&lt;br&gt;†-Assumes 6.6 kW charging power&lt;br&gt;‡-Charging power varies by vehicle and battery state of charge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 1: Comparison Table of Level 1, Level 2, and Level 3 chargers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;Which region is the cheapest for EV charging across the\nUS? &lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“What will be the charging cost for the electric car?” &amp;#8211; &lt;/strong&gt;This is the most asked question by EV users and new adopters of the technology and can only be answered by a thorough evaluation of the geography and the policies adopted by the region. The charging cost for electric cars in America depends on various factors such as geography, connectors, power consumed, charging time, type of battery, and many other such factors. In order to understand which US region has the cheapest &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charging price&lt;/a&gt;, it can be understood by the monthly electricity rates and the number of charging points in the vicinity. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Based on the number of charging ports, it\nis evident that California and Florida have the maximum number of charging\nports. However, the cost of electricity varies in different states of the US.\nFor instance, In the residential areas of California and New York have rates as\nhigh as 26.71 and 19.74 cents per kWh respectively, while states like Florida,\nUtah, Washington Oregon, and Montana have low electricity rates (Cents per Kilowatt-hour)\nlike 13.50, 10.55, 10.14, 11.01, and 10.76 cents per kWh respectively as per\nthe EIA electric Power Monthly. These costs vary for the transportation sector\nregion-wise. Further, the home charging prices are usually lower than the\npublic charging stations as the home charging prices do not include\ninstallation, infrastructure development, maintenance, host fees, etc. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Through the above analysis, it can be\nevaluated that a lower electricity consumption rate of 13.50 cents per kWh and\nthe number of charging ports across the region at regular miles make &lt;strong&gt;Florida\nthe cheapest region for EV charging as of now for the home EV charging&lt;/strong&gt;.\nWhile based on the US state electricity rates for the transportation sector and\nthe number of charging stations, Texas’s electricity rate for the\ntransportation sector is 7.27 cents per kWh and 5,372 public charging ports\nwhich is the third-largest number of charging ports available across the US.\nTherefore&lt;strong&gt;, Texas can be considered the cheapest region for EV charging.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/which-region-has-the-cheapest-ev-charging-prices-in-america/\"&gt;Which region has the cheapest EV charging prices in America?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/which-region-has-the-cheapest-ev-charging-prices-in-america/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Top benefits of charging a Car at Home over a Commercial EV Charging Station (EVCS)","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-benefits-of-charging-a-car-at-home-over-a-commercial-ev-charging-station-evcs/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-benefits-of-charging-a-car-at-home-over-a-commercial-ev-charging-station-evcs/#respond","pubDate":"Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:53:17 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"360Quadrants"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging station"},{"#cdata-section":"Americans Charge EVs"},{"#cdata-section":"Commercial EVCS"},{"#cdata-section":"electric charging systems"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging stations"},{"#cdata-section":"EV Infrastructure"},{"#cdata-section":"free EV charging"},{"#cdata-section":"public charging stations"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2920"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles offer several benefits over conventional ICE-based vehicles. EVs are cheaper in the long run, easy to maintain, and have a lower carbon footprint. With more users realizing the benefits of the EVs, they are looking for charging options that are convenient, time-saving, and easy to use. It was observed that a huge EV [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-benefits-of-charging-a-car-at-home-over-a-commercial-ev-charging-station-evcs/\"&gt;Top benefits of charging a Car at Home over a Commercial EV Charging Station (EVCS)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles offer several benefits\nover conventional ICE-based vehicles. EVs are cheaper in the long run, easy to\nmaintain, and have a lower carbon footprint. With more users realizing the\nbenefits of the EVs, they are looking for charging options that are convenient,\ntime-saving, and easy to use. It was observed that a huge EV user base\npreferred the home charging points over the commercial charging stations. The\nprobable reasons for the mass shift could be the advantages offered by the home\ncharging systems. The home or the residential chargers do not essentially mean\na private home connection, it may also mean a private workplace, shopping mall,\nor home offering charging service to only a certain number of users. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;EVs are usually charged at the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;public charging stations&lt;/a&gt; or with the home charging points. Through the data analysis done by companies, a majority of charging was done using the home charging points during the nighttime whereas the daytime charging was split between public charging stations and private charging stations at the workplaces or malls, etc. Even though the public charging stations offer a rapid charging facility and zero installation costs to the user, it also has some potential drawbacks. The long waiting queues and the time required to charge the vehicle thereafter cause great inconvenience, thereby deviating users towards adopting home charging systems. Another prominent setback of the public charging station is the DC fast charging ports, which when used constantly degrade the car batteries at a faster rate and come with premium pricing.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the home charging points may have some initial deployment costs but offers several benefits over the public charging stations in the long term. The current home chargers are usually Level 1 and Level 2 chargers which provide charging through 120 V and 240 V AC circuits respectively. The Level 3 chargers i.e., the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;DC fast chargers&lt;/a&gt; are compatible only with certain car models and are available at the public charging stations only. The below-listed points further enlighten the three levels of charging and their throughput.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level I Charger:&lt;/strong&gt; Overnight charging using a 120-volt AC outlet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II Charger:&lt;/strong&gt; 4-6 hours to charge with 240 volts and 40 amps continuous load&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level III Charger (DC Fast Charger):&lt;/strong&gt; Capable of providing a 100% charging in less than 30 minutes (voltage and current rating vary according to the CPOs)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Top-Benefits-of-Charging-a-car-at-Home.jpg\" alt=\"Types of charging connectors \" class=\"wp-image-2922\"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span style=\"background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);\"&gt;Figure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; 1: Types of charging connectors&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;With these charging options, most EV users are now able to meet the driving range requirements by easily charging their vehicles overnight through the home charging points. Some of the top benefits of having a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;home EV charging point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; can be enlisted as:&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charge at ease: &lt;/strong&gt;The home charging points eliminate the need to wait in a long queue to charge the vehicle at the charging stations during peak hours. The EV consumers can easily charge their vehicles at their preferred time and convenience without investing a dedicated time at the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;charging station&lt;/a&gt;. Also, since most countries do not have a significant number of charging stations required to address the increasing sales of EVs, installing home chargers will give users a sense of reliability with EV usage.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affordable&lt;/strong&gt;:\nEV chargers at home only require a dedicated power outlet near the parking\nlocation home and no other additional installation costs are required, unless\nLevel 2 chargers are installed which have minimal installation costs. The household\nelectricity rates per kWh are low as compared to the public charging station electricity\nrates, therefore the users need to pay the high charging rates set by the\nthird-party energy companies like BP and Shell. Such eliminated overhead\ncharges at the public charging stations make the home charging system more\naffordable. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It was observed that the users who used solar\npanels for electricity saved more with the home charging solutions. These home\nchargers also provide real-time time data using which the EV consumers can also\nclaim tax benefits in some countries.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery Health Optimization: &lt;/strong&gt;Any battery degrades over a certain period of time, however even if the\npublic charging station offers great charging at a faster speed, it may cause\npotential damage to the car battery health due to its high-power charging\nports. The home charging points on the contrary charge the vehicle with minimal\nvoltage levels, leading to delayed battery degradation and optimized usage&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compatibility: &lt;/strong&gt;Most EV home chargers are compatible with a wide array of electric\nvehicles. Such additional benefits add in terms of future EV purchases by the\nuser from a different manufacturer. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster and Safer Charging: &lt;/strong&gt;Using a home charging point can be faster than the public charging\nstation unless the user is using the fast-charging port which has very high\nprices. The home charge&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Another major benefit of using the home\ncharging points is safety and security. At the public stations, leaving the car\nfor a longer duration may expose it to several risks of theft and vandalism,\ntherefore using home charging points assures the users with safe charging of\nthe vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;How Americans Charge EVs &amp;#8211; At home or at Commercial EVCS&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;As per the Alternative Fuel Data Center of\nthe US Department of Energy, the present American EVCS network consists of a\ntotal of 48,298 public charging stations out of which only 6,265 are the DC\nfast chargers and the rest mostly are equipped with the Level 2 chargers. About\n80% of these charging points comprise Level 2 chargers. These Level 2 chargers\ncharge the vehicles ~6.8 times faster than the Level 1 chargers and come with\nan optimized pricing structure as compared to the DC fast chargers, therefore\nare the most widely preferred chargers across America. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;As electric vehicles are getting ubiquitous in the US, the need for fast and accessible charging systems has also increased. Automakers like Ford, General Motors, and Volkswagen through its subsidiary Electrify America are investing in expanding the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charging stations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; across America. However, the problem of accessible charging points will persist unless the deployments of these planned charging infrastructures are completed. To address this problem the state governments and the local authorities are figuring out ways to make the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;electric charging systems&lt;/a&gt; available to maximum EV users. For instance, to reach the target of net-zero emission by 2028, Los Angeles has started providing a rebate to developers and managers who are offering charging stations in the parking lots for buildings with multiple families. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In a densely populated area like New York\nCity, where owning a private space for parking is a luxury, maximum residents\ncannot use private home charging systems. To ease such a problem, the local\ngovernment of the city launched a curbside charging network called PlugNYC,\nthrough a partnership with Con Edison and Canadian charging station company FLO.\nThe PlugNYC has an initial installation of 34 stations with 100 plugs and\nadditional 4 stations with 20 plugs for the city’s fleet vehicles. It further plans\nto install 40,000 public Level 2 chargers and 6,000 DC fast chargers by 2030. NYC\nis focused on creating one of the largest municipal electric vehicle charging\nnetworks to support the goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2050. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;As for the rural American areas, the US Department of Transportation has introduced the Rural &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; Toolkit under the ROUTES Initiative to help rural entities plan the infrastructure and fund EV chargers. While in West Virginia, State Parks has installed electric charging stations where EV drivers get the complimentary service of free EV charging, while they rent the lodge or spend money in the shop. The Colorado Energy Office and Regional Air Quality Council have supported the installation of the first Level 2 charging station in the parking spaces. The Carbondale has expanded to 16 charging stations, of which 15 are free Level 2 charging stations.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Through such initiatives, it is evident\nthat the US government is working in its direction to achieve the target set by\nthe federal government of net-zero emissions. However, shifting the usage from\nICE-based vehicles to electric or hybrid electric vehicles will be a critical\nfactor in deciding the EV charging infrastructure of the US in near future. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;Growth Strategy Ahead &amp;#8211; American Commercial EVCS Network&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;During the period 2011 to 2013, the US\nDepartment of Energy along with ChargePoint installed 17,000 AC Level 2\ncharging and over 100 fast charging ports in 22 regions of the country for\nresidential and commercial usage. Through this project, it was noticed that\ndespite the installation of several public charging stations, the major\npopulation of EV consumers utilized the home or work charging stations.\nHowever, now with the higher installations of public and home charging stations,\na survey conducted on the consumer behavior, reflected that around 57% of the\nEV user population is willing to invest in the home charging Level 2 chargers,\nwhile the rest of the EV drivers are tending towards paying a premium for DC\nfast charging points.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, the US government\nannounced the Electric Vehicle Charging Action Plan which is aimed at building\na national network of 500,000 EV charging stations. The plan includes a total\ninvestment of USD 7.5 billion, where USD 2.5 billion will be utilized in rural\ncharging, improving local air quality, and increasing EV charging access in\ndisadvantaged communities and corridors. The government has also planned on\nincreasing the domestic manufacturing of EV batteries and components. Such\ninitiatives by the US government in the EV charging systems are transformative\nwith an aim to touch down the net-zero emissions by the year 2050. Additionally,\ncompanies like Electrify America are also extending their support in achieving\nthe net-zero emission target. The company is planning to invest USD 2 billion\nin Zero Emission Vehicle (ZEV) infrastructure across the US, thereby supporting\nincreased adoption of ZEV technology.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h4&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The home charging points tend to offer\nnumerous benefits over the public charging stations. By charging the vehicles\novernight at home, the EV drivers can save their time and are able to drive conveniently.\nIt is not far that the advancements in the home charging solutions will reduce\nthis charging time and further accelerate EV adoption. However, it is to take\nnote that the users will still need to top up the charging while on the long-run\nroutes. A co-existing public and private charging infrastructure will foster\nthe growth of EV charging networks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Even though the US has been an early adopter of electric vehicle charging technology, nearly half of the users still step back from buying an EV due to the limited network of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;Level 2 charging stations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the premium price of the fast-charging systems. To increase the adoption rate of EV technology, more installation of home chargers will be critical as the EV drivers tend to charge their vehicles with convenience in line with the optimized pricing. &lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-benefits-of-charging-a-car-at-home-over-a-commercial-ev-charging-station-evcs/\"&gt;Top benefits of charging a Car at Home over a Commercial EV Charging Station (EVCS)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-benefits-of-charging-a-car-at-home-over-a-commercial-ev-charging-station-evcs/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"How Commercial Vehicles can get optimum Cybersecurity?","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-commercial-vehicles-can-get-optimum-cybersecurity/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-commercial-vehicles-can-get-optimum-cybersecurity/#respond","pubDate":"Wed, 22 Jun 2022 06:54:03 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging station"},{"#cdata-section":"Commercial Vehicle Telematics"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity vendors"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging companies"},{"#cdata-section":"ev charging station business"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2911"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;Automotive Cyber security &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Hackers can target up to fifty different automotive IoT devices (computers) in modern vehicles. As a result, vehicle cybersecurity is crucial for vehicle safety. There are dozens of computers in modern cars, and they are not simply for navigation or music. Nearly every system in a vehicle, including steering, brakes, and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-commercial-vehicles-can-get-optimum-cybersecurity/\"&gt;How Commercial Vehicles can get optimum Cybersecurity?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Cyber security &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Hackers can target up to fifty different automotive IoT devices (computers) in modern vehicles. As a result, vehicle cybersecurity is crucial for vehicle safety. There are dozens of computers in modern cars, and they are not simply for navigation or music. Nearly every system in a vehicle, including steering, brakes, and the engine itself, is monitored and controlled by computers. As a result, cyber security for automobiles is essential.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;div class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;figure class=\"alignleft\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Vehicle-cybersecurity.png\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2912\"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Hackers can steal data or even\ntake control of a car if the computer systems are not properly protected. As you\nmight expect, this makes vehicle cyber security a top priority for customers,\nautomakers, and OEMs.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vehicle cybersecurity entails\nputting in place proven defences to: &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• prevent data theft (such as GPS\nlocation information or data from your smartphone connected to the Bluetooth\nspeaker), &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• prevent hackers from\ncontrolling or manipulating your vehicle (for example, by disabling the burglar\nalarm or fooling the collision avoidance system), and &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• ensure that no one can damage\nyour vehicle (for example, by resetting your oil change counter so you do not\nget your oil changed).&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive cybersecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a relatively new sector that is rapidly evolving to keep up with the industry&amp;#8217;s fast-paced technological improvements and the growing number of cyber events. Traditional car safety laws and security standards, unfortunately, do not adequately encompass the cyber dangers posed by today&amp;#8217;s connected vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Cyber security\nmarket&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;As connectivity advancements\nalter the automobile industry, the global market for connected cars is expected\nto rise dramatically over the next several years. Consumers benefit from a\nvariety of features, including high-definition streaming video, Wi-Fi access,\nbetter entertainment systems, and the ability to manage components of the\nvehicle remotely using mobile phone applications, such as the locking/unlocking\nand ignition mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;However, much like any other gadget that connects to the internet, cyber thieves can pose a threat to car security. Leaked personal data, risks to a vehicle&amp;#8217;s vital security and safety procedures, and, in extreme situations, full remote control of the vehicle can all come from security breaches. Because of the increased reliance on applications, connectivity, and more complex and integrated electronic components as the industry goes toward more autonomous vehicles, these dangers are only going to get worse. Consumer confidence, privacy, and brand reputation might all suffer if these issues are not addressed. Worse, client safety is jeopardised.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/automotive-cyber-security.png\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2913\"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The market for automotive cyber security is presently valued at $1.75 billion. By 2026, the worldwide &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;automotive cybersecurity industry&lt;/a&gt; is expected to rise from $2.0 billion to $5.3 billion. By 2028, the market for automotive cyber security is estimated to reach $7.89 billion.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;With the daily increase in the number of vehicles on the road and the rapid advancement of the technology involved, it is critical to establish a strong &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cybersecurity system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If this is not paid attention to, one can hack into the system and start a slew of fraudulent operations. By recognising the risk, correcting it, and protecting the computer&amp;#8217;s security system from future threats, an automotive cybersecurity system is an efficient and effective approach for dealing with cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The increased demand for an\neffective and efficient security system is due to the growing acceptance of\ninnovative technologies in the automotive industry. Rising cyber dangers in the\ntransportation and automobile industries will boost demand even more. The\nvehicle cyber security market will continue to grow and expand as intercity\ntransportation and logistics services improve. In addition, rising demand for\ncommercial and passenger automobiles equipped with innovative technologies, as\nwell as rising personal income, will expand market potential.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vehicle connectivity is rapidly\nexpanding, resulting in a plethora of new capabilities and appealing business\nmodels. Simultaneously, the threat of cyber-attacks on vehicle networks is\nincreasing. Such attacks endanger the vehicle&amp;#8217;s functioning safety and may\nresult in monetary loss.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In addition to long-established\ntechnologies like artificial intelligence (AI) and big data and analytics,\nnewer technologies like the internet of things (IoT) and blockchain have\nseveral uses in the automotive industry.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric Vehicle Cyber\nsecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Because technology is rapidly\nadvancing, there is an increasing need to concentrate on the cyber security of\nelectric vehicles. Owners and the EV industry should boost up their efforts to\nprotect vehicles and charging infrastructure from cyber-attacks, given the rush\nto migrate to electric cars and trucks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The spread of potentially vulnerable &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EV charging stations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; around the world offers a significant cyber threat as electric vehicles become a larger part of the market. If cybersecurity is not prioritised, these stations might become a hacker superhighway.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;There are a few key cybersecurity\nbest practises that serve as the first line of defence against hackers.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• It is critical to evaluate\nfirewall and router setups on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• Make a list of all the\ncomponents in EVCS and look for vulnerabilities on a granular level in each of\nthem.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• Public-facing web instances\npose a substantial threat to important sectors, yet security teams routinely\nignore them. As a result, the entire environment is more vulnerable to\ncyberattacks. It is critical to keep track of your assets&amp;#8217; exposure, especially\nin certain industries.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• Have a robust password policy\nin place.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• Limit access to assets based on\nthe employee&amp;#8217;s clearance level.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;• Employees and those working in\nvital industries must receive cybersecurity awareness training.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, electric vehicle\ncharging infrastructure is a device (or set of devices) that waits for another\ndevice to connect and begin communicating without the use of a third-party\nfirewall or other cybersecurity devices &amp;#8211; all these technologies must be built\ninto the charging station itself. EV charging stations/technologies are\nparticularly vulnerable to attacks due to their complexity and quick\nproliferation, as some security precautions may be disregarded. Hackers appear\nto have a lot of access to electric vehicle charging facilities.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The global effort to extend the\nuse of electric vehicles is picking up speed, and 2021 saw a boom in EV sales.\nElectric vehicle sales are at an all-time high as purchasers rush to switch\nfrom gasoline-powered vehicles to EVs due to rising fuel costs, which are\nexacerbated by global geopolitical tensions. With the growing demand for electric\nvehicles (EVs) around the world, malicious attackers will target the EV\nindustry to cause disorder among the citizens of a country and disrupt\nday-to-day operations of a metropolis.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charging infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;, like any other connected device, is subject to cyber-attacks. Nonetheless, the complexity and rapid evolution of technology and connected gadgets endangers this technology. Whether on the device itself or through a third-party app, they will require the same level of monitoring and protection to ensure that they do not open doors for hackers to pass through. As the number of electric vehicles on the road increases and more EV charging stations are built around the world, it is vital that we focus on sophisticated cybersecurity measures to keep drivers safe and safeguard the critical data in our vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Keeping a continual eye on both\nknown and unknown threats is the best method for cybersecurity professionals to\nprotect charging stations from intrusions. Utilities, for example, rely on\nIPKeys Cyber Partners&amp;#8217; developing VSOC (Vehicle Security Operations Centre)\nplatform. This programme provides for cybersecurity during the post-production\nphase. Protecting connected vehicles and the smart mobility ecosystem is\ncritical, as it allows companies to monitor their whole infrastructure and\nvehicles in real time, as well as detect cyber threats using\nautomotive-specific analytics.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity approaches and\nsolutions for commercial Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;For the commercial vehicle\ndomain, there are a range of cybersecurity techniques and solutions. Most\nsolutions appear to come from other disciplines, particularly the automobile\ndomain. However, due to the characteristics of the commercial vehicle area,\nsome adaptations will be required.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy Vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Improving the cybersecurity\ncharacteristics of commercial cars that are already on the road is difficult,\nif not impossible. To prevent the most likely attack scenario, either use a\nfleet management solution to connect vehicles with known vulnerabilities to the\nInternet and turn off all wireless interfaces or use a filter between all\nexternal communication interfaces and the vehicle&amp;#8217;s electronics network.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separation and Network\nArchitectures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Modern network topologies use\ngateways to divide networks and use firewalls and filters to separate network\nsegments. No network with external interfaces links directly to a\nsafety-critical network, such as the powertrain network, and all traffic is\nrouted through a gateway with a firewall first. There may be dedicated networks\nconnecting only two nodes, such as an ADAS controller and a camera.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The car industry is already\nmoving toward the next domain controller architecture, in which only a few\nsophisticated domain controllers, often connected by Ethernet, connect to basic\nelectronics components. The domain controller design follows the same network\nisolation paradigm for security reasons.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Board Communication\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;One of the most important\nsecurity goals is to secure on-board communication. Authentication is usually\nalways the essential security purpose; however, encryption is also interesting\nin a few circumstances. An adversary&amp;#8217;s ability to develop further is highly\nhampered by such authenticated on-board communication. For example, if an\nadversary successfully compromises a telematics unit or an OBD dongle, the\nattacker is only able to authenticate messages sent to components on a\npre-defined list but not to messages sent to any safety-critical component\nprovided the system is properly constructed.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform for Secure Computing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vehicle electronics necessitate a\nsafe computer platform. Secure boot protects integrity during start up,\nhypervisors or software containers with secure inter-process communication\nseparate software components, and a hardened kernel as well as memory\nprotection (e.g., address randomization) safeguard the kernel. There are also\nmechanisms for monitoring the computing platform&amp;#8217;s integrity, such as employing\na whitelist of binary files that are allowed to be executed.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anomaly Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Protecting a vehicle against\ncyber-attacks and data extraction is a top priority. A second objective is the\ncapacity to monitor the vehicle&amp;#8217;s network and computing platforms to identify\npotential breaches and improve cybersecurity over time. The output of on-board\nnetwork anomaly detection systems and ECU platform integrity monitors can be\nmerged, used for local anomaly detection (which may result in a basic local\nreaction), and then sent via telematics to a Security Operations Centre (SOC),\nwhich then runs analytics over all data to find anomaly patterns in the big\npicture. This information is then given to automobile manufacturers and\nsuppliers, who examine it and begin the incident response process.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centre for Security Operations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The network anomaly detection\nsystems and ECU platform integrity monitors of vehicles send reports to the\nsecurity operations centre (SOC). The SOC then takes these reports, analyses\nthem, and looks for connections between the occurrences that have been\nrecorded. Human analysts investigate facts to determine whether filtered\noccurrences are related to cybersecurity incidents, other abnormalities, or\nfalse alarms, using automated algorithms. The fundamental system can be\nrectified, and software can be updated via firmware over-the-air procedure\nafter a genuine cybersecurity event is proven and the mechanisms are\nunderstood. Naturally, the more reports from various vehicles that a SOC\nreceives, the more successful it becomes.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over-the-Air Firmware Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;FOTA (firmware over-the-air) is a\nmethod of updating functionality and fixing faults, some of which may be\nsecurity-related. The use of FOTA has the potential to reduce recalls. However,\nthere are countless cases of FOTA systems being hacked in the PC network\nenvironment. Flame malware, for example, exploited several cryptographic flaws\nbefore hijacking the Windows update mechanism and distributing malware.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Software updates are usually\nprotected by digitally certifying the revised firmware, so that an ECU will\nonly update with it if the verification is successful. The OEM and/or supplier\nsign the code, ideally on a secure computer that is offline and not easily\naccessible. A secure communication connection between the cloud and the car,\nsuch as the widely used transport layer security (TLS), can further improve\nsecurity. The Uptane framework for safe FOTA strengthens security and divides\nduties of the relevant entities, allowing the complete system to recover even\nif a single server is compromised.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-commercial-vehicles-can-get-optimum-cybersecurity/\"&gt;How Commercial Vehicles can get optimum Cybersecurity?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-commercial-vehicles-can-get-optimum-cybersecurity/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Electric Vehicle Charging Station","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/electric-vehicle-charging-station/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/electric-vehicle-charging-station/#respond","pubDate":"Tue, 21 Jun 2022 21:15:09 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"EV charging station"},{"#cdata-section":"EV"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging companies"},{"#cdata-section":"ev charging station business"},{"#cdata-section":"Top EV charging companies"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2916"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;USE Cases Use Case #1: Charging at home Even though the public charging stations offer the benefits of no installment cost, they come with some potential drawbacks such as long wait times, inconvenience caused to locate charging stations in the vicinity, and battery damage due to level 3 high charging output power. Residential chargers are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/electric-vehicle-charging-station/\"&gt;Electric Vehicle Charging Station&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USE Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #1:&lt;/strong&gt;\n&lt;strong&gt;Charging at home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Even though the public charging stations offer the benefits of no installment cost, they come with some potential drawbacks such as long wait times, inconvenience caused to &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;locate charging stations&lt;/a&gt; in the vicinity, and battery damage due to level 3 high charging output power.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Residential chargers are usually level 2 charging stations and deliver output power between 3.7 – 22kW through either phase 1 or phase 3 of the house.  The level 2 charging at home, most of the cars take overnight to charge, however, this speed of charging also depends on the phase to which the charger is connected and the conversion rate of the AC to DC power converter of the EV. These chargers are an economically viable option as they consume electricity from the residential energy power grid or through solar energy modules at home. Several &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charger manufacturers&lt;/a&gt; have made compatible chargers such that they can easily charge other EV models and help through intelligent software and mobile applications.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #2:&lt;/strong&gt;\n&lt;strong&gt;Wireless Charging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Even with ongoing electric vehicle growth, there are several drawbacks to the traditional &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;wired charging stations&lt;/a&gt;. For instance, connectors and charging cables can wear down over a period of time, reducing the charging efficiency. Next, the need for a unified charging cable has been constantly pointed out by EV users. Such features limit the overall charging capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;Wireless charging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; offers enormous benefits over traditional wired charging stations. There are different types of wireless charging technologies available which include, inductive wireless charging, resonant inductive coupling, capacitive wireless charging, microwaves, etc. By using these technologies, a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;wireless charging system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is installed where vehicles remain stationary such as in parking lots. In the near future, this wireless charging system can be embedded into the roads as well, such that it will become a commercially viable option and vehicles will be charged continuously without downtime.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #3:&lt;/strong&gt;\n&lt;strong&gt;Public Charging Stations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles using public charging stations only bear the usage costs and are saved from paying the huge installment costs. The public charging stations usually use the level 2 chargers such that they are compatible with all types of vehicles. Such &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;charging stations&lt;/a&gt; are maintained by the manufacturers and are managed by management software. These systems are easy to use for the consumer with their simple plug-and-play interface. With public charging available at more locations, the USAge of electric vehicles is set to become mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #4: DC&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Fast Charging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The number of electric vehicles is growing\nsubstantially. However, downtime for charging is the major pullback for the\nwider adoption of the technology. Several automakers offer the swappable\nbattery option to consumers, but this option is not suitable for long-term\nusage, and other levels 1 and level 2 charging options are time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The DC fast charging technology offers higher charging rates which chargers the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV battery&lt;/a&gt; much faster than the conventional charging options available. These offer a much faster charging experience within a shorter time period and the output power ranges usually from 50- 350kW. The major benefit of using a DC fast charging charger is that once it charges the vehicle’s battery up to 80% it automatically slows down the charging rate, thereby reducing the overcharging of the battery and thus maintaining the life of the EV battery. There are currently rising thermal issues over DC fast charging to which several measures to handle the battery life are underway.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/electric-vehicle-charging-station/\"&gt;Electric Vehicle Charging Station&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/electric-vehicle-charging-station/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"How fast are some of the best EV charging stations","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-fast-are-some-of-the-best-ev-charging-stations/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-fast-are-some-of-the-best-ev-charging-stations/#respond","pubDate":"Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:40:47 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"360Quadrants"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging station"},{"#cdata-section":"charging infrastructure"},{"#cdata-section":"charging station business"},{"#cdata-section":"electric charging cost"},{"#cdata-section":"EV charging companies"},{"#cdata-section":"ev charging station business"},{"#cdata-section":"wireless electric vehicle charger"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2906"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles are rapidly gaining huge momentum in the ongoing scenario of rising CO2 emissions and scarce fossil fuel resources. It is due to the ongoing research and development of fast charging solutions; users find electric vehicles as the most viable option. The electric vehicle (EV) charging systems are categorized as Level 1, Level 2, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-fast-are-some-of-the-best-ev-charging-stations/\"&gt;How fast are some of the best EV charging stations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles are rapidly gaining huge momentum in the ongoing scenario of rising CO2 emissions and scarce fossil fuel resources. It is due to the ongoing research and development of fast charging solutions; users find electric vehicles as the most viable option. The electric vehicle (EV) charging systems are categorized as Level 1, Level 2, and Level 3 based on the output power delivered. Level 3 chargers are the real game-changer of electromobility. These level 3 chargers are designed to offer power ranging from 150 kW to 400 kW and more and are operated by private networks which directly connect the charging station to the electricity grid. Some of the prominent players active in the electric vehicle charging station include ABB, Electrify America, Voltempo, EVgo, ChargePoint, and others. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;After the global pandemic, the year 2020\nwitnessed a major boom in the adoption of electric vehicles. Cars such as Tesla\nModel 3, ID.3 Volkswagen, Kia EV6, Porsche Taycan, Hyundai Ioniq 5etc. were\nseen to drive the fast-charging market. These cars are based on the concept of DC\nfast charging and the batteries installed in these cars are capable of charging\nfrom 10 percent to 80 percent in less than 30 minutes when connected to a 350-kW\ncharging line. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Currently, automakers are collaborating with other giant groups in order to expand ultra-rapid &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;charging infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; across geographies. Hyundai for instance has collaborated with huge South Korean giant Lotte Group and KB Asset Management. Together the companies have targeted to add 5,000 ultra-fast chargers (UFC) by the year 2025. This involves leasing high-power charging stations to private operators. Another company Porsche has deployed 35 ultra-fast charging stations in partnership with Iberdrola in Southern Europe. The charging station has a capacity of up to 400 kW, capable of recharging car batteries in less than five minutes. Such initiatives by automakers will boost the electric vehicle mobility market.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;Types of EV charging at stations in North America &lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The North American market is witnessing an\noverwhelming surge in electric mobility due to Level 2 and fast charging\nsolutions, which allow EV users to charge vehicles with ease in their homes.\nWhile the Level 1 chargers constitute about 2% of the total EV charger across\nthe US, Level 2 chargers comprise a majority of 80% of charging systems, mainly\ndue to the higher power rating as compared to the Level 1. It was observed that\nby 2021, 15% of the public EVSE port in the US were DC fast chargers. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Canadian market specifically is also pursuing the EVCS market potentially well. It has a huge deployment of the Level 2, and an increasing growth was observed in the adoption of DC fast chargers. Tesla is one of the most prominent EVCS vendors in Canada. Other prominent companies include ChargePoint, FLO, EcoCharge, Electrify Canada, Petro-Canada, Greenlots, and SWTCH Energy among others. These companies are expanding their infrastructure and have made several advancements in the roaming network agreements and application interfacing, therefore attracting a huge customer base.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/North-America-EV-Charging-Station.png\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2907\"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt; &lt;em&gt;Figure1: Electric Vehicle Charging Stations (Level 2 and DC Fast Charging) Across North America&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Source: Alternative Fuels Data Center (&lt;a href=\"https://afdc.energy.gov/fuels/electricity_locations.html#/find/nearest?fuel=ELEC\"&gt;https://afdc.energy.gov/fuels/electricity_locations.html#/find/nearest?fuel=ELEC&lt;/a&gt;\n)&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;With more and more DC fast charging\nsolutions are being deployed across North America, the major contributor being\nthe US. It is anticipated that DC fast chargers will further accelerate EV\nadoption across the US and Canada. Companies like Electrify America,\nChargePoint, Blink, Tesla, Volta, and EVgo are some of the prominent vendors of\nultra-fast charging systems in the North American market. These companies have\ndeployed numerous fast-charging stations across America thereby easing\ninterstate transportation through highways. Automakers like General Motors and\nPorsche are partnering with several vendors to expand the production of their\nlatest EV models which are compatible and give high performance to the user\nwhen the electric vehicle is charged using fast charging systems. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;ABB another prominent &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;electric vehicle charging station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; manufacturer is seen to be expanding its footprint in the North American market by deploying ABB’s Terra 53 DC charging stations. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;EV Charging Station Business Opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;electric vehicle charging business&lt;/a&gt; heavily relies on uniformity across the EV charging station standards and equipment. EVCS ecosystem consists of participants such as Charge Point Operators, Energy companies, and Automotive OEMs. In order to increase the adoption of EV technology, CPOs are focusing on offering DC fast charging systems that could rapidly charge the EV batteries within minutes. The Energy companies on the other hand are offering EV fast charging at their existing gas stations by adding the appropriate infrastructure. Further, the Automakers are also considering the EVCS business as a standalone opportunity to expand their business by both entering the new market and expanding their existing EV sales. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charging stations&lt;/a&gt; come with an end-to-end customized solution offering. The additional support of backend power infrastructure, compatibility for different EV charging standards, and various software are now easing the usage of electric charging systems. Several places such as public malls, restaurants, workplaces, and housing societies are now having charging stations thereby providing more convenient options to charge their vehicle on the go. China, the US, and Germany are investing heavily in the research and development of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station\"&gt;EV charging infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It is expected that the electric vehicle\nwill constitute about 30% of the total vehicles by 2025, and this trend will\nkeep on increasing majorly because of the efforts taken by both automakers and\nusers to reduce the CO2 emissions. This ultimately creates the need for\nhigh-power and reliable charging stations for a mass number of users. EV users\nare now leveraging the intelligent options used by the CPOs. These intelligent\nfeatures include dynamic power allocation, highway transit charging, locating\nthe charging stations, battery conditions, etc., further accelerating the EVCS\nmarket.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It can be expected that with several options of AC and DC chargers for home and public charging stations and a wide geographic footprint, companies such as ABB, Tesla, &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/automotive/electric-vehicle-charging-station/chargepoint-inc\"&gt;ChargePoint&lt;/a&gt; will dominate the electric vehicle charging station market. Even though the ultra-fast charging system looks attractive for the electric vehicle market, it might not find major user adoption due to its high premium prices, thereby limiting the wider adoption of the technology. With more moderately priced charging systems, the CPOs can expect a major turn-on in the establishment of the fast-charging technology.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;h2&gt;The ultra-fast charging scenario&lt;/h2&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;ABB has been dominating the electric\nvehicle charging station market with its Terra HP Generation III. Other\ncomparable systems such as Siemens’ SICHARGE D and Pantograph (for buses and\ntrucks), EV Box’s Utraoniq, Hypernova from WallBox, Electrify America’s DC Fast\nChargers and others have proven to be equally good when it comes to offering a\nfast-charging system ranging from 300 kW to 350 kW in 15 minutes. However, what\nsets apart the ABB is the wide range of charging and electrification solutions\nfor electric cars, hybrid buses, trucks, vans, ships, and railways and the\noutput power of 360 kW. ABB’s 3rd generation charger has a wide range of output\nvoltage ranging from 150 to 920 VDC and charges one EV at 350 kW or two\nelectric vehicles simultaneously at 175 kW. However, the only setback is the 350\nkW or 175 kW (for two EVs) charging line is applicable only to the version with\ntwo CCS connections.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In 2022, &lt;strong&gt;Voltempo&lt;/strong&gt; a leading technology developer of electric automakers launched its &lt;strong&gt;HyperCharging&lt;/strong&gt;. As per the company, the HyperCharging system can deliver 1,000kW of power which is around 2.8 times more than the power delivered by the other comparable charging stations. This solution is able to charge the compatible electric vehicle within 6 minutes and has a unique capability of charging 24 vehicles simultaneously. Through its demonstration, the charging system looks promising for now and Voltempo has further stated that it will be able to build a charging system with the efficiency that could match a similar time that it takes to refuel a conventional, petrol-driven vehicle. Another prominent company, &lt;strong&gt;Iberdrola&lt;/strong&gt; has launched an ultra-fast charging hub for electric vehicles having a capacity of up to 400 kW and is capable of recharging car batteries in less than five minutes and can charge up to 16 vehicles simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;figure class=\"wp-block-image\"&gt;&lt;img src=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Analysis-of-the-Electric-Vehicle-Charging-System.png\" alt=\"\" class=\"wp-image-2908\"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Analysis of the Electric Vehicle Charging System based on power and charging time taken&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Even though, with such high-power charging\ntechnologies in place, how much the EV users will be able to leverage the\nfast-charging technology will entirely depend on the vehicle since not all\ntypes of EV batteries are designed to handle such high-power ratings. However,\nit can be predicted that once the automakers develop the compatible EV\nbatteries and Voltempo expands its geographic presence with the 1000 kW power\ntechnology, a major transformation across the electric mobility market is bound\nto take place.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-fast-are-some-of-the-best-ev-charging-stations/\"&gt;How fast are some of the best EV charging stations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/how-fast-are-some-of-the-best-ev-charging-stations/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Cybersecurity Software","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/cybersecurity-software/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/cybersecurity-software/#respond","pubDate":"Mon, 20 Jun 2022 12:24:28 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity software"},{"#cdata-section":"Network security"},{"#cdata-section":"Network security software"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2904"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;USE Cases Use Case #1: Network Security The underlying network architecture of an organization consists of hardware and software systems that are highly susceptible to data breaches, intrusions, and other cyber-attacks. Further, the advent of the 4G, 5G, and a more cloud-centric working structure have made organizations more vulnerable to cyber-attacks. Therefore, features like network [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/cybersecurity-software/\"&gt;Cybersecurity Software&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USE Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #1: Network Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The underlying network architecture of an organization\nconsists of hardware and software systems that are highly susceptible to data\nbreaches, intrusions, and other cyber-attacks. Further, the advent of the 4G,\n5G, and a more cloud-centric working structure have made organizations more\nvulnerable to cyber-attacks. Therefore, features like network security become\nan essential aspect to protect the electronic network infrastructure of an\norganization from unauthorized access, misuse, or malfunctioning of the entire system.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;Network\nsecurity&lt;/a&gt; helps in identifying such malicious activities by deploying the\nproper security architecture. This security architecture provides visibility\nacross the network and takes measures to prevent potential threats. &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;Network\nsecurity tools&lt;/a&gt; such as firewalls, remote access VPN, zero-trust network\naccess, email security, etc. secure the networks, clouds, and other\ninfrastructure against the evolving vulnerabilities in the network.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #2: Identity Access and Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Identity Access and Management are an important part of any enterprise.\nAs businesses are shifting toward a remote working model, data security becomes\ncritical. Such rapid transformation across organizations have pushed the\ncompanies to incorporate proper identity and access management frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The identity access and management are automated frameworks that\nmanage the digital identities and users’ access to company resources both on\nthe premises and remotely. It also includes the management of technologies,\nnetworks, and systems used for data processing. Now instead of conventional\npassword login systems, robust authentication techniques like multifactor\nauthentication, risk-based authentication, and zero-trust are in place to\ncombat the growing cyber-attacks. &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Case #3: Threat Intelligence&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In the world of &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity software&lt;/a&gt;, organizations are continuously under the threat of cyber-attacks. Cyber attackers gain access to the data through social engineering techniques or phishing emails, causing heavy security vulnerabilities. Such evolving cyber threat landscape puts immense pressure on the organizations to inculcate practices to detect and monitor the malicious activities in advance.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Threat intelligence constantly gathers information on\nemerging and existing cyber threats from various sources. It efficiently\nanalyzes the data and provides insightful feeds to outmaneuver the threat\nactors or agents. By using proactive monitoring techniques such as threat\nintelligence organizations can ensure real-time security and be well informed\nabout the potential advanced persistent threats, thereby preventing any data\ncompromise.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/cybersecurity-software/\"&gt;Cybersecurity Software&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/cybersecurity-software/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"The 12 Hottest AI Security Companies You Need to Know","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/the-12-hottest-ai-security-companies-you-need-to-know/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/the-12-hottest-ai-security-companies-you-need-to-know/#respond","pubDate":"Fri, 20 May 2022 08:41:14 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Top cybersecurity companies"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2830"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;When it comes to cybersecurity, artificial intelligence is a double-edged sword, with defenders using it to respond to and predict threats and attackers using it to execute even more refined attacks. For example, AI systems can send &amp;#8216;spear phishing&amp;#8217; tweets (tailored tweets sent to selected individuals to fool them into disclosing critical information) six times [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/the-12-hottest-ai-security-companies-you-need-to-know/\"&gt;The 12 Hottest AI Security Companies You Need to Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;When it comes to\ncybersecurity, artificial intelligence is a double-edged sword, with defenders using\nit to respond to and predict threats and attackers using it to execute even\nmore refined attacks. For example, AI systems can send &amp;#8216;spear phishing&amp;#8217; tweets\n(tailored tweets sent to selected individuals to fool them into disclosing\ncritical information) six times faster and twice as effectively as a human.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;AI has become a\nmajor tool in stopping cyberattacks as the attack surface has become larger and\nattacks have become more sophisticated. Organizations are turning to artificial\nintelligence because cyber analysts are finding it increasingly difficult to\nadequately monitor current levels of data volume, velocity, and variety across\nfirewalls.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Here is a look\nat what 12 hot AI security companies is up to, from finding qualities that\nseveral threats share to taking on well-camouflaged malware to advising\ncorporations on how to deploy security resources.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Awake\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Awake Security\nmixes artificial intelligence with human knowledge to seek for insider and\nexternal attacker behaviours autonomously. The NDR provider, which is now part\nof Arista, provides triage, digital forensics, and incident response\ncapabilities across campus, data centre, Internet of Things, operational\ntechnology, and cloud networks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Awake analyses\nbillions of network interactions to discover, profile, and classify every\ndevice, user, and application on any network automatically. Awake then analyses\ncomplicated adversarial behaviour and detects threats by connecting the dots\nacross entities, time, protocols, and attack stages using a multi-dimensional\nensemble machine learning approach.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Awake&amp;#8217;s\nsituational awareness solution detects, profiles, and monitors devices, users,\nand applications using AI-based fingerprinting, while its high-fidelity threat\nhunting offering uncovers complex threats with low false positives and\nnegatives. Awake&amp;#8217;s autonomous security system automates tasks such as triage,\ninvestigation, and reaction.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. BlackBerry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;BlackBerry\nProtect is an artificial intelligence-based endpoint security software that\nprotects against advanced cyberthreats by blocking breaches and adding\ncontrols. This is accomplished without the need for user or administrator\nintervention, a cloud connection, signatures, heuristics, or sandboxes.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Artificial\nintelligence detects and blocks attacks before they can take place, preventing\nBlackBerry consumers from visiting spoofing pages that seem like real websites.\nBlackBerry&amp;#8217;s resilient AI model stops zero-day payloads from running, and the\ncompany&amp;#8217;s field-proven AI inspects any programme attempting to run on an\nendpoint before it runs.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;BlackBerry\nProtect also uses artificial intelligence to recognise and block dangerous\nURLs, including those that contain phishing components. According to\nBlackBerry, the company&amp;#8217;s AI-driven security endpoint offering provides\nproactive protection, detection, and response, as well as integrated mobile\nthreat defence, continuous authentication, and adaptive risk scoring.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Balbix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Balbix&amp;#8217;s\nBreachControl technology employs artificial intelligence to provide continuous\nrisk projections, risk-based vulnerability management, and proactive breach\ncontrol. The platform assists &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\ncompanies&lt;/a&gt;’ teams in being more efficient and effective at the myriad tasks\nrequired to maintain a strong security posture, such as keeping systems patched\nand combating ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;BreachControl\nhas a thorough awareness of the setup and usage information for an\norganization&amp;#8217;s extended enterprise inventory, as well as the business\ncriticality of each asset and user. Balbix is quite familiar with the numerous\nsecurity solutions and methods that &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;top cybersecurity\ncompanies&lt;/a&gt; use as part of their overall breach risk reduction strategy.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Balbix also\nprovides prescriptive advice on how businesses can effectively setup and\nupgrade their security policies and processes to maximise cyber-resilience\nwhile minimising business disruption. Users, security operations, CISO,\nauditors, CIO, CEO, and board members will benefit from the company&amp;#8217;s\nvisualisations and reports, which explain calculations and provide\nrecommendations.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Blue\nHexagon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Blue Hexagon&amp;#8217;s\ndeep learning models examine millions of attributes in payloads, protocols, and\nheaders in less than a second to identify threats. The business claims that\ntheir cloud security and network detection and response (NDR) solution use deep\nlearning-based artificial intelligence to detect a wide range of known and\nundiscovered file-based and protocol-based threats.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Blue Hexagon\nclaims that by using deep learning to scan all headers and payloads in real\ntime, it can detect cloud misconfigurations and defend cloud assets without the\nneed to deploy and manage agents. When applied to network traffic, Blue Hexagon\ncan make intelligent choices about whether the traffic is malicious, allowing\nfor near-real-time response.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cloud\nconfigurations, network traffic, cloud storage activity, and the complete\nthreat kill chain can all be analysed in real time using the company&amp;#8217;s technologies.\nIts agentless artificial intelligence is ready to use right now, requiring no\nre-architecting, baselining, signatures, or sandboxing. Blue Hexagon claims\nthat its system can protect against zero-day exploits, ransomware, lateral\nmovement, C2, and exfiltration.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Callsign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Callsign uses\nArtificial Intelligence and Machine Learning to authenticate a person&amp;#8217;s\nidentity based on swipes on a touchscreen, keystrokes on a keyboard, locations\nvisited, and other behaviours. The company&amp;#8217;s hallmark platform, intelligence-driven\nauthentication, combines multi-factor authentication with fraud analytics\npowered by deep learning technology to tackle everything from identity fraud to\nSMS phishing.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Intelligence\nEngine from Callsign is a secure and compliant solution for any situation. It\nanalyses hundreds of data points in real time from devices, locations,\nbehaviours, and third-party systems. It warmly welcomes legitimate users while\nleaving bad actors out in the cold, protecting you from malware, bots, sophisticated\nscams, and telecom fraud.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Darktrace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Across email and\ncloud services, industrial equipment, and the corporate network, the Darktrace\nImmune System can detect what is harmful or malicious in real time. It enables\nsecurity teams to move away from a plethora of segregated point solutions with\nlimited visibility in favour of a single AI &amp;#8220;brain&amp;#8221; that benefits\nfrom enterprise-wide context and leaves attackers with nowhere to hide.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Darktrace&amp;#8217;s\nEnterprise Immune System learns normal &amp;#8216;patterns of life&amp;#8217; to identify\nunforeseen cyber-threats while providing total visibility across the\nenterprise, from cloud and collaboration tools to endpoints and the corporate\nnetwork. And Cyber AI Analyst combines various security occurrences into a\nsingle security incident and presents its results in a clear,\neasy-to-understand narrative.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile,\nAntigena Network protects key data and operations autonomously around the\nclock, surgically interrupting threats across cloud services, IoT, and the\ncorporate network. Antigena Email, on the other hand, leverages Darktrace&amp;#8217;s\ncore artificial intelligence to stop the most complex email threats, and it\nworks for everyone from small charity to large enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Fortinet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Fortinet&amp;#8217;s\nFortiAI is designed to help SOC teams with limited resources defend against\nadvanced persistent threats by detecting, classifying, and responding to\nmalware, including well-hidden threats. FortiAI uses deep learning technology\nto help enterprises respond to many types of synthetic AI and non-AI-based\nthreats in an automated manner.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The Virtual\nSecurity Analyst from FortiAI complements a company&amp;#8217;s Security Operations\n(SecOps) by simulating a professional Security Analyst to analyse threats and\ndetect malware outbreaks. Fortinet&amp;#8217;s artificial intelligence is capable of\nlearning new features and can apply over six million malware features to obtain\nsub-second judgements.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;By analysing an\norganization&amp;#8217;s specific traffic and adjusting to freshly disguised threats, the\nproduct&amp;#8217;s on-premises learning decreases false positives. FortiAI analyses\nzero-day threats, including fileless threats, and categorises them into more\nthan twenty malware attack scenarios, which it uses in conjunction with\nFortiGate firewalls to automatically quarantine attacks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software/ibm-corporation\"&gt;IBM Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;With IBM\nSecurity&amp;#8217;s QRadar Advisor, organisations can receive complete threat coverage,\nprioritise warnings, and speed up investigations using artificial intelligence.\nAnalysts can validate the threat, see how the attack has occurred and is\ndeveloping, and discover what techniques are still possible by looking at the\nconfidence level for each attack development.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;QRadar Advisor\nfrom IBM Security uses cognitive reasoning to determine the most likely danger\nand connect threat items such as malware files, suspicious IP addresses, and\nrogue entities to draw relationships between them. External unstructured data,\nsuch as threat intelligence feeds, websites, and forums, are automatically\napplied using Watson for Cyber Security.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;IBM&amp;#8217;s QRadar\nAdvisor analyses the local environment and recommends which fresh\ninvestigations should be escalated to help the analyst drive faster and more\ndecisive escalations. QRadar Advisor can swiftly identify the most dangerous\ninvestigations, run many investigations at the same time, and sort and filter\nthe data to see where businesses should focus their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&amp;nbsp;Securiti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The artificial\nintelligence driven PrivacyOps technology from Securiti enables privacy by\ndesign by continuously scanning and monitoring data for non-compliance with\nsubject rights, data residency, and security measures. While processing\npersonal data, classification, risk monitoring, and policy-based warnings and\nremediation provide end-to-end security.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of\nsensitive data items can be discovered, classified, and labelled in multicloud\nand self-managed structured and unstructured data systems at petabyte scale\nusing the company&amp;#8217;s technology. Securiti can find and visualise sensitive data\npieces in an organization&amp;#8217;s structured and unstructured data systems, as well as\nsynchronise them with third-party data catalogues to populate metadata.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;With a\nprecise analysis of risk factors such as specific data items, data locations,\nand user residencies, Securiti can also detect data risk hotspots in an\norganization&amp;#8217;s environment. The company tracks the security posture of an\norganization&amp;#8217;s cloud assets, implements policies to mitigate security risks,\nand prioritises and mitigates risk in assets that contain sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Sentry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Sentry is a\nvideo analytics solution for public safety and physical security that uses\nartificial intelligence. The company&amp;#8217;s security-specialized neural network\nanalyses context to help security professionals do their jobs more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The company uses\ninnovative artificial intelligence technology to create unique algorithms for\nsecurity use cases and provides enhanced identity management via single sign-on\nand interaction with Enterprise Mobility Management providers.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Sentry works in\ntandem with existing security systems to provide real-time warnings for key\noccurrences, removing the need for ongoing monitoring. Custom reports give\nbusinesses with relevant data, and the company provides corporations with\ncamera status and system health analytics.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Vectra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vectra use\nartificial intelligence to improve detection and response over time, reducing\nfalse positives and allowing enterprises to focus on real threats. The\ncompany&amp;#8217;s automated threat detection and response platform combines human\nknowledge with data science and machine learning approaches to provide a\ncontinuous cycle of threat intelligence based on cutting-edge research and\nlearning models.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;The organisation\ncan recognise the commonalities across threats, identify what is normal and\nabnormal in the local network, and link disparate occurrences to show the\nbigger assault story. Vectra begins by identifying and analysing as many\nthreats as possible to determine what they have in common, which necessitates a\nlarge-scale examination of malicious traffic as well as the skill to determine\nwhat is genuinely important.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vectra&amp;#8217;s local\nlearning models check for signs of an attacker investigating the network,\nevaluating hosts for attack, or exploiting stolen credentials, among other\nthings. The company&amp;#8217;s model follows events throughout the cyberattack kill\nchain, tying them to individual hosts that exhibit threat characteristics and\nincorporating them into a real-time risk score.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Vade\nSecure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vade Secure is a\nleading email defence company that uses artificial intelligence and machine\nlearning to defend mailboxes from attacks such as spear phishing, ransomware,\nand malware. Vade will use the funds to continue investing in its AI-based\nthreat detection engine and expand its leadership in email security for ISPs.\nVade&amp;#8217;s email security solutions are chosen by ISPs, MSPs, and SMBs to safeguard\ntheir users and organisations against advanced cybersecurity threats.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Their AI-based email security solutions are meant to identify the undetectable, whether they are safeguarding consumers through leading ISPs or businesses through MSP partners. Vade&amp;#8217;s multi-layered analysis uses threat knowledge from one billion secured mailboxes to combine a heuristic methodology with behavioural analysis technology. With patented Machine Learning and Deep Learning technologies that predict, block, and remediate sophisticated threats, the company&amp;#8217;s behavioural approach to threat detection goes beyond signature and reputation-based scanning.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read\nmore on cybersecurity blogs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity Companies in North America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/\"&gt;Top 10 Best Cybersecurity Companies in the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/the-12-hottest-ai-security-companies-you-need-to-know/\"&gt;The 12 Hottest AI Security Companies You Need to Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/the-12-hottest-ai-security-companies-you-need-to-know/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Top 16 Startups developing AI for Cyber Security","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-16-startups-developing-ai-for-cyber-security/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-16-startups-developing-ai-for-cyber-security/#respond","pubDate":"Thu, 19 May 2022 06:53:00 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity software"},{"#cdata-section":"cybersecurity vendor"},{"#cdata-section":"Top cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Top cybersecurity vendor"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2834"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;1. Appthority Nation: USA Financing: $25.3M Mobile threat intelligence that is precise and actionable to improve your mobile and entire enterprise security. 2. CrowdStrike Nation: USA Financing: $481M Through cloud-based endpoint protection, CrowdStrike is the market leader in next-generation endpoint protection, threat intelligence, and incident response. 3. Cybereason Nation: USA Financing: $388.6M EDR, NGAV, anti-ransomware, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-16-startups-developing-ai-for-cyber-security/\"&gt;Top 16 Startups developing AI for Cyber Security&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Appthority&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$25.3M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Mobile threat\nintelligence that is precise and actionable to improve your mobile and entire\nenterprise security.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. CrowdStrike&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing: $481M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Through\ncloud-based endpoint protection, CrowdStrike is the market leader in\nnext-generation endpoint protection, threat intelligence, and incident\nresponse.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Cybereason&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$388.6M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;EDR, NGAV,\nanti-ransomware, fileless malware protection, and managed services powered by a\nproprietary AI hunting engine round out next-generation endpoint security.\nCybereason use machine learning to boost the number of endpoints a single\nanalyst can control across a distributed network.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. CashShield&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation:\nSingapore &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$25.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;CashShield is a\nrisk management organisation that assists businesses in reducing the risk of\nfraudulent payments and hostile accounts. CashShield&amp;#8217;s algorithm is\nself-teaching in real time, thus no data scientist or fraud analyst is\nrequired.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Darktrace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: UK &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$179.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Darktrace is the\nworld&amp;#8217;s premier cyber security machine learning business.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Deep\nInstinct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: Israel &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$92.1M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Deep Instinct is\none of the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;top\ncybersecurity companies&lt;/a&gt; that use deep learning to provide unrivalled\nzero-day attack defence.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Dtex\nSystems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$57.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Dtex Systems\nuses user behaviour intelligence to assist businesses in detecting &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\ncompanies’&lt;/a&gt; threats while maintaining their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$111.4M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Endgame&amp;#8217;s\nendpoint security software safeguards data around the world from sophisticated\nthreats.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Insight\nEngines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$15.8M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Natural Language\nProcessing (NLP) technology from Insight Engines allows you to query your\nmachine data in &amp;#8220;plain English,&amp;#8221; reducing the need to learn and\nutilise sophisticated, proprietary query languages.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Obsidian\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing: $9.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Obsidian\nSecurity transforms how businesses employ data science and security technology\nto fight cyber threats in hybrid cloud settings.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. PerimeterX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$34.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;PerimeterX\nprotects your website from web scraping, scalping, account takeover, ad fraud,\nclick fraud, carding, and other bot threats using machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. SentinelOne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$696.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is\nan AI-based endpoint protection solution that successfully blocks, detects, and\nresponds to assaults from all primary vectors.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Shape\nSecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing: $183M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Shape Security offers best-in-class &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity vendor&lt;/a&gt; to safeguard your business against automated web and mobile app attacks. Its artificial intelligence designed to answer one question: is this a real user?&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Tessian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: UK &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$123.7M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Tessian, the\ncreators of Human Layer Security, allows people to do their best job without\nhaving to worry about security.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. Traceable\nAI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing: $80M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Traceable AI\nprovides machine learning-based services to protect APIs from hackers.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16. Vectra AI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Nation: USA &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Financing:\n$222.5M&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Vectra allows businesses to detect, and halt cyberattacks in real time across cloud, data centre, corporate, and IoT networks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on cybersecurity blogs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-cybersecurity-software-2022/\"&gt;Top 10 Cybersecurity Companies Software 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-vendors/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity vendors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-16-startups-developing-ai-for-cyber-security/\"&gt;Top 16 Startups developing AI for Cyber Security&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-16-startups-developing-ai-for-cyber-security/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Top 10 Best Cybersecurity Companies in the World","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/#respond","pubDate":"Wed, 18 May 2022 07:07:40 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity vendors"},{"#cdata-section":"Top cybersecurity companies"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/?p=2831"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;To maintain the internet era orderly and safe for consumers, the necessity for cybersecurity has grown. Data, information, and entire enterprises are protected by cybersecurity solutions from cyber thieves, fraudsters, and dangerous hackers. The top cybersecurity companies available for hire now are listed below. These businesses may be able to assist you in protecting your [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/\"&gt;Top 10 Best Cybersecurity Companies in the World&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;To maintain the\ninternet era orderly and safe for consumers, the necessity for cybersecurity\nhas grown. Data, information, and entire enterprises are protected by\ncybersecurity solutions from cyber thieves, fraudsters, and dangerous hackers. The\n&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;top\ncybersecurity companies&lt;/a&gt; available for hire now are listed below. These\nbusinesses may be able to assist you in protecting your company&amp;#8217;s networks and\nsystems.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;World’s Top 10 Best\nCybersecurity Companies in the Market: By Revenue &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cisco Systems, Inc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Corporation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Palo Alto Networks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;IBM&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McAfee&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Oracle Corporation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Juniper Networks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fortinet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Synopsys&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;CyberArk&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Cisco\nSystems Inc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$49.3 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cisco Systems is\nan American multinational technology business that develops and sells network\nand telecommunications hardware, as well as other innovative goods. Domain\nsecurity, Internet of Things, and energy-related services are among the\ncompany&amp;#8217;s specialties. Cisco cybersecurity solutions are tailored for small and\nmedium-sized businesses, with a high detection rate of malware, exploits, and\nevasions, and the ability to identify 100% of attacks in under five minutes.\nCisco Start is a modular security suite that protects the cloud, networks, and\nendpoints. Cisco Umbrella, for example, is a cloud-based security solution that\nserves as a first line of defence against malware and other cyber threats. It\nmakes use of the Internet&amp;#8217;s interface to eliminate dangers before establishing\na secure connection. Small and medium businesses can benefit from Cisco Meraki\nMX Security Appliances&amp;#8217; Unified Threat Management (UTM) solution. Before,\nduring, and after a cyberattack, AMP Solutions defends businesses and\norganisations.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Microsoft\nCorporation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue US$143.02\nBillion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is an\nAmerican technology corporation that offers a comprehensive set of security,\nidentity, and cybersecurity services. The services encompass strategy,\nplanning, implementation, and support for a wide range of Security and Identity\nservices. These services are designed to help businesses implement security\nsolutions that align with their objectives. Microsoft Security Risk Assessment\n(MSRA) was created to assist businesses in overcoming problems and assessing\nthe efficacy of security strategies deployed through a thorough review of the\ndefence-in-depth concept, which is the use of layered defences.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Palo\nAlto Networks &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$3.4 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto Networks, Inc. is one of the renowned &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity vendors&lt;/a&gt; situated in the United States that provides innovative firewalls and cloud-based security services. Palo Alto Networks&amp;#8217; automated delivery of upgraded security solutions across cloud and network infrastructure helps enterprises detect and mitigate successful intrusions. Palo Alto Networks, along with McAfee, Fortinet, and Symantec, created the ‘Cyber Threat Alliance’ in 2014, a non-profit organisation aimed at increasing collaboration and partnerships amongst cybersecurity businesses through the sharing of cyber threat intelligence. In 2019, the business launched the K2-Series, a 5G-ready next-generation firewall intended exclusively for telecom service providers and built with 5G and IoT infrastructure in mind. Cortex, a continuous security platform based on Artificial Intelligence (AI), was introduced the same year.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. IBM &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$76.2 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;IBM Corporations\nis a multinational corporation headquartered in the United States that\nspecialises in cloud computing, artificial intelligence, and other innovative\ntechnology. IBM has one of the most comprehensive portfolios of security\nconsulting and managed services. Large companies can benefit from IBM Security\nServices&amp;#8217; top-notch assessments and security policies, including zero trust.\nIBM Security Services assists enterprises and organisations in assessing and\nanalysing risks, improving resources, accelerating threat detection and\nresponse, and bolstering security priorities to accelerate business\ntransformation. To detect and respond to cyber threats in real time and\nquickly, IBM uses Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Watson.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. McAfee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$2.90 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;McAfee Corp.,\nsituated in California, is one of the world&amp;#8217;s most well-known network security provider.\nMcAfee specialises in digital security software for personal PCs, servers, and\nmobile devices. McAfee IntruShield, currently known as McAfee Network Security\nPlatform, is a network-based intrusion prevention sensor appliance that is\nprimarily used to protect against zero-day attacks, denial-of-service assaults,\nspyware, and malware threats. McAfee LiveSafe includes features such as\nantivirus, firewall, anti-spyware, and anti-ransomware. It provides\nsophisticated security solutions that identify, protect, and eradicate threats\non any device. Advanced Cyber Threat Services from McAfee assist enterprises in\ndefending against potential threats, developing effective security strategies,\nand safeguarding essential and valuable data.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Oracle\nCorporation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$39.07 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Oracle Corporation\nis a multinational computer technology firm based in California that produces\nand distributes database software and technologies, cloud-based systems, and\ndatabase development and system tools. Oracle&amp;#8217;s security solutions in the cloud\nand on-premises architecture provide increased protection for valuable and\nsensitive data. Oracle Cloud Infrastructure provides enterprises with\ncloud-based solutions with increased security to assist them safeguard their\ninfrastructure, apps, and data from cyber threats and attacks. Furthermore,\nthese solutions comply with the General Data Protection Regulation of the\nEuropean Union and the California Consumer Privacy Act. Businesses are\nprotected by Autonomous Database and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure&amp;#8217;s always-on\nencryption and ongoing monitoring of user behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Juniper\nNetworks &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$4.44 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Juniper Networks\nInc is a multinational firm based in the United States that develops and\nmanufactures networking devices and is a global leader in Artificial Intelligence\nnetworking and cloud-based services. Through its extensive spectrum of products\nand services, Juniper security products provide better visibility,\nintelligence, and enforcement. To extend security across every endpoint in the\nnetwork, services include next-generation firewalls for on-premises and cloud\narchitecture, advanced threat prevention, threat intelligence, management and\nanalytics, and security analysis. Juniper vSRX Virtual Firewalls provide AWS,\nGoogle Cloud, Azure, IBM Cloud, and Oracle Cloud systems with a high level of\nflexibility, effectiveness, and better performance.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.\nFortinet &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$2.59 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Fortinet is an\nAmerican multinational firm that provides protection to the world&amp;#8217;s major\ncorporations, service providers, and government agencies. Fortinet provides\nhighly intelligent, seamless defence against a wide range of threats. The\nFortinet Security Fabric architecture provides security that addresses\nimportant security concerns and is one of the industry&amp;#8217;s most high-performing\ncybersecurity solutions. It is supported by FortiOS and is developed\nspecifically for a broad threat surface to provide enterprises with increased\nand integrated security to secure and streamline their IT backbone. It\ncontinuously evaluates risks and adjusts automatically to provide complete\nreal-time protection over the cyberattack surface.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Synopsys\n&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$3.69 Billion&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Synopsys is an\nelectronic design automation firm based in the United States that specialises\nin software security and quality. Throughout the application life cycle,\nSynopsys products assist enterprises in successfully managing security and\nquality issues. It helps businesses to implement an enterprise wide AppSec\nprogramme that ensures personnel, processes, and technologies are prepared to\nfight against cyber threats and assaults on the software they use.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. CyberArk\n&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Revenue\nUS$343 Million&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;CyberArk,\nsituated in Massachusetts, is a publicly traded network security service\nprovider. It provides Privileged Account Security, which is widely used in\nfinancial services, retail, healthcare, and government markets. CyberArk\nBlueprint is a sophisticated tool for creating highly configurable security\nroadmaps that are simple to use and implement, resulting in improved security\nagainst threats and assaults. CyberArk announced advancements to its CyberArk\nIdentity Security Platform in June 2021, including Dynamics Privileged Access,\nLifecycle Management for Privileged Users, and new SaaS offerings such as\nSecure Web Sessions, which adds safety and security to browser-based\napplications that are vulnerable to breaches.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on cybersecurity blogs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top\nCybersecurity Companies in North America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/best-cybersecurity-company-shares-to-watch-in-2022/\"&gt;Best\nCybersecurity Company Shares to watch in 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/\"&gt;Top 10 Best Cybersecurity Companies in the World&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-10-best-cybersecurity-companies-in-the-world/feed/","slash:comments":"0"},{"title":"Top Cybersecurity Companies in North America","link":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/","comments":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/#respond","pubDate":"Tue, 10 May 2022 06:24:23 +0000","dc:creator":{"#cdata-section":"user"},"category":[{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity Software"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Cybersecurity vendors"},{"#cdata-section":"Top cybersecurity companies"},{"#cdata-section":"Top Cybersecurity vendors"}],"guid":{"@isPermaLink":"false","#text":"https://blog.360quadrants.com/?p=2827"},"description":{"#cdata-section":"&lt;p&gt;With a growing number of firms devoting significant operational resources to digital transformation, the usage of top cybersecurity vendor capabilities is critical for ensuring the protection of sensitive data and infrastructure. The numerous enterprise-level top Cybersecurity companies in North America that you should keep an eye on for your Cyber Security services are listed below. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity Companies in North America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"content:encoded":{"#cdata-section":"\n&lt;p&gt;With a growing number of firms devoting significant operational resources to digital transformation, the usage of top cybersecurity vendor capabilities is critical for ensuring the protection of sensitive data and infrastructure. The numerous enterprise-level &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;top Cybersecurity companies&lt;/a&gt; in North America that you should keep an eye on for your Cyber Security services are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. McAfee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Santa\nClara, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Threat\nDetection and Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;McAfee has been\nproducing cybersecurity software since 1987, making it one of the best\ncybersecurity companies on the market. McAfee offers security software for\nresidential users to secure their mobile devices and computers. Endpoint and\nmobile security products from McAfee defend end-user devices from assaults,\nwhile network security products and services safeguard corporation servers,\ndatabases, and data centres. McAfee also collaborates with governments across\nthe world, using its McAfee Global Threat Intelligence to keep businesses,\ngovernments, and consumers one step ahead of hackers.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;It is now a\nmajor player in the protection of corporate networks and customers both online\nand when they are connected to corporate networks. The corporation remains a\nprominent cybersecurity player for both businesses and consumers, thanks to its\npervasive solutions.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Cisco &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: San Jose,&amp;nbsp;California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cisco Systems is\na well-known &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;top cybersecurity\nvendors&lt;/a&gt;. Cisco has 300,000 security clients and its products protects 61\nmillion endpoints and 840,000 networks. Cisco&amp;#8217;s goal is to give its major\ncorporate customers with a complete cybersecurity platform. Cisco&amp;#8217;s security\nplatform covers user and email access, device and endpoint protection, network\nsecurity, and app and data lockdown. Additionally, the company offers incident\nresponse services. Cisco&amp;#8217;s security platform is built on a land-and-expand\nstrategy. Around 80% of Cisco security customers start with one of four popular\nproducts, and a quarter of them go on to purchase at least one additional\nsecurity product.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Cisco is trying\nto expand its security customer base through enterprise agreements, which allow\na company to manage all its software licences and subscriptions under a single\ncontract. The company now has roughly 4,500 customers thanks to enterprise\ncollaborations. The average Cisco customer owns 1.4 security products, compared\nto 4.1 for business agreement customers. Cisco estimates that the security\nbusiness will be worth $80 billion by 2025. The company will need to expand its\npresent enterprise customer base to enhance its market share.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. IBM &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Armonk, New York, United States&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Threat\nDetection and Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;IBM is a &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\nservice provider&lt;/a&gt; that offers hardware, software, and middleware, as\nwell as hosting and consulting services. IBM protects the entire company&amp;#8217;s\nnetwork from known and unknown threats. It assists in the detection and\nprevention of complex threats. IBM&amp;#8217;s IAM services help organisations avoid data\nbreaches, increase productivity and competitiveness, and achieve and maintain\nregulatory compliance. The federal government of the United States uses this\ncompany&amp;#8217;s cybersecurity products.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Palo Alto\nNetworks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Santa\nClara, California&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Threat\nDetection and Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto\nNetworks, founded in 2005, is a global network security provider with about\n54,000 customers in roughly 150 countries. The company&amp;#8217;s core Security Operating\nPlatform uses analytics to automate regular activities and enforcement, making\nsecurity easier to manage so clients can focus on securing users, apps, and\ndata. Financial services and healthcare are among the industries for which the\nplatform is well-suited. Cloud security, advanced firewall, endpoint\nprotection, and threat detection and prevention are among the services offered\nby the worldwide cybersecurity firm.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;More than 85% of\nFortune 100 firms and 63% of the Global 2000 employ Palo Alto Networks&amp;#8217;\nsophisticated firewalls and cloud-based security technologies. Following a long\nrun of acquisitions, the business recently launched a new 5G security solution\nand bought Expanse to boost its automated security responses in its Cortex\nsegment.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Redmond, Washington, United States&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Threat\nDetection and Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is one of the &lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/software/cybersecurity-software\"&gt;cybersecurity\ncompanies&lt;/a&gt; in the world. Microsoft offers both\nintelligent security solutions and cloud security advantages. Their cybersecurity\nservices help you stay safe from spyware, malware, and other potentially\nharmful applications. Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics (ATA) is a tool that\nhelps in threat detection. It&amp;#8217;s a simple and quick way to see what&amp;#8217;s going on\nwith your network. The detection of threats and the recovery from incidents is\naided by Microsoft&amp;#8217;s cloud infrastructure and services, as well as its own\ndevices and products, as well as its own corporate resources.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Fortinet &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Sunnyvale, California, United States&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In the year\n2000, Fortinet was founded with the purpose of offering complete end-to-end\nsecurity solutions. It is top\ncybersecurity company that specialises in firewall, antivirus, intrusion\nprevention, and endpoint security. Physical firewalls, antivirus software, an\nintrusion prevention system, and endpoint security components have all been\npraised. It develops specialised security processing unit (SPU) solutions for\nits customers to boost performance and cut costs. Fortinet is a network\nsecurity service provider that offers users effective cybersecurity and\ncompliance solutions via email, the web, the cloud, and social media.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Amazon Web Services &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location: Seattle, Washington, United States &lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Infrastructure security&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Amazon is a\ncompany that focuses on e-commerce, artificial intelligence, and cybersecurity.\nAWS provides businesses with enterprise-grade security and analytics solutions\nthat can help them gain total visibility into their application traffic. This\ncomputer security firm also specialises in data centre and network design, as\nwell as cloud security. The AWS Data Protection services help businesses\nprotect their data, accounts, and workloads against unauthorised access.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Code42&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location:\nMinneapolis, Minnesota&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category:\nInsider Risk Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Code42 is\nfocused on securing enterprise collaborative cultures and has built its\nservices on detecting and responding to insider threats. Its Incydr SaaS\nservice aids enterprises in reducing the time it takes to detect and respond to\ndata insider threats. It prioritises file exposure and exfiltration events that\npose dangers to businesses by watching behaviour across endpoints, email, the\ncloud, and the surface. Code42 boasts an easy-to-use interface, quick setup, and\nhassle-free policy management.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Code42 has been\ndesignated as a Black Unicorn twice, indicating that it is a cybersecurity firm\nwith the potential to attain a $1 billion market cap. Incydr, a new product\nfrom Code42 that protects intellectual property, source code, and trade\nsecrets, is the company&amp;#8217;s focus.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. LexisNexis\nRisk Solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location:\nAlpharetta, Georgia&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Risk\nManagement&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;LexisNexis Risk\nSolutions, a data and analytics leader, offers content-enabled risk management\nworkflow solutions. Its risk management services provide customers with\ndecision-making tools that blend public and industry content with analytics to\nassess and predict risk. LexisNexis Risk Solutions delivers a holistic\nperspective of the customer and the identity world by combining physical and\ndigital identities, as well as behavioural, biometric, device, and\ncredit-seeking insights.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;LexisNexis Risk\nSolutions protects sensitive information and develops creative solutions to\ncomplex risk data analytics problems. The company has launched two new products\ngeared at ensuring that identification attributes are covered across all risk\ndomains. One is Fraud Intelligence, a technology that helps to prevent new\naccount fraud by combining identification events and consumer application behaviour\ninto a score that represents the user&amp;#8217;s entire identity. Emailage, the other\nnew product, is a fraud risk score tool that employs email intelligence to\nimprove fraud detection and prevention.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.\nSecureWorks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Location:\nAtlanta, Georgia&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;Category: Threat\nDetection and Management&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;SecureWorks was\nfounded in 1999 and was acquired by Dell Technologies in 2011. SecureWorks\nfocuses on information security services and provides network, IT, and managed\nsecurity solutions. To secure businesses, the company&amp;#8217;s security information\nand event management platform employs applied security research and\nGIAC-certified professionals. Its services also rely on automation and\nartificial intelligence (AI), as well as actionable information, analysts, and\nvisibility from hundreds of clients, to generate a powerful network effect for\npredicting and countering cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;In 2020, SecureWorks purchased vulnerability management company Delve Laboratories, a partnership that can take use of Delve&amp;#8217;s scalable vulnerability prioritisation to provide clients with actionable data throughout their network. SecureWorks enhanced its Threat Detection and Response software to help security teams detect and respond to security issues more effectively. Users can also proactively &amp;#8220;search&amp;#8221; for known and undiscovered dangers by integrating with third-party companies and employing threat intelligence and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on cybersecurity blogs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/fastest-growing-cybersecurity-companies/\"&gt;Fastest Growing Cybersecurity Companies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity Companies in North America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;\n\n\n\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/\"&gt;Top Cybersecurity Companies in North America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel=\"nofollow\" href=\"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog\"&gt;360Quadrants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;\n"},"wfw:commentRss":"https://www.360quadrants.com/blog/2022/top-cybersecurity-companies-in-north-america/feed/","slash:comments":"0"}]}}}</feed>
</Logs>