<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
    <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 03:39:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <image>
      <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
      <url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
      <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
    </image>
    <description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-carried-out-nuclear-capable-underwater-weapon-test-3930296]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[North Korea Says It Carried Out Nuclear-Capable Underwater Weapon Test]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-carried-out-nuclear-capable-underwater-weapon-test-3930296]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 03:39:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[North Korea carried out an underwater strategic weapon system test from April 4 to April 7, state media KCNA said on Saturday.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea carried out an underwater strategic weapon system test from April 4 to April 7, state media KCNA said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The country tested another kind of a nuclear-capable unmanned underwater attack weapon called "Haeil-2", after it disclosed a new underwater drone system designed to make sneak attacks in enemy waters.</p>

<p>"The test perfectly proved the reliability of the underwater strategic weapon system and its fatal attack ability," the North's state news agency said.</p>

<p>North Korea has ramped up its military activities in recent weeks in a show of force against the United States and South Korea that conduct joint military drills.</p>

<p>It unveiled new, smaller nuclear warheads and fired an intercontinental ballistic missile capable of striking anywhere in the United States.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/85c1dul_north-korea-reuters_625x300_30_June_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[North Korea has ramped up its military activities in recent weeks amid US-South Korea military drills.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrested-us-wall-street-journal-journalist-evan-gershkovich-charged-with-spying-in-russia-3930278]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Arrested US Journalist Charged With Spying In Russia]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrested-us-wall-street-journal-journalist-evan-gershkovich-charged-with-spying-in-russia-3930278]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 02:14:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Moscow has formally charged US journalist Evan Gershkovich with espionage, Russian news agencies reported Friday, adding that he had denied the accusations.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Moscow has formally charged US journalist Evan Gershkovich with espionage, Russian news agencies reported Friday, adding that he had denied the accusations.</p>

<p>The arrest of Wall Street Journal correspondent Evan Gershkovich prompted an outcry from media outlets and rights groups, as well as government officials in Washington.</p>

<p>"FSB investigators charged Gershkovich with espionage in the interests of his country," Russian state-run agency TASS said, citing a law enforcement source.</p>

<p>"He categorically denied all accusations and stated that he was engaged in journalistic activities in Russia," TASS said.</p>

<p>Gershkovich's arrest is seen as a serious escalation of Moscow's crackdown on the media.</p>

<p>His publication, one of the most prestigious in the United States, "vehemently denies the allegations" against its "trusted and dedicated reporter".</p>

<p>The case has been classified as secret, limiting the amount of information available.</p>

<p>His arrest also comes as Moscow's relationship with Washington has been severely downgraded because of the Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>Washington has long accused Moscow of arbitrarily arresting Americans in order to secure the release of detained Russians.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden called for Gershkovich's release on Friday, the White House describing the accusations against him as "ridiculous".</p>

<p>The Democratic and Republican leaders of the US Senate also denounced his arrest.</p>

<p>"We strongly condemn the wrongful detention of US citizen and Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich, and demand the immediate release of this internationally known and respected independent journalist," Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and Republican Leader Mitch McConnell said in a rare joint statement.</p>

<p>"Let there be no mistake: journalism is not a crime," the Senate leaders wrote. "We demand the baseless, fabricated charges against Mr. Gershkovich be dropped and he be immediately released."</p>

<p>Schumer and McConnell also reiterated their "condemnation of the Russian government's continued attempts to intimidate, repress, and punish independent journalists and civil society voices."</p>

<p>But Russia said on Thursday it was "pointless" to try to pressure Moscow over the case.</p>

<p>Gershkovich worked for AFP in Russia before taking a job with the Journal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/etgd98qo_evan-gershkovich_625x300_30_March_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Evan Gershkovich's arrest is seen as a serious escalation of Moscow's crackdown on the media.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-shootout-between-two-armed-groups-in-bangladesh-cops-3930262]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[8 Killed In Shootout Between Two Armed Groups In Bangladesh: Cops]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-shootout-between-two-armed-groups-in-bangladesh-cops-3930262]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:57:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups at Rowangchhari upazila in Bandarban on Thursday night, said police, reported Dhaka Tribune.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups at Rowangchhari upazila in Bandarban on Thursday night, said police, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Officials suspect the United People's Democratic Front (Democratic) and Kuki-Chin National Army, the military wing of Kuki-Chin National Front (KNF), were engaged in the gunbattle.</p>

<p>Abdul Mannan, officer-in-charge (OC) of Rowangchhari police station, said the bullet-riddled bodies were taken to the Bandarban Zila Sadar Hospital morgue. The bodies will be handed over to their families after the autopsy, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Locals said they heard on-and-off gunshots from Thursday evening till Friday morning. They claimed the gunfight took place between KNF and United People's Democratic Front (UPDF-reformist).</p>

<p>Based on an inspection of their clothes, the deceased are believed to be members of the Kuki Chin National Army (KNA), the armed wing of the KNF. It is suspected that the opposition armed group took heavy weapons that the deceased were carrying.</p>

<p>The KNF in a social media post claimed that just seven people were killed in the gunfight. They blamed a reformist group for the incident, without mentioning any name, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>While the KNF is the armed wing of the Kuki Chin National Front, that harbours separatist demands, the original UPDF under Prasit Khisa has in the past stated 'full autonomy' for the CHT districts as its principal demand. Its official position on the CHT Accord signed between the government of Bangladesh and the PCJSS in 1997, has been 'skeptical'.</p>

<p>UPDF (Democratic) has never clarified its position or distanced itself from the original founding principles. Their reasons for splintering are thought to be personality-based.</p>

<p>The deaths reported on Thursday are the highest in an armed incident in the area since the July 2020 incident, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>On March 12 this year, a senior army warrant officer was killed and two other soldiers suffered injuries when members of KNA opened fire on a patrol team in Rowangchhari upazila of Bandarban.</p>

<p>On March 15, KNF members abducted nine people, including Sergeant (Retd) Anwar Hossain, while they were working on the road in the Longthasi Jhiri area of Ruma.</p>

<p>In a message on March 18, the KNF claimed that 30 people from the Bom community were detained by the joint forces from September 9 till March, and demanded their release, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>After Thursday's incident, some 175 families in the neighbourhood have taken refuge in Rowangchhari Government High School.</p>

<p>Manik Khiang, a shopkeeper in the Khamtam neighbourhood, said: "There was a shooting incident between two groups on Thursday evening. At that time, many people left their homes in fear. So far, I have learned that more than 50 families have left their homes. Many of them have taken refuge in nearby educational institutions."</p>

<p>Since November 15 last year, at least 548 people from 132 families have taken refuge in Mizoram. On January 28, some 140 Marma women, men and children took refuge in Ruma Sadar from Mulpi Para, but they returned to their homes on February 5, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>On March 10, around 220 people of 56 families from Barathli 4 Union of Rangamati's Bilaichhari took shelter in Tangchangya Reichha and Rowangchhari Sadar Upazila in fear of the armed activities by KNF members.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-01/k0915tug_gun-generic-pixabay-650_625x300_31_January_19.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups In Bandarban. (Representational)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-4-injured-in-terror-attack-in-israels-tel-aviv-3930253]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[1 Killed, 5 Injured In Terror Attack In Israel's Tel Aviv]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-4-injured-in-terror-attack-in-israels-tel-aviv-3930253]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:35:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[One man was killed and four people were wounded in an attack Friday in central Tel Aviv, Israeli rescue services said, updating a previous casualty toll of two injured.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu mobilised police and army reserves late Friday after one man was killed and five people were wounded in a car-ramming attack in central Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The Magen David Adom emergency service said in a statement a man aged about 30 had been declared dead and five others were taken to hospital with moderate injuries after the attack.</p>

<p>"All the victims were tourists," it added, without providing details on their nationalities.</p>

<p>Three of them, including a 17-year-old, were moderately injured, while two had light injuries, the rescue service added.</p>

<p>A police spokesman meanwhile told AFP "the terrorist was neutralised, it was a terror attack against civilians, a car ramming attack".</p>

<p>Netanyahu ordered the mobilisation of police and army reserves following the attack, his office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, two British-Israeli sisters aged 16 and 20 were killed and their mother seriously wounded in a shooting attack in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim of responsibility for either attack.</p>

<p>The attacks came hours after Israel bombarded Lebanon following rocket fire from there that the army blamed on Palestinian militants.</p>

<p>The violence comes amid an upsurge in tensions during Jewish, Muslim and Christian religious holidays.</p>

<p>It follows the storming early Wednesday by Israeli riot police of the Al-Aqsa mosque in Jerusalem, Islam's third holiest site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/police-generic-international-afp_650x400_41520126059.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Israeli police said that it was a terrorist attack. (Representational)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-hosts-iftar-slams-russian-repression-of-crimea-muslims-3930251]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Hosts Iftar, Slams Russian "Repression" Of Crimea Muslims]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-hosts-iftar-slams-russian-repression-of-crimea-muslims-3930251]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:19:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority Tatar community in Kremlin-controlled Crimea and vowed to recapture the peninsula from Russia during a first official state iftar.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority Tatar community in Kremlin-controlled Crimea and vowed to recapture the peninsula from Russia during a first official state iftar.</p>

<p>Russia wrested control of the Black Sea territory from Ukraine in 2014 and pushed through a referendum on the annexation that was condemned as fraudulent and illegitimate by Ukraine and its Western allies.</p>

<p>"Russia's attempt to enslave Ukraine ... began exactly with the occupation of Crimea, exactly with repressions against Crimean, Ukrainian and Crimean Tatar freedom and of Crimean Muslims," he told Ukrainian Muslim leaders and ambassadors from Muslim countries.</p>

<p>The Tatar community, which accounted for 12-15 percent of the two million Crimea residents, largely boycotted the 2014 vote.</p>

<p>Moscow then banned the Mejlis -- the traditional assembly of the Tatar Muslim minority in Crimea -- declaring it an extremist organisation and has jailed members of the community since, citing security concerns.</p>

<p>"There is no alternative for Ukraine, or for the world, other than the de-occupation of Crimea. We will return to Crimea," Zelensky said, before handing out awards to several Muslim Ukrainian servicemen.</p>

<p>Zelensky, speaking at a mosque outside the centre of the capital, announced that Ukraine was beginning a new tradition of hosting an official iftar, the meal breaking the daily fast during the holy month of Ramadan.</p>

<p>"Ukraine is grateful to the Muslims of our country and to everyone in the Muslim community of the world who, like us, longs for peace and protection from evil," he added.</p>

<p>Several Muslim-majority countries, including Turkey and Saudi Arabia, have positioned themselves as mediators in the conflict in Ukraine, brokering agreements between Kyiv and Moscow on grain exports or prisoner exchanges.</p>

<p>Russia has a large Muslim minority from southern regions, including Chechnya and Dagestan, many of whom are fighting for Moscow in Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/l7ul8h9g_zelensky-reuters_625x300_12_December_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Zelensky criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority in Russian-controlled Crimea.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/spaniards-were-consuming-drugs-3-000-years-ago-study-finds-3930102]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Spaniards Were Consuming Drugs 3,000 Years Ago, Study Finds]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/spaniards-were-consuming-drugs-3-000-years-ago-study-finds-3930102]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:06:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[After examining Bronze Age hair fragments discovered in the Es Carritx cave on the Spanish island of Menorca, researchers made the finding.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ancient humans were using hallucinogenic chemicals to get high during cave ceremonies 3,000 years ago, according to a recent study by researchers studying ancient human civilizations.</p>

<p>The finding of hairs from a burial site in Menorca, Spain, by specialists demonstrates that drugs originating from plants and bushes were utilised by prehistoric human civilizations.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-65211722" target="_blank"><em>The BBC</em></a>, the findings, published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-31064-2" target="_blank"><em>Scientific Reports</em></a>, showed signs of human activity at the Es Carritx cave, on the south-western side of Menorca. The cave houses more than 200 human graves and is believed to have served as a ritual and funerary site for about 600 years, until 800 BCE.</p>

<p>The authors of the study explained that "as early as the Palaeolithic period, humans came across the non-food properties of certain plants." The results presented here indicate that several alkaloid-bearing plants were consumed by Bronze Age people from Menorca (although Solanaceae and Ephedra were not the only ones to have been consumed)."</p>

<p>"Interestingly, the psychoactive substances detected in this study are not suitable for alleviating the pain involved in severe palaeopathological conditions attested in the population buried in the cave of Es Carritx, such as periapical abscesses, severe caries, and arthropathies."</p>

<p>"Considering the potential toxicity of the alkaloids found in the hair, their handling, use, and applications represented highly specialised knowledge. This knowledge was typically possessed by shamans, who were capable of controlling the side effects of the plant drugs through an ecstasy that made diagnosis or divination possible."</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/qlq2f2lo_bronzeage-people-took-hallucinogenic-drugs-in-menorca-study-reveals_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The study found psychoactive substances on hair strands.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-maid-jailed-for-six-months-for-biting-baby-who-refused-to-sleep-3930057]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Singapore Maid Jailed For Six Months For Biting Baby Who Refused To Sleep]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-maid-jailed-for-six-months-for-biting-baby-who-refused-to-sleep-3930057]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:47:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[A 33-year-old maid in Singapore who was hired to care for twin babies bit one of them out of frustration when the toddler refused to go to sleep, and now she is serving jail time.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 33-year-old maid in Singapore who was hired to care for twin babies bit one of them out of frustration when the toddler refused to go to sleep, and now she is serving jail time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The domestic help, identified as Masita Khoridaturochmah, was sentenced to six months' jail on Tuesday for one charge of ill-treating the one-year-old girl by willfully causing her unnecessary physical pain, <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/courts-crime/6-months-jail-for-maid-who-bit-forearm-of-baby-under-her-care" target="_blank"><em>The Straits Times </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A court in Singapore heard that Ms Masita, an Indonesian national, started working for the victim's mother in 2021. Her primary duties included taking care of her employer's twin babies, as well as household chores.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On May 26, 2022, Ms Masita's employer left home to pick up her older daughter from preschool. Ms Masita was left at home with the twin infants, who were aged 14 months at the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is when the maid attempted to put them to sleep, however, after about a half-hour, she lost patience with one of the babies because she thought the victim was keeping her from preparing dinner. Ms Masita then bit the little girl once on her left forearm, leaving a bruise.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When the child's mother returned home about half an hour later, she went to cook dinner for her children and fed them. While preparing the baby girl for bed, the mother saw a bruise in the shape of a bite mark on the baby's arm. The woman suspected that Ms Masita had bitten the little girl and questioned her about it.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/canadian-man-chronicles-his-weight-loss-journey-it-started-after-a-conversation-with-daughter-3929897" target="_self">Canadian Man Chronicles His Weight Loss Journey. It Started After A Conversation With Daughter</a></strong></p>

<p>The 33-year-old initially denied doing so but eventually acknowledged her behaviour. According to The Straits Times, Ms Masita even knelt down and apologised to her employer, but the child's mother reported the matter to the police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The prosecutor claimed that the victim was particularly vulnerable and especially young, and Ms Masita had abused the position of trust she was placed in. According to him, Ms Masita hurt the victim "willfully," and the offence was committed because she was upset that the victim wasn't nodding off as quickly as she would have liked.</p>

<p>District Judge Tan Jen Tse also observed that Ms Masita had committed the offence out of annoyance in a singular instance of abuse involving a single act and had shown regret shortly after. The judge agreed to Ms Masita's request to postpone her sentence for a week so she could put her affairs in order, including contacting her family in Indonesia over arrangements for her return after her imprisonment.</p>

<p>The 33-year-old is now expected to surrender herself at the State Courts on Tuesday in order to begin serving her sentence.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/it8dmhbo_baby-generic_625x300_09_June_21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The maid is expected to surrender herself at the State Courts on Tuesday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-organisations-sanctioned-by-china-for-hosting-taiwan-president-3930006]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[American Organisations Sanctioned By China For Hosting Taiwan President]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-organisations-sanctioned-by-china-for-hosting-taiwan-president-3930006]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:27:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[China on Friday slapped sanctions on two American organisations that hosted Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen during her visit to the US and her meeting with the House Speaker.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Friday slapped sanctions on two American organisations that hosted Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen during her visit to the US and her meeting with the House Speaker, a day after President Xi Jinping said it is "wishful thinking" to expect Beijing to "compromise" on its stand on the self-ruled island.</p>

<p>Ms Tsai's meeting with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy - the third most senior official in the US - on Thursday took place against the backdrop of repeated warnings from Beijing to Washington that the meeting should not happen. It was the first time a Taiwan president had met a US Speaker on American soil.</p>

<p>China views any official exchanges between foreign governments and Taiwan as an infringement on Beijing's claims of sovereignty over the island.</p>

<p>China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs announced that the Washington-based think tank Hudson Institute and the Ronald Reagan Presidential Library in California would be banned from any cooperation, exchange or transaction with institutions and individuals in China.</p>

<p>The Ronald Reagan Presidential Library in Simi Valley was the site where Tsai met McCarthy and a bipartisan group of congressional leaders. It was the second high-profile meeting between an American official and Taiwan's president.</p>

<p>China also sanctioned the Hudson Institute, which hosted an event and presented Tsai with its global leadership award on March 30.</p>

<p>The sanctioned groups included Asia-based groups --The Prospect Foundation and the Council of Asian Liberals and Democrats for their involvement in promoting Taiwan's independence.</p>

<p>"[The] Taiwan issue is the core of China's core interests. The Chinese government and Chinese people will never agree to anyone making a fuss about the one-China issue," President Xi told European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen during a meeting in Beijing on Thursday.</p>

<p>It was his first comment after the US House Speaker McCarthy met Tsai, which Beijing sharply criticised.</p>

<p>"Anyone who expects China to compromise on the Taiwan question could only be wishful thinking and self-defeating," Xi was quoted as saying by the state-run Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters after the meeting, von der Leyen said the Taiwan issue had been discussed and she had told Xi that "the threat to use force to change the status quo is unacceptable. It is important that some of the tensions that might occur should be resolved through dialogue", Hong Kong-based South China Morning Post reported.</p>

<p>On Friday's sanctions, the foreign ministry in Beijing said that both American institutions were banned from having exchanges, cooperation, and other activities with any individuals, universities or institutions in China.</p>

<p>"We want to stress China will take resolute measures to safeguard its sovereignty and territorial integrity," Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said at a media briefing.</p>

<p>She also sought to dismiss a question on how Beijing can integrate Taiwan, which follows a multiple-party democratic system with that of China's one-party rule headed by the ruling Communist Party.</p>

<p>The Taiwan question is not about democracy but about China's territorial integrity and reunification and Taiwan is an inalienable part of China's territory, Mao said.</p>

<p>"The sovereignty and territory of China have never been divided and will never be divided," she asserted.</p>

<p>"Some countries support Taiwan in the name of democracy and use the Taiwan question to contain China. This move is dangerous and gets nowhere. Taiwan's future lies in the development of cross-strait relations and reunification with the mainland," she added.</p>

<p>The difference in systems is not a barrier to reunification or an excuse for division, Mao said and advocated the 'one country-two systems' formula which Beijing sought to apply to Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Peaceful reunification and the 'one country two systems' take Taiwan's realities into full account and help to achieve peace and stability after re-unification, she said.</p>

<p>"It is the basic principle to resolving the Taiwan question and the best way for realising reunification," she said.</p>

<p>The sanctions came a day after China vowed reprisals against Taiwan.</p>

<p>China and the US also flexed their naval might by deploying aircraft carriers in a rare showdown in the Taiwan Strait.</p>

<p>Under its longstanding "One China" policy, the US acknowledges China's position that Taiwan is part of China, but has never officially recognised Beijing's claim to the island of 23 million. Under the Taiwan Relations Act, it is also bound by law to provide the democratic island with the means to defend itself.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Taiwan's foreign ministry on Friday said the head of state of the Republic of China (Taiwan) exercises a basic right of a sovereign nation when travelling to other countries to engage in diplomatic activities. China has no right to intervene.</p>

<p>"China is overreacting when it uses this as a pretext to further suppress Taiwan's international space and impose so-called sanctions on related individuals and organisations. Such irrational behaviour not only increases the Taiwanese people's antipathy to China but also exposes the erratic and absurd nature of the communist regime," Taiwan's foreign ministry said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/0nobu66_tsai-ing-wenkevin-mccarthy_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Taiwan President met with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy on Thursday]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-needs-to-repay-77-billion-debt-to-china-saudi-arabia-by-2026-report-3929817]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pak Needs To Repay $77 Billion Debt To China, Saudi Arabia By 2026: Report]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-needs-to-repay-77-billion-debt-to-china-saudi-arabia-by-2026-report-3929817]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 21:13:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Pakistan, currently tackling a major economic crisis, is grappling with high external debt, a weak local currency and dwindling foreign exchange reserves.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan needs to repay a whopping USD 77.5 billion in external debt from April 2023 to June 2026 and the cash-strapped country may face "disruptive effects" if it ultimately defaults, a prominent US think tank has warned.</p>

<p>The analysis published on Thursday by the United States Institute of Peace (USIP) warned that amid skyrocketing inflation, political conflicts, and rising terrorism, Pakistan is facing the risk of a default due to its massive external debt obligations, the Geo News reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Pakistan, currently tackling a major economic crisis, is grappling with high external debt, a weak local currency and dwindling foreign exchange reserves.</p>

<p>The USIP report called the USD 77.5 billion that Pakistan needs to repay in external debt from April 2023 to June 2026 a "hefty amount" for a USD 350 billion economy.</p>

<p>It stated that if Pakistan ultimately defaults, there will be a "cascade of disruptive effects".</p>

<p>In the next three years, the debt-struck country has to make major repayments to Chinese financial institutions, private creditors and Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>From April to June 2023, Pakistan faces near-term debt repayment pressure as the external debt servicing burden is USD 4.5 billion, the report said.</p>

<p>According to the report, substantial repayments are due in June, when a USD 1 billion Chinese SAFE deposit and a roughly USD 1.4 billion Chinese commercial loan would mature.</p>

<p>Pakistani authorities hope to convince the Chinese to refinance and roll over both debts, the report said, noting that the Chinese government and commercial banks have done so in the past.</p>

<p>Even if Pakistan manages to meet these obligations, the next fiscal year will be more challenging as the debt servicing will rise to nearly USD 25 billion, the report said.</p>

<p>Pakistan is awaiting a much-needed USD 1.1 billion tranche of funding from the International Monetary Fund, originally due to be disbursed in November last year.</p>

<p>The funds are part of a USD 6.5 billion bailout package the IMF approved in 2019, which analysts say is critical if Pakistan is to avoid defaulting on external debt obligations.</p>

<p>The IMF programme, signed in 2019, will expire on June 30, 2023, and under the set guidelines, the programme cannot be extended beyond the deadline.</p>

<p>Pakistan and the IMF have been negotiating the programme's resumption for months but have yet to reach an agreement.</p>

<p>There is no easy solution available to fix the ailing economy of Pakistan, and the government is of the view that they have taken all the tough decisions for reviving the stalled IMF programme.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/jqlsd7mk_pakistan-rupee-generic-pkr-generic-istock_625x300_04_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Pakistan is awaiting a much-needed USD 1.1 billion tranche of funding from IMF.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pope-francis-to-skip-good-friday-procession-due-to-cold-weather-3929557]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pope Francis To Skip Good Friday Procession Due To Cold Weather]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pope-francis-to-skip-good-friday-procession-due-to-cold-weather-3929557]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 19:39:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis, who left hospital last weekend following a bout of bronchitis, will skip Friday's outdoor "Way of the Cross" procession due to cold weather, the Vatican said in a statement.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pope Francis, who left hospital last weekend following a bout of bronchitis, will skip Friday's outdoor "Way of the Cross" procession due to cold weather, the Vatican said in a statement.</p>

<p>The 86-year-old pontiff will still attend an indoor Good Friday service earlier in St. Peter's Basilica, Vatican spokesman Matteo Bruni said in response to a question from Reuters.</p>

<p>It is the first time the pope will not preside at the "Via Crucis" service at Rome's Colosseum since he was elected in 2013.</p>

<p>The Vatican said he would follow it from his residence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/cja2600g_pope-francis_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The Vatican said the Pope would follow it from his residence. (File)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-stop-exchanges-with-the-world-taiwan-president-after-us-visit-3929421]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA["Will Not Stop Exchanges With The World": Taiwan President After US Visit]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-stop-exchanges-with-the-world-taiwan-president-after-us-visit-3929421]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:54:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Taiwan will not be stopped from engaging with the world and will not give in to pressure, President Tsai Ing-wen said on Friday as she arrived back from a trip to Central America and United States, where she met US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan will not be stopped from engaging with the world and will not give in to pressure, President Tsai Ing-wen said on Friday as she arrived back from a trip to Central America and United States, where she met US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.</p>

<p>China, which claims democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, reacted with anger to the McCarthy meeting having demanded it not take place, though so far has held off ratcheting up military tensions to show its displeasure.</p>

<p>Speaking after stepping off her flight, Tsai said her enthusiastic welcome overseas was a powerful message.</p>

<p>"We showed the international community that in the face of pressure and threats Taiwan will be even more united and will absolutely not yield to suppression, nor due to obstructions stop exchanges with the world," she said at Taiwan's main international airport at Taoyuan outside of Taipei.</p>

<p>China staged war games around Taiwan last August following a visit to Taipei by then-House Speaker Nancy Pelosi.</p>

<p>While Taiwan has reported a Chinese aircraft carrier group far off its eastern coast, it has not reported any other unusual military movements.</p>

<p>China's Taiwan Affairs Office, in a statement released shortly after Tsai's flight landed, reiterated its opposition to her US trip, technically billed as a "transit" though in reality where her most important meetings took place.</p>

<p>"The so-called 'transit' is just an excuse, but it is actually a provocation, relying on the United States to seek independence," it said.</p>

<p>However, the statement did not announce any specific retaliatory steps.</p>

<p>But underscoring the sensitivity of Tsai's return, Taiwan's Defence Ministry denied, around 30 minutes before touchdown, a Taiwanese media report that her flight had been subjected to "unknown interference", saying this was not true.</p>

<p>It did say, though, that a special military task force was deployed to "control the whole process", using naval and air forces to stand guard.</p>

<p>Tsai travelled on an A350 specially chartered from Taiwan's China Airlines.</p>

<p>Tsai and her government reject China's sovereignty claims, saying only Taiwan's people can decide their future. She has repeatedly offered talks with China but been rebuffed, with Beijing viewing her as a separatist.</p>

<p>China has never renounced the use of force to bring Taiwan under its control.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/g8e01ov8_tsai-ingwen_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Taiwan President Tsai Ing-wen said her enthusiastic welcome overseas was a powerful message]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-developed-a-new-recyclable-plastic-that-isnt-derived-from-crude-oil-3929357]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Researchers Make New Recyclable Plastic That Isn't Derived From Crude Oil]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-developed-a-new-recyclable-plastic-that-isnt-derived-from-crude-oil-3929357]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:31:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[The poly(ethyl cyanoacrylate), or PECA, that serves as the basis for the new recyclable plastic is created from the same monomer as Super Glue.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every area of human life has been contaminated by plastic, including medical devices, educational materials, and, arguably, every occupation and way of life on the world. The packaging for daily-use products is not even imaginable without plastic wrapping. An environmental crisis has been brought on by years of excessive use and a rise in single-use, disposable plastics.</p>

<p>Researchers, developers, and scientists have been attempting to create new eco-friendly and simple processes for producing plastic. In the quest for solutions, recent research has achieved a breakthrough.</p>

<p>A new type of plastic has just been created by researchers at <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adg2295" target="_blank">Boise State University</a> in the US that, unlike other plastics, is not made from crude oil and its byproducts.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2365324-recyclable-plastic-made-from-super-glue-could-replace-polystyrene/" target="_blank"><em>New Scientist</em>, </a>Allison Christy and Scott Phillips at Boise State University in Idaho used ethyl cyanoacrylate-the main ingredient in super glue-to create a plastic that could replace polystyrene, which is commonly used in yoghurt pots, disposable cups, and cutlery and accounts for 6 percent of plastic waste.</p>

<p>The scientists explained the process, saying ethyl cyanoacrylate can be made from formaldehyde, which in turn can be made from carbon dioxide. When super glue is exposed to moisture, ethyl cyanoacrylate molecules bond to form polymer chains, but the reaction is so fast that you only get short chains. The researchers created a way to slow that process down in order to form longer polymer chains and therefore a stronger material, known as poly(ethyl cyanoacrylate), or PECA.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="https://www.un.org/pga/73/plastics/" target="_blank">United Nations</a>, up to 12 million tonnes of plastic are being swept into the oceans annually, and gyres, or so-called 'islands of plastic', are blossoming. While most plastics are expected to remain intact for decades or centuries after use, those that do erode end up as micro-plastics, which are consumed by fish and other marine wildlife and quickly make their way into the global food chain. Indeed, micro-plastics have been found everywhere, from the Arctic to the Swiss mountains, in tap water, and in human faeces.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/0pour1r8_plasticafp_625x300_13_October_21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Superglue-based recyclable plastic could take the place of polystyrene.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-says-ai-will-be-added-to-search-engine-3928819]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Google CEO Sundar Pichai Says AI Will Be Added To Search Engine]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-says-ai-will-be-added-to-search-engine-3928819]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:45:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[According to Mr Pichai, improvements in AI would enhance Google's capacity to respond to a variety of search queries.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google CEO Sundar Pichai has announced that it will be integrating artificial intelligence (AI) into its search engine, as per a report in the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-says-search-to-feature-chat-ai-2fa0f54c?mod=hp_lead_pos2" target="_blank">Wall Street Journal</a> (WSJ). Google's decision to integrate AI into its widely used search tools shows the competition it faces from OpenAI's ChatGPT and others.</p>

<p>According to Mr Pichai, improvements in AI would enhance Google's capacity to respond to a variety of search queries. Although, as per the outlet, Mr Pichai rejected the idea that chatbots threatened Google's search business, which generates more than half of its parent Alphabet Inc's revenue. "The opportunity space, if anything, is bigger than before," the Chief Executive said in the interview.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is to be noted that large language models (LLMs) are computer programmes that can provide responses to questions that mimic those of people and Google has been a pioneer in this field. The tech giant will now try to improve user experience on its search engine using the technology. "Will people be able to ask questions to Google and engage with LLMs in the context of search? Absolutely," Mr Pichai told WSJ.</p>

<p>In addition to investor pressure to cut costs, Mr Pichai is grappling with one of the largest threats to Google's main business in years as Microsoft recently rolled out its enhanced version of the Bing search engine which is now powered by ChatGPT.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella stated after the launch of the company's new AI-powered search engine that the new developments will "reshape every software category" they know including search, much like earlier advancements in personal computers and cloud computing.</p>

<p>Mr Pichai told WSJ that the consumer excitement surrounding the "adoption of these technologies, and some of that is a pleasant surprise as well" has been "incredible" with regard to Google's chatbot Bard, which is yet to acquire traction. When questioned why Google had not introduced an AI chatbot earlier, he replied that the business was "iterating to ship something, and maybe timelines changed, given the moment in the industry."</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/pnl1d01g_google_625x300_29_March_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Mr Pichai is grappling with one of the largest threats to Google's main business.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/colonial-era-file-sheds-light-on-indian-gems-and-jewels-in-uks-royal-treasury-3928509]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Colonial-Era File Sheds Light On Indian Jewels In UK's Royal Treasury]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/colonial-era-file-sheds-light-on-indian-gems-and-jewels-in-uks-royal-treasury-3928509]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:20:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[The discovery of a colonial-era file from the archives of the India Office, the then-British government department responsible for its rule over India, has shed light on precious gems and jewels that came into possession of the royal family.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The discovery of a colonial-era file from the archives of the India Office, the then-British government department responsible for its rule over the Indian subcontinent, has shed light on many precious gems and jewels that came into the possession of the royal family.</p>

<p>As part of a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/series/cost-of-the-crown" target="_blank">'Cost of the crown' series, The Guardian</a> newspaper has been chronicling an investigation into Britain's royal wealth and finances in the lead-up to the Coronation of King Charles III next month.</p>

<p>In one of the reports this week, it references a "remarkable" 46-page file uncovered from the India Office archives that detail an investigation, apparently commissioned by Queen Mary - the grandmother of the late Queen Elizabeth II, into the imperial origins of her jewels.</p>

<p>Among its references is an emerald-encrusted gold girdle used to decorate the horses in the stables of Maharaja Ranjit Singh of Punjab, which now forms part of King Charles' royal collection.</p>

<p>"The report, from 1912, explains how priceless pieces, including Charles's emerald belt, were extracted from India as trophies of conquest and later given to Queen Victoria," The Guardian investigation reveals.</p>

<p>"The items described are now owned by the monarch as property of the British crown," it notes.</p>

<p>Among the discoveries included a journal recording a tour in 1837 of Punjab by the British society diarist Fanny Eden and her brother George, then Britain's governor general of India, who visited Ranjit Singh - the powerful king who had signed a so-called "treaty of friendship" with the British at the time.</p>

<p>Dazzled by his kingdom's jewels, Eden wrote: "He puts his very finest jewels on his horses, and the splendour of their harness and housings surpasses anything you can imagine." "If ever we are allowed to plunder this kingdom, I shall go straight to their stables," Eden wrote.</p>

<p>Later in the 19th century, Ranjit Singh's son and heir, Duleep Singh, was forced to sign Punjab over to the East India Company and according to historical records, the kingdom's stables would have been among the many targets of plunder.</p>

<p>The infamous Koh-i-Noor diamond is said to have come into the possession of Queen Victoria as a result of just such a plunder by East India Company officials.</p>

<p>While modern-day royals averted a diplomatic row by not choosing the traditional Koh-i-Noor encrusted crown for Queen Camilla's Coronation on May 6, the 'Cost of the crown' has cast a spotlight on the wider extent of colonial-era jewels in royal possession today.</p>

<p>Among the jewels identified in the document uncovered by The Guardian is a "short necklace of four very large spinel rubies", the largest of which is a 325.5-carat spinel that later came to be identified as the Timur ruby.</p>

<p>However, research by the academic Susan Stronge in 1996 concluded it was probably never owned by the Mongol conqueror and belonged to several kings of Persia and Mughal emperors before Queen Victoria sent it from India.</p>

<p>Another Indian item chronicled is a pearl necklace consisting of 224 large pearls, which is also believed to have come from Ranjit Singh's treasury.</p>

<p>"We have finally entered an era where colonial loot and pillage is being recognised for what it really was, rather than being dressed up as the incidental spoils of some noble 'civilising mission'," Congress MP and author of 'Inglorious Empire: What the British Did to India' Shashi Tharoor told the newspaper.</p>

<p>"As we are seeing increasingly, the return of stolen property is always a good thing. Generations to come will wonder why it took civilised nations so long to do the right thing," he said.</p>

<p>According to the investigative series, Queen Mary's interest in investigating the origins of her jewellery appears to have been prompted by a curiosity about some of her pearls' origin rather than any moral concern about their colonial origins.</p>

<p>A Buckingham Palace spokesperson told the newspaper that slavery and colonialism were matters that King Charles III "takes profoundly seriously". It has also been revealed that the palace is supporting research into the British monarchy's historical links with slavery.</p>

<p>"Historic Royal Palaces is a partner in an independent research project, which began in October last year, that is exploring, among other issues, the links between the British monarchy and the transatlantic slave trade during the late 17th and 18th centuries," the palace has said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-04/kohinoor-diamond-crown_650x400_81460987923.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The report, from 1912, explains how priceless gems and jewels were extracted from India]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-reinstates-twitters-blue-bird-logo-removes-doge-meme-3928469]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Reinstates Twitter's Blue Bird Logo, Removes Doge Meme]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-reinstates-twitters-blue-bird-logo-removes-doge-meme-3928469]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:34:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[In another update to the microblogging website, the new owner has reinstated the original blue bird logo on the web version.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twitter's Chief Executive Officer Elon Musk stunned the world when he <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-replaces-twitters-blue-bird-logo-with-doge-meme-3918125" target="_self">changed the iconic blue bird</a> logo, which has served as a home button on the web version, with the "doge" meme of the Dogecoin cryptocurrency. Today, he changed it again, reverting to the original blue bird logo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, the original logo remained intact on Twitter's mobile app. Noticing the same, many people flooded social media with comments on the update of Twitter's logo.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="hvq9ougo" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/hvq9ougo_tw-logo_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Add image caption here</p>
</div>

<p>"It was for like 3 days, mine is back to shitty twitter logo, i preferred the doge one," said a user.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Twitter has reverted back to their original blue bird logo and as a result, the Dogecoin (DOGE) price has come down," said another person.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A third user added, "Finally! Twitter logo's back, goddamn those smol pixels on top of doge were annoying the ever living crap outta me."</p>

<p>"@elonmusk who was short of funds , changed twitter logo to doge , we started running after the hype and pumped doge coin and elon filled his bag and then again brought old twitter logo," said a person.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dogecoin soared by nearly 30 per cent, according to Bloomberg, after its picture suddenly appeared in the website interface. However, The 'Dog' meme as logo also sparked a range of comments on Twitter. "Elon Musk changed Twitter Logo to Doge. Is it fun Tuesday on Twitter?" one user asked. "Always some attention seeky nonsense happening on Twitter. Who cares if it's a bird or a doge," said another.</p>

<p>The billionaire had shared the screenshot of the March 26 conversation between him and an anonymous account where the latter was asking to change the bird logo to "doge." Sharing this post on Twitter, Musk wrote, "As promised."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As promised <a href="https://t.co/Jc1TnAqxAV">pic.twitter.com/Jc1TnAqxAV</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1642976364080041984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It is to be noted that <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/2023/3/31/23664041/elon-musk-twitter-checkmark-pay-play-subscription-blue-doge-dog-dogecoin-shiba-logo" target="_blank">Vox</a> had highlighted a "relevant" piece of news attributing Reuters reports that said Mr Musk is facing a $258 billion lawsuit alleging he ran a pyramid scheme to support dogecoin. The Twitter CEO's legal team had asked the court to dismiss the dogecoin suit a few days before the meme appeared on Twitter's site.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/hh3vsktg_elon-musk-afp_625x300_14_November_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Notably, the original logo remained intact on Twitter's mobile app.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-national-jailed-for-dozing-off-at-wheel-while-drunk-causing-chain-collision-in-singapore-3928410]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Indian National Jailed For Dozing Off At Wheel While Drunk In Singapore]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-national-jailed-for-dozing-off-at-wheel-while-drunk-causing-chain-collision-in-singapore-3928410]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:07:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[A 45-year-old Indian national has been sentenced to 10 months in jail in Singapore for falling asleep while driving a cement mixer under the influence of alcohol that caused a chain collision, injuring several people, according to a media report on F]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 45-year-old Indian national has been sentenced to 10 months in jail in Singapore for falling asleep while driving a cement mixer under the influence of alcohol that caused a chain collision, injuring several people, according to a media report on Friday.</p>

<p>Sowrirajulu Karunakaran last May was driving a cement mixer under the influence of alcohol when he fell asleep and collided with the rear of a lorry, reported The Straits Times newspaper.</p>

<p>This caused a chain collision involving four vehicles and injured several people, including a man who had pelvic fractures, the newspaper said.</p>

<p>Deputy Public Prosecutor said that Sowrirajulu was working for Infinite Logistics and Trading at the time of the accident in May 2022, it said Sowrirajulu pleaded guilty to a charge of driving under the influence of alcohol and causing grievous injury while driving without due care or reasonable consideration, the report said.</p>

<p>His blood ethanol concentration was found to be about three times that of the legal limit.</p>

<p>When he woke up, he realised the traffic light ahead was red and jammed on the brakes, but was unable to stop in time.</p>

<p>The two passengers of the lorry who were injured were both Indian nationals, the report said.</p>

<p>As a result of the damage caused to it, the lorry had to be disposed of by the company that owned it.</p>

<p>A 44-year-old Singaporean woman, who was driving a van that was hit by the lorry, had a minor head injury.</p>

<p>A third vehicle, a Toyota, had damage to its rear.</p>

<p>Sowrirajulu will also be disqualified from driving for 14 years after his release.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/jq3u9mls_jail-generic_625x300_19_October_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Sowrirajulu will be disqualified from driving for 14 years after his release. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/proud-day-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-on-mother-in-law-sudha-murty-receiving-padma-bhushan-3928383]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak Reacts To Post On Mother-In-Law Sudha Murty's Padma Award]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/proud-day-uk-pm-rishi-sunak-on-mother-in-law-sudha-murty-receiving-padma-bhushan-3928383]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:56:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[UK PM Rishi Sunak reacted to Akshata Murty's post and said it was a "proud day".]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Author and philanthropist Sudha Murty was recently conferred Padma Bhushan for her social work by President Droupadi Murmu. Her daughter, Akshata Murty, who is married to the UK Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, was one of the attendees of the ceremony. Later, she took to Instagram to share her "unspeakable pride" as her mother received the award for her extraordinary journey. UK PM Rishi Sunak reacted to the same and said it was a "proud day".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Yesterday I watched with unspeakable pride as my mother received the Padma Bhushan award from the President of India in recognition of her contributions in social work," wrote Ms Murty.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqsd46Rs5tZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqsd46Rs5tZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqsd46Rs5tZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqsd46Rs5tZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Akshata Murty (@akshatamurty_official)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Although Sudha Murty's charity and voluntary activities became her daughter's greatest influence, the UK First Lady claimed that her mother has had a remarkable journey. She emphasised several ways her mother has supported those less fortunate, including forming and managing charitable institutions for 25 years, sponsoring various programmes to increase literacy and assuring prompt relief for those living in remote areas of the country following natural disasters.</p>

<p>"Her example has put volunteering, learning and listening at the heart of how I hope to live in @10downingstreet," she said.</p>

<p>The First Lady of the United Kingdom further said that the ceremony was a "moving experience". "My mother doesn't live for recognition. The values my parents have instilled in my brother and me - hard work, humility, selflessness - mean she is always on to the next thing. But it was such a moving experience to see her have a moment of recognition yesterday," she concluded.</p>

<p>Reacting to the same, her husband and UK PM Rishi Sunak commented on the post, "A proud day," alongside two clapping emojis.</p>

<p>Sudha Murty's husband and Infosys founder, NR Narayana Murthy, son Rohan Murty and her sister Dr Sunanda Kulkarni were also present at the ceremony. A philanthropist, and renowned author, Sudhar Murty, was also the chairperson of the Infosys Foundation until December 2021.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/m9j8ij8_sudha-murty-_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Author and philanthropist Sudha Murty was recently conferred Padma Bhushan.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-sends-warships-aircraft-near-taiwan-for-2nd-day-after-us-hosts-its-leader-3928371]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[China Sends Warships, Aircraft Near Taiwan Again After US Hosts Its Leader]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-sends-warships-aircraft-near-taiwan-for-2nd-day-after-us-hosts-its-leader-3928371]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:50:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[China sent warships and aircraft near Taiwan for a second day on Friday, Taipei said, after President Tsai Ing-wen angered Beijing by meeting with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China sent warships and aircraft near Taiwan for a second day on Friday, Taipei said, after President Tsai Ing-wen angered Beijing by meeting with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.</p>

<p>Three Chinese warships sailed in waters surrounding the self-ruled island, while a fighter jet and an anti-submarine helicopter also crossed the island's air defence identification zone, Taiwan's Ministry of National Defence said.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, China's Shandong aircraft carrier, one of two in its naval fleet, sailed through Taiwan's southeastern waters on its way to the western Pacific, hours before Tsai met McCarthy in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Beijing, which views Taiwan as part of its territory, had repeatedly warned against the meeting, and reiterated on Thursday that it would take "forceful measures to firmly safeguard national sovereignty".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tsai told reporters her government was committed to ensuring "the free and democratic way of life of the people of Taiwan" before she left Los Angeles, where she was stopping on her way back from Latin America.</p>

<p>"We also hope to do our best to maintain peace and stability between the two sides," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last August, China deployed warships, missiles and fighter jets around Taiwan for its largest show of force in years following a trip to the island by McCarthy's predecessor Nancy Pelosi.</p>

<p>Its response to the Tsai-McCarthy meeting has so far been on a much lower level, but still left Taiwan on alert.</p>

<p>Premier Chen Chien-jen said on Friday that Taiwan's defence and security agencies were keeping a close eye on developments, and asked "the public to rest assured".&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Thursday, the defence ministry said three warships had been detected around the Taiwan Strait and one Chinese naval helicopter crossed the island's ADIZ.</p>

<p>The display prompted calls from the United States asking China "to cease its military, diplomatic and economic pressure against Taiwan and instead engage in meaningful diplomacy".</p>

<p>"We remain committed to maintaining open channels of communication so as to prevent the risk of any kind of miscalculation," State Department spokesman Vedant Patel told reporters.</p>

<p>'Quite common'</p>

<p>McCarthy, who is second in line for the US presidency, had originally planned to go to Taiwan himself but opted instead to meet Tsai in California.</p>

<p>The decision was viewed as a compromise that would underscore support for Taiwan but avoid inflaming tensions with China, a move analysts say has so far proven successful.</p>

<p>Tsai said on Thursday that it was "quite common for us to meet our US friends during transits," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I also hope the Chinese side can exercise self-restraint and don't overreact."&nbsp;</p>

<p>McCarthy had vowed that US arms sales to Taiwan -- which infuriate Chinese leadership -- would continue, in what he said was a proven strategy to dissuade aggression.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"And what we know through history, the best way to do that is supply the weapons that allow people to deter war," he said.</p>

<p>"It is a critical lesson that we learned through Ukraine, that the idea of just sanctions in the future is not going to stop somebody" who wants to wage war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Tsai acknowledged the weapons deal on Thursday but did not provide further details.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We have purchased arms from the US and we hope the arms will be delivered on time," she said.</p>

<p>Sanctions</p>

<p>On Friday, China slapped sanctions on Taipei's de facto ambassador to the United States, Hsiao Bi-khim, banning her from entering China and accusing her of "deliberately inciting cross-strait confrontation".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Beijing's foreign ministry also announced sanctions against the Hudson Institute, a Washington-based conservative think-tank, as well as the Ronald Reagan Presidential Library, for "providing a platform and facilitating Tsai Ing-wen's engagement in 'Taiwan separatism' activities in the United States".</p>

<p>The two organisations are now barred from engaging in transactions and cooperation with Chinese entities, while four individuals linked to them are blocked from entering or conducting business in China.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-01/9pcoi6fo_tsai-ing-wen-reuters_625x300_06_January_19.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Taiwan President Tsai Ing-wen angered Beijing by meeting with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bursting-with-pride-bill-gates-ex-wife-melinda-share-pics-with-newborn-granddaughter-3928255]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Bill Gates, Ex-Wife Melinda Share Pics With Newborn Granddaughter]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bursting-with-pride-bill-gates-ex-wife-melinda-share-pics-with-newborn-granddaughter-3928255]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:03:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Many people including Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai, Union Minister Smriti Irani and YouTuber Nas Daily congratulated the grandparents.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jennifer Gates, the eldest child of Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates and his ex-wife Melinda French Gates, welcomed her first child with husband Nayel Nassar last month. She took to Instagram to announce the happy news. The grandparents were elated by the announcement and have now shared pictures with their first grandchild on social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a picture posted by the Microsoft Co-founder on Instagram, he can be seen wearing a navy blue sweatshirt and pants and playfully touching his granddaughter's tiny fingers. The baby appears dressed in an adorable pink onesie. He captioned the post, "I can't wait to watch you discover the world."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1uaZr8dx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1uaZr8dx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1uaZr8dx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1uaZr8dx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Bill Gates (@thisisbillgates)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The new grandmother also shared a snap of herself holding her granddaughter on social media. Ms Melinda is seen holding her granddaughter close to her chest while smiling at the camera. She is sporting an orange top and black trousers. The philanthropist wrote in the caption, "There is nothing quite like holding your first grandchild It seems like just yesterday I was holding Jenn at this age. Now she has a baby of her own-and I am bursting with pride watching her and Nayel step into their new role as parents."</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1w_-Lb1k/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1w_-Lb1k/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1w_-Lb1k/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cqs1w_-Lb1k/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Melinda French Gates (@melindafrenchgates)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Many people including Nobel Peace Prize laureate Malala Yousafzai, Union Minister Smriti Irani and YouTuber Nas Daily congratulated the grandparents.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bill and Melinda Gates' eldest daughter Jennifer tied the knot with Nayel Nassar in 2021 at her home in Westchester, New York. Mr Nassar is an Egyptian equestrian.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reacting to the news of her daughter's pregnancy, Bill Gates wrote in a blog last year that he "started looking at the world through a new lens recently-when my older daughter gave me the incredible news that I'll become a grandfather next year".&nbsp;</p>

<p>He added, "Simply typing that phrase, 'I'll become a grandfather next year,' makes me emotional. And the thought gives a new dimension to my work. When I think about the world my grandchild will be born into, I'm more inspired than ever to help everyone's children and grandchildren have a chance to survive and thrive."</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/mqvvpj3_bill_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Bill and Melinda French Gates with their granddaughter.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bosses-try-to-lure-gen-z-workers-with-early-finish-fridays-3928178]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[UK Bosses Try To Lure Gen Z Workers With 'Early Finish Fridays']]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bosses-try-to-lure-gen-z-workers-with-early-finish-fridays-3928178]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 11:21:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[UK employers desperate to recruit and retain Gen Z workers are increasingly offering "early finish Fridays" in a bid to fill vacant roles amid an ongoing staff shortage crisis.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK employers desperate to recruit and retain Gen Z workers are increasingly offering "early finish Fridays" in a bid to fill vacant roles amid an ongoing staff shortage crisis.</p>

<p>Online jobs portal Adzuna has seen a sharp increase in postings offering shorter days on Friday, effectively meaning workers can start their weekends a few hours earlier. There were 1,426 job ads on the site citing "early finish Friday" this March, compared to only 583 in the same month five years earlier - before the Covid-19 pandemic upended working life.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The perk appears to be targeted at junior staff, in roles with salaries between &amp;#163;20,000 and &amp;#163;40,000 ($50,000), according to Adzuna data provided to Bloomberg. It's more prominent in certain industries, with Adzuna's live ads showing 348 early finish Friday jobs in engineering as of April 3. There were 207 similar perks offered for sales jobs, 156 in information technology roles and 90 for graduate positions.</p>

<p>Andrew Hunter, co-founder of Adzuna, said the shift reflects the fact that employees are "demanding more" from employers after the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"For jobseekers, a company offering early-finish Fridays signals that they are flexible in their attitude to working hours and care about their employees' wellbeing - two factors of utmost importance in today's jobs market," Hunter said in an emailed statement.</p>

<p>Employers offering the perk include several mid- to large-scale companies. Fashion supplier DCK Group includes an early start to the weekend in its list of benefits for a merchandising graduate position. Aerospace firm Raytheon Technologies Corp is offering the perk in a job ad for a contracts manager.</p>

<p>Companies have been trialing a variety of measures, including a four-day work week, to attract staff in the face of record vacancies.</p>

<p>Emma, a 21-year-old staffer at a music publishing firm in London, whose employer is planning to relax its working hours on Friday during July and August, said she is excited about the idea of finishing early and taking advantage of the better weather.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A formal - if temporary - reduction in working hours also means staff can take an extra day off work when booking holidays and it will only count for half a day, &nbsp;said Emma, who didn't want to use her full name when discussing her employer.</p>

<p>However, attempts to tinker with terms and conditions have not yet eased the UK's labor shortage problem. There are 216,000 fewer working age people in the workforce than before the pandemic, making Britain the only Group of Seven economy not to have recovered to pre-Covid levels.</p>

<p>In his Budget speech last month, Chancellor of the Exchequer Jeremy Hunt removed the lifetime allowance on UK pension savings in an effort to attract older workers back into the job market, a move that will benefit some of the country's wealthiest savers.</p>

<p>Some remain skeptical of the value of using benefits to attract younger staff. "At some point, you'll be doing things you don't like," Lewis Kemp of Manchester-based Lightbulb Media wrote on LinkedIn recently. "Being trusted, respected &amp; paid appropriately is worth much more than pizzas, holidays and 'early finish Fridays.'"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-01/b369q1jg_office-generic-istock_625x300_11_January_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[There were 1,426 job ads on the site citing "early finish Friday" this March.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>