<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>PC Matic Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Tech Tips and Tricks</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 14:27:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Torrent Usage Trends &amp; Statistics: A Year-By-Year Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/torrent-usage-trends-statistics-a-year-by-year-analysis/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/torrent-usage-trends-statistics-a-year-by-year-analysis/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Chad Rasnake]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 15:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PC Matic Blog]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66301</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The use of torrents has been a hot topic of debate for years, with some arguing that it’s a tool for piracy, while others defend it as a way to share large files. In this blog post, we’ll be analyzing the use of torrents by year, looking at how the trend has evolved over the &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/torrent-usage-trends-statistics-a-year-by-year-analysis/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Torrent Usage Trends &#38; Statistics: A Year-By-Year Analysis</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The use of torrents has been a hot topic of debate for years, with some arguing that it’s a tool for piracy, while others defend it as a way to share large files. In this blog post, we’ll be analyzing the use of torrents by year, looking at how the trend has evolved over the past decade.</p>



<p>Before we dive into the analysis, let’s define what torrents are. Torrents are a peer-to-peer (P2P) file sharing protocol that allows users to distribute and download large files quickly and efficiently. Instead of downloading a file from a single server, the file is divided into smaller pieces and distributed across a network of users, with each user sharing the parts they have already downloaded.</p>



<p>Now, let’s take a look at how the use of torrents has evolved over the years.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/Torrent-Data.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img width="1873" height="1027" src="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/Torrent-Data.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-66445" srcset="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/Torrent-Data.jpg 1873w, https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/Torrent-Data-768x421.jpg 768w, https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/Torrent-Data-1536x842.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1873px) 100vw, 1873px" /></a><figcaption><sub>Click the chart to enlarge</sub></figcaption></figure>



<p>A clear trend emerges after 2013 where we see a steep decline in torrent client usage. I hypothesize that this is due to the rise of inexpensive media streaming services. In 2023 people are just not downloading and storing large amounts of video on their devices. The convenience of streaming movies, tv, and music in high quality has nearly eliminated the need to keep space hogging files on personal devices. </p>



<h3>2010-2013: The Golden Age of Torrenting</h3>



<p>According to data from Google Trends, the popularity of torrents peaked in 2012 and has been declining ever since. In 2022, the search volume for torrents was about half of what it was in 2012. This could be due to the rise of streaming services like Netflix and Hulu, which offer a more convenient and legal way to access content.</p>



<p>Between 2010 and 2013, the use of torrents was at its peak. During this period, sites like The Pirate Bay, KickassTorrents, and ExtraTorrents were extremely popular, with millions of users downloading and sharing files on a daily basis. This was also the time when many popular TV shows like Breaking Bad, Game of Thrones, and The Walking Dead were at the height of their popularity, leading to a surge in torrent downloads.</p>



<h3>2014-2016: The Rise of Streaming</h3>



<p>In the mid-2010s, the popularity of streaming services like Netflix and Hulu started to increase, and many users began to move away from torrents in favor of these services. While torrents continued to be popular for downloading movies and TV shows that weren’t available on streaming services, the overall usage of torrents began to decline during this period. </p>



<h3>2017-2018: The Fall of Major Torrent Sites</h3>



<p>In 2017, KickassTorrents and ExtraTorrents were shut down by law enforcement, and The Pirate Bay faced numerous legal battles that led to its temporary shutdown. These events marked a significant blow to the torrent community, and many users began to migrate to alternative torrent sites or switch to other file sharing methods.</p>



<h3>2019-Present: Torrents Still Popular, but Facing Competition</h3>



<p>Today, torrents continue to be popular, with millions of users still downloading and sharing files on a daily basis. However, they are facing competition from other file sharing methods like cloud storage services and direct downloads. The rise of cryptocurrency mining has also led to the use of torrents for distributing mining software and malware, further complicating the picture.</p>



<p>Additionally, different torrent clients have varying levels of popularity. uTorrent is one of the most popular torrent clients, with a market share of around 8% as of 2021. BitTorrent, another popular client, has a market share of around 3%, while qBittorrent has a market share of around 2%. Transmission, a lightweight client popular among Linux users, has a market share of around 1%, and Deluge has a market share of around 0.5%. These statistics are based on estimates and can vary depending on the source.</p>



<p>The use of torrents has evolved significantly over the past decade. While they were once the go-to method for downloading and sharing large files, they are now facing competition from streaming services, cloud storage, and other file sharing methods. Despite this, torrents continue to be a popular and widely used tool for file sharing, and it’s likely that they will continue to be so in the foreseeable future. The popularity of different torrent clients can also fluctuate over time, as new players enter the market and user preferences change.</p>



<p>Now, as content becomes more fragmented across multiple streaming platforms, users are forced to purchase multiple services which sometimes add up to the prices that made them pirate content via torrents in the first place. Will we see a resurgence in torrent usage as more and more streaming platforms are created?</p>



<h3>Top Torrent Sites 2023</h3>



<p>Despite the decline in overall torrent usage, some sites continue to attract a large number of visitors. According to torrentfreak.com the top torrent sites as of 2023 are:</p>



<ol><li><strong>YTS:</strong> This site specializes in high-quality movie torrents and is known for its user-friendly interface.</li><li><strong>1337x</strong>: This site has gained popularity in recent years for its user-friendly interface and large selection of torrents.</li><li><strong>NYAA</strong>: The most popular Anime torrenting site.</li><li><strong>RARBG</strong>: &nbsp;This site has remained steady over the past year. The site operates from several popular domain names, but only the one with the most traffic is taken into account for this list. RARBG was founded in 2008 and specializes in high-quality video releases.</li><li><strong>The Pirate Bay</strong>: This site has been around since 2003 and is known for its vast collection of torrents, including movies, TV shows, music, and software.</li></ol>



<h3>Top Torrent Clients 2023</h3>



<p>When it comes to downloading torrents, there are many clients to choose from:</p>



<ol><li><strong>qBittorrent</strong>: This open-source client is known for its simplicity and low resource usage.</li><li><strong>Deluge</strong>: Another open-source client, Deluge is highly customizable and offers advanced features like encryption and proxy support.</li><li><strong>uTorrent</strong>: One of the most popular clients, uTorrent is known for its speed and user-friendly interface.</li><li><strong>BitTorrent</strong>: This client is similar to uTorrent but is more focused on the business and enterprise markets.</li><li><strong>Transmission</strong>: A lightweight client that is popular among Mac users, Transmission is known for its simplicity and ease of use.</li></ol>



<h3>Mac vs. Windows</h3>



<p>When it comes to using torrents, there are some differences between Mac and Windows users. While both operating systems can be used to download and share torrents, there are some variations in the software available and the level of security.</p>



<p>Mac users are generally considered to be less vulnerable to viruses and malware than Windows users, but this doesn&#8217;t mean that Macs are immune to security threats. Some Mac users may still be at risk if they download torrents from untrusted sources or if they fail to keep their antivirus software up to date.</p>



<p>On the other hand, Windows users are generally considered to be more vulnerable to security threats than Mac users. This is partly due to the fact that Windows is a more widely used operating system and therefore a bigger target for malware creators. However, Windows users can still protect themselves by using antivirus software, avoiding downloading torrents from untrusted sources, and being vigilant when browsing the internet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/torrent-usage-trends-statistics-a-year-by-year-analysis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC Matic Blocks Compromised 3CXDesktopApp</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/3cx-desktop-app-compromise/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/3cx-desktop-app-compromise/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 01:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[The Pit Blog]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66438</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In late March 2023, PC Matic was alerted to malicious activity coming from 3CXDesktopApp, a phone system software created by business communication software developer 3CX. What is 3CXDesktopApp? 3CXDesktopApp is a a Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) desktop client created by business communication software developer 3CX. First published in 2006, 3CX was one of the &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/3cx-desktop-app-compromise/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">PC Matic Blocks Compromised 3CXDesktopApp</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In late March 2023, PC Matic was alerted to malicious activity coming from 3CXDesktopApp, a phone system software created by business communication software developer 3CX.</p>



<h2>What is 3CXDesktopApp?</h2>



<p>3CXDesktopApp is a a Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) desktop client created by business communication software developer 3CX. First published in 2006, 3CX was one of the first VoIP clients used in Microsoft Windows environments. Since then, 3CX now works in both Windows and MacOS environments, and has a separate client for desktop and mobile.</p>



<h2>How did 3CXDesktopApp become compromised?</h2>



<p>Initial <a href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/blog/crowdstrike-detects-and-prevents-active-intrusion-campaign-targeting-3cxdesktopapp-customers/">reports</a> revealed a trojanized version of 3CXDesktopApp coming from the digitally signed, but compromised, 3CXDesktopApp client. <a href="https://www.3cx.com/blog/news/desktopapp-security-alert/">According to Pierre Jourdan</a>, CISO of 3CX, “the issue appears to be one of the bundled libraries that we compiled into the Windows Electron App via GIT.” Simply put, the trojan was directly injected into the 3CXDesktopApp github repository code base, compromising the entire library. The 3CXDesktopApp installer essentially became a trigger for a multi-stage attack chain that uses shellcode to load 2 compromised DLL second-stage payloads that collect system and browser information, commonly referred to as an infostealer. It does not appear that the main executable, 3cxdesktopapp.exe, was compromised.</p>



<h2>Who is responsible for the supply chain attack?</h2>



<p>While the investigation is still continuing, most indications currently point towards Labyrinth Chollima, a state-sponsored hacker group connected to North Korean-backed Lazarus Group. Labyrinth Chollima and Lazarus Group have a long history of executing similar complex supply chain attacks.</p>



<h2>Who is affected by the 3CXDesktopApp compromise?</h2>



<p>3CXDesktopApp is used by more than 12 million daily users across 600,000 companies around the world, including many big names like American Express, Coca-Cola, McDonald’s, BMW, Honda, Air France, Toyota, Mercedes-Benz, IKEA, and more. While the compromise mostly affected Windows and Mac users who ran the 3CXDesktopApp installer, the full extent of the breach is still being analyzed. 3CX users utilizing the PWA web-based app were not affected as the malicious files were only found with the desktop application. Most mobile devices, including iOS and Android were not affected.</p>



<h2>How does the 3CXDesktopApp compromise affect PC Matic users?</h2>



<p>PC Matic users should not be affected by the 3CXDesktopApp compromise. PC Matic’s software utilizes a default deny strategy called application allowlisting, meaning any known-bad or unknown files are not able to execute. During the early stages of the attack, it was possible for the 3CXDesktopApp to execute because the main .exe file was not compromised. However, the 2 compromised DLLs were not able to execute. While 3CXDesktopApp was likely not functional because of the missing DLLs, the malware was not able to execute and infect devices. Directly following the attack, all software coming from 3CX was updated to a known-bad status to ensure further attacks would not occur. Since then, 3CX has assured the compromised files have been removed. As an additional precaution, we have temporarily updated all 3CX software to unknown in the Global Allowlist to guarantee safety by default, while still enabling businesses to allow 3CX locally if the software is crucial for business operation. Do so with caution, as the attack is still under investigation. The 2 malicious DLLs remain as known-bad and will not be able to execute should any future attacks occur.</p>



<h2>How does the 3CXDesktopApp compromise affect users who do not have PC Matic?</h2>



<p>If you are utilizing another default deny solution, you will most likely be unaffected as well, but you should verify that the 2 malicious DLLs are not being executed with the installer. PC Matic’s Malware Research team analyzes threats and updates the global allowlist in real-time, while other default-deny solutions rely on a traditional manual whitelisting approach. If 3CXDesktopApp was <em>not</em> on your whitelist before the compromise, you should be safe. If it was on your whitelist before the compromise, and it was not proactively removed, you will likely be affected. Furthermore, if you are not using a default deny solution, you will want to verify that the installer did not run. Specific EDR solutions like SentinelOne and CrowdStrike proactively caught and eliminated the threat, but most antivirus solutions likely did not catch the malicious DLLs before execution, leaving you vulnerable to the attack.</p>



<h2>How can I stay protected against future attacks?</h2>



<p>The only way to guarantee protection against threat actors is by using cybersecurity software that utilizes a default deny approach for your endpoints. Application allowlisting software is specifically built to prevent unknown or known-bad files from executing, ensuring that potentially malicious files don’t get the chance to infect your devices or network. In this case, even though the main executable still had a legitimate, signed digital signature, the 2 malicious DLLs were not known and therefore would not have executed. You should also pay attention to indicators of compromise, such as regular crashing, sudden slow performance due to increased resource usage, or spammy popups.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/3cx-desktop-app-compromise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC Matic Receives 5-Star Rating in the 2023 CRN Partner Program Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/pc-matic-receives-5-star-rating-in-the-2023-crn-partner-program-guide/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/pc-matic-receives-5-star-rating-in-the-2023-crn-partner-program-guide/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 17:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Business Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66429</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[When it comes to cybersecurity software, finding the right solution can be a very difficult task, which is especially true for MSPs, resellers, and affiliates who need to cater their offerings to a large variety of customers. Beyond the quality of the software, the partnership with the vendor plays a big role in the solutions &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/pc-matic-receives-5-star-rating-in-the-2023-crn-partner-program-guide/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">PC Matic Receives 5-Star Rating in the 2023 CRN Partner Program Guide</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When it comes to cybersecurity software, finding the right solution can be a very difficult task, which is especially true for MSPs, resellers, and affiliates who need to cater their offerings to a large variety of customers. Beyond the quality of the software, the partnership with the vendor plays a big role in the solutions being offered, and rightfully so.</p>



<p>With that in mind, PC Matic is honored to be awarded with a 5-star rating in the 2023 CRN Partner Program Guide, reaffirming not just the quality of our Application Allowlisting software, but also the relationship we form with each of our partners.</p>



<h2>What is the CRN Partner Program Guide?</h2>



<p>In a nutshell, the CRN Partner Program Guide is a collection of the best IT vendors for each year. Organizations need a lot of IT vendors that provide services, software, and digital solutions, and it can be tough to know which IT vendors each business should work with given the complexity of modern digital environments.</p>



<p>The CRN Partner Program Guide cuts through all of that and provides business owners with the best solution providers and strategic service operators in the industry. By reading the Partner Program Guide, businesses can determine which organizations and software they should use to reach their business goals and/or help their customers reach their business goals as well.</p>



<p>More specifically, the CRN Partner Program Guide provides a comprehensive look at:</p>



<ul><li>What a vendor has to offer to help partners be more successful in their chosen endeavors. This includes margins, financial incentives, training and certifications, and more</li><li>The reputation of each IT vendor, and why they have received a high rating from the CRN organization overall</li></ul>



<p>In essence, the CRN Partner Program Guide is intended to assist with evaluating which IT vendors a business should align with, not just for the best product, but also for a mutually beneficial partnership. Each year, the guide comes out with a fresh batch of ratings and information. Every new guide is based on detailed applications that are submitted by over 300 vendors and solutions providers.</p>



<p>PC Matic has appeared on the CRN Partner Program Guide previously across several years, and our 5-star rating in 2023 is an indication of the dedication we provide to helping each of our partners.</p>



<h3>What Are 5-Star Ratings?</h3>



<p>Five-star ratings, also called profiles, are the highest-rated vendor channel programs that CRN was able to find. These are programs that offer comprehensive, high-quality collections of training, services, incentives, and benefits. In other words, they are the best of the best and businesses would do well to pay attention to, and consider partnering with, five-star-rated providers.</p>



<h2>Reasons PC Matic Received a 5-Star Rating</h2>



<p>The CRN Partner Program Guide takes a lot of things into account when deciding which vendors and security solutions providers receive five-star ratings. There were several reasons why PC Matic received a five-star rating this year and in previous years.</p>



<h3>Constantly expanding offerings</h3>



<p>Perhaps the best reason to join the PC Matic Partner Program is our commitment to constant improvement. The digital world is constantly evolving, making the need for improved cybersecurity more important than ever, and PC Matic is always looking to push the bar higher. In 2022, PC Matic launched several new features, achieved FedRAMP authorization, and deployed the most robust integrations marketplace in the industry, enabling our partners to register new customers and increase incremental revenue.</p>



<h3>Elite sales and technical training</h3>



<p>All partners of the PC Matic Partner Program receive nothing but the absolute best when it comes to training resources. Our team is constantly available to help you learn more about the product or improve sales. Furthermore, upon entry into the Partner Program, all partners are provided with an unparalleled complementary onboarding process. </p>



<h3>Unrivaled growth</h3>



<p>2022 saw PC Matic&#8217;s Partner Program achieve record-breaking levels, partnering with thousands of new MSPs across the world and protecting hundreds of thousands of endpoints and servers globally. </p>



<h2>What is the PC Matic Partner Program?</h2>



<p>The PC Matic Partner Program is an extension of the core PC Matic Application Allowlisting suite that enables MSPs, resellers, and affiliates to manage multiple customers under a single pane of glass. Put simply, the PC Matic Partner Program enables MSPs, resellers, and affiliates to offer elite cybersecurity solutions while greatly improving their own profits and efficiency.</p>



<h3>Benefits of the PC Matic Partner Program</h3>



<p>Every partner in the PC Matic Partner Program receives the following benefits:</p>



<ul><li>Global allowlist of over 22 billion verified software files, processes, and certificates</li><li>USA based Malware Research team to assist with continuous updates of global allowlist</li><li>Real-time local allowlist remediation across the entire network</li><li>Automatic default-deny for unauthorized scripts commands out of the box</li><li>Digital certificate local allowlisting for access control enforcement</li><li>No supply chain risk &#8211; 100% made and supported in America</li><li>Multi-tenant and fully white-labelable console</li><li>Protection for Windows, Mac, and Linux devices</li><li>Dedicated onboarding support</li><li>Flexible payments</li></ul>



<p>The PC Matic Partner Program is available for enterprise, SMB, SLED, and federal customers, enabling partners to work with virtually any customer.</p>



<p>Many partners find PC Matic to be a quick road to incremental revenue. With tier-based pricing and dynamic lead sharing, business owners can drive profits to their enterprises without having to sacrifice extra time or money. They can find customers just as quickly as before while keeping their existing ones, all without compromising security at any point. Good security will quickly lead to a good reputation, as well, which may help retain customers over the long term.</p>



<p>Then there’s increased efficiency. With the PC Matic Partner Program, organizations benefit from cloud-based management, plus built-in remote monitoring. In this way, business owners don’t need to worry about remote attacks catching them off guard. Furthermore, they can rest easy without having to react to malware. PC Matic uses prevention-first security principles, focusing on stopping cyber attacks from occurring in the first place instead of scrambling to fix things after they are already broken.</p>



<p>With all of these elements, business owners can focus on keeping customers secure, satisfied, and safe, all while driving increased revenue to their own organizations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/pc-matic-receives-5-star-rating-in-the-2023-crn-partner-program-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Should You Use a Managed Service Provider (MSP) for Your Cybersecurity?</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/why-should-you-use-a-managed-service-provider-msp-for-your-cybersecurity/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/why-should-you-use-a-managed-service-provider-msp-for-your-cybersecurity/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 13:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Business Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66366</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[There are a lot of good reasons to switch to a managed service provider. Most people, and businesses, know about the benefits of having a managed service provider for IT services instead of using an in-house IT team, but did you also know that managed service providers can help improve your cybersecurity? It does depend &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/why-should-you-use-a-managed-service-provider-msp-for-your-cybersecurity/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Why Should You Use a Managed Service Provider (MSP) for Your Cybersecurity?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There are a lot of good reasons to switch to a managed service provider. Most people, and businesses, know about the benefits of having a managed service provider for IT services instead of using an in-house IT team, but did you also know that managed service providers can help improve your cybersecurity?</p>



<p>It does depend a little on the managed service provider you choose, of course. Not every MSP will offer the same services, and cybersecurity can be a complicated service that not every MSP wants to offer.</p>



<p>But, when it comes to improving day-to-day security, information protection, and avoiding system downtime, having a good managed service provider can work wonders.</p>



<p>Here’s what you need to know about managed service provider, the kinds of services you can get, and why it’s a good idea to use an MSP for your cybersecurity needs.</p>



<h2>What Is A Managed Service Provider?</h2>



<p>On the most basic level a managed service provider is a third-party company that manages a specific set of services for companies, and, sometimes, individuals. They have a service level agreement for the specific services they provide, from IT infrastructure maintenance to help desk services.</p>



<p>One of the big advantages of using an MSP is outsourcing IT support, getting remote monitoring for your infrastructure, and improving system scalability if you expect your IT needs to grow over time.</p>



<p>There are a lot of good reasons to plan on outsourcing IT services in your business model, so let’s dig in and talk more about the specific services an MSP can offer, and then specifically why using an MSP is good for your cybersecurity.</p>



<h2>What Kinds Of Services Do Managed Service Providers Offer?</h2>



<p>MSPs started in the 1990s offering remote application hosting, and then later providing remote support for IT infrastructure. But, as more and more companies started outsourcing their IT needs to MSPs, more and more companies started branching out and offering different levels of services to differentiate themselves from their competition.</p>



<p>These days, as cloud services are more common and IT infrastructure is getting more complicated and <em>critical</em> for the day to day function of businesses, MSPs offer a wider range of services than ever.</p>



<p>That’s good news for businesses and individuals who want to use managed service providers because it means that there are more benefits of managed service providers than there used to be, more competitive pricing, and it’s easier to find the exact suite of services you need.</p>



<p>Here are some of the common services MSPs provide today:</p>



<ul><li>Handle IT infrastructure, updates, maintenance, and improvements</li><li>Technical support and help desk</li><li>Cybersecurity monitoring and software</li><li>Manage user access and accounts access</li><li>Compliance and risk management</li><li>Payroll services</li><li>Contract management</li><li>and more</li></ul>



<p>But one of the biggest advantages that you get when you work with an MSP is top of the line IT professionals who focus on implementing IT systems that improve end-user experience, and work to stay up to date on the latest improvements in cloud computing, cybersecurity, and reducing the risk of serious cyber attacks.</p>



<h2>How A Managed Service Provider Can Improve Your Cybersecurity</h2>



<p>Modern cybersecurity is complicated, and there are always new ways hackers and cybercriminals are finding to get into IT systems.</p>



<p>Medium-size businesses and small businesses are particularly common targets because cybercriminals assume they have the capital to buy their way out of an attack if their systems are taken hostage, but are unlikely to have the expertise to keep their systems safe.</p>



<p>Worse, there is always new technology and new techniques being discovered to help breach online security systems.</p>



<p>Staying up to date with the changes in cybersecurity is time-consuming, difficult, and can often take a team of professionals with different kinds of expertise.</p>



<p>That’s a lot to ask from small and medium businesses, especially if you use cloud computing services, or if your business needs to meet higher security requirements because of the type of data you work with.</p>



<p>For example, healthcare companies have a responsibility to provide a high level of security and better firewalls to protect personal patient information because of HIPAA regulations.</p>



<p>Outsourcing these kinds of high demand concerns can be a lot more affordable than having a full-time IT department handle it internally, and can often actually improve your cybersecurity and threat response times.</p>



<h2>Key Benefits Of Having A Managed Service Provider For Large And Small Businesses</h2>



<p>There are a lot of potential benefits to switching to an MSP for your IT support services, no matter what level of IT support you need or what size business you run.</p>



<p>Here are some of the key benefits of having a managed IT services provider, especially when it comes to your cybersecurity needs.</p>



<h3>Stay On Top Of The Latest Technology Advancements</h3>



<p>One of the biggest things you need to maintain business continuity is to stay on top of technology advancements, software updates, and the latest in cyber security.</p>



<p>Having your own IT team can help with that, but most in-house IT teams end up spending more time working on business infrastructure, and less time researching the latest updates.</p>



<p>MSPs are able to keep their staff up to date with the latest advancements in technology, of all types, because that’s one of their core business responsibilities.</p>



<p>Since it’s their job to stay on top of these advancements, they can pass on that expertise to your business. Plus, MSPs are able to better evaluate your business needs and help adapt your existing infrastructure for the advancements that will most benefit your business.</p>



<h3>Maintain A Top Of The Line Security Service</h3>



<p>One of the big challenges with cybersecurity is that the security risks and challenges are always changing, and every software update comes with some risk of new vulnerabilities in your system.</p>



<p>Staying on top of the latest security threats while simultaneously keeping your IT infrastructure working the way it should can be difficult, and is yet another full time job for in house professionals.</p>



<p>Having an MSP optimize and monitor your system in real time can help keep malware risk to a minimum, and to eliminate malware that does get through before it can cause a problem or access critical systems.</p>



<h3>Improved Efficiency And Up Time</h3>



<p>Network monitoring can help make sure your system stays up and running longer, while having an MSP automate and run updates when you aren’t using those systems.</p>



<p>They can also help improve efficiency by recommending specific software that better suits your needs, or setting up internal networks to keep your systems communicating faster.</p>



<p>Even if you aren’t looking for software improvements or recommendations, having an MSP take care of your system can help reduce slowdowns and keep it running the way it’s supposed to longer.</p>



<h3>Easier Automation Opportunities</h3>



<p>One of the best ways to improve efficiency and increase profits, no matter what size business you’re running, is to increase automation.</p>



<p>The more you’re able to automate the less time you have to spend manually generating information or looking for answers in your system.</p>



<p>MSPs can help automate reporting processes and many other systems your business relies on. Chances are that you’ll be surprised by how many things can be effectively automated, at least partially, and how it can improve your business efficiency.</p>



<h3>Disaster Recovery Services</h3>



<p>Not every MSP will offer disaster recovery services, but this can be an important part of keeping your business afloat no matter what happens.</p>



<p>Having secure data backups, recovery services that can access your system after a crisis can give you a lot of added security when you’re dealing with a natural disaster.</p>



<p>There are a lot of different ways to protect your business before a disaster, having an MSP help with your IT management and security is a big part of that.</p>



<h3>Cut IT Staff Costs</h3>



<p>A lot of businesses and individuals worry about spending too much on IT services when they hire an MSP. The thing is, having a MSP is often more affordable as well as more effective than having an internal IT department.</p>



<p>This is because you only get the services you need as you need them. You only pay for the time you need spent on your IT systems.</p>



<p>A good MSP will help recommend exactly the kind of services you need, the amount of time you need every month, and the amount of preventive maintenance that will help keep your business working at peak efficiency.</p>



<h3>Better Protection From Cyber Attacks</h3>



<p>Cyber attacks are often creative, difficult to come back from, and can cause extensive problems, including potential liability for lost or stolen information.</p>



<p>Having real time monitoring to help prevent attacks, to detect them when they happen, and to close off access so that your critical business information is protected, you’ll be in good shape.</p>



<h3>Avoid The Break/Fix Model</h3>



<p>One of the top reasons to work with an MSP is to avoid the break/fix model of IT services.</p>



<p>Break/fix is when you only pay for IT services when something is already broken, paying a professional to come in and fix whatever has gone wrong.</p>



<p>The problem with this model is that it increases downtime, can be more expensive than preventive maintenance, and that there’s no incentive for the IT professionals who fix your problems to prevent those problems from happening in the first place.</p>



<p>Having an MSP that’s paid regularly gives them an incentive to keep your systems up and running and make sure you’re satisfied with the services being provided. That means greater efficiency, more preventive maintenance, and more reason to research and recommend the best systems for your needs.</p>



<h2>Are Managed Service Providers Only For Businesses?</h2>



<p>Typically managed service providers work with businesses of all sizes to meet their technical needs and maintain their IT systems.</p>



<p>However, with the increase in personal technologies and devices, and increased use of home networks and complicated systems, there are some individuals who also hire MSPs, and some MSPs that offer in-home services.</p>



<p>That isn’t the norm, but if you’re looking for an MSP that can work with your home system, provide maintenance and schedule updates, as well as troubleshooting compatibility issues and recommending better equipment, there are some options out there.</p>



<p>That said, MSPs are generally better value for businesses, while individual users might be better off working with IT contractors on a as-needed basis simply because of the difference in scale of demand and how often those kinds of services are likely to be necessary.</p>



<h2>Wrap Up</h2>



<p>Managed Service Providers (MSPs) are a great way for businesses of all sizes to maintain cost-efficient IT teams with diverse skillsets. Regarding cybersecurity specifically, the expertise of MSPs ensure that their clients are always following best practices and using the most up-to-date technologies since they follow industry developments much more closely than most internal teams can. Furthermore, many MSPs form partnerships with the vendors they recommend which may provide them with exclusive discounts, rapid support, and early access to new features. When thinking about your cybersecurity stack and how you want to set it up, consider weighing the pros and cons of using a Managed Service Provider against using an internal team to determine which path is best for your organization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/why-should-you-use-a-managed-service-provider-msp-for-your-cybersecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Android Update Addresses Critical Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/new-android-update-addresses-critical-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/new-android-update-addresses-critical-vulnerabilities/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Home Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66358</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Google is typically closemouthed about known vulnerabilities, patches, and what kinds of malware they are countering at any given time. Some of that is to protect android users, by avoiding letting hackers and other bad actors know about critical vulnerabilities they might not have already found, but it can also mean that android users may &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/new-android-update-addresses-critical-vulnerabilities/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">New Android Update Addresses Critical Vulnerabilities</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Google is typically closemouthed about known vulnerabilities, patches, and what kinds of malware they are countering at any given time. Some of that is to protect android users, by avoiding letting hackers and other bad actors know about critical vulnerabilities they might not have already found, but it can also mean that android users may not always pay attention to the security updates they need to keep their devices safe.</p>



<p>If you are an android user running android versions 11, 12, 12L, or 13 and haven’t already updated your device after the most recent patch, you should do so immediately.</p>



<p>You can check to see if your device has updated recently, and see what android version your device is using, by checking the About Phone, About Device, or About Software tab in your device settings.</p>



<p>Here’s what you need to know about the latest android security bulletin, the most recent security patch, and what we know about the vulnerabilities being patched.</p>



<h2>Android Patch Fixes 2 Critical Security Vulnerabilities and Many High Severity Vulnerabilities</h2>



<p>It’s very rare for patches to come out that address only a couple of security vulnerabilities. Almost every security patch is going to have a wide range of mitigation tasks included, which patch low-risk vulnerabilities along with critical vulnerabilities.</p>



<p>Most users should be concerned about critical vulnerabilities, while other security issues are less important but still included in information disclosure messages and the android security log just in case they are relevant or more important for some users.</p>



<p>The most recent round of security patches, which came out on March 5th, 2023, patched two critical vulnerabilities: CVE-2023-20951 and CVE-2023-20954, which are both RCE, or remote code execution vulnerabilities.</p>



<p>Remote code execution vulnerabilities are especially important because, as in this case, they can sometimes be allow for remote code execution without needing any additional execution privileges.</p>



<p>Basically, that means that the vulnerability would allow a hacker to execute, or use, inserted code without requiring the user to approve that execution, often without any direct interaction at all.</p>



<p>That means that these kinds of cybersecurity threats may exist on your mobile device without you doing anything &#8211; which can also make them difficult to trace. Often, these remote code execution vulnerabilities can allow malware to be installed without the knowledge of the user.</p>



<p>Fortunately, these two critical vulnerabilities have been closed assuming you’ve downloaded the most recent patch.</p>



<p>In addition, this security update also patched CVE-2022-33213 and CVE-2022-33256, which are both memory corruption vulnerabilities. These kinds of vulnerabilities crop up when the memory is altered without an explicit assignment, and how and where that happens can open up a variety of vulnerabilities that hackers can exploit to do a range of things.</p>



<p>There were quite a few other vulnerabilities patched in this most recent update. For a more detailed changelog, or to learn more about the specific vulnerabilities that have been patched, you can look at the <a href="https://source.android.com/docs/security/bulletin/2023-03-01">March Android Security Bulletin</a>.</p>



<p>Just remember that Google tends to keep vulnerability information relatively limited to help avoid giving away information that could help hackers exploit the vulnerabilities before everyone’s devices are updated.</p>



<h3>What Is Considered A Critical Vulnerability On Android Devices?</h3>



<p>Critical vulnerabilities are vulnerabilities that can potentially give hackers a high level of access or control over the affected devices. Sometimes these can allow the installation of ransomware, which give hackers the option of making a device unusable or wiping data unless the user agrees to certain terms.</p>



<p>Serious ransomware attacks on large systems have made this kind of attack particularly threatening, but they aren’t the only options.</p>



<p>Critical vulnerabilities may also allow denial of service attacks, or DoS attacks, which allow hackers to deny access to your device. However, these don’t always give away any data or information stored on the device &#8211; they’re more of an inconvenience unless there is other malware also mining for data or otherwise exploiting the device.</p>



<p>Generally, a critical vulnerability means that the device can be entirely controlled in some way by the hacker. They can involve elevation of privilege once the malware is installed, and often work without needing the user do to anything to trigger the attack.</p>



<p>The most threatening of these are so-called zero-day vulnerabilities. That just means that the security team or security researchers that have identified a vulnerability have had 0 days to work on the problem. A zero-day vulnerability may also mean that hackers have identified and used the vulnerability before the security researchers involved in protecting a system have a chance to fix it.</p>



<p>Some vulnerabilities may come through the Google Play store on Android, but other system connections, including Bluetooth, may also be vulnerable if you have an out-of-date Android system.</p>



<h2>Are Android Phones More Vulnerable Than Competitors?</h2>



<p>Generally, yes, Android phones and other devices are more vulnerable than Apple, Microsoft Windows, or Linux devices. Apple’s IOS is widely considered the least vulnerable, but there are a range of reasons for the different vulnerabilities.</p>



<p>One of the key problems that Android faces are coding problems and vulnerabilities that came along with 3rd party programs.</p>



<p>There are a large number of known system components that are potentially vulnerable, and while a patch-level security update can help, it won’t necessarily address the underlying problem that caused the vulnerability in the first place.</p>



<h3>Which Mobile OS Is Considered The Most Vulnerable</h3>



<p>There are two different ways to think about phone cybersecurity when you’re trying to figure out which systems are the most vulnerable.</p>



<ol><li>The number of vulnerabilities that have been identified/exploited/fixed in the OS</li><li>The severity of the specific known vulnerabilities in each OS.</li></ol>



<p>Both of these measures are important, but they can lead to very different results depending on what you’re looking for and trying to protect against.</p>



<p>For instance, some people might be willing to buy a phone with more known security concerns if those vulnerabilities are generally low-risk. I.E. someone using that particular vulnerability is unlikely to come away with personal information about the person using the phone, or be able to access more protected information stored in the phone, like payment information or bank account access.</p>



<p>Both Android and Apple mobile OS are being hit with an increasing number of hacking attempts, with more and more people seeking out vulnerabilities. That means that there are going to be more vulnerabilities found, more critical security patches released, and an increased rate of high-severity vulnerabilities found.</p>



<p>Ultimately, there is no such thing as a perfectly secure operating system, and new security issues may be introduced with every patch, including patches meant to keep your mobile devices safer.</p>



<p>That said, Android operating systems are generally considered more vulnerable than Apple operating systems. There are generally more security threats to android smartphones, especially devices running the older Android 10 OS.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, Android also tends to experience more severe vulnerabilities, according to top security researchers. That means that Android users, including Samsung, Pixel devices, and other mobile devices running Android OS need to be especially careful about keeping their devices up to date and monitoring for security patches that help protect their devices.</p>



<h2>Can You Skip Android Security Updates?</h2>



<p>We don’t recommend it, and, past a certain point, you may not be allowed to skip critical updates.</p>



<p>There are a few reasons for this. For one thing, if you skip an update that contains a critical security patch, like the most recent security update did, your phone or device is significantly more likely to end up infected with malware. Depending on the program, you may not even notice a change in your device’s function, meanwhile malicious code is mining your data, gathering personal information about you and your accounts, or opening up new vulnerabilities in your device’s operating system.</p>



<p>Even if you aren’t concerned with malware, at a certain point your device will be <em>forced</em> to update. This happens in part because of new regulations after several companies and the NHS had critical systems attacked with ransomware that used a known vulnerability that had been patched months before the attack took place. Because those companies opted out of updates that might have caused problems in their internal systems, they were left vulnerable in a way they shouldn’t have.</p>



<p>So now, software companies are required to force updates when there are critical fixes, they can no longer allow consumers to opt-out in order to prevent the kinds of massive disruption that happens when malware makes it into a large company’s systems.</p>



<p>Not every update is considered critical this way, but your Android device will likely need to install <em>all </em>the skipped updates every time a critical security update is required. So rather than skipping small updates and leaving your phone vulnerable, and then having to wait for them all to be installed when a critical update is released, it’s better to accept updates as they are released.</p>



<p>Better yet, you should be installing security updates on your Android device as soon as they are made available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/new-android-update-addresses-critical-vulnerabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prêmio AV-TEST  2022 para PC Matic</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/premio-av-test-2022-para-pc-matic/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/premio-av-test-2022-para-pc-matic/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Solange Cheng]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 19:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Portuguese (BR)]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66356</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Com o Prêmio AV-TEST 2022, o Instituto AV-TEST declara os melhores produtos da área de Segurança de TI. O instituto de pesquisa mundialmente conhecido e renomado para segurança de TI examinou a maior parte dos produtos de segurança no mercado para usuários domésticos e usuários corporativos por um ano inteiro em seus laboratórios. A avaliação &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/premio-av-test-2022-para-pc-matic/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Prêmio AV-TEST  2022 para PC Matic</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Com o Prêmio AV-TEST 2022, o Instituto AV-TEST declara os melhores produtos da área de Segurança de TI. O instituto de pesquisa mundialmente conhecido e renomado para segurança de TI examinou a maior parte dos produtos de segurança no mercado para usuários domésticos e usuários corporativos por um ano inteiro em seus laboratórios. A avaliação do prêmio foi baseada em todas as descobertas que os especialistas obtiveram e registraram dentro do ciclo de um ano para cada produto. Com seu prêmio, o AV-TEST homenageia produtos que foram capazes de alcançar resultados consistentes índices de pico nos resultados de longo prazo. Os Prêmios 2022 nas duas categorias de teste de Melhor.Desempenho para usuários consumidores e melhor proteção avançada para usuários consumidores sob o Windows vai para PC Matic. Desempenho para usuários consumidores e melhor proteção avançada para usuários consumidores sob o Windows vai para PC Matic.</p>



<p><strong>Prêmio AV-TEST – para segurança de TI testada</strong></p>



<p>Todos os produtos testados pelo Instituto AV-TEST são avaliados de acordo com uma estrutura de teste predeterminada. Isso é sempre transparente para empresas e usuários e pode ser entendido logicamente em todos os momentos. Em um ano de testes, os produtos de segurança são examinados e avaliados várias vezes nas áreas de teste de Proteção (função de proteção), Desempenho (velocidade) e Usabilidade (facilidade de uso). Além disso, há também os testes Advanced Threat Protection, nos quais é testada a eficácia especial dos produtos na defesa contra ransomware, por exemplo. Para a conclusão bem-sucedida de um teste, a solução de segurança recebe um certificado de teste de segurança testada contra ameaças de TI. Os produtos para Windows que concluírem um teste com resultados claramente acima do padrão da indústria são premiados com a avaliação extra de &#8220;TOP PRODUCT&#8221;.   </p>



<p>Cada valor individual que um produto oferece em um ano de teste é adicionado a uma grande matriz de avaliação interna do AV-Test Institute. Se uma solução de segurança for capaz de demonstrar resultados máximos durante todo o ano, ela terá a oportunidade de receber um dos cobiçados prêmios AV-TEST. Todos os testes individuais no ano de 2022 agora formam a base para a escolha e apresentação dos prêmios na primavera de 2023. Muitas empresas podem esperar um ou vários dos 26 prêmios no total na 12ª cerimônia de premiação dos prêmios AV-TEST, que agora se tornou uma rica tradição. Ao fazer isso, eles recebem não apenas um certificado pela segurança testada de seu produto, mas também reconhecimento por seu desenvolvimento consistente e trabalho de pesquisa. A entrega de um prêmio AV-TEST também é uma prova para os usuários finais e usuários corporativos que estão comprando ou já usando um produto com segurança testada e premiada.</p>



<p><strong>Prêmio AV-TEST para PC Matic – mais do que apenas reconhecimento</strong></p>



<p>O problema de desempenho costumava ser uma das maiores fontes de aborrecimento para os usuários quando se tratava de software de segurança. Por esse motivo, o teste de desempenho sempre foi um elemento integrante de todas as avaliações de software de segurança no Windows nos laboratórios da AV-TEST. Nesse campo, o PC Matic com seu pacote de proteção Application Whitelisting mostrou continuamente que uma boa proteção precisa apenas de poucos recursos do sistema. Para esta economia e resultados positivos relacionados na avaliação no ano de teste de 2022, o laboratório do AV-TEST conferiu ao PC Matic Application Whitelisting o Prêmio AV-TEST de Melhor Desempenho 2022 no Windows para Usuários Consumidores.</p>



<p>Na rodada de premiação de 2022, o AV-TEST Institute selecionou pela primeira vez os vencedores na nova categoria de teste de Proteção Avançada contra Ameaças. Neste tipo de testes ao vivo, o laboratório avaliou cenários de ataque, por exemplo devido a ransomware, passo a passo. Ao fazê-lo, registrou quando o ataque foi detectado e em que etapa foi interrompido, ou não interrompido, ou apenas parcialmente frustrado. Por seu desempenho excepcional nesta categoria de teste, o AV-Test Institute escolheu o PC Matic Application Whitelisting para o Prêmio de Melhor Proteção Avançada 2022 no Windows para&nbsp; o usuário.</p>



<p>&#8220;Queremos parabenizar de coração a PC Matic pelos dois cobiçados prêmios. Principalmente no Windows, além da proteção, a performance é uma questão extremamente frequente que preocupa os usuários, devido à velocidade com que um watchdog do sistema opera. A PC Matic conseguiu conquistar não apenas o importante Prêmio de Desempenho, mas também o Prêmio Especial de Proteção Avançada 2022 no Windows, que comprova a segurança no teste, passo a passo&#8221;, disse Andreas Marx, CEO da AV-TEST.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/premio-av-test-2022-para-pc-matic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Deliveries in Limbo – How Royal Mail Could Have Avoided Ransomware Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/international-deliveries-in-limbo-how-royal-mail-could-have-avoided-ransomware-attack/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/international-deliveries-in-limbo-how-royal-mail-could-have-avoided-ransomware-attack/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 16:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberNews]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66351</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Back in January, it was reported that the UK&#8217;s primary postal service and courier company, Royal Mail, halted all international mail and parcel deliveries due to a ransomware attack by Russian-backed ransomware gang, LockBit. The incident, confirmed by Royal Mail CEO Simon Thompson, caused severe service disruption and left businesses and customers feeling the financial &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/international-deliveries-in-limbo-how-royal-mail-could-have-avoided-ransomware-attack/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">International Deliveries in Limbo – How Royal Mail Could Have Avoided Ransomware Attack</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Back in January, it was reported that the UK&#8217;s primary postal service and courier company, Royal Mail, halted all international mail and parcel deliveries due to a ransomware attack by Russian-backed ransomware gang, LockBit. The incident, confirmed by Royal Mail CEO Simon Thompson, caused severe service disruption and left businesses and customers feeling the financial impact.</p>



<p>According to the statement released by the company, the attack did not affect delivery and collection services within the UK, but international shipping services were suspended for over 6 weeks. The company advised customers to hold off on exports as items could not be dispatched to overseas destinations due to the &#8216;severe service disruption&#8217; caused by the ransomware attack.</p>



<h2>Royal Mail Ransomware Attack – The Official Stance</h2>



<p>Initially, the UK business did not reveal the actual nature of the incident. Instead, they began investigating the causes and hired cybersecurity experts to investigate what went wrong and how it could have been avoided.</p>



<p>The incident also affected the Track and Trace website, causing delays and inconvenience for customers. The Click &amp; Drop website was also experiencing payment issues, making it difficult for people to print postage labels from home.</p>



<p>The attack on Royal Mail highlights the vulnerability of mail delivery services to cyberthreats and the importance of implementing robust cybersecurity measures to protect against such incidents. The business&#8217;s reputation is at risk, and it must resolve the issue and restore normal operations quickly.</p>



<p>The incident is a stark reminder for people and organizations that they need to be vigilant and take necessary precautions to protect their sensitive information and transactions. This attack could have easily been avoided.</p>



<h2>What Are Some Possible Causes for the Royal Mail Cyber Attack?</h2>



<p>Criminals on the internet are always looking for easy ways to generate money. Large corporations and affluent businesspeople with access to sensitive information are their primary targets. If we stop to think about it, we are vulnerable to cyberattacks whenever we are in close contact with the internet.</p>



<h3>Systems &amp; Servers Were Easy-to-Access</h3>



<p>Protecting a system from data breaches when using new technologies is usually challenging or impossible. Security can be put in danger only when hackers have simple access to the system. To obtain unauthorized access, hackers with advanced expertise can bypass access codes, retinal scans, and speech recognition. They could have easily gotten past the Royal Mail system&#8217;s firewall.</p>



<h3>Lack of Cybersecurity Measures</h3>



<p>The most likely cause could be a need for proper cybersecurity measures, such as outdated software and hardware, weak passwords, and employee training on cybersecurity best practices. Traditional blacklist antivirus is no longer optimal for protecting businesses against modern day ransomware attacks. Without an effective application allowlisting platform, Royal Mail was essentially inviting attackers into an unlocked door. Many government agencies around the world have acknowledged the importance of application allowlisting, yet businesses continue to fail to adapt to these new standards. As a result, they stay vulnerable to ransomware attacks.</p>



<p>Another possibility is that the attackers may have used a phishing email or a malicious link to access the company&#8217;s systems. This highlights the need for companies to have robust email filtering and spam blocking systems and educate employees on identifying and avoiding phishing attempts.</p>



<h2>How Did the Cyberattack Affect Royal Mail&#8217;s Operations?</h2>



<p>The suspension of international shipping services disrupted operations and caused significant revenue loss. Additionally, the <a href="https://www.computerweekly.com/news/252529095/Royal-Mail-overseas-services-hit-by-major-cyber-attack">attack has caused technical issues</a> on the Track and Trace website and the Click &amp; Drop website, causing inconvenience for customers and potentially leading to a loss of customer loyalty.</p>



<p>While the short term impacts are damaging, the long term impacts could potentially be catastrophic. The incident has led to reputational damage for them, as customers may question their ability to protect their information. Royal Mail also has to bear costs related to the investigation, clean-up, and any ransom that may have been paid, greatly impacting their financials.</p>



<h2>What Were the Consequences of the Cyberattack On Customers &amp; Businesses?</h2>



<p>The attack on Royal Mail had consequences for customers, who have been affected by delays and inconvenience in tracking their parcels and letters. The incident may also have caused financial losses for customers whose shipments have been delayed or lost. The attack could have compromised sensitive information, such as personal and financial data, which may not even be known for years, if ever. </p>



<p>The incident also serves as a reminder for customers to be vigilant in protecting their sensitive information and transactions and to take necessary precautions, such as avoiding making payments through compromised websites and being vigilant about suspicious emails and messages.</p>



<p>Customers may also need more trust in Royal Mail&#8217;s services and may opt to use alternate shipping services in the future. This can lead to a loss of business for Royal Mail and potentially harm its reputation as a reliable and secure delivery service. Overall, the attack on Royal Mail has caused significant consequences for the company and its customers.</p>



<p>The incident highlights the importance of robust cybersecurity measures and the need for companies to be proactive in protecting their systems and sensitive information. Customers must also take necessary precautions to protect their sensitive data and transactions.</p>



<h2>How Could the Attack on Royal Mail Have Been Prevented?</h2>



<p>Businesses often risk losing business due to a simple system issue or breach. Since prevention against such crimes is vital, we&#8217;ll show you a few ways to stop ransomware attacks and how to defend your company properly:</p>



<h3>Prioritize Endpoint Security</h3>



<p>Endpoint security safeguards networks that are connected to devices via a small bridge. Security concerns arise when access points are connected to enterprise networks using laptops, tablets, and mobile devices. Endpoint protection software is required to safeguard these routes. Furthermore, the method of security is equally important. Traditional antivirus is no longer acceptable. Allowlisting is an absolutely crucial piece of any cybersecurity stack, and must be implemented by any organization seeking to protect themselves from ransomware.</p>



<h3>Separate Personal Accounts for Employees</h3>



<p>Each employee needs a unique login for each software and application. Making numerous contacts with people sharing your credentials could harm your company. You can lessen the number of assault fronts by providing each employee with their login. Users will only use their own set of logins and will only log in once each day. You&#8217;ll enjoy better usability as well as increased security.</p>



<h3>Create Awareness Among Your Employees</h3>



<p>Employees are one of the most popular methods by that fraudsters get access to your data. To access certain files or provide personal information, they will send phishing emails while pretending to be employees of your company. Links can seem genuine to an untrained eye, and it&#8217;s easy to fall into the trap. Knowledge is essential since untrained employees may subsequently fall into those traps.</p>



<h2>What Role Does Cyber Insurance Play?</h2>



<p>Cyber insurance coverage is designed to protect organizations from the financial impact of a cyberattack. It can provide coverage for responding to an attack, restoring lost or stolen data, and covering the cost of liability lawsuits.</p>



<p>However, it is essential to note that cyber insurance is not a protection guarantee. In some cases, insurance companies may deny a claim or dispute the extent of the damages. Additionally, even if a claim is paid out, the financial losses and reputational damage caused by a cyberattack can still be significant.</p>



<p>Moreover, organizations must be aware that the cyber insurance policy they are getting is tailored to their specific needs, as not all policies are created equal. Some may cover certain types of attacks or data breaches but not others. Organizations should carefully review their cyber insurance policy&#8217;s terms and conditions and understand their coverage before an attack occurs.</p>



<p>While cyber insurance is an important piece to consider when establishing your cybersecurity stack, it should only be considered as a last resort. Absolute prevention is the most important thing to consider.</p>



<h2>Best Practices for Protecting Against Ransomware Attacks</h2>



<p>In the wake of the ransomware attack on Royal Mail, businesses and individuals need to be aware of the best practices for protecting against such incidents. Some critical approaches include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Implement an application allowlisting platform</strong>: Applicaiton allowlisting platforms, like PC Matic Pro, prevent anything unknown from executing on your endpoints or network. </li><li><strong>Regularly updating software and hardware</strong>: Keeping software and hardware up-to-date can help protect against known vulnerabilities and prevent attackers from exploiting them.</li><li><strong>Implementing strong passwords</strong>: Complex and unique passwords can help prevent attackers from guessing or cracking them.</li><li><strong>Conducting regular employee training on cybersecurity best practices</strong>: Educating employees on identifying and avoiding phishing attempts and other attack methods can help prevent them from falling victim to a ransomware attack.</li><li><strong>Backing up data</strong>: Regularly backing up data can recover important information in an attack.</li><li><strong>Investing in cybersecurity insurance</strong>: Cybersecurity insurance can help cover the costs of an attack and provide assistance in the event of an incident.</li><li><strong>Regular vulnerability assessments and penetration testing</strong> can help prevent attackers from gaining access to sensitive information and disrupting operations.</li><li><strong>Be vigilant in protecting sensitive information</strong> and transactions, such as avoiding making payments through compromised websites and being vigilant about suspicious emails and messages.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/international-deliveries-in-limbo-how-royal-mail-could-have-avoided-ransomware-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove AphroditeTechResults</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/how-to-remove-aphroditetechresults/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/how-to-remove-aphroditetechresults/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Home Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66348</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[If you’ve noticed strange pop-ups, new tabs opening without your permission, or your homepage and search engine changing unexpectedly, your Mac may be infected with AphroditeTechResults. AphroditeTechResults is a type of adware and browser hijacker that can cause a lot of frustration and even harm to your computer. In this article, we’ll discuss what AphroditeTechResults &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/how-to-remove-aphroditetechresults/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">How to Remove AphroditeTechResults</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you’ve noticed strange pop-ups, new tabs opening without your permission, or your homepage and search engine changing unexpectedly, your Mac may be infected with AphroditeTechResults.</p>



<p>AphroditeTechResults is a type of adware and browser hijacker that can cause a lot of frustration and even harm to your computer.</p>



<p>In this article, we’ll discuss what AphroditeTechResults is, the dangers of adware and browser hijackers, and most importantly, how to remove AphroditeTechResults from your Mac.</p>



<p>AphroditeTechResults can infect your Mac through various means, including bundling with free software, scam websites, and suspicious downloads. Once installed, it can cause a range of symptoms, including slow performance, crashes, and unwanted applications and browser extensions.</p>



<p>To remove AphroditeTechResults from your Mac, there are both manual and automatic methods available, including uninstalling the application from the Applications folder, deleting suspicious files and plists from the System folder, and using anti-malware and antivirus software.</p>



<p>Prevention is key when it comes to avoiding AphroditeTechResults and other types of adware and browser hijackers. It’s important to only install software from reliable sources, keep your Mac and apps updated, and avoid suspicious websites and downloads.</p>



<p>In the following sections, we’ll discuss how AphroditeTechResults infects Macs, the symptoms of AphroditeTechResults on Macs, and the various methods to remove AphroditeTechResults from your Mac.</p>



<h2>How AphroditeTechResults Infects Macs</h2>



<p>AphroditeTechResults can infect your Mac through various means, including bundling with free software, scam websites, and suspicious downloads. Here’s a closer look at how AphroditeTechResults can infect your Mac:</p>



<ol><li><strong>Bundling with Free Software</strong>: AphroditeTechResults can be bundled with free software that you download from the internet. When you download and install free software, AphroditeTechResults can piggyback on the installation process and get installed alongside the software without your knowledge or consent.</li><li><strong>Scam websites</strong>: Some websites may trick you into downloading and installing software that contains AphroditeTechResults. These websites may display misleading pop-ups, fake error messages, or other tactics to persuade you to download and install the software.</li><li><strong>Suspicious Downloads</strong>: Downloading files from suspicious sources can also infect your Mac with AphroditeTechResults. For example, downloading files from peer-to-peer networks or clicking on suspicious links in emails can lead to the installation of AphroditeTechResults or other types of malware.</li></ol>



<p>It’s important to be cautious when downloading and installing software from the internet. Stick to reputable sources, and always read the terms and conditions before installing software.</p>



<p>Be wary of websites that display suspicious pop-ups or messages, and avoid downloading files from sources you don’t trust. By taking these precautions, you can reduce the risk of infecting your Mac with AphroditeTechResults or other types of malware.</p>



<h2>Symptoms of AphroditeTechResults on Macs</h2>



<p>AphroditeTechResults can cause a range of symptoms on Macs. Here are some of the most common symptoms you may notice if your Mac is infected with AphroditeTechResults:</p>



<p><strong>Pop-up Ads</strong>: AphroditeTechResults can generate pop-up ads on your Mac. These ads may appear in new browser windows or tabs, or they may appear as notifications on your desktop.</p>



<p><strong>Homepage and Search Engine Changes</strong>: AphroditeTechResults can change your Mac’s homepage and search engine without your permission. You may notice that your browser opens to a different homepage than you normally use or that your searches are being redirected to a different search engine.</p>



<p><strong>New Tabs and Web Pages Opening without Permission</strong>: AphroditeTechResults can cause new tabs and web pages to open on your Mac without your permission. These pages may contain advertisements, fake error messages, or other types of content.</p>



<p><strong>Slow Performance and Crashes</strong>: AphroditeTechResults can slow down your Mac’s performance and cause crashes. Your Mac may run more slowly than usual, and you may experience frequent freezes or crashes.</p>



<p><strong>Unwanted Applications and Browser Extensions</strong>: AphroditeTechResults may install unwanted applications or browser extensions on your Mac. These applications or extensions may appear in your Applications folder or your browser’s add-ons or extensions menu.</p>



<p>If you notice any of these symptoms on your Mac, it’s possible that your computer is infected with AphroditeTechResults or another type of adware or browser hijacker. It’s important to take action to remove the infection as soon as possible to prevent further damage to your Mac and protect your personal information.</p>



<h2>How to Remove AphroditeTechResults from Macs</h2>



<p>If you get infected and need to remove AphroditeTechResults from your Mac, the good news is that it’s relatively easy to do. There are a few different ways to remove AphroditeTechResults from your Mac, including using an anti-malware program, running a manual scan, and resetting your browser settings. If you have PC Matic, you can run a scan and any infected files will be quarantined.</p>



<p>Depending on your proficiency level with your Mac, one method might be more appealing than others. If you’re not comfortable with more advanced techniques, then an anti-malware program is probably the best choice for you.</p>



<p>Anti-malware programs are designed to detect and remove malicious software from your Mac, and they can be very effective in removing AphroditeTechResults.</p>



<h3>Manual Removal Method</h3>



<p>Uninstalling AphroditeTechResults from Applications Folder:</p>



<ol><li>Click on the “Finder” icon on the dock.</li><li>Click on the “Applications” folder.</li><li>Look for “AphroditeTechResults” or any suspicious applications, and drag them to the Trash bin.</li><li>Right-click on the Trash bin and select “Empty Trash.” Think of this as an uninstall button for the virus.</li></ol>



<p>Removing AphroditeTechResults from Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, and Apple Safari Settings:</p>



<ol><li>Open the browser affected by AphroditeTechResults.</li><li>Go to the Chrome settings (or whatever browser you use), usually by clicking on the three dots or three lines at the top right corner of the browser window.</li><li>Look for any unfamiliar extensions or add-ons and remove them.</li><li>Reset the browser’s homepage and search engine to their default settings.</li></ol>



<p>Deleting Suspicious Files and Plists from Mac’s System Folder:</p>



<ol><li>Click on the “Finder” icon on the dock.</li><li>Click on the “Go” menu on the menu bar and select “Go to Folder.”</li><li>Type “/Library/Application Support” and click “Go.”</li><li>Look for any suspicious files or folders related to AphroditeTechResults and delete them.</li><li>Repeat steps 2 through 4, but this time type “/Library/LaunchAgents” and “/Library/LaunchDaemons” instead of “/Library/Application Support.”</li></ol>



<h3>Automatic Removal Method</h3>



<p>Using Anti-malware and Antivirus Software:</p>



<ol><li>Install anti-malware or antivirus software on your Mac, such as Malwarebytes or Combo Cleaner.</li><li>Scan your Mac and follow the instructions to remove AphroditeTechResults and other malware.</li></ol>



<p>Combo Cleaner:</p>



<ol><li>Download and install Combo Cleaner on your Mac.</li><li>Open Combo Cleaner and click on “Antivirus” on the left-hand side menu.</li><li>Click on “Scan” to scan your Mac for malware.</li><li>Click on “Remove” to remove AphroditeTechResults and other malware.</li></ol>



<p>Malwarebytes:</p>



<ol><li>Download and install Malwarebytes on your Mac.</li><li>Open Malwarebytes and click on “Scan.”</li><li>Click on “Quarantine” to remove AphroditeTechResults and other malware.</li><li>Lastly, restart your Mac. Malwarebytes should have then removed any malicious files from your system.</li></ol>



<p>It’s important to note that manual removal can be time-consuming and may not always completely remove AphroditeTechResults or other malware. Automatic removal methods are generally more effective at removing malware, but it’s still important to follow prevention tips to avoid future infections.</p>



<h2>Prevention Tips to Avoid AphroditeTechResults on Macs</h2>



<p>Prevention is key when it comes to avoiding AphroditeTechResults and other types of adware and browser hijackers. Here are some prevention tips to help you avoid infections on your Mac:</p>



<h3>Install from Reliable Sources Only</h3>



<p>Protect yourself and your computer by only downloading and installing software from reliable sources. Refrain from acquiring programs or applications through untrustworthy websites, P2P networks, or dubious links, as these could contain deadly viruses that can endanger your device’s safety.</p>



<h3>Keep Your Mac and Apps Updated</h3>



<p>To keep your Mac and applications secure and well-protected, make sure to update them with the recent security patches. Doing so will quickly address any existing vulnerabilities that could put you at risk.</p>



<h3>Avoid Suspicious Websites and Downloads</h3>



<p>Be alert of websites that present suspicious pop-ups, pretend error notifications, or other activities intended to convince you to download and install software. Abstain from getting files from dubious sources or pressing on questionable connections in emails.</p>



<h3>Disable Automatic Downloads in Browser Settings</h3>



<p>To protect yourself from any unwanted downloads and installations, make sure to disable automatic downloads in your browser settings. The setting to do this is readily available in the browser’s system Preferences menu.</p>



<h3>Disabling Pop-up Ads in Browser Settings</h3>



<p>For a safer browsing experience, disable pop-up ads in the settings of your web browser. This will keep those pesky advertisements out and protect you from accidentally clicking on something malicious or potentially harmful.</p>



<p>To safeguard your Mac from AphroditeTechResults and other types of browser hijacking, follow these preventive measures. If you suspect any suspicious activity on your device, act quickly to eliminate the virus so that further destruction is avoided and all personal data remains secure.</p>



<h2>Other Viruses to Watch Out for and How to Prevent Them from Infecting Your Mac</h2>



<p>In addition to AphroditeTechResults, there are several other viruses and malware that can infect your Mac. Here are some of the most common types of malware on Macs and how to prevent them from infecting your computer:</p>



<p><strong>Trojan Viruses</strong>: Trojan viruses are a type of malware that can disguise themselves as legitimate software. They can infect your Mac through email attachments, malicious downloads, or other means. To prevent Trojan viruses, avoid opening attachments or downloading files from unknown sources, and use anti-malware software to scan your computer regularly.</p>



<p><strong>Ransomware</strong>: To keep your Mac safe from malicious ransomware, be sure to steer clear of any downloads or email attachments that appear suspicious. You should also make it a practice to back up all important files on a regular basis in order to protect them against potential encryption and extortion demands. Taking these precautions will help ensure the security of your data and Mac device.</p>



<p><strong>Browser Hijackers</strong>: If you wish to avoid the threat of browser hijackers such as AphroditeTechResults, it’s important to take some precautionary measures. Refrain from downloading software from sketchy sources and ensure that your browser and extensions are regularly updated.</p>



<p>Also, having anti-malware software running on your computer can help in detecting any malicious programs before they cause too much damage. Taking these simple steps will go a long way in protecting yourself.</p>



<p><strong>Pop-up Ads and Potentially Unwanted Programs (PUPs)</strong>: Unwanted pop-ups and potentially unwanted programs (PUPs) can make their way onto your Mac through malicious downloads or bundled software.</p>



<p>The best way to protect yourself is by avoiding downloading any files from unreliable sources, using ad blockers and pop-up blockers in your browser, and scanning regularly for malware with anti-malware software. With these precautions taken, you will be able to enjoy a safe browsing experience free of intrusive ads.</p>



<p><strong>Spyware</strong>: To safeguard yourself against spyware—a type of malware that can steal your personal information when tracking your online behaviors—it’s vital to be vigilant. Do not download software from untrusted sources or open email attachments unless you are certain of their origin.</p>



<p>Additionally, regularly running anti-malware software on your Mac computer and staying alert for phishing scams will help protect you from becoming infected by spyware.</p>



<p>By adhering to these precautionary measures and staying alert against malicious software, you can ensure the safety of your Mac from viruses as well as other types of malware. Moreover, it is essential that all applications on your computer are current with the latest security patches and updates. Your Mac will remain secure if you keep following those tips consistently.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>The most important action you can take to protect your Mac from viruses and other types of malware is to stay informed. Knowing the latest threats, being aware of any suspicious activity on your computer, and taking precautionary steps like installing anti-malware software can go a long way in safeguarding your Mac against malicious viruses.</p>



<p>AphroditeTechResults is just one of many viruses that can infect your Mac device, so it’s crucial that you stay vigilant and take the necessary steps to ensure the safety of your Mac.</p>



<p>Keeping yourself up-to-date on the latest threats, as well as taking necessary precautions like backing up data, avoiding suspicious downloads and updates, and running anti-malware software regularly can help prevent becoming infected by malware. With these tips in mind, you will be able to enjoy a safe and secure online experience on your Mac.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/how-to-remove-aphroditetechresults/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O que é Application Whitelisting?</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/o-que-e-application-whitelisting/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/o-que-e-application-whitelisting/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Solange Cheng]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 17:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Portuguese (BR)]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66327</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A Application whitelisting, também conhecida como application allowlisting, controle de execução de aplicativos e gerenciamento de recursos de software, é uma medida de segurança cibernética que fornece acesso de aplicativos aprovados a quaisquer terminais na rede. Utilizando a abordagem default-deny, e o modelo zero trust na segurança cibernética, a application whitelisting garante que qualquer aplicativo &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/o-que-e-application-whitelisting/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">O que é Application Whitelisting?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">A Application whitelisting, também conhecida como <em>application allowlisting,</em> controle de execução de aplicativos e gerenciamento de recursos de software, é uma medida de segurança cibernética que fornece acesso de aplicativos aprovados a quaisquer terminais na rede. Utilizando a abordagem <em>default-deny, </em>e o modelo <em>zero trust</em> na segurança cibernética, a <em>application whitelisting </em>garante que qualquer aplicativo indesejado, não confiável, desconhecido ou não autorizado não tem permissão de ser executado até que seja aprovado manualmente ou colocado na <em>application whitelisting</em> pelo administrador do sistema de TI do usuário final. Ao bloquear aplicativos suspeitos e maliciosos antes da execução, isso previne ameaças cibernéticas e ataques cibernéticos complexos que podem ser evitados em tempo real.</p>



<p style="font-size:28px"><strong>Como <em>Application Whitelisting</em> funciona</strong></p>



<p>Simplificando<em>, application whitelisting</em> funciona criando uma lista de aplicativos aprovados e comparando quaisquer aplicativos novos ou desconhecidos com essa lista. Normalmente, as comparações são feitas analisando o nome do arquivo, o caminho do arquivo, o tamanho do arquivo, a assinatura digital ou o hash criptográfico do aplicativo. Se um aplicativo não estiver na lista, sua execução será bloqueada. Isso pode ajudar a reduzir as chances de malware ser instalado em um dispositivo ou de vazamento de dados confidenciais.</p>



<p style="font-size:28px"><strong>Os 5 Método da<em> Application Whitelisting</em></strong></p>



<p>A <em>Application Whitelisting </em>funciona em diferentes formatos, geralmente em uníssono, para minimizar o risco de execução de malware. De acordo com o National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), os cinco principais métodos de <em>application whitelisting</em> são: </p>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:100%">
<ul><li>nome do arquivo</li><li>caminho de arquivo</li><li>tamanho do arquivo</li><li>assinatura digital/editor</li><li>hash criptográfico</li></ul>
</div>
</div>



<p><strong>Nome do Arquivo</strong></p>



<p>Application whitelisting por nome de arquivo é um dos três tipos de <em>application whitelisting</em> baseada em arquivo, o tipo mais comum de <em>whitelisting</em>, que compara o nome do arquivo executável com o índice da application <em>whitelisting</em>. Talvez o mais fácil de proceder com o tipo de <em>application whitelisting</em> pode ser simplesmente modificando o nome do software malicioso para o de um aplicativo permitido na <em>application Whitelisting</em> . Além disso, se um aplicativo reconhecido ou aprovado se tornar malicioso depois de ter sido colocado na lista de permissões, ele ainda pode ser executado, desde que o nome do arquivo não seja alterado.</p>



<p><strong>Caminho do Arquivo</strong></p>



<p>Whitelisting por nome de arquivo é um dos três tipos de lista branca baseada em arquivo, o tipo mais comum de <em>application whitelisting</em>, que compara o nome do arquivo executável com o índice de aplicativos whitelisting. Este processo de <em>whitelisting</em> é flexível porque pode ser configurado por directório ou por caminho de arquivo completo, mas esta flexibilidade é também a sua maior fraqueza. Para manipular a <em>whitelisting</em> do caminho do arquivo, os criminosos podem alterar o caminho do seu malware para corresponder ao caminho de um programa aprovado. De facto, os invasores podem desviar a whitelisting do caminho do arquivo apenas colocando malware no mesmo directório que uma aplicação aprovada, mesmo que o resto do caminho do arquivo não corresponda. Além disso, a whitelisting do caminho do arquivo tem o mesmo problema de pós-aprovação que a whitelisting do nome do arquivo, em que as aplicações que se tornam maliciosas após a aprovação ainda poderão ser executadas porque foram previamente aprovadas.</p>



<p><strong>Tamanho do arquivo</strong></p>



<p>Whitelisting por tamanho de arquivo é o terceiro de três tipos de whitelisting baseado em arquivo que compara o tamanho do arquivo executável com o índice de <em>application whitelisting</em>. A whitelisting por tamanho de arquivo é muito semelhante à whitelisting por nome de arquivo e caminho do arquivo, e tem muitas das mesmas falhas. Tipicamente, os três métodos de whitelisting baseados em arquivos são utilizados em uníssono para proporcionar a maior proteção possível. Desta forma, se um atacante quisesse infectar uma rede protegida por <em>application whitelisting</em>, teria de duplicar um nome do arquivo, caminho do arquivo, e tamanho do arquivo, o que pode ser bastante difícil. Mesmo assim, ainda é possível, e tem sido feito em muitos ataques do mundo real. Embora a maioria das soluções tradicionais de <em>application whitelisting </em>ajuda a prevenir, a PC Matic dá um passo em frente para assegurar que os seus endpoints são impenetráveis.</p>



<p><strong><em>Assinatura Digital/Editor</em></strong></p>



<p>As assinaturas digitais são essencialmente marcas de água para aplicações específicas criadas por um editor. Quando um novo software é criado, alguns editores podem assinar a aplicação, o que se pode tornar um atributo muito forte para a application <em>whitelisting.</em> Se confiar um editor, a sua assinatura digital pode ser permitida na whitelist, o que permitirá que todas as aplicações, e todas as versões subsequentes de cada aplicação, criadas por esse editor, sejam autorizadas. Embora esta seja uma forma bastante segura e conveniente de gerenciar uma whitelist, há uma importante advertência a abordar. A whitelisting via assinatura digital pressupõe que, uma vez que um editor é “conhecido”, todas as suas aplicações estão sempre livres de código malicioso, o que é quase impossível de garantir.</p>



<p><strong>Hash Criptográfico</strong></p>



<p>Cada arquivo tem um hash criptográfico único que é usado como uma identidade para cada aplicação. A elaboração da<em> whitelisting</em> usando hashes criptográficos é incrivelmente difícil, ou se não impossível, para os atacantes contornarem. O principal desafio da <em>whitelisting</em> por hash criptográfico provém da manutenção regular necessária para manter a whitelist atualizada. Sempre que há uma revisão de gestão ou correção de um arquivo de aplicação, é criado um novo hash de arquivo. Até a whitelist ser atualizada com este novo hash, ele será tratado como uma aplicação não autorizada e não será permitido executar. Sendo assim, com a global whitelist da PC Matic, tratamos disso para minimizar preocupações em atualizar continuamente o seu índice de aplicações da whitelist.</p>



<p style="font-size:28px"><strong>Application Whitelisting vs Blacklisting</strong></p>



<p>Com a tradicional<em> application blacklisting</em>, que previne apenas aplicações conhecidas sejam executadas, a <em>application whitelistin</em>g passa por um processo muito mais completo na avaliação de cada aplicativo e analisado antes de ser permitida a sua execução. Os apoiadores da <em>application blacklisting</em> argumentam que o software <em>application whitelisting</em> não está maduro e, portanto, sendo complexo, alto custo, ou desnecessário.</p>



<p>Historicamente, a <em>application whitelisting</em> era vista como uma medida avançada de ciber-segurança que só era necessária em ambientes de alto risco. Para a maioria dos ambientes, pensava-se que a colocação de <em>application blacklisting</em> era tipicamente suficiente. Embora isto possa ter sido verdade há vários anos, os cyberattacks tornaram-se tão avançados que já não é este o caso, e a <em>application whitelisting</em> tornou-se mesmo uma linha de base nas melhores práticas de segurança cibernética para a segurança de endpoints.</p>



<p>As soluções de whitelisting e as ferramentas de segurança são superiores porque impedem que o malware ou os agentes de ameaça&nbsp; executem o seu código malicioso na sua rede ou dispositivo. Os programas antivírus típicos de blacklist esperam que uma máquina ou sistema seja infectado ou seja reportada uma vulnerabilidade para adicionar malware às suas listas negras. Neste momento, já é tarde demais para impedir o ataque e a blacklists irá tentar impedir o próximo ataque. Na <em>application whitelist</em> são ferramentas de prevenção de malware; na<em> application blacklist</em> são ferramentas de reação contra malware.</p>



<p style="font-size:28px"><strong>Controle de Aplicão x Application Whitelisting</strong></p>



<p>Na <em>application whitelisting</em> é uma medida de segurança que permite que apenas as aplicações aprovadas sejam executadas num dispositivo ou rede. O controle de aplicações, por outro lado, é uma medida de segurança que restringe o acesso a determinadas aplicações. O software de <em>application whitelisting</em> é concebido para monitorizar infra-estruturas de informática completa, incluindo redes, servidores e sistemas operativos, enquanto o controlo de aplicações é tipicamente utilizado numa escala menor para simplesmente gerir a execução de aplicações. A a<em>pplication whitelisting</em> é também utilizada para estende-se a prática de todos os processos executáveis no seu dispositivo, incluindo arquivos, scripts, macros, controladores, e patches de segurança. Em resumo, o controle de aplicações é um subconjunto de <em>application whitelisting</em>, e o software de controle de aplicações carece, de muitas características e funcionalidades do software de whitelisting de aplicações.Tanto a <em>application whitelisting </em>como o controle de aplicações podem ser utilizados para impedir que software malicioso funcione num dispositivo ou rede. Porém, a <em>application whitelisting</em> é geralmente considerada mais eficaz do que o controle de aplicações. Isto porque <em>whitelisting</em> só permite a execução de aplicações confiáveis, enquanto que o controle de aplicações pode permitir a execução de aplicações maliciosas se estas não estiverem especificamente incluídas na lista de aplicações restritas. Como resultado, a <em>application whitelisting</em> é tipicamente a medida de segurança preferida para impedir a execução de software malicioso num dispositivo ou rede. Embora sejam frequentemente utilizadas de forma alternada, é importante compreender que não são as mesmas quando se tomam decisões de mais um nível de segurança.</p>



<p style="font-size:28px"><strong>Por que <em>Application Whitelisting </em>é importante?</strong></p>



<p>Application whitelisting é importante para organização de todos os tamanhos e indústrias porque ajuda a prevenir, não a reagir, a ataques de zero-day, malware, e ransomware no mundo digital cada vez mais complexo. Basicamente, a whitelisting também consiste no controle de aplicações, que proporciona aos administradores de TI um controle significativamente maior sobre quais as aplicações que podem ser executadas na rede e quaisquer endpoint. Embora a gestão de aplicações individuais represente um encargo cada vez maior para os profissionais de TI, não há dúvida que o nível seja extremamente elevado de proteção proporcionado pela tecnologia de <em>application whitelisting</em>. Veja exemplos de benefícios da application whitelisting:</p>



<p><strong>Protege a sua rede e todos os aparelhos conectados na rede</strong></p>



<p>A <em>application whitelisting</em> é uma medida de cibersegurança que proporciona um elevado nível de proteção para redes e computadores. Ao permitir apenas a execução de programas aprovados no sistema, a <em>appplictaion whitelisting</em> ajuda a evitar a execução de código malicioso. Isto, por sua vez, reduz o risco de ataques e previne a violação de dados. Além disso, a application whitelisting também pode ajudar a melhorar o desempenho do sistema, bloqueando programas indesejados que podem interromper um sistema. Como resultado, a <em>application whitelisting</em> é uma forma eficaz de proteger redes e computadores de ameaças.</p>



<p><strong>Proporciona controle à equipa de TI</strong></p>



<p>Sendo uma ferramenta importante, a <em>application whitelisting</em> para os profissionais de TI que precisam manter o controle total sobre o software que está sendo utilizado nas suas redes. Ao criar uma <em>application whitelist</em> aprovada, os profissionais de TI podem ter a certeza de que apenas o software autorizado será utilizado. Isso ajuda a evitar a instalação de software malicioso, e também ajuda a reduzir o risco de violação de dados. Além disso, a <em>application whitelisting</em> pode ajudar a melhorar o desempenho do sistema, eliminando a necessidade de procurar e remover software não autorizado. A application whitelisting é uma ferramenta poderosa para profissionais de TI que precisam de manter o controle total sobre as suas redes.</p>



<p><strong>Sendo fundamental para o NIST CSF e para o cumprimento Essential Eight&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>O NIST CSF e o Essential Eight são duas directrizes diferentes fornecidas pelos governos dos EUA e da Austrália que detalham formas de organizar e melhorar os níveis de cibersegurança. O requisito estrito do cumprimento de uma ou ambas, destas directrizes assegura a protecção das organizações contra as modernas ameaças cibernéticas. </p>



<h6><strong>Oque é National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Cybersecurity Framework (CSF)?</strong></h6>



<p>&nbsp;O National Institute of Standards and Technology Cybersecurity Framework&nbsp; (NIST CSF) é um conjunto de diretrizes voluntárias que fornece às organizações uma abordagem baseada no risco para a gestão dos problemas de ciber-segurança.&nbsp; A estrutura foi projetada para ajudar as organizações a avaliar seus riscos de segurança cibernética, identificar lacunas em suas defesas e implementar soluções para amenizar esses riscos. O NIST CSF é baseado em um conjunto de cinco funções centrais: Identificar, Proteger, Detectar, Responder, e Recuperar. Cada uma destas funções contém um conjunto de atividades e resultados que as organizações podem utilizar para avaliar a sua postura de ciber-segurança e melhorar a sua posição global de segurança. O NIST CSF não é um padrão obrigatório, mas muitas organizações optam por adotá-lo porque proporciona uma abordagem abrangente à gestão dos riscos de cibersegurança. Além disso, o NIST CSF é constantemente atualizado para refletir as últimas ameaças e tendências no cenário da ciber-segurança.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="1752" height="1062" src="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/nist-cybersecurity-framework-new-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-65193" srcset="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/nist-cybersecurity-framework-new-2.png 1752w, https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/nist-cybersecurity-framework-new-2-768x466.png 768w, https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/nist-cybersecurity-framework-new-2-1536x931.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1752px) 100vw, 1752px" /></figure>



<p><strong>O que é o Essential Eight?</strong></p>



<p>O Essential Eight é um termo utilizado para descrever oito atividades de alta prioridade que ajudam as organizações a protegerem-se contra as ameaças à segurança cibernética. As atividades são: controle de aplicações, monitorização da atividade dos usuários, proteção de dados, controle de acesso, contracepção, gestão de vulnerabilidades, resposta a incidentes e recuperação. Ao implementar estas atividades, as organizações podem reduzir significativamente o seu risco de serem violadas por criminosos cibernéticos sofisticados. O termo foi criado pelo Australian Cyber Security Centre (ACSC), e desde então tem sido adotado por outros governos e organizações de segurança em todo o mundo.</p>



<p><strong>Desafios na <em>application Whitelist</em></strong></p>



<p>Embora a nossa global <em>whitelist</em> tenha uma taxa de sucesso de 99,996%, não é perfeita, e provavelmente nunca será. Apesar de ser extremamente raro, é possível aos agentes de ameaça criar uma aplicação maliciosa que &#8220;se parece&#8221; com uma aplicação conhecida, duplicando o nome do arquivo, caminho do arquivo, tamanho do arquivo, assinatura digital, e/ou hash criptográfico. Além disso, os ataques de engenharia social podem facilmente contornar todas as medidas de segurança, e a <em>application whitelisting </em>não é diferente. Nestes eventos, é importante ter um nível de segurança completo que ajuda a detectar e responder a ameaças.&nbsp;O software de <em>application whitelisting</em> requer manutenção pró-activa &#8211; não se pode configurar e esquecer. As soluções tradicionais whitelisting têm colocado um peso sobre os processos de trabalho de profissionais de TI. A nossa solução aborda este problema na nossa lista patenteada de aplicações de whitelisting global que é atualizada 24/7/365 pela nossa equipa especializada de investigadores de malware que são totalmente operados e geridos nos Estados Unidos. Atribuindo na extensão da sua equipa de TI que está constantemente a avaliar cada nova aplicação em busca de vulnerabilidades.</p>



<p><strong>Melhores Práticas para um Processo Eficaz de Whitelisting</strong></p>



<p>A implementação de um processo eficaz de <em>whitelisting</em> é a melhor forma de proteger a sua rede e os seus dados. Mas como é que se procede à criação de um processo de whitelisting? Aqui algumas das melhores práticas a ter em mente:</p>



<p><strong>Antes da implementação</strong></p>



<p>Primeiro, faça uma lista de todas as aplicações que são essenciais para o seu negócio. Esta será a base para a sua whitelist. Em seguida, desenvolva uma política de gestão e aprovação das inscrições. Esta deve incluir quem é responsável pela aprovação da <em>application whitelisting</em>. Durante este processo, sinta-se à vontade para contactar a nossa equipe de apoio ao cliente, se tiver alguma dúvida ou precisar de assistência</p>



<p><strong>Durante a implementação</strong></p>



<p>Uma vez implementada a sua política, é tempo de começar a implementá-la. Comece por realizar uma auditoria completa da sua rede para garantir que nada de malicioso está atualmente a ser autorizado a ser executado. Em seguida, bloqueia todas as aplicações que não estejam na whitelist, tanto as aplicações on-prem como as aplicações nebulosas, se aplicável. Isto pode ser feito de forma geral, por departamento/grupo, ou por utilizador, para garantir que todos têm as permissões corretas para a sua função. Depois, implemente o seu processo de aprovação para adicionar novas application whitelisting.</p>



<p><strong>Após a implementação</strong></p>



<p>Por último, rever regularmente a whitelist para garantir que está actualizada. Recomendamos auditorias regulares da sua rede para verificar possíveis vulnerabilidades, ou pode utilizar as nossas ferramentas de relatório integradas para obter informações em tempo real sobre aplicações bloqueadas, novas sessões de RDP, arquivos em quarentena, e mais. Finalmente, informe-se sobre as tendências de cibersegurança e procure constantemente formas de melhorar o seu nível de segurança.</p>



<p><strong>Proteja a sua rede</strong></p>



<p>Serviços gratuitos de proteção de endpoints como o Windows AppLocker da Microsoft simplesmente não são o suficiente para proteger a sua empresa contra os ataques de malware nos dias de hoje. A PC Matic assegura a segurança do seu ambiente.</p>



<p><strong>Tecnologia Proativa da Whitelist</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p>A nossa<em> application whitelist</em> é mais abrangente do que as soluções tradicionais de application whitelisting, foi testada com 99,996% com eficácia de arquivo, e bloqueia uniformemente malware e ransomware desconhecido do que a tradicional blacklist e soluções heurísticas. A nossa application whitelist patenteada é constituída:</p>



<ul><li>Por uma Global Application Whitelist: Uma whitelist global automatizada de aplicações confiáveis por endpoint que pode verificar e atualizar em tempo real.</li><li>Uma Local Application Whitelist: As aplicações personalizadas podem ser adicionadas localmente com um simples clique à whitelist global automatizada.</li><li>Assinatura Whitelist: As aplicações de assinaturas são adicionadas através da assinatura do editor, eliminando a necessidade de hashes de <em>application whitelisting </em>anteriores e futuras.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Pesquisa Avançada de Malware baseada a 100% nos E.U.A.</strong></p>



<p>Ao ser um cliente PC Matic, obtém imediatamente acesso a uma equipa de pesquisadores de malware que avaliam milhões de novas ameaças 24/7/365. Pense em nós como a sua própria equipa pessoal de cibersegurança ou como uma extensão da sua equipe, mas sem custos adicionais.</p>



<p><strong>Pare o Ransomware nos seus Percursos</strong></p>



<p>A Ransomware está rapidamente a tornar-se uma epidemia global para as empresas que dependem da tecnologia. A PC Matic aplica proteção contra adulterações em cada dispositivo para garantir que a<em> appplication whitelist</em> esteja sempre em operação e seja capaz de bloquear até os mais recentes ransomware.</p>



<p><strong>Análises de Aplicativos</strong></p>



<p>O PC Matic realiza diagnósticos em cada dispositivo. Ao ser avaliado no teste AV-Test, o nosso produto teve o menor impacto entre as soluções AV no tempo de transferência, tempo de execução, tempo de instalação, tempo de carregamento da web, e tempo de cópia de arquivo. A lentidão dos usuários pode levar a menos produtividade e mais chamadas de TI.</p>



<p><strong>Gerenciamento Customizado</strong></p>



<p>Com um gerenciamento baseado em nuvem, que protege todos os dispositivos na sua rede, ao mesmo tempo utiliza um VNC integrado, Prompt CMD remoto, Gerenciador de arquivos, Remoto de encerramento e reinicialização, Programação de RDP, </p>



<p><strong>Pare o Ransomware nos seus Percursos</strong></p>



<p>A Ransomware está rapidamente a tornar-se uma epidemia global para as empresas que dependem da tecnologia. A PC Matic aplica proteção contra adulterações em cada dispositivo para garantir que a<em> appplication whitelist</em> esteja sempre em operação e seja capaz de bloquear até os mais recentes ransomware.</p>



<p><strong>Análises de Aplicativos</strong></p>



<p>O PC Matic realiza diagnósticos em cada dispositivo. Ao ser avaliado no teste AV-Test, o nosso produto teve o menor impacto entre as soluções AV no tempo de transferência, tempo de execução, tempo de instalação, tempo de carregamento da web, e tempo de cópia de arquivo. A lentidão dos usuários pode levar a menos produtividade e mais chamadas de TI.</p>



<p><strong>Gerenciamento Customizado</strong></p>



<p>Com um gerenciamento baseado em nuvem, que protege todos os dispositivos na sua rede, ao mesmo tempo utiliza um VNC integrado, Prompt CMD remoto, Gerenciador de arquivos, Remoto de encerramento e reinicialização, Programação de RDP, e outros.</p>



<p><strong>Não reage às ameaças cibernéticas &#8211; previna-as com PC Matic.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/o-que-e-application-whitelisting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Employment Identity Theft?</title>
      <link>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/what-is-employment-identity-theft/</link>
      <comments>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/what-is-employment-identity-theft/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nick Buikema]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 13:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Home Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/?p=66306</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Many Americans already know about identity theft, which occurs when someone takes your personal information, like your address, credit card number, and Social Security number, and carries out fraudulent transactions in your name. But that’s not the only type of identity theft you might encounter. In fact, if you’re unlucky, you might be the victim &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/what-is-employment-identity-theft/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is Employment Identity Theft?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Many Americans already know about identity theft, which occurs when someone takes your personal information, like your address, credit card number, and Social Security number, and carries out fraudulent transactions in your name. But that’s not the only type of identity theft you might encounter. In fact, if you’re unlucky, you might be the victim of employment identity theft.</p>



<p>But what exactly is employment identity theft, and how does it happen? More importantly, how can you protect yourself against it? This guide will break down the answers to these questions and more.</p>



<h2>Employment Identity Theft Explained</h2>



<p>Employment identity theft, in a nutshell, is the use of a person’s personal information to apply for and work jobs. For example, an identity thief may scoop the information from a person using a cyber attack or by stealing their Social Security number in another way, then apply for and get a job for remote work using that information. They earn money under the identity theft victim’s name, then abandon the identity when they get what they want.</p>



<p>Put another way, employment identity theft is <em>any</em> identity theft where the point of the theft is to use the victim’s credentials for employment purposes. It’s contrasted with “standard” identity theft only because most normal identity theft occurs out of a desire to sell the victim’s information on the black market.</p>



<h3>Is Employment Identity Theft Illegal?</h3>



<p>Yes. Employment identity theft is always illegal. Once reported, organizations like the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Social Security Administration (SSA), and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) will work with the victim in order to correct the record and alleviate any negative effects the victim may experience.</p>



<h3>Effects of Employment Identity Theft</h3>



<p>Unfortunately, employment-related identity theft can lead to a wide range of negative effects, some of which are short-term and some of which can follow the victim for years.</p>



<p>For example, a victim of employment identity theft may find that the thief used their information to not only acquire employment but also to open up several lines of credit and to acquire various bills. Over months, the identity thief doesn’t pay down the credit or bills, resulting in damage to the victim’s credit score in the eyes of the three major credit bureaus: Experian, Equifax, and TransUnion.</p>



<p>As another example, a victim of employment identity theft may be terminated from their current place of employment if their employer finds out that they have been applying to or working at competing jobs, even if it wasn&#8217;t really them. The victim may need to explain the situation quickly and prove their innocence in order to keep their job, which can be very difficult to do.</p>



<p>No matter what, employment identity theft always results in anxiety, major headaches, and long-term frustration as victims work to resolve the issue.</p>



<h2>How Does Employment Identity Theft Happen?</h2>



<p>This form of identity theft can happen under a variety of circumstances. Here are some examples.</p>



<h3>Employer Uses Inaccurate Credentials</h3>



<p>One way in which employment identity theft can happen involves an employer hiring someone with inaccurate or stolen credentials. They may interview an employee, find that they have a Social Security number, driver’s license number, and other key information, and hire them assuming that they are hiring the person they claim to be. This can happen if they don’t do a comprehensive background check, including a check of bank account info and a check of an applicant’s credit report.</p>



<p>However, later on, they determine that the credentials used were false or inaccurate in some way. When they go to investigate, the identity thief vanishes or flees, leaving the employer confused as to who they really hired and who they inadvertently hurt in the process.</p>



<h3>Applications for Limited-Term Job Offers</h3>



<p>Many organizations and industries offer limited time job opportunities for short-term work, usually at distant worksites and for periods of between three months and two years. Those with criminal records or other reasons not to apply to jobs with their real information may steal the identities of the victims, then apply to these limited term job offers in the hopes that their crimes will not be noticed until the jobs are done.</p>



<h3>Employment Identity Theft by Colleagues</h3>



<p>Additionally, victims may experience employment identity theft because of their coworkers or colleagues. A jealous colleague, for example, may voluntarily steal the information of a coworker who received a promotion during a data breach, then sell the information on the dark web.</p>



<p>Alternatively, they may use the credentials of a victim to perform fraudulent or harmful workplace actions in the hope of framing the victim in some way. Such scenarios are not very common, but they can happen if you aren’t careful about who knows your personal information and who has access to key workplace terminals/information.</p>



<h2>Ways to Guard Against Employment Identity Theft</h2>



<p>Fortunately, employers and employees alike can both guard against employment identity theft by following several secure strategies.</p>



<h3>ID Theft Protection for Employees</h3>



<p>As an employee, there are lots of ways to keep your identifying information safe, including:</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Always keep your personally identifiable information confidential, particularly your Social Security number. Don’t voice your SSN in public and keep your Social Security card at home unless you need to take it with you</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Similarly, don’t store any personal information on your work computer, including passwords, your personal email address, debit and credit card info, tax return info, and so on</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Always be cautious when using public Wi-Fi networks. If possible, use a VPN in order to mask your IP address</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stay aware of and avoid phishing scams. These are email based cyber attacks that occur when someone uses an email or text to trick you into providing financial or other personal information. These types of messages often appear to come from a legitimate source, but really mask an attempt from a cyber criminal to get your personal info</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Utilize cybersecurity software at your workplace terminal and at your home computers. Security software can prevent malware and other malicious software from being installed on your devices, thus keeping your personal identifying information safe</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Try to lock your Social Security number with E-Verify, a US government service that enables government services and employees to verify your identity and employment eligibility. E-Verify also lets you lock your SSN, which prevents employers from hiring fraudulent job applicants</p>



<p>It’s always best to practice these before you become the victim of identity theft. While it’s possible to reclaim your identity and get out of any credit damage or debts that may have been made in your name, it’s a lot of work to do so, and you may not be able to recover fully.</p>



<p>Instead, practice these tips ASAP to keep your personal information secure at all times.</p>



<h3>ID Theft Protection for Employers</h3>



<p>If you’re an employer, you can take steps to protect your employees against employment identity theft by following strategies like these:</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Train your employees to recognize cyber attacks and identity scams, like phishing scams, through seminars and mandated workplace training. This is good for your overall cyber hygiene as well, as it will help your business stay safe and secure against digital attacks</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Be sure to use workplace firewalls and to implement other digital security best practices. Encrypt vital employee information and don’t store employee information on any computers that are connected to the Internet</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Try to screen new employees and handle sensitive information properly. For example, you should minimize the number of employees who have access to other employees’ personal data. Always screen new candidates carefully by double checking Social Security numbers and other information. That way, you won’t accidentally contribute to employment identity theft or hire a fraudulent employee</p>



<p>·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Offer your employees identity theft protection as one of your benefits. Theft protection services can help victims intervene quickly and alert them when their sensitive information appears somewhere online. Fraud alerts can also connect directly to government agencies to facilitate a fast response. These are great benefits both for your employees and you since you’ll save money by not hiring fraudulent employees in the first place</p>



<p>In the end, integrating and implementing these strategies will benefit your bottom line in more ways than one. You’ll inspire more confidence in your employees, plus save money since you won’t hire bad employees and have to replace them with new ones sooner rather than later.</p>



<h2>Wrap Up</h2>



<p>Ultimately, employment identity theft can happen to anyone. But by taking the right preventative steps, you can minimize the likelihood that you’ll ever experience this or have to deal with frustrating situations with the IRS and credit bureaus. Keep these tips in mind, and remember to keep your work ID information safe and secure at all times!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.pcmatic.com/blog/what-is-employment-identity-theft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>