<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="0.92">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest World News Headlines | Daily Telegraph</title>
    <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au</link>
    <description>We're for Sydney</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:33:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <item>
      <title>Israel strikes back with airstrikes after rocket attacks from militants</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have launched airstrikes on Lebanon and Gaza in retaliation to rocket attacks by Palestinian militants.

Two sisters have also been killed by a Palestinian gunman in the West Bank.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/israel-strikes-back-with-airstrikes-after-rocket-attacks-from-militants/video/1a478973e9462ae3dc6bc2ca7888381c</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekend marks one year since triple murder at Grantville gun store</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Hawk family is asking their neighbors to remember Tommy, Evenlyn and Luke in their prayers and celebrate their lives this weekend. It has been one year since they were gunned down at their family-owned gun store in Grantville.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/weekend-marks-one-year-since-triple-murder-at-grantville-gun-store/video/68ab3b6fbb07668fd587444c1a4b375b</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Push continues for Michigan animal abuse registry</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Michigan voters could soon decide on if there should be a registry for people who have abused animals.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/push-continues-for-michigan-animal-abuse-registry/video/1d2d7d404d1ef180e2bf483c1f730746</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turf war between DeSantis, Disney could lead to higher prices at Disney World</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis' objection to Disney opposing some of his conservative legislation and the company's advocacy for LGBTQ+ rights has led to a fight that could increase prices to visit the amusement park.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/turf-war-between-desantis-disney-could-lead-to-higher-prices-at-disney-world/video/02e865d958934323fd9e02fab88c5f77</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study: 4 in 10 Michigan nurses say they plan to leave job</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Many Michigan nurses are leaving their jobs, and according to a board member with the state's Nurses Association, hospital conditions are to blame for this.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/study-4-in-10-michigan-nurses-say-they-plan-to-leave-job/video/811e1aa0b2eea8639d3194f44f15f8a8</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former NFL player works to sign up organ donors after getting new kidney</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Former Tampa Bay Bucs player Bobby Howard life changed in 1994 after the NFL running back went into kidney failure at just 28. After 7 months on dialysis, he finally found a donor. Now, he is working to ensure others sign up to be organ donors.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/former-nfl-player-works-to-sign-up-organ-donors-after-getting-new-kidney/video/d9e78a55a673752ff8470254f12f4758</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivy City Hotel issues statement after deadly stabbing</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Ivy City Hotel issued a statement Friday - one week after a Virginia woman was stabbed to death inside one of their hotel rooms.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/ivy-city-hotel-issues-statement-after-deadly-stabbing/video/1eab585b603424619435e1bab3919eb6</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Day Atlanta: What’s the best food at Augusta National?</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The pimento cheese and egg salad sandwiches are just as legendary as the Masters Tournament golf. Kelly Price sets out to find the best menu item of all at Augusta National.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/good-day-atlanta-whats-the-best-food-at-augusta-national/video/955e575cde11d841e90687c461f0ae9d</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At least 20 families displaced after massive apartment fire in Detroit</title>
      <description><![CDATA[A fire at an apartment in Detroit injured 11 people and has left at least 20 families without a home. Police are now investigating whether a deadly shooting at the apartment is connected to the fire.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/at-least-20-families-displaced-after-massive-apartment-fire-in-detroit/video/b30593157ad260a6619667759ac2be14</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family trip to Delaware County store turns into life-changing moment they will never forget</title>
      <description><![CDATA[A family just trying to make life easier for their son, walks out of a store with not just a new friend, but some life-changing help.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/family-trip-to-delaware-county-store-turns-into-lifechanging-moment-they-will-never-forget/video/7a36e80a5335a4d6b578f4bc30d9c910</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>