<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:ctv="http://www.ctv.ca/rss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[CTVNews.ca - World - Public RSS]]></title>
    <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/rss/world/ctvnews-ca-world-public-rss-1.822289</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 19:03:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright Bellmedia</copyright>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Blast at north Iraqi airport raises tension in Kurdish area]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/blast-at-north-iraqi-airport-raises-tension-in-kurdish-area-1.6347147</link>
      <description><![CDATA[An explosion struck next to the Suleimaniyah International Airport in northern Iraq's semi-autonomous Kurdish region Friday, local officials said. The blast came days after Turkiye closed its airspace to flights to and from the airport, citing an alleged increase in Kurdish militant activity threatening flight safety.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6347147</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 15:33:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 15:33:10 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6347150.1680895758!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[New housing development is seen in the town of Sulaimaniyah, Iraq, Tuesday, March 21, 2023. (AP Photo/Hawre Khalid, Metrography)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Report: Russia formally charges Wall Street Journal reporter]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/report-russia-formally-charges-wall-street-journal-reporter-1.6347007</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Jailed Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich has been charged with espionage in Russia and has entered a formal denial, two Russian news agencies reported Friday.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6347007</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 12:39:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 12:48:47 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6345944.1680805869!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[The Wall Street Journal journalist Evan Gershkovich is shown in this undated photo. Russia's security service arrested the American reporter for The Wall Street Journal on espionage charges, the first time a U.S. correspondent has been detained on spying accusations since the Cold War, the Federal Security Service, known by the acronym FSB, said Thursday, March 30, 2023. The newspaper denied the allegations and demanded his release. (The Wall Street Journal via AP)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris to meet with expelled Tennessee lawmakers]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/kamala-harris-to-meet-with-expelled-tennessee-lawmakers-1.6347279</link>
      <description><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris made a last-minute trip to Tennessee on Friday, hours after the Republican-controlled House expelled two Democratic lawmakers from the Legislature in retaliation for their role in a protest calling for more gun control.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6347279</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 19:03:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 19:03:38 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6347280.1680908552!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris greets Tennessee lawmakers at an event where she was meeting with Gloria Johnson, D-Knoxville, Justin Jones and Justin Pearson at Fisk University in Nashville, Tenn., on Friday, April 7, 2023. (Andrew Nelles/The Tennessean via AP)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Russia hits illegally annexed Ukraine areas from ground, air]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/russia-hits-illegally-annexed-ukraine-areas-from-ground-air-1.6347106</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Russian forces used ground- and air-fired missiles, rocket launchers and weaponized drones to bombard the provinces of Ukraine it has illegally annexed but doesn't fully control, causing casualties, building damage and power outages Friday.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6347106</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 14:54:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 14:54:43 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6347110.1680893494!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[A lifeless body covered by plastic lies on the ground at a street market after the shelling that Russian officials in Donetsk said was conducted by Ukrainian forces, in Donetsk, in Russian-controlled Donetsk region, eastern Ukraine, Friday, April 7, 2023. (AP Photo)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Man kills hostage at California park after wounding officer]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/man-kills-hostage-at-california-park-after-wounding-officer-1.6346908</link>
      <description><![CDATA[A man fleeing police in Northern California took two hostages at a public park, killing one of them before surrendering, after earlier wounding a California Highway Patrol officer, authorities said.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6346908</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 08:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 12:46:58 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6346910.1680872157!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[Police investigate a shooting near Mahany Park in Roseville, Calif., Thursday, April 6, 2023. (Scott Strazzante/San Francisco Chronicle via AP)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Pope Francis skips Good Friday at Colosseum in chilly Rome]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/pope-francis-skips-good-friday-at-colosseum-in-chilly-rome-1.6347272</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis, hospitalized recently with bronchitis, skipped the traditional Good Friday nighttime procession at the Colosseum because of chilly weather in Rome, staying instead at his home at the Vatican while thousands of faithful turned out for the torchlit event.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6347272</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 18:48:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 18:48:53 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6347273.1680907650!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[People hold candles is prior to the start of a Via Crucis (Way of the Cross) torchlight procession on Good Friday, in Rome, Friday, April 7, 2023]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[SKorea, U.S., Japan call for support of ban on NKorea workers]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/skorea-u-s-japan-call-for-support-of-ban-on-nkorea-workers-1.6346926</link>
      <description><![CDATA[South Korea, the U.S. and Japan called for stronger international support of efforts to ban North Korea from sending workers abroad and curb the North's cybercrimes as a way to block the country's means to fund its nuclear program.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6346926</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 09:44:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 09:44:01 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6346928.1680874844!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[From left to right, Japanese nuclear envoy Takehiro Funakoshi, chief South Korean nuclear negotiator, Kim Gunn, and Sung Kim, the U.S. special representative to North Korea pose together before their three-way meeting at the Foreign Ministry in Seoul, South Korea, Friday, April 7, 2023. (Joen Heon-Kyun/Pool Photo via AP)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Attacks in Israel, West Bank kill 3 in worsening violence]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/attacks-in-israel-west-bank-kill-3-in-worsening-violence-1.6346904</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Palestinian militants carried out a pair of attacks on Friday, killing three people and wounding at least six as tensions soared after days of fighting at Jerusalem's most sensitive holy site. Earlier in the day, retaliatory Israeli airstrikes had hit Lebanon and the Gaza Strip, sparking fears of a broader conflict.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6346904</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 08:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 18:33:05 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6346906.1680871791!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[Palestinians inspect damage from overnight Israeli airstrikes in Gaza City, Friday, April 7, 2023. (AP Photo/Fatima Shbair)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[China sanctions groups, Taiwan official in U.S. as retaliation]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/china-sanctions-groups-taiwan-official-in-u-s-as-retaliation-1.6346816</link>
      <description><![CDATA[China announced sanctions Friday against two Asia-based organizations and Taiwan's representative in the U.S. in response to the closely watched meeting this week between the U.S. House Speaker and Taiwan's president.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6346816</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 6 Apr 2023 23:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 15:03:26 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6346820.1680837135!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[In this photo released by the Taiwan Presidential Office, Michael McCaul, chairman of the Foreign Affairs Committee in the United States House of Representatives, centre left, and his wife Linda Mays McCaul, center right, gesture with Taiwan's deputy foreign minister Tah-ray Yui, third from left, and their delegations upon arrival in Taipei, Taiwan, Thursday, April 6, 2023.]]></enclosure>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Afghanistan women-run radio resumes broadcasts after shutdown]]></title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/world/afghanistan-women-run-radio-resumes-broadcasts-after-shutdown-1.6346893</link>
      <description><![CDATA[A women-run radio station in northeastern Afghanistan has resumed its broadcasts, after officials shut it down for a week for playing music during the holy month of Ramadan, a Taliban official and the head of the station said Friday.]]></description>
      <author>
      </author>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Associated Press]]></dc:creator>
      <creditLine><![CDATA[Staff]]></creditLine>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1.6346893</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 08:23:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <ctv:lastModifiedDate>Fri, 7 Apr 2023 08:23:56 -0400</ctv:lastModifiedDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.6346894.1680870100!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_800/image.jpg"><![CDATA[Najia Sorosh head of Sadai Banowan a women-run radio station, left, speaks into a microphone in the broadcasting studio in Badakhshan province, north-eastern of Afghanistan, Wednesday, Jan. 4, 2023. (Sadai Banowan via AP)]]></enclosure>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>