<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="0.92">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest World News Headlines | Daily Telegraph</title>
    <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au</link>
    <description>We're for Sydney</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 02:54:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer, heart disease jabs by end of decade</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The pharmaceutical firm behind a major Covid jab has claimed it has the ability to manufacture vaccines for cancer, heart conditions and auto-immune diseases by the end of the decade.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/cancer-heart-disease-vaccines-by-end-of-decade/news-story/150bedc96937b7af2e5a15e086147458</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police: Girl, 12, badly hurt in Cobbs Creek shooting</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Police say a 12-year-old girl was shot in the backside Friday night in Philadelphia's Cobbs Creek section.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/police-girl-12-badly-hurt-in-cobbs-creek-shooting/video/ec1e6fb1ce6ca090b3f52dc011c60ae0</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walk for Hope returns to Detroit with urgent call to end gun violence</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Demonstrators took to the streets in Detroit on Friday evening as they called for an end to gun violence during the Walk for Hope.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/walk-for-hope-returns-to-detroit-with-urgent-call-to-end-gun-violence/video/2e9ff3be26a525a08bdc3905204d8a39</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada’s infant mortality rate on the rise</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Canada’s infant mortality rate is on the rise. The country has fallen from the top 10 of developed nations to near the bottom of the ranking — a clear sign that health care and support for new mothers is slipping.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/canadas-infant-mortality-rate-on-the-rise/video/d9d67e894933b3adc6c77fa71c253228</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quebec major junior hockey league bans fighting</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Quebec Major Junior Hockey League has voted to ban fighting, with players facing automatic expulsion starting next season. The aim is to protect the health of vulnerable young adults.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/quebec-major-junior-hockey-league-bans-fighting/video/73d9bf9e8ba234e44bd88e787b50d873</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ice storm death toll rises amid widespread power outages</title>
      <description><![CDATA[A third person has died in connection with a powerful ice storm that hit Quebec and Ontario. This comes as hundreds of thousands of customers remain without power.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/ice-storm-death-toll-rises-amid-widespread-power-outages/video/b751d495ba7c73a37fad55c7ff22c349</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family celebrates first Easter holiday in Canada after escaping war</title>
      <description><![CDATA[A family is celebrating their first Easter holiday in Canada after escaping the war in Ukraine. They say their prayers for safety, after spending years trapped between wars, have been answered.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/family-celebrates-first-easter-holiday-in-canada-after-escaping-war/video/f9349432bb41039406ba08070c78f4f2</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critics say new rental regulations do little to help renters</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Ontario has proposed new rental regulations in an effort to protect renters from so-called ‘renovictions’. But critics say the changes will mostly help landlords and do little to help renters.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/critics-say-new-rental-regulations-do-little-to-help-renters/video/5661ab9931b12ac0ed47fb5e269a3415</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Philadelphia schools close, due to asbestos, school district officials say</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Mitchell Elementary, in Southwest Philly, and Frankford High School, in Frankford, are closing, due to asbestos found.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/2-philadelphia-schools-close-due-to-asbestos-school-district-officials-say/video/ffb867468402a5ea2c4dfda1aceb1624</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canadian schools grappling with use of ChatGPT</title>
      <description><![CDATA[As artificial intelligence like ChatGPT begins to arrive in Canadian schools, teachers consider its impact on education. Some argue it should be banned, while others suggest making it a part of learning while focusing on critical thinking and creativity.]]></description>
      <link>https://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/world/canadian-schools-grappling-with-use-of-chatgpt/video/b98a5a0d7dfa798f4d61b4db7c1b18ee</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>