<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Avira Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.avira.com/en/blog/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Security News, Reviews and Recommendations</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 09:59:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.webassetscdn.com/avira/prod-blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/cropped-Logo_only_500-1-300x300.png</url>
      <title>Avira Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>How secure is online banking from hackers’ attacks?</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/how-secure-is-online-banking-from-hackers-attacks</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 09:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67906</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Many banks have reduced the number of branches significantly simply because huge numbers of us have long since been using online banking for everyday financial matters. Getting small amounts of money paid out at the supermarket checkout also means there’s no need anymore to pop to the bank. You could say it’s a win-win: Banks]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is scareware &amp; how do I protect myself?</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/what-is-scareware-how-do-i-protect-myself</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 06:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67856</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[At some point in your life, you&#8217;ve probably been scammed or threatened by someone telling you that something bad is going to happen unless you do what they ask right away. Almost every scam in the analog world has its counterpart in the digital world, and cybercriminals are very cunning at constantly coming up with]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phone hacking: Here’s how not to become a victim</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/phone-hacking-heres-how-not-to-become-a-victim</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67723</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[From banking online to storing photos and saving log-in details for many different online platforms and services — it feels like our smartphones are an extension of ourselves. This makes your smartphone a lucrative target for cyberattacks, with phone hacking posing a particularly serious threat. Read on to learn what the tell-tale warning signs are]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If your WhatsApp account’s been hacked, here’s how to get it back</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/if-your-whatsapp-accounts-been-hacked-heres-how-to-get-it-back</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 11:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67585</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Meta (formerly Facebook) has owned the messaging service WhatsApp since 2009. Unlike texting or making calls, WhatsApp is packed full of great features many of us can’t do without, such as free international calls via the internet and end-to-end encryption. But if your WhatsApp account gets hacked, it can quickly turn your world upside down.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avira’s Cyber Threat Report: Latest Trends and Emerging Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/avira-cyberthreat-report-22-h2</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira Protection Labs]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 16:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67079</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Foreword The Avira Threat Protection Labs has released a second global threat report for 2022, which delves into the latest threats and trends observed in Avira global telemetry during the latter half of the year. Given the diverse and complex nature of the cyber threat landscape, this research concentrates on emerging and developing cyber threats,]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If your Snapchat account’s been hacked, here’s our step-by-step guide to getting your account back</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/if-your-snapchat-accounts-been-hacked-heres-our-step-by-step-guide-to-getting-your-account-back</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 13:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67528</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In Q2 2022 Snapchat reached the phenomenal figure of 347 million users globally, making it one of the most popular social networks among youngsters. And since this platform continues to grow in popularity, you can imagine just how much of a honey pot it is to an increasing number of cybercriminals despite Snapchat taking loads]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to block ads in your browser?</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/want-to-block-ads-in-your-browser</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 16:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=66460</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Many of us have stuck a “No Flyers!” notice on our front doors or mailboxes because we don’t want any ads or direct mail. Things are just as bad in the online world, with those online ads that pop up driving us to despair just as quickly. Thankfully, virtual equivalents exist to the no-flyer notice.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A VPN helps protect your online privacy and make surfing more secure</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/a-vpn-helps-protect-your-online-privacy-and-make-surfing-more-secure</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=66008</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Entering your PIN when paying with your debit card, a confidential chat, your own four walls: Many of us value privacy as something precious, and we’d do anything to protect ourselves and our loved ones from any kind of attack. That is, apart from when using our many digital devices, when many of us drop]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can you protect yourself from cyberstalkers?</title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/how-can-you-protect-yourself-from-cyberstalkers</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 10:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=67002</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[We’re always hearing in the press about celebrities being cyberstalked. But now they’re not the only ones. According to various studies, like the Norton Cyber Safety Insights Report, around 12% of people will be stalked at least once in their lifetime — and an even sadder statistic is that it’s mostly (over 80%) women who]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top 10 absolute must-see hacker movies </title>
      <link>https://www.avira.com/en/blog/the-top-10-absolute-must-see-hacker-movies</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Avira]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.avira.com/en/blog/?p=66664</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Love science fiction movies, where people are threatened by an AI created by cybercriminals, where only smart but also marginalized or underground programmer nerds can save our world?   Then we’ve got something for you: Our top 10 absolute must-see hacker movies and series on true and fictional stories about hacking and cybersecurity. Sometimes decades old,]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Content Delivery Network via Amazon Web Services: S3: www.webassetscdn.com/avira/prod-blog
Minified using disk

Served from: 10.165.130.85 @ 2023-04-06 13:18:22 by W3 Total Cache
-->