<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>IdentityIQ</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.identityiq.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.identityiq.com/</link>
    <description>Identity Theft Protection</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 16:57:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.identityiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
      <title>IdentityIQ</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>How to Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-airline-scams/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tristini Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 21:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=6188</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-airline-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Scammers are always looking for ways to take advantage of people, and the airline industry is no exception. Whether through fake airline ticket booking sites or fake flight cancellation emails, travelers need to be vigilant and protect themselves from airline scams. In this blog, we provide tips and advice on recognizing and avoiding airline [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-airline-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/ttomlinson/">Tristini Tomlinson</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-airline-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-1 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-1 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-0 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-1"><p>Scammers are always looking for ways to take advantage of people, and the airline industry is no exception. Whether through fake airline ticket booking sites or fake flight cancellation emails, travelers need to be vigilant and protect themselves from airline scams.</p>
<p>In this blog, we provide tips and advice on recognizing and avoiding airline scams to help you have a safe and stress-free travel experience.</p>
<h2>How Do Airline Scams Work?</h2>
<p>Airline scams trick unsuspecting travelers into paying for something that either doesn&#8217;t exist or is poor quality. These scams can take many forms, and scammers use a variety of tactics to lure in their victims.</p>
<p>For example, some may create fake websites to advertise phony deals or services, while others may pose as legitimate airlines or booking companies in phishing scams designed to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">steal personal information</a> or credit card information.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, these scams can be difficult to detect, as scammers are often skilled at making their offers appear legitimate.</p>
<h2>6 Common Airline Scams</h2>
<p>Here are six common airline scams to watch out for.</p>
<h3>Fake Flight-Booking Websites</h3>
<p>Scammers create websites that mimic legitimate booking sites with similar logos and layouts. These sites may offer attractive deals on flights or vacation packages that are often too good to be true.</p>
<p>After customers enter their payment information, scammers may provide fake tickets. Or, they may disappear altogether. Therefore, it&#8217;s important to double-check the website&#8217;s URL and ensure that it&#8217;s the airline&#8217;s official site or a reputable booking platform.</p>
<h3>&#8220;Too Good to Be True&#8221;</h3>
<p>Scammers may use ads or emails to offer customers incredibly low prices on flights or travel packages. They may use fake customer reviews to make their offer seem more legitimate. After customers make a payment, scammers may provide fake tickets. Or, once again, they may disappear altogether.</p>
<p>To help avoid this scam, customers should be wary of any deal that seems too good to be true and double-check the seller&#8217;s credentials.</p>
<h3>Fake Flight Cancellation Emails</h3>
<p><a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/how-recognize-and-avoid-phishing-scams">Scammers send emails</a> that look like they&#8217;re from a legitimate airline or booking platform, claiming that the customer&#8217;s flight has been cancelled. The email may direct the customer to a link to reschedule or obtain a refund.</p>
<p>However, the link leads to a fake website where the customer enters their payment or personal information, which the scammer then uses for fraud. Therefore, customers should be wary of any email requesting payment or personal information and double-check the airline&#8217;s website or customer support for information about flight cancellations.</p>
<h3>&#8220;Declined&#8221; Credit Card Payments</h3>
<p>Scammers send emails or call customers claiming their payment has been declined, asking them to enter their credit card information to complete the transaction. This information is then used for fraudulent purposes.</p>
<p>Customers should be cautious of any unexpected communication regarding payment, especially if it asks for personal or payment information.</p>
<h3>Robocalls Offering &#8220;Free&#8221; Vacations</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/can-robocalls-steal-your-identity/">Scammers use robocalls</a> to offer customers a &#8220;free&#8221; airfare and vacations but require them to pay hidden fees or attend a timeshare presentation. Unfortunately, these vacations are usually not as advertised, and the fees are exorbitant.</p>
<p>Customers should be wary of unsolicited offers for free airline tickets and vacations and double-check the seller&#8217;s credentials before agreeing to anything.</p>
<h3>Fake Airline Customer Support</h3>
<p><a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/consumer-alerts/2020/08/scammers-and-customer-service-another-imposter-scam">Scammers set up fake customer support</a> lines or social media accounts pretending to be a legitimate airline, helping customers with issues. The scammers then ask for personal or payment information, which they use for fraud.</p>
<p>Customers should only contact customer support through official channels and refrain from providing personal or payment information over the phone or through social media.</p>
<h2>How to Help Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</h2>
<p>Protecting yourself from airline scams requires a combination of vigilance and caution. First, always research before booking a flight and double-check the seller&#8217;s credentials or booking platform. Be wary of deals that seem too good to be true. Never provide personal or payment information to an unsolicited source.</p>
<p>Additionally, monitor your credit card transactions regularly to ensure no unauthorized charges. Finally, consider <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">signing up for identity theft protection</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a> identity theft protection services can help safeguard your personal information and alert you to suspicious activity. By staying informed and cautious, you can minimize your risk of falling prey to airline scams.</p>
<h2>Where to Report Airline Scams</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;ve fallen victim to an airline scam, it&#8217;s important to report it to the appropriate authorities to help prevent future fraud and potentially recover your losses.</p>
<p>You can report the scams to your local law enforcement authorities as well as to the <a href="https://reportfraud.ftc.gov/#/">Federal Trade Commission (FTC)</a> or the <a href="https://www.bbb.org/scamtracker">Better Business Bureaus (BBB)</a>.</p>
<h2>Bottom Line</h2>
<p>To protect yourself from airline scams, be cautious of deals that seem too good to be true, double-check the seller&#8217;s or booking platform&#8217;s credentials, and never provide personal or payment information to unsolicited sources.</p>
<p>Monitor your credit card transactions regularly and invest in <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/how-we-protect-you/">identity theft protection</a>.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-0{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-0 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-0{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-0 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-0{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-0 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-1{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-yourself-from-airline-scams/">How to Protect Yourself from Airline Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/ttomlinson/">Tristini Tomlinson</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romance Scams and Relationship Scams: What’s the Difference?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/romance-scams-and-relationship-scams-whats-the-difference/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 20:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=6185</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/romance-scams-and-relationship-scams-whats-the-difference/">Romance Scams and Relationship Scams: What&#8217;s the Difference?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Romance Scams Romance scams are a type of fraud that involves criminals using deception to take advantage of victims looking for companionship. These scams typically involve criminals posing as potential partners on dating websites or social media platforms. They can often use fake profiles and photos. And they often claim to be from another [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/romance-scams-and-relationship-scams-whats-the-difference/">Romance Scams and Relationship Scams: What&#8217;s the Difference?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/romance-scams-and-relationship-scams-whats-the-difference/">Romance Scams and Relationship Scams: What&#8217;s the Difference?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-2 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-2 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-1 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-2"><h2>Romance Scams</h2>
<p>Romance scams are a type of fraud that involves criminals using deception to take advantage of victims looking for companionship. These scams typically involve criminals posing as potential partners on dating websites or social media platforms.</p>
<p>They can often use fake profiles and photos. And they often claim to be from another country. The scammer’s goal is to gain the victim&#8217;s trust and then ask for money, gifts, or steal personal information to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">commit identity theft</a>.</p>
<p>The scammer can ask the victim for money to come visit them or to cover the cost of a phone so they can speak with them. Once the victim sends money, the victim will likely never hear from the love interest again.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/looking-for-love-online-be-aware-of-scammers-and-fraud/">Romance scams</a> can be very costly for victims.</p>
<p>In 2021, <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2022/02/ftc-data-show-romance-scams-hit-record-high-547-million-reported-lost-2021">Americans lost over $547 million</a> to romance scams. The median loss for victims of romance scams was $2,400, according to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).</p>
<h2>Relationship Scams</h2>
<p>Relationship scams are also a type of fraud that involves criminals using deception to take advantage of victims. These scams typically involve criminals posing as potential partners and building a relationship with the victim, similar to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-you-should-know-about-pig-butchering-scams/">pig butchering scams</a>.</p>
<p>These scammers are in for the long con and build a relationship with the victim for months and even years. Again, the goal is to gain the victim&#8217;s trust and then ask for money, gifts, or personal information.</p>
<p>In relationship scams, the victim may send thousands of dollars over a period of years to the scammer.</p>
<h2>How to Protect Yourself from Romance Scams and Relationship Scams</h2>
<p>Here are some tips to help you avoid romance scams and relationship scams:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be aware of the signs of a scam.</li>
</ul>
<p>Scammers often use the same patterns and techniques, so if you know what to look for, you can be more likely to spot a scam. Some common signs of a romance scam include:</p>
<ul>
<li>The person you&#8217;re talking to is very charming and attentive.</li>
<li>They are in a hurry to move the relationship forward.</li>
<li>They ask for money or personal information, such as your bank account number or Social Security number.</li>
<li>They disappear after you send them money or personal information.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Do your research before meeting anyone online.</li>
</ul>
<p>Check their social media profiles, look for news articles about them, and see if there are any reviews or complaints about them.</p>
<ul>
<li>Be careful about what information you share with anyone online.</li>
</ul>
<p>Never give out your personal information, such as your bank account number or <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/6-tips-for-protecting-your-social-security-number/">Social Security number</a>, to someone you don&#8217;t know and trust.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you believe you have been the victim of a romance or relationship scam, contact your local law enforcement agency.</li>
</ul>
<p>You should also <a href="https://reportfraud.ftc.gov/#/">report the scam</a> to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). The FTC can help you file a complaint and get information about how to protect yourself from scams.</p>
<p>Protecting your personal information with <a href="http://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ services</a> is also essential. Scammers can use your personal data to open credit cards, apply for a car loan, or even commit crimes in your name.</p>
<p>An <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">identity theft protection plan</a> provides you with alerts for possible suspicious activity, so you can act fast and get in front of scammers.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-1{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-1 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-1{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-1 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-1{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-1 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-2{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/romance-scams-and-relationship-scams-whats-the-difference/">Romance Scams and Relationship Scams: What&#8217;s the Difference?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Malware?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/</link>
      <comments>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://identitydev.wpengine.com/?p=4580</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">What is Malware?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Malware is an umbrella term used to describe any malicious software designed to harm, exploit, or extract sensitive data from a system, device, or network.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">What is Malware?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">What is Malware?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-3 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-3 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-2 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-3"><p>Malware is an umbrella term for malicious software designed to harm, exploit, or extract sensitive data from a system, device, or network. For example, cybercriminals use malicious software to access sensitive information they can use for financial gain. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">Stolen data</a> can include anything from your payment details to your medical records, passwords, and more.</p>
<h2>How Do I Get Malware?</h2>
<p>Malware is commonly spread by visiting suspicious websites, downloading files, or emailing. Here are some other ways malware can find its way into your devices.</p>
<h3>Phishing Emails</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/how-to-spot-an-email-phishing-attempt-at-work/">Phishing emails</a> trick a victim into clicking on a link or opening an attachment that contains a malicious file. These emails appear to come from friends, trusted sources, or reputable organizations. Once opened, however, the malware code runs and starts carrying out actions on your system.</p>
<h3>Infected USB Drive</h3>
<p>Infected USB drives are used whenever an attacker needs physical access to a computer. Once plugged into your device, an infected USB drive auto-executes the malware code.</p>
<h3>Malicious Advertisement</h3>
<p>Malicious advertisement is a tactic that attempts to distribute malware through online advertisements. It typically involves cybercriminals injecting infected ads into legitimate advertising networks displayed on websites we trust. While some malicious ads require you to click on them to get infected, others can infect you automatically as soon as the page loads.</p>
<h3>Fake Software Installations</h3>
<p>You may think you found a movie, song, or software for free, but in reality, you fell for bait that downloads malware to your computer.</p>
<h3>Infected Apps</h3>
<p>While apps available on an official app store are usually safe, some come from less legitimate sources that can contain malware.</p>
<h2>How Can I Tell If My Computer Has a Malware Infection?</h2>
<p>If you notice that your computer is acting strange, there’s a possibility it has been infected with malware. Here are the most common signs that malware has compromised your system.</p>
<h3>Slow Computer</h3>
<p>If your operating system and other programs take a while to startup, it indicates that your system might be infected by malware. This is especially true if you recently installed a program, you are unfamiliar with.</p>
<h3>Blue Screen of Death</h3>
<p>If your computer crashes regularly, it may be a malware infection. Known as the blue screen of death (BSOD) – it’s a common indicator a malware is causing trouble behind the scenes.</p>
<h3>Suspicious Activity</h3>
<p>If your hard drive is working excessively when no other programs are running, you should scan your system for malware. Similarly, if you see unrecognized changes or files generated on your computer, this can indicate a malware infection.</p>
<h3>Frequent Pop-Ups</h3>
<p>if you have ads unwanted ads pop up frequently, it may be a sign of adware or scareware.</p>
<h3>Browser Redirects</h3>
<p><strong> </strong>If your browser frequently takes you to websites you intend to avoid visiting.</p>
<h2>Types of Malware</h2>
<p>There are many types of malware, and understanding the different types can help you better protect your devices. Here are some of the most common types:</p>
<h3>Viruses</h3>
<p>A virus is a program that self-replicates by inserting its code into other programs. Viruses are distributed via emails, websites, or flash drives and activate when a victim opens the infected file. Viruses can lead to deleted or encrypted files, modified applications or malfunctions.</p>
<h3>Ransomware</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/">Ransomware</a> is a malware designed to block access to a computer system until a ransom is paid. Then, hackers demand cryptocurrency for the decryption key that allows you to re-access your data.</p>
<h3>Scareware</h3>
<p>Scareware is a malware tactic that manipulates users into downloading malicious software. It usually comes in pop-up ads that impersonate anti-virus companies informing you that your system’s files have been infected. This tactic takes advantage of a user’s fear to pressure them into buying fake anti-malware software.</p>
<h3>Worm</h3>
<p>A <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/worm#:~:text=Definition(s)%3A,may%20consume%20computer%20resources%20destructively.">computer worm</a> is malware reproducing and spreading from system to system without human assistance. Worms can exploit security software vulnerabilities, steal sensitive information, corrupt files, and install backdoor access to a system. They also utilize a large amount of memory, so affected computers and servers can overload and fail to respond.</p>
<h3>Spyware</h3>
<p>Spyware is software designed to capture your activity and sensitive information without your knowledge or consent. Your information is then relayed to data firms and advertisers or sold on the dark web for profit.</p>
<h3>Trojan</h3>
<p>A trojan, or trojan horse, is malware disguised as legitimate software. Many modern forms of this malware allow cybercriminals to create a backdoor in your computer system that gives them unauthorized access. Unlike worms or viruses, trojans do not replicate themselves but are often used in ransomware attacks to access users’ sensitive information.</p>
<h3>Adware</h3>
<p>Adware is software designed to serve advertisements to you, either within your web browser or in other programs. Adware isn’t always bad. Some free apps, for instance, include adware to make revenue from ads. Malicious adware, however, bombards you with infected ads that harm your computer.</p>
<h3>Rootkit</h3>
<p>Rootkit is a form of malware that provides hackers access to control a target’s computer or smart device. Anything with an operating system is a potential target for this particular malware.</p>
<h3>Keylogger</h3>
<p>A keylogger is another malware that records the user’s keystrokes on a keyboard. The cybercriminal uses this gathered information to access personal accounts and information.</p>
<h2>Do Macs Get Malware?</h2>
<p>Yes, Macs can get infected with malware. Despite the security features that come with Macs, they can still catch viruses and other malware.</p>
<h2>Do Mobile Devices Get Malware?</h2>
<p>Our mobile devices can be vulnerable to malware and other viruses. Malware can slow down your phone’s performance and make it easy for criminals to steal your information.</p>
<h2>How Can I Tell If My Mobile Device Has Malware?</h2>
<p>Here are some helpful signs that your mobile device has malware.</p>
<h3>1. Notice Invasive Pop-Ups.</h3>
<p>If you have noticed an increase in pop-ups or if they appear spammy, you may have installed something that hides adware.</p>
<h3>2. An Increase in Data Usage.</h3>
<p>Malware can use up your data, especially when displaying invasive pop-ups.</p>
<h3>3. Low Battery.</h3>
<p>Malware drains your battery life without your knowledge.</p>
<h3>4. Your Mobile Device is Hot.</h3>
<p>If your device feels hot to the touch, it could be a sign of malware. As mentioned before, malware drains your device’s power, which can make your phone get warm.</p>
<h3>5. Notice Unfamiliar Apps.</h3>
<p>If you notice new apps, you never downloaded, that could be a sign of malware.</p>
<h2>How Can I Help Protect Myself From or Get Rid of Malware?</h2>
<p>The best thing you can do to protect your information and devices from malware is to practice safe online habits. Here are some tips you can follow:</p>
<h3>Avoid Suspicious Sites and Downloads</h3>
<p>Torrent sites, illegal downloads and apps that come from an unknown source all put your devices at risk of malware.</p>
<h3>Double-Check the Source</h3>
<p>Think twice before clicking on a link. Make sure it’s from a trusted source.</p>
<h3>Update Your Devices</h3>
<p>Keep your software, applications, and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/how-important-are-phone-software-updates/">operating system updated</a>. Hackers always look for vulnerabilities in outdated software. So, make sure to install updates regularly.</p>
<h3>Protect Your Devices</h3>
<p>Do not leave your devices unattended; make sure to lock them with a <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/5-password-best-practices-you-should-be-using/">password</a> or biometric lock.</p>
<h3>Keep the Essentials</h3>
<p>Limit the number of applications on your device. Only keep those apps on your phone that you use regularly. Uninstall an application if you no longer use it.</p>
<h3>Use Anti-Malware Software</h3>
<p><a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/antivirus_software">Anti-malware software</a> is designed to prevent, detect, and remove malware that tries to infect your devices.</p>
<h3>Consider Identity Theft Protection</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">Identity theft protection</a> can be a great solution to protect your data. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a> identity theft protection plans offer real-time monitoring, fraud alerts, <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing-bitdefender/">antivirus software, and VPN</a>.</p>
<h2>We Recommend Anti-Malware Software That Has the Following Features:</h2>
<h3>Complete Data Protection.</h3>
<p>Anti-malware that defends against all e-threats, including viruses, worms, Trojans, ransomware, zero-day exploits, rootkits, and spyware. Rest easy knowing your data is safe.</p>
<h3>Anti-Phishing</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/phishing-and-malware-attacks-most-common-techniques-for-credential-theft/">Phishing scams</a> are on the rise and are one of the main ways people get tricked into exposing their sensitive information. Look for anti-malware software with advanced anti-phishing protection to help you easily avoid malicious software designed to steal your passwords, financial data, and other data.</p>
<h3>Anti-Fraud</h3>
<p>Look for a filtering system that alerts you when you visit a website that may try to scam you.</p>
<h3>Advanced Threat Defense</h3>
<p>You should be able to scan apps on your devices for any signs of malware. If any suspicious activity is detected, you want to be able to take immediate action to protect your data and devices.</p>
<h3>Web Attack Prevention</h3>
<p>Check for web-filtering technology that helps you avoid harmful websites. Good anti-malware software will block infected links and let you know whether your search results are safe to access before you click on a link.</p>
<h3>Social Network Protection</h3>
<p>Stay protected from malicious links and other online threats on social media.</p>
<h3>Anti-Spam</h3>
<p>This feature allows you to filter spam and other suspicious emails from your inbox.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-2{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-2 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-2{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-2 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-2{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-2 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-3{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">What is Malware?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Ransomware and How Does It Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 03:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5168</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/">What Is Ransomware and How Does It Work?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Ransomware is one of the most common types of cyberattacks. With how vastly the internet has become embedded in our day-to-day lives, cyberattacks such as ransomware can cause costly disruptions. According to the Harvard Business Review, the amount of money paid to ransomware hackers increased 300% from 2020 to 2021. This is after ransomware attacks rose [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/">What Is Ransomware and How Does It Work?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/">What Is Ransomware and How Does It Work?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Ransomware is one of the most common types of cyberattacks. With how vastly the internet has become embedded in our day-to-day lives, cyberattacks such as ransomware can cause costly disruptions.</p>
<p>According to the Harvard Business Review, the amount of money paid to ransomware hackers increased 300% from 2020 to 2021. This is after <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/data-breaches/organizations-and-businesses-face-500-increase-in-ransomware-attacks/">ransomware attacks rose 500%</a> the previous year.</p>
<p>But learning more about ransomware can help protect yourself from becoming a victim.</p>
<h2>What is Ransomware?</h2>
<p>Ransomware is a type of cyberattack used by hackers to extort a “ransom” from their victims. Malicious software infects your computer and restricts access to your files and networks.</p>
<p>The cyberthief then demands a certain amount of money for you to regain access to your data. However, as you are dealing with cyber criminals, there are no guarantees that the hackers will restore access once you have paid the amount.</p>
<p>Over time, ransomware attacks have grown to become more complex and dangerous. Some examples of well-known ransomware attacks are as follows:</p>
<h3>Cloudstar</h3>
<p>Last year, <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/data-breaches/a-national-emergency-cloudstar-down-after-ransomware-attack/">Cloudstar was the victim of a ransomware attack</a>. The attack and subsequent blockage of Cloudstar’s system meant homebuyers waiting to close on their new home purchases were affected while third-party forensics experts attempted to recover their data.</p>
<h3>City of Atlanta</h3>
<p>Atlanta was the victim of a ransomware attack. The attack included infecting the city’s system with malware and grinding the city’s services to a halt.</p>
<p>Atlanta officials ended up paying the $50,000 ransom demand and paid millions in their data recovery efforts.</p>
<h2>How Does Ransomware Work?</h2>
<p>Hackers use <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">malware</a> in the form of an email, a clickable link, an online advertisement, or a website to lure victims in. Once your computer has become infected with the malware, your data is encrypted, and you cannot gain access to it.</p>
<p>The severity of the attack depends on the kind of malware that has infected your computer. It can range from between a few files and folders, the computer itself becoming encrypted, to external drives and networked computers.</p>
<p>In most cases, the victim is unaware that their computer is infected unless they try to access the restricted files; or get a prompt demanding ransom.</p>
<h2>Why is Ransomware Spreading?</h2>
<p>Unfortunately, ransomware attacks continue to spread because they are more accessible and inexpensive for cybercrimes to pull off. Plus, more people working from home encourages more of these attacks.</p>
<h2>Popular Ransomware Variants</h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s look at the four types of Ransomware listed below to understand better.</p>
<h3>Ryuk</h3>
<p>Ryuk is usually done by phishing emails or compromised logins to lock sensitive files until a ransom is paid. Ryuk typically targets businesses, hospitals, and other organizations.</p>
<h3>Maze</h3>
<p>The Maze ransomware is known for encrypting files and stealing them. If demands aren&#8217;t met under this ransom, sensitive information is exposed or sold off.</p>
<h3>REvil (Sodinokibi)</h3>
<p>The REvil (also known as Sodinokibi ) is a filing-blocking virus that encrypts sensitive files after infection and holds them hostage.</p>
<h3>DearCry</h3>
<p>DearCry sends a ransom message with instructions for the user to email the ransomware operators to learn how to decrypt their files.</p>
<h2>Who is at Risk of Ransomware?</h2>
<p>Any device connected to the internet is at risk of becoming the next ransomware victim.</p>
<p>Ransomware scans a local device and any network-connected storage, which means that a vulnerable device also makes the local network a potential victim.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Defend Against Ransomware</strong></h2>
<p>Ransomware can result in breaches of confidential information, data loss, work disruption, and financial loss due to damages. However, simple tips can help defend yourself from malicious software and cyberattacks.</p>
<p>These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keeping all applications, software, and operating systems up to date</li>
<li>Downloading and browsing content only on trusted sites</li>
<li>Downloading anti-virus and anti-malware software, running regular scans, and keeping them up to date</li>
<li>Not opening emails or clicking on links sent through dubious unknown accounts</li>
<li>Regularly creating and securing backups of all your data</li>
<li>Having a robust continuity and contingency plan for your business in case of such attacks</li>
</ul>
<p>Ransomware is, unfortunately, a common type of cyberattack. Hackers use different methods to infect your computer with malicious software that encrypts your data and restricts your access.</p>
<p>Although new cybersecurity tools and <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/antivirus_software">anti-malware software</a> provide some security against such attacks, it is always better to be careful on the internet to help avoid becoming a victim of ransomware.</p>
<h2>How to Remove Ransomware</h2>
<p>While you can remove ransomware, it can be a challenging process. Here are some ways you can remove ransomware.</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep your computer on. Turning the computer off could cause you to lose more files and lower your chances of recovery.</li>
<li>Wipe and restore your computer using the most recent data and applications. But before you do this, ensure you have wiped out the ransomware.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t respond to a ransom message. If you respond to the message, it reveals to the hacker their ransomware attack was successful. Plus, there&#8217;s no guarantee that a hacker will give back your data.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to Report Ransomware</h2>
<p>Ransomware is a severe crime with strict laws in place to punish perpetrators. If you are a victim of a ransomware attack, you must report the incident as soon as possible. You can report such incidents through:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your local law enforcement office</li>
<li><a href="https://www.ic3.gov/">Internet Crime Complaint Center (IC3)</a></li>
<li>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA)</li>
<li>U.S. Secret Service Field Office</li>
<li><a href="https://www.fbi.gov/investigate/cyber/national-cyber-investigative-joint-task-force">National Cyber Investigative Joint Task Force</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Once you have contacted one of the departments mentioned above, the appropriate authorities can help you deal with your case, retrieve your data, and attempt to apprehend the criminals.</p>
<p>If you need extra protection after a ransomware attack, consider <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">signing up for identity theft protection</a>. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a> identity theft protection plans offer real-time monitoring and fraud alerts so you can act quickly to recover your identity and your data.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-ransomware-and-how-does-it-work/">What Is Ransomware and How Does It Work?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a VPN and How Do They Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/</link>
      <comments>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 02:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://identitydev.wpengine.com/?p=4570</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/">What is a VPN and How Do They Work?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>A VPN is a service that hides your IP address and encrypts your data to ensure your online privacy. Think of it as a private tunnel that allows you to connect to the internet without being tracked or traced.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/">What is a VPN and How Do They Work?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/">What is a VPN and How Do They Work?</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-4 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-4 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-3 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-4"><p>If you want to help <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/how-we-protect-you/">protect your digital identity</a>, a virtual private network (VPN) is an excellent tool for added online privacy. A VPN hides your IP address and encrypts your data, making it difficult for cybercriminals to steal.</p>
<p>This blog explains VPNs, how they operate and why they are becoming essential tools for people in today&#8217;s digital world.</p>
<h2>How Does A VPN Work?</h2>
<p>A <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/virtual_private_network">VPN</a> hides an IP address by letting the network redirect it through a configured remote server run by a VPN host. It encrypts your data while you&#8217;re online, making it hard for <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">someone to steal this sensitive information</a>.</p>
<h3>How Does an Encryption Tunnel Work?</h3>
<p>Encryption is the process of turning information into code to prevent unauthorized access. With a VPN, any data (search queries, link clicks, payment information, etc.) that passes through the encryption tunnel gets replaced with a cipher, or “secret code,” that can only be deciphered by the intended user or destination.</p>
<h2><strong>The Benefits of a VPN Connection</strong></h2>
<h3>Security of Public Wi-Fi.</h3>
<p><a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/how-safely-use-public-wi-fi-networks">Public Wi-Fi</a> is convenient, but it comes at the expense of security. For example, if you’re at your favorite coffee shop using their public Wi-Fi to answer emails, there’s a good chance someone could be tracking your online activity.</p>
<p>A VPN would be helpful for this situation because it would keep your online activity private and secure from strangers.</p>
<h3>Data Privacy from Your Internet Service Provider.</h3>
<p>While connected to your Wi-Fi at home, you are less likely to run into online attacks. However, internet service providers, such as Verizon, Spectrum, and COX, can access all your internet activity.</p>
<p>But if you use a VPN, your browsing history is kept to yourself.</p>
<h3>Data Privacy from Apps and Services You Use.</h3>
<p>A VPN can prevent apps and websites from attributing your behavior to your computer’s IP address.</p>
<h3>Access to Any Content in Any Place.</h3>
<p>You may or may not know this, but streaming platforms license content differently depending on the country you’re in. For example, say you travel to Europe while you’re in the middle of your favorite show.</p>
<p>You bring your smart devices to binge in your spare time but then realize you can’t access the same content. With a VPN, you won’t have to worry about regional restrictions to streaming because you can choose to appear anywhere in the world if your VPN provider has a server.</p>
<p>So, if you can’t access U.S. Netflix in Europe, you can connect to a VPN server in the United States. The same works in reverse.</p>
<p>If you want to access shows only available in the United Kingdom or France, you can connect to the internet from a server in those locations.</p>
<h3>Security When Working Remotely.</h3>
<p>A VPN is a valuable investment to keep confidential material safe, especially if you’re a remote employee. Most companies provide VPNs to employees to avoid hackers and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/working-from-home-make-sure-your-data-is-secure/">better protect employee and company information</a>.</p>
<h3>Smart Savings.</h3>
<p>Do you know you may be paying higher prices for goods and services depending on your area? It’s called price discrimination.</p>
<p>This is when people are charged based on their perceived ability to pay. So, if you live in areas with a higher average income, like Boston, New York or Los Angeles, you can be charged higher prices on airline tickets, hotels, and rentals.</p>
<p>With your IP address hidden, you can check for prices as if you were inquiring from a different city or country.</p>
<h2>The Potential Drawbacks of A VPN Connection</h2>
<h3>Potentially Slower Internet Speed.</h3>
<p>There is a possibility that using a VPN can impact your internet speed. However, if you find yourself in this position, here are easy tips to fix this issue.</p>
<h3>No Cookie Protection.</h3>
<p>While a VPN does a great job of protecting your online activity, it does not prevent cookies from tracking you.</p>
<p>Luckily you can delete tracking cookies. You can also use a private browser that prevents tracking cookies from following your internet browsing.</p>
<h3>Not Legal Everywhere.</h3>
<p>Some countries, including Russia and China, have banned or highly regulated VPN use.</p>
<h2>What to Watch Out For When Choosing a VPN</h2>
<p>If you’re considering getting a VPN, here are some things you should watch out for when choosing a VPN service.</p>
<h3>Beware of a Free VPN.</h3>
<p>A free VPN may sound great, but some downsides exist. For instance, they tend to impact internet speed, come with unwanted ads, and have weak security protections.</p>
<h3>Speed.</h3>
<p>Ensure the VPN offers sufficient speed, as many providers need help to stay fast enough for streaming or downloading.</p>
<h3>Reputation.</h3>
<p>Make sure to research the VPN service. Consider finding consumer and professional reviews to learn more about the VPN provider.</p>
<h3>Look for Shared IP Addresses.</h3>
<p>Choose a VPN that offers shared IP addresses because it can add another layer of privacy to your browsing experience.</p>
<h3>Helpful Features.</h3>
<p>When exploring VPN services, consider what you need from your VPN service. For example, some VPN services offer ad-blocking, firewalls, kill switches, simultaneous connections or the ability to change your IP address and server location at will.</p>
<h3>Good Customer Support.</h3>
<p>The best VPNs have customer support standing by in case anything goes wrong.</p>
<h2>Can VPNs Be Hacked?</h2>
<p>VPNs are susceptible to hacks and malware. Ensure your VPN properly encrypts your data to help <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/data-breaches/how-can-i-protect-my-personal-information-after-a-data-breach/">prevent hacks and data leaks</a>.</p>
<h2>What Kind of VPNS Are There?</h2>
<p>VPNs use different types of VPN protocols to encrypt your data. Here are the three main types of VPNs.</p>
<h3>1. SSL VPN.</h3>
<p>A Secure Sockets Layer Virtual Private Network (SSL VPN) works to create a secure connection over an unsecured network. For example, remote users can access a company&#8217;s network without installing special software.</p>
<h3>2. Site-to-Site VPN</h3>
<p>A Site-to-Site VPN is a connection set up between multiple networks. This VPN can be helpful if you have two private networks between which you want to send files without users from one private network explicitly accessing the other.</p>
<h3>3. Client-to-Server VPN</h3>
<p>A client-to-Server VPN establishes a secure connection between the user and the server. This VPN is unique. Instead of creating an encryption tunnel to hide the internet connection, the VPN can automatically encrypt the data before making it available to the user.</p>
<h2>How Do I Install A VPN on My Computer?</h2>
<p>To set up a VPN connection to your computer, you must choose a VPN service. Then consider the type of computer you own because installation instructions may differ.</p>
<p>If you need step-by-step instructions, reach out to your VPN provider.</p>
<h2>How To Install A VPN Connection on Your Smartphone?</h2>
<p>As mentioned before, you need to decide on a VPN service. Then your VPN provider can instruct you to download their app. From there, you can set up your account and have access to your VPN.</p>
<p>Again, if you need help, contact your VPN provider, and they can guide you through the process.</p>
<p>If you are interested in keeping your data secure, consider<a href="https://www.identityiq.com/"> IdentityIQ</a> services! If you sign up, you receive identity theft protection and an option to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing-bitdefender/">add antivirus and VPN</a> to your plan for complete protection.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-3{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-3 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-3{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-3 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-3{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-3 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-4{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/">What is a VPN and How Do They Work?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Common Hotel Scams and How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/5-common-hotel-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 17:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=6178</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/5-common-hotel-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">5 Common Hotel Scams and How to Avoid Them</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Staying at a hotel should be an enjoyable experience. But unfortunately, there are many scams out there that can make it a nightmare. To help protect your personal information and money, it is important to be aware of the most common hotel scams and how to help avoid them. 5 Common Hotel Scams Hotels [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/5-common-hotel-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">5 Common Hotel Scams and How to Avoid Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/5-common-hotel-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">5 Common Hotel Scams and How to Avoid Them</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-5 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-5 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-4 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-5"><p>Staying at a hotel should be an enjoyable experience. But unfortunately, there are many scams out there that can make it a nightmare. To help protect your personal information and money, it is important to be aware of the most common hotel scams and how to help avoid them.</p>
<h2>5 Common Hotel Scams</h2>
<p>Hotels are a popular target for scammers due to the high volume of guests and transactions that take place. Here are 5 common hotel scams that you should be aware of:</p>
<h3>Fake Booking Websites</h3>
<p>Scammers can create fake hotel booking websites that look identical to legitimate ones. They can then trick unsuspecting travelers into making a reservation and paying for it, only to find out upon arrival that their booking doesn&#8217;t exist. To know if you are booking with reliable hotel websites, check the URL. It should have a secure HTTPS connection. Also, review the site itself. It&#8217;s likely a scam website if there are typos, grammar errors and overall poor website design.</p>
<h3>Wi-Fi Scam</h3>
<p>Free Wi-Fi is a doorway for scammers, but not everyone realizes it. The problem is that cybercriminals use various techniques and tools to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">steal personal data</a>, passwords, and banking information. When your data is exposed, you are more vulnerable to serious security risks.</p>
<p>Some of the most common threats include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Man-in-the-Middle (MITM) </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This is a type of cyberattack where the attacker intercepts communication between two parties and can eavesdrop or manipulate the communication. In this type of attack, the attacker sits between the two parties and pretends to be each of them, intercepting communication and controlling the flow of information between them.</p>
<p>MITM attacks can steal sensitive information, such as login credentials, credit card information and other personal data.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wi-Fi Snooping</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Wi-Fi snooping, also known as Wi-Fi hacking or Wi-Fi piggybacking, is a practice where someone gains unauthorized access to a Wi-Fi network through various means. This can be done by intercepting the wireless signals between a Wi-Fi access point and a device or using software tools to crack the encryption to secure the Wi-Fi network.</p>
<p>Wi-Fi snooping can steal sensitive information from the devices connected to the Wi-Fi network, such as login credentials or personal data. It can also be used to monitor the users&#8217; online activities connected to the network.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Malicious Hotspots </strong></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/can-hackers-create-fake-hotspots/">Malicious hotspots</a>, also known as rogue hotspots, are Wi-Fi networks set up by hackers or cybercriminals to steal sensitive information from unsuspecting users. These hotspots are designed to look like legitimate Wi-Fi networks but are set up to capture the data transmitted by users who connect to them.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t access sensitive information if you use free Wi-Fi in your hotel room or elsewhere. Instead, use a <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-a-vpn-and-how-does-it-work/">VPN</a> and stick to HTTPS websites. Enable the firewall and use antivirus software regularly. Options such as these give you some sense of security and reliability.</p>
<h3>Fake Food Delivery</h3>
<p>A scammer can distribute a fake food menu to your hotel room. This menu has a phone number that connects you to the scammer rather than the hotel staff or a real business. They can ask for your credit card information on the phone but never deliver food.</p>
<p>Before you decide to order delivery, call the front desk. Ask them for any recommendations in the local area that offer reputable services.</p>
<h3>Fake Front Desk Calls</h3>
<p>You might get a phone call in the middle of the night from someone who impersonates the front desk. These are some of the most well-known hotel scams. The person may ask about your credit card information or claim there is a problem with it, its expiration date, etc.</p>
<h3>Checkout Scams</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://www.bbb.org/article/news-releases/18352-what-you-should-know-about-scams-when-you-are-staying-in-a-hotel">Better Business Bureau (BBB) warns travelers</a> to pay close attention to checkout scams. When you check out of your accommodations, pick the same form of payment that you used when you checked in. You should use a credit card instead of a debit card.</p>
<p>But some travelers prefer to pay in cash. Regardless of the payment method you use, ask the front desk for a receipt. Keep this receipt so that you have a record of the charges made while you stayed in the hotel. Then, you can dispute any charges with the receipt.</p>
<h2>Best Tips for Avoiding Hotel Scams</h2>
<h3>Do Some Research</h3>
<p>Do some research when booking a hotel and check the reviews. See what other people say and if scams were reported. Also, check if the address listed on the hotel website exists. For any further information, contact the front desk.</p>
<p>Ideally, you should book your accommodation directly by contacting the hotel.</p>
<h3>Monitor Credit Card Transactions</h3>
<p>Check your credit card transactions regularly to catch any suspicious activity on your account. This can include unauthorized charges, duplicate charges, or charges from merchants that you don&#8217;t recognize.</p>
<h3>Protect Your Personal Information</h3>
<p>Consider using <a href="http://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ identity theft protection services</a>. This service helps keep your information safe and helps minimize identity theft risk. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">IdentityIQ plans</a> include real-time <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/what-is-credit-report-monitoring-and-why-is-it-important/">credit monitoring</a>, fraud alerts, <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/what-is-dark-web-monitoring/">dark web monitoring</a> and identity restoration experts ready to assist you.</p>
<h2>How to Report Hotel Scams</h2>
<p>If you are a victim of hotel scams, you can issue a <a href="https://reportfraud.ftc.gov/#/">report to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)</a>. You can also <a href="https://www.bbb.org/scamtracker/reportscam">report the hotel scam to the Better Business Bureau (BBB)</a>.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-4{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-4 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-4{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-4 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-4{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-4 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-5{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/5-common-hotel-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">5 Common Hotel Scams and How to Avoid Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Avoid Tax Scams</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicole Bitting]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Scams and Fraud]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=5185</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/">How To Avoid Tax Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Tax season is here, and watching out for common tax scams is essential. The IRS reports that tax scams have cost victims more than $23 million in the last nine years. Here are three scams to be aware of and a few tips for how you can help avoid them. Phone Scams A phone scam is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/">How To Avoid Tax Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/">How To Avoid Tax Scams</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-6 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-6 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-5 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-6"><p>Tax season is here, and watching out for common tax scams is essential. The IRS reports that tax scams have cost victims more than $23 million in the last nine years.</p>
<p>Here are three scams to be aware of and a few tips for how you can help avoid them.</p>
<h2>Phone Scams</h2>
<p>A <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/this-tax-season-beware-irs-phone-scams-that-target-taxpayers/">phone scam</a> is a common tax scam where someone calls and claims to be from the IRS.</p>
<p>Fraudsters use fake names and provide bogus IRS identification numbers. In addition, they use sophisticated technology to display their phone number on caller ID as if the phone call is from the IRS.</p>
<p>Victims are told that they owe money to the IRS. Then, they’re told that they need to pay the balance they owe via a wire transfer, prepaid debit card or <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/gift-card-scams-and-how-to-avoid-them/">gift card</a>.</p>
<p>This is a common technique that scammers use. Unfortunately, recovering money converted into a gift card or prepaid debit card is challenging once the payment is sent. The same applies to a wire transfer; it’s gone once the money is sent.</p>
<p>These scammers tell their victims that they will be arrested, deported or have their business or <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/can-a-drivers-license-be-used-for-identity-theft/">driver’s license</a> revoked if they don’t quickly pay what they owe.</p>
<p>Sometimes, the scammer may tell the victim they’re due a tax refund to get them to reveal private personal and financial information.</p>
<h3>How Do You Know This is a Scam?</h3>
<p>The IRS informs you of any money you owe via a <a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/ten-things-to-know-about-irs-notices-and-letters">letter or notice</a>.</p>
<p>They never demand immediate payment over the phone. They don’t request you pay your balance in gift cards or a wire transfer. An IRS agent won’t make threats or harass you.</p>
<p>If you receive a call from someone claiming to be from the IRS stating that you owe money, hang up and initiate contact with the IRS by calling 1-800-829-1040.</p>
<p>If you don’t owe taxes, call 1-800-366-4484 to report this IRS impersonation scam. Or fill out a form on the <a href="https://www.treasury.gov/tigta/">Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration</a> web page.</p>
<h2>Email Phishing Scams</h2>
<p>Email <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/what-is-phishing-prevent-attacks-with-common-examples/">phishing</a> scams occur when a fraudster sends an email impersonating the IRS. The email from the IRS claims information about the taxpayer’s refund or tax return.</p>
<p>The recipient can click a link for more information about their refund or return. This link resembles an IRS webpage, but it’s a malicious file that helps the scammer download tracking software to the victim’s device.</p>
<p>This software is known as <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/digital-security/what-is-malware/">malware</a>. It provides the scammers with login info and passwords to the victim’s accounts.</p>
<p>A variation of this scam claims to provide taxpayers with a copy of their tax transcript. However, when they click the document, it’s a malicious file.</p>
<h3>How Do You Know This is a Scam?</h3>
<p>The IRS doesn’t send unsolicited emails to taxpayers. They do not send sensitive information or files via email.</p>
<p>Don’t open any emails that claim to be from the IRS, and never click on any attachments. Instead, forward them to <a href="mailto:phishing@irs.gov">phishing@irs.gov</a>.</p>
<h2>Fake Letters from the IRS</h2>
<p>Scammers also like to impersonate IRS officials in letters. So, if you receive a letter from the IRS in your mail that seems suspicious, call the IRS, and confirm if the letter is legit before responding.</p>
<h3>How Do You Know This is Scam?</h3>
<p>Like phishing emails, but on paper, the scam will try to convince you it&#8217;s from the IRS with a demanding and threatening tone.</p>
<h2>Tips for Avoiding a Tax Scam</h2>
<p>You can do a few things to protect yourself from a tax scam.</p>
<h3>File Your Taxes Early</h3>
<p>Try to file your taxes as early as possible. This helps prevent a criminal from obtaining your information and attempting to file a fraudulent return in your name.</p>
<h3>Understand How the IRS Initiates Contact</h3>
<p>The IRS doesn’t start contact with a taxpayer by text message, email or social media page. But, occasionally, they can try to contact a taxpayer via the phone.</p>
<h3>Utilize Identity Theft Protection</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">Getting identity theft protection</a> can be beneficial if you fall victim to a scam during the tax season. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a> identity theft protection services monitor your personal and financial information and alert you of possible suspicious activity so you can act quickly.</p>
<p>Plans include credit monitoring, identity theft insurance underwritten by AIG and dark web monitoring to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/how-we-protect-you/">help keep your information secure</a>. Again, this service can be beneficial if you need extra protection from a tax scam.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-5{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-5 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-5{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-5 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-5{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-5 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-6{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-do-you-avoid-tax-scams/">How To Avoid Tax Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/nbitting/">Nicole Bitting</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Tax Identity Theft</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/</link>
      <comments>https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/#respond</comments>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Acton]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 08:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Identity Theft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[hackers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[identity theft]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[IRS]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[scammers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[scams]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[taxpayer]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://identityiq.wpengine.com/?p=4417</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/">How to Prevent Tax Identity Theft</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>Every year, tax season presents a seasonal opportunity for criminals seeking monetary gain from identity theft. There are many ways that scammers may try to obtain personal information, but the end goal is to file a falsified tax return in the taxpayer’s name and claim a tax refund. The scheme may not be discovered [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/">How to Prevent Tax Identity Theft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/">How to Prevent Tax Identity Theft</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-7 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-7 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-6 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-7"><p>Every year, tax season presents a seasonal opportunity for criminals seeking monetary gain from identity theft. There are many ways that scammers may try to obtain personal information, but the end goal is to file a falsified tax return in the taxpayer’s name and claim a tax refund.</p>
<p>The scheme may not be discovered until the taxpayer attempts to file a legitimate tax return when the criminal has moved on.</p>
<p>Clearing up issues related to identity theft and fraudulent tax returns can be messy and significantly delay any tax refund you may be owed.</p>
<p>It pays to protect your identity now. Here’s how to help prevent <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/what-is-id-theft/">identity theft</a> during the tax season.</p>
<h2>Know the Signs of Identity Theft</h2>
<p>Understanding the signs can help you quickly recover your identity. Here are the top signs of <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/articles/tax-identity-theft-how-to-recover-your-return/">tax identity theft</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Receiving a letter from the IRS alerting you about a suspicious tax return you did not file.</li>
<li>Receive a tax transcript in the mail that you didn’t request from the IRS.</li>
<li>You get alerts from the IRS about suspicious account activity. For example, your existing online account has been hacked or disabled.</li>
<li>You get an IRS notice that you owe additional tax or receive a refund for a year you did not file a tax return.</li>
<li>The IRS notifies you of an employer you didn’t work for.</li>
<li>You have been assigned an Employer Identification Number but didn’t request one.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Take Action if You Are a Victim</h2>
<p>If you’re a victim of tax identity theft, then you need to take immediate action. Here are some steps to help prevent further damage.</p>
<ol>
<li>Contact the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) online at <a href="https://www.identitytheft.gov/">IdentityTheft.gov</a> or 1-877-438-4338. The FTC will collect the details of your case.</li>
<li>Contact the IRS at 800-908-4490, so they can help assist you in protecting your tax account.</li>
<li>Complete an IRS Identity Theft Affidavit. <a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f14039.pdf">Form 14039, Identity Theft Affidavit</a>, can be found on the IRS website. You’ll have to print it, fill it out and then mail it to the IRS.</li>
<li>Consider placing a freeze and fraud alert on your credit report. You’ll have to contact the three major credit bureaus, Experian®, Equifax®, and Transunion®, requesting the freeze and fraud alert. This will help protect your credit from identity thieves.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Protect Your Data and Identity</h2>
<p>To help <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/scams-and-fraud/how-to-protect-your-identity-during-tax-season-scams/">protect against identity theft during tax season</a>, consider the following tips.</p>
<h3>Secure Social Security Number.</h3>
<p>Your <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/6-tips-for-protecting-your-social-security-number/">Social Security card should be in a secure place</a> at home. Never carry your SSN card in your wallet; only provide it if necessary.</p>
<h3>Use Strong Passwords.</h3>
<p>A strong and unique is the best way to defend your accounts and private information from identity thieves. If you need help creating a solid password, consider investing in a password manager.</p>
<h3>Protect Against Email Spam and Computer Viruses.</h3>
<p>Scammers typically send emails with attachments and links containing malware to steal personal information. So, if you receive an email from an unknown source demanding money or additional information, it&#8217;s likely spam, and you should delete it. As for computer viruses, consider investing in anti-virus software to better protect your computer and data.</p>
<h3>Keep Financial Information Private.</h3>
<p>The IRS will never call and ask for your bank or credit card account information. So, if you find yourself in this situation, hang up and report them to the IRS or the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<h3>Beware of Phishing.</h3>
<p>Scammers love to impersonate IRS officials through emails. Phishing emails try to look like legit emails from an organization or company to try to steal your personal information, such as your SSN, bank account information or account logins. Typically signs of a phishing email include grammar errors, misspelled words, email addresses and domain names that don&#8217;t match. There is usually a demand or urgency to respond. Don&#8217;t respond, click links or download attachments if you encounter a phishing email. Delete it.</p>
<h3>Shred Bank and Tax Documents.</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-protect-your-physical-documents-from-identity-theft/">Shredding sensitive documents</a> can reduce your chances of an identity thief getting a hold of your documents.</p>
<h3>Reduce Credit Card Solicitations.</h3>
<p>Credit card offers are also considered sensitive information. So, to help protect your identity, you should also shred them. To help reduce your shredding pile, you can get off the list for pre-approved credit card offers by calling 1-888-5-OPTOUT.</p>
<h3>Keep on Top of Data Breaches.</h3>
<p>If a company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/data-breaches/how-can-i-protect-my-personal-information-after-a-data-breach/">data breach impacted you</a>, contact them to see how they protect you as a client. Furthermore, contact the three major credit bureaus and place a fraud alert on your credit. If necessary, consider filling out the IRS Form 14039, Identity Theft Affidavit, mentioned previously.</p>
<h3>File Your Taxes on Time.</h3>
<p>File your taxes sooner than later to help reduce your risk of tax identity theft. If an identity thief manages to steal your Social Security number, you&#8217;ll play into their hands with a delayed tax return. According to the Federal Trade Commission, they <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2022/02/new-data-shows-ftc-received-28-million-fraud-reports-consumers-2021-0">received 2.8 million fraud reports</a> from consumers in 2021, with fraud losses increasing by 70% compared to the previous year. So, consider filing those taxes as soon as possible.</p>
<h3>Obtain an IP PIN.</h3>
<p>Get an Identity Protect PIN from the IRS if you need extra protection this tax season. This six-digit PIN can help prevent someone from filing taxes in your name.</p>
<h2>Know What the IRS Does and Does Not Do.</h2>
<ol>
<li>The IRS may contact you about money owed but will never demand immediate payment. It&#8217;s important to note all payments will only go to the U.S. Treasury.</li>
<li>The IRS will always contact you first by mail delivered through the U.S. Postal Service.</li>
<li>The IRS will never contact you through social media or text messages.</li>
<li>The IRS will only contact you via phone, email and in-person method, as a secondary option under rare instances, after sending you notice in the mail.</li>
<li>The IRS will only ask for personal information after mailing a notice.</li>
<li>If you are on the phone with an IRS official and need clarification on whether they are legit, consider asking for two forms of identification.</li>
<li>The IRS will never accept payments through a wire transfer or gift card.</li>
</ol>
<p>Another solution to help reduce the risk of tax identity theft is to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">sign up for identity theft protection</a>. <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a> identity theft protection is dedicated to <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/how-we-protect-you/">protecting you</a>. IdentityIQ services can help alert you of possible suspicious activity with real-time alerts and help you recover your identity quickly.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-6{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-6 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-6{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-6 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-6{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-6 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-7{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/">How to Prevent Tax Identity Theft</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <wfw:commentRss>https://www.identityiq.com/identity-theft/how-to-help-avoid-tax-identity-theft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Utility Payments to Your Credit Report</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/how-to-add-utility-bills-to-your-credit-report/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Acton]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 22:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Credit Monitoring]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Featured Articles]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Headline]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=6172</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/how-to-add-utility-bills-to-your-credit-report/">How to Add Utility Payments to Your Credit Report</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>The traditional way to build credit requires getting a credit card and/or loan and making monthly payments on time. But that activity doesn’t include all the other utility bills you pay. So, it only represents a small portion of your financial behavior. Most utility providers don’t report payment activity to the credit bureaus, which [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/how-to-add-utility-bills-to-your-credit-report/">How to Add Utility Payments to Your Credit Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/how-to-add-utility-bills-to-your-credit-report/">How to Add Utility Payments to Your Credit Report</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-8 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-8 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-7 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-8"><p>The traditional way to build credit requires getting a credit card and/or loan and making monthly payments on time. But that activity doesn’t include all the other utility bills you pay. So, it only represents a small portion of your financial behavior.</p>
<p>Most utility providers don’t report payment activity to the credit bureaus, which means your utility bills aren’t doing anything to help your credit history or build your credit scores. Not reporting on-time utility payments puts you at a disadvantage, especially if you don’t already have any credit cards or loans.</p>
<p>Reporting your utility bill payments can help you correct this disadvantage. By adding your utility payments to your <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-is-a-credit-report-en-309/">credit report</a>, you open an alternative path to better credit.</p>
<h2>Which Utility Bill Payments are Added to My Credit Report?</h2>
<p>Before a payment can show up on your credit report and affect your credit score, it must be reported to at least one of the major credit bureaus:  Experian<sup>®</sup>, Equifax<sup>®</sup>, or TransUnion<sup>®</sup>. Traditionally, the only types of accounts that get reported involve pre-approved lines of credit, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Credit cards</li>
<li>Student loans</li>
<li>Auto loans</li>
<li>Mortgages</li>
<li>Personal loans</li>
</ul>
<p>In other words, you borrow money or get approval to build a credit history. Other types of services do not usually show up on your credit report.</p>
<h2>Why Aren’t My Utility Bills Added to My Credit Report?</h2>
<p>Most traditional service providers, like landlords and service companies, charge you a monthly fee in exchange for a service but do not report on-time payments.</p>
<p>The exception is that if you don’t pay your bills for too long, the company may send your account to collections, which does show up on your credit report. Ironically, this means that on-time payments rarely help your credit scores, but failing to make your payments can negatively impact your credit scores.</p>
<h2>Can I Self Report My Utility Bills?</h2>
<p>You can’t just send a copy of your paid electric bill to the credit bureaus and have them include it on your credit report.</p>
<p>But some services let you self-report utility bill payments so that your on-time payments can help you build positive credit history. For example, with utility payment reporting from IdentityIQ services, you can easily report your monthly utility payments to the credit bureaus.</p>
<h2>Which Utility Bills Can I Add to My Credit Report?</h2>
<p>Utility reporting from <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ services</a> reports your on-time utility payments to the credit bureaus, including up to 24 months of  past payments. These payments appear as a separate tradeline on your credit report and can improve your credit scores. The types of utility payments you can report include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Electricity</li>
<li>Gas</li>
<li>Water</li>
<li>Sewer</li>
<li>Waste management</li>
<li>Cable and internet</li>
<li>Cell phone</li>
<li>Landline</li>
</ul>
<h2>Benefits of Reporting Your Utility Bills</h2>
<p>Whether you have strong credit or limited credit history, there are many benefits to reporting your utility payments:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Improve your credit scores. </strong>Reporting on-time utility bill payments can build a positive payment history to raise your credit scores.</li>
<li><strong>Get access to credit. </strong>Once you establish strong credit history, you can more easily qualify for loans and <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/consumer-tools/credit-cards/">credit cards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Lower interest rates. </strong>With better credit, you can access lower interest rates, saving you hundreds or thousands of dollars in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Timely reporting.</strong> Utility payments are reflected on your credit report soon after you report them to the credit bureaus.</li>
<li><strong>Comprehensive credit history.</strong> Paint a full picture of your financial activity that reflects your ability to pay your bills beyond loans and credit cards.</li>
<li><strong>Alternative credit data.</strong> Alternative data like utility payments enables you to build credit, especially if you would otherwise do not have a credit history.</li>
<li><strong>Credit transparency. </strong>The more information you use to build your credit scores, the greater visibility you gain into how those scores are calculated.</li>
<li><strong>Improve financial literacy.</strong> Build financial literacy and knowledge about your credit scores and what goes into them using monthly expenses you’re familiar with.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bottom Line</h2>
<p>Reporting your utility bill payments is essential to building credit and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">improving your credit scores</a>. By reporting your on-time utility payments, you gain greater control over the information that makes up your credit scores.</p>
<p>Utility reporting from IdentityIQ services gives you the ability to report your on-time utility payments. You also get access to various tools that <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/plans-pricing/">protect your identity</a>, monitor your credit, and keep you informed as a consumer.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-7{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-7 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-7{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-7 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-7{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-7 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-8{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/credit-monitoring/how-to-add-utility-bills-to-your-credit-report/">How to Add Utility Payments to Your Credit Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/bacton/">Brian Acton</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDIQ Wins Prestigious Gold Stevie® Award for Customer Service Department of The Year</title>
      <link>https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-wins-prestigious-gold-stevie-award-for-customer-service-department-of-the-year/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristin Austin]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 15:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Newsroom]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.identityiq.com/?p=6164</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-wins-prestigious-gold-stevie-award-for-customer-service-department-of-the-year/">IDIQ Wins Prestigious Gold Stevie® Award for Customer Service Department of The Year</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<p>—IDIQ Customer Care Department Has Been Recognized as Best in the Industry for Consumer Products and Services — Temecula, California, March 14, 2023 – IDIQ®, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, has earned the prestigious Gold Stevie® Award as the Customer Service Department of the Year. The Stevie Awards are [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-wins-prestigious-gold-stevie-award-for-customer-service-department-of-the-year/">IDIQ Wins Prestigious Gold Stevie® Award for Customer Service Department of The Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-wins-prestigious-gold-stevie-award-for-customer-service-department-of-the-year/">IDIQ Wins Prestigious Gold Stevie® Award for Customer Service Department of The Year</a><br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a></p>
<div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-9 fusion-flex-container gradient-container-9 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row fusion-flex-align-items-flex-start" style="max-width:1216.8px;margin-left: calc(-4% / 2 );margin-right: calc(-4% / 2 );"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-8 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-flex-column"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-justify-content-flex-start fusion-content-layout-column" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-9"><p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>—IDIQ Customer Care Department Has Been Recognized as Best in the Industry for Consumer Products and Services —</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Temecula, California, March 14, 2023</strong> – <a href="https://www.idiq.com/">IDIQ</a><strong><sup>®</sup></strong>, an industry leader in identity theft protection and credit monitoring, has earned the prestigious Gold Stevie® Award as the Customer Service Department of the Year.</p>
<p>The Stevie Awards are the world’s top honor for businesses that focus on customer service, customer contact centers, business development and sales professionals. The Stevie Awards organizes eight of the world’s leading business awards programs that also include the celebrated American Business Awards® and International Business Awards®.</p>
<p>This year IDIQ has been recognized as the gold winner for Customer Service Department of the Year in the Consumer Products and Consumers category. The company received the award during an event held earlier this month.</p>
<p>The company was honored for its 100% U.S.-based customer care as well as its mission to deliver identity theft protection and credit monitoring information and education to its more than 3 million members. IDIQ has three customer care centers located in three time zones. The company has operated its California and Illinois customer care centers for more than a decade and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-continues-growth-trajectory-with-new-office-in-tampa-florida/">opened its Tampa, FL., customer care center</a> last year.</p>
<p>“Our customer care team is the best in the industry,” said Jason Royal, senior vice president of customer care operations. “We are excited that our team has again been recognized for great service to our members.  We are also very proud that our service level has increased, which has been recognized with gold at the Stevie Awards this year. This is truly a testament to the outstanding quality of our IDIQ Customer Care team and their ability to help and guide our members when it comes to identity theft protection and credit education needs. Our team includes certified identity theft restoration specialists who are passionate in helping members restore their identity and bring them peace of mind.”</p>
<p>“Once again IDIQ is being recognized as a top company in not only the nation but the world,” said Scott Hermann, CEO of IDIQ. “We are proud that our customer care department has received this gold award and for the amazing service they provide our members.”</p>
<p>IDIQ offers the flagship <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/">IdentityIQ</a><sup>®</sup> and <a href="https://www.myscoreiq.com/">MyScoreIQ</a><sup>®</sup> brands for identity theft protection and credit monitoring. The company’s additional brands include <a href="https://resident.link/">Resident-Link</a><sup><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></sup> for positive rental payment reporting; <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-announces-acquisition-of-credit-debt/">Credit &amp; Debt</a>®, a credit and debt education-based membership platform; and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-acquires-countrywide-pre-paid-legal-services-inc/">Countrywide Pre-Paid Legal Services</a><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, a leading provider of voluntary employee benefits.</p>
<p>“The nominations we received for the 2023 competition illustrate that business development, customer service, and sales professionals worldwide, in all sorts of organizations, have continued to innovate, thrive and meet customer expectations,” Stevie Awards President Maggie Miller said. “The judges have recognized and rewarded their achievements, and we join them in applauding this year&#8217;s winners for their continued success.”</p>
<p>For more information on the company’s gold award for Customer Service Department of the Year as well as other Stevie Award winners for this year, visit <a href="https://stevieawards.com/sales/2023-stevie-award-winners">https://stevieawards.com/sales/2023-stevie-award-winners</a>.</p>
<h2>About IDIQ:</h2>
<p>IDIQ<sup>®</sup> is recognized as one of the fastest-growing industry leaders in identity theft protection and credit report monitoring. The IDIQ full suite of products includes its flagship <a href="http://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a><sup>®</sup> and <a href="http://www.myscoreiq.com">MyScoreIQ</a><sup>®</sup> brands that deliver identity and credit monitoring and education along with <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-announces-acquisition-of-resident-link/">Resident-Link<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a> for positive rental payment reporting, <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-announces-acquisition-of-credit-debt/">Credit &amp; Debt®</a> that provides a credit and debt education-based membership platform and <a href="https://www.identityiq.com/newsroom/idiq-acquires-countrywide-pre-paid-legal-services-inc/">Countrywide<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>, a leading provider of voluntary employee benefits. The company features 100% U.S.-based customer service and support. For more information, visit <a href="https://www.idiq.com/">www.IDIQ.com</a>.</p>
</div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-8{width:100% !important;margin-top : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;}.fusion-builder-column-8 > .fusion-column-wrapper {padding-top : 0px !important;padding-right : 0px !important;margin-right : 1.92%;padding-bottom : 0px !important;padding-left : 0px !important;margin-left : 1.92%;}@media only screen and (max-width:1024px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-8{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-8 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}@media only screen and (max-width:640px) {.fusion-body .fusion-builder-column-8{width:100% !important;}.fusion-builder-column-8 > .fusion-column-wrapper {margin-right : 1.92%;margin-left : 1.92%;}}</style></div></div><style type="text/css">.fusion-body .fusion-flex-container.fusion-builder-row-9{ padding-top : 0px;margin-top : 0px;padding-right : 0px;padding-bottom : 0px;margin-bottom : 0px;padding-left : 0px;}</style></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/press-release/idiq-wins-prestigious-gold-stevie-award-for-customer-service-department-of-the-year/">IDIQ Wins Prestigious Gold Stevie® Award for Customer Service Department of The Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com">IdentityIQ</a> written by <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.identityiq.com/author/kaustin/">Kristin Austin</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>