<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog – CheapSSLShop Blogs, News, Updates and Online Security Tips</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com</link>
    <description>cheap price ssls</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 14:31:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/favicon.png</url>
      <title>Blog – CheapSSLShop Blogs, News, Updates and Online Security Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix “SSL_ERROR_NO_CYPHER_OVERLAP” Error on Firefox?</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/how-to-fix-ssl_error_no_cypher_overlap-error-on-firefox</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL University]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Error]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Firefox Error]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate Error]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=12195</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Undoubtedly, Google Chrome is the most popular web browser, holding the highest market share. But Mozilla Firefox is close enough. In 2022, Firefox was the third most popular web browser, holding a market share of 4.92%. In other words, Firefox is an excellent alternative to Google Chrome. However, although Firefox has many standalone features, it does not mean it is immune to errors. One of the most common errors you will likely encounter when using Firefox is the ssl_error_no_cypher_overlap error. This error could be frustrating and significantly hinder users’ browsing experiences. What is SSL_ERROR_NO_CYPHER_OVERLAP Error It is essential to understand that the ssl_error_no_cypher_overlap error only happens with Firefox, no other browser. The error occurs when Firefox fails to obtain the necessary security data from a website you are trying to access. Usually, the error occurs when a user tries to access an old website without up-to-date SSL protection. Older versions of SSL certificates that users used before have been scrapped off because of security concerns. But suppose a website uses the old version of the secure socket layer certificate with an outdated encryption cipher. In that case, Firefox will not allow users to use such a website as it might easily compromise their security and privacy. [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Difference between Code Signing Certificate and SSL Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/code-signing-certificate-vs-ssl-certificate</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 04:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News and Announcement]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Code Signing Certificate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=12191</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Code signing certificates and SSL certificates are digital security certificates that are used to establish trust and authenticity in digital communications. However, they serve different purposes and are used in different contexts. But before we move to their differences, let’s check out what both these certificates offer in terms of security. What is an SSL Certificate? SSL/TLS (Secure Socket Layer/Transport Layer Security) certificates are cryptographic protocols that use encryption security for securing digital data. They secure all the browser-server exchanges with encryption, thus providing a secured link between two network devices. This digital certificate safeguards the website/customer data against hackers since it encrypts data by converting the plain text into a cipher text which looks gibberish. Nowadays, this secured HTTPS (hypertext transfer protocol secure) protocol is majorly used in all e-mail communications, instant messaging, digital transactions, etc. thus securing all communications over unsecured HTTP (hypertext transfer protocol) networks. How does SSL Certificate Work? When a user visits a website, the user’s browser and the web server communicate with each other. An SSL handshake process commences ensuring that there is secured and encrypted communication between these two parties. The initial process commences with the browser trying to communicate with the server [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Common Myths and Facts about SSL Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/myths-and-facts-about-ssl-certificate</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 06:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL University]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[HTTPS]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=9481</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In a world where having an online presence is becoming a business necessity, many businesses have to transfer sensitive information over the internet, where there are numerous evolving threats of hacking, phishing, identity theft, and so on. Hence the need for a secure system to process and transfer data online! Many steps could be taken to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive information, and one of the most pertinent is a secure socket layer certificate called an SSL certificate. SSL certificates are a security protocol that creates a secure link between a client and a server. The data is transferred in encrypted form, which prevents misuse by anyone getting access. However, many lies and myths are circulating on the internet about SSL certificates, some of which are genuine misunderstandings, while others are perpetrated by people with an interest in having more untrustworthy businesses with unsecured data lying around for easy access. This article discloses some of those myths and confusion regarding SSL certificates. Myth #1 – Self-Signed Certificates are Sufficient for All Purposes Fact: Self-signed certificates can be quite useful for in-house testing and pilot runs of your website. You don’t need to pay anyone for the registration, which is usually [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 WAY SSL Certificate: Brief Overview of How it Works?</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/what-is-2-way-ssl-and-how-does-it-work</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL University]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[2 WAY SSL]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=11343</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A secure socket layer (SSL) certificate, Currently Transport Security Layer (TLS) certificate, is a small cryptographic technology applied in encrypting data and communications between web servers and web browsers. But I am sure you already know what an SSL Certificate is. When people talk of TLS certificates, they often refer to server certificates. As the name implies, server certificates are essential in authenticating servers to clients. Typically, this is the standard way of authentication. But have you ever wondered how it would be when you wanted to authenticate the client to the browser? This is where 2 Way SSL (or two-way SSL if you like) comes into sight. Wondering what that is and how it works? Wonder no more! In our endless quest to simplify all complex tech-related topics, we will break down everything for you by telling you what a two-way SSL certificate is and how it works. To better understand a two-way TLS certificate, it would be best to start by looking at the working of SSL authentication. How do TLS certificates provide authentication? First, the owner of a website purchases an SSL certificate for their website domain/s. The website owner then sends an unsigned certificate together with [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does an EV Code Signing Certificate Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/how-does-ev-code-signing-certificate-works</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 12:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL University]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Code Signing Certificate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[EV Code Signing Certificate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=11346</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Have you ever heard about EV Code Signing Certificate? If not, you must know what it is and how it works. Generally, Code Signing certificates are of two types: the OV Code Signing certificate and the EV Code Signing certificate. This blog will discuss the EV Code Signing Certificate, its features, and its functioning. What are EV Code Signing Certificates? What is EV Code Signing Certificate? An EV Code Signing Certificate is a file containing a digital signature that can be used to sign executables and codes to authenticate a developer’s identity and make sure that code is validated and signed. As a result, software users can blindly trust that the software can be trusted. EV Code Signing certificates are frequently confused with SSL certificates; however, SSL certificates secure the web and data. In contrast, EV code signing certificates secure the software, driver, and app code. EV code signing certificates are an excellent amalgamation of varied security benefits. This includes the benefits of digital signatures on codes, a thorough vetting process for strong security, fulfilling all code security needs, etc. These certificates help verify the publisher&#8217;s authenticity when they sign their software/app since their name and the company name are [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Tell If an Email Is Fake or Real</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/how-to-tell-if-email-is-fake-or-real</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 10:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Email]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Fake Mail]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SECURITY]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=9427</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Wondering how to confirm that the email you sent and received is real or fake? It is no longer a myth that email is becoming an indispensable tool of communication. But at the same time, there are some pitfalls we all should be concerned about as hackers are actively spying on those emails to execute scams or fraud in any way. What kinds of emails attract cybercriminals the most? Emails that are free Email with less security measures Emails that can send one or more emails at once Fast emails Emails that can be sent via computers or mobile phones with an internet connection Emails are becoming extremely popular and essential due to their convenience to communicate quickly and inexpensively for personal or professional reasons. It has paved the way for hackers to execute fake email attacks to grab your information. These fake emails are also termed phishing emails. Research indicates: 6 billion emails are sent and received daily. 94% of people fail to tell the difference between a real email and a phishing email. According to a report, every day 3.4 billion phishing emails are sent and most of these emails are automated. Phishing attacks originate anywhere in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Certificate Authority (CA) and What Do They Do?</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/what-is-certificate-authority</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 11:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[CA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Certificate Authority]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Certificate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=9530</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Key Takeaways Comodo is the largest certificate authority worldwide and has already issued 100 million certificates. A website with HTTPS means a website is using certificate authority. CA issues digital certificates, protects information, and encrypts millions of transactions and communications.. The fact that the identity of the certificate holder is confirmed by a reliable third party is the primary advantage of using SSL certificates from a CA. CA verifies domain names and organizations to authenticate the identity. The aim of a CA is to validate the authenticity and trustworthiness of a website, domain, and organization so users can be assured of who they’re communicating with to share information. Introduction There would be no person who hasn&#8217;t visited a website once in their lifetime. But do you know whether the website you are visiting or plan to visit is secure or not? Well, you often see websites starting with HTTPS, which means you are interacting with secured websites. Again, do you know what a website with HTTPS means? That means the website owner is using a certificate authority. What exactly is CA (Certificate Authority) and how does it work? You might be here to find those answers. So, don’t worry; here, [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Malware Attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/prevent-malware-attacks</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 11:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Attacks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malware Attacks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Prevent Malware Attacks]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=8611</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[According to an IBM study, the average cost of a ransomware attack (all ransomware is malware) is $4.62 million. Here we will discuss what it is?, the types of Malware, and How to protect against Malware attack. Malware is termed as malicious software too. It has many types such as ransomware, trojans, and worms. Each has its own form and act differently, but the common thing between them is that they all can put your business at risk. In this article, we are going to inform you about the actions you can take to secure your business from malware. Also, we will let you know who&#8217;s at the risk of malware, types of malware and provide unbiased information on top tips to prevent business against malware What is Malware? Malware is a type of malicious file or program that is catastrophic to a computer user, designed to cause extensive damage to a website or application. It is something that no business is immune to, whether small, medium, or enterprise-level. We are all aware of cybercriminals&#8217; activities, and cyberattacks are becoming a universal concern. Also, cyber actors are very creative in developing more and more devious ways to deposit malware into [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need to Know About SSL Offloading</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/everything-you-need-to-know-about-ssl-offloading</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 12:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL University]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SSL Offloading]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=11351</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The digital market is increasing rapidly, with more people staying online than offline. Online marketing, shopping, gaming, making transactions, viewing news/sports, etc., have increased tremendously. You may have encountered times when sites slow down or hang up as an internet user. This usually happens due to heavy network traffic. However, another reason for poor site performance may be the SSL/TLS certificate installed for site security. Since this security solution is essential and cannot be removed, you can only try to enhance the server speed with SSL Offloading. This topic is alien to many not from IT/technical backgrounds; hence, in this article, we will discuss SSL Offloading, its need, its functioning, and its pros and cons. What is SSL Offloading? SSL Offloading is the best and ideal solution for companies that crave site performance and security. In short, SSL offloading helps enhance site performance without affecting site security. It balances the extra load of SSL/TLS functions like encryption/decryption and the SSL handshake process by using separate ASIC (Application-Specific Integrated Circuit) processors. This, in turn, emancipates the processing power for the respective website/application. This process is also termed load balancing. The main motto of load balancers is to distribute workloads evenly across [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Security: What It Is, Importance, Types, and Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.cheapsslshop.com/blog/data-security</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[afgnalngasan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Data]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Data Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SECURITY]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://beta.cheapsslshop.com/?p=8721</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Digital business has its advantages, but cyber attacks like IP Spoofing attacks, DDOS Attacks, and unauthorized access overshadow these advantages, which has created the need for robust data security. Thus, digital security, or data security as you choose to name it, is a pivotal factor in today’s world. What is Data Security? As the name states, data security is the process of securing sensitive data from intruders and hackers. It&#8217;s not a one-time process but involves a lifetime updating process. It is not only restricted to networks and servers but also includes the security of hardware, software, business information, login credentials, etc. Preventing these unauthorized accesses needs to implement varied cybersecurity solutions like limiting accesses, encryption security, installing other security software, etc. The Covid-19 pandemic has increased the need for data security since employees have started working from remote destinations, which lack proper security solutions. Be it home Wi-Fi, remote server, lack of encryption, or lack of intrusion detection software. All these factors are responsible for a hike in intrusions. Hackers are taking complete advantage of the pandemic situation, leading to a phenomenal rise in cyberattacks. So irrespective of your business being big or small, data security is extremely important [&#8230;]]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>