<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>VISTA InfoSec</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com</link>
    <description>Vista Infosec</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 06:38:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Your Business: The Importance of Industry-Specific Cybersecurity Measures</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/securing-your-business-the-importance-of-industry-specific-cybersecurity-measures/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ronak Patel]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 06:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5157</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[As the world has evolved in significant ways over the &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/securing-your-business-the-importance-of-industry-specific-cybersecurity-measures/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the world has evolved in significant ways over the past several decades, so have the threats that businesses face daily evolved. In particular, cybercrime has grown into a nefarious force that harms businesses and causes irreparable damage. From holding information ransom to stealing private financial information, there is no limit to the damage that cybercriminals can inflict upon your operations.</p>
<p>Thankfully, cybersecurity has also evolved over the years to meet the growing and evolving challenges in the industry. From new technologies to an influx of experienced cybersecurity professionals, there are many ways that business operators can protect the digital assets of their company. One significant method to do this is by engaging in industry-specific cybersecurity measures.</p>
<p>Understanding the value, that taking this approach to cybersecurity can offer will put you in a better position to safeguard your business from threats.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Here is the importance of industry-specific cybersecurity measures.</strong></p>
<h3><strong>Understanding Which Threats Are Most Common in Your Industry</strong></h3>
<p>In each industry, certain cybersecurity threats are more prevalent than others. To truly protect your business from the dangers of cybercrime, it is important to understand what threats are typically the most dangerous to your specific industry. Often, drawing upon <a href="https://www.fullstackacademy.com/blog/benefits-of-data-analytics">data analytics</a> insights can help elucidate which types of cybersecurity threats pose the biggest risks to your business.</p>
<p>In addition to being aware of common threats, it is also important to understand the specific vulnerabilities of your company. Some common industry-specific threats include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Compromised Third-party Vendors in Healthcare</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>For effective operations and business processes, healthcare institutions typically work with many third-party vendors. This includes businesses such as linen suppliers and medical equipment suppliers, cloud services, etc. Cybercriminals are aware of the access that third-party networks can have to healthcare institution networks, making them the prime target. This being the case, third-party networks getting hacked and giving hackers access to healthcare institution networks has become a substantial threat in healthcare.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Phishing in Banking</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As the world has evolved, so has the way banks operate. Almost all financial data kept by banks have become digital and, as a result, can be accessed digitally. Unfortunately, cybercriminals have been attempting to exploit this by duping customers into giving their private information through phishing scams. Phishing scams involve cybercriminals posing as someone else, such as a bank employee, to trick victims into downloading malware that gives the hacker access to the victim’s personal information. Nefarious phishing schemes have become one of the most common and notable cybersecurity threats facing banks in recent years.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Data Breaches in Cloud Computing</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>For businesses of all sizes, storing data on the cloud has become a common practice. To do this, businesses typically enlist the services of cloud storage providers. Unfortunately, not all cloud storage providers are secure.</p>
<p>Cybercriminals are aware of the fact that cloud service providers often hold private business information and personal data that are critical to business. For these reasons they frequently seek to breach defenses and gain access to data on the cloud network of various cloud. As this has become a common threat, ensuring that cloud storage providers are engaging in safe practices has become a significant area of focus in business and cloud computing.</p>
<h3><strong>Industries with the Greatest Need for Industry-Specific Cybersecurity</strong></h3>
<p>Some specific industries are uniquely vulnerable to cyberattacks. This is because they each have specific vulnerabilities that cybercriminals commonly try to exploit. Here are some industries with a significant need for industry-specific cybersecurity measures.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Healthcare Industry</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Healthcare is an extremely vulnerable industry when it comes to cybersecurity threats. This is because their networks typically house copious amounts of personal information and <a href="https://online.maryville.edu/blog/data-analytics-in-healthcare/">healthcare data</a> about masses of individuals. To help ensure that patient information is kept safe, the American federal government developed what is called The <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/phlp/publications/topic/hipaa.html">Health Insurance and Portability Act</a> (HIPAA) which is established as a national standard that all healthcare organizations must adhere to keep patient information safe.</p>
<p>One key aspect of HIPAA is the Privacy Rule, which notes that patient information cannot be shared or used in certain ways without patient consent and also states that healthcare organizations must keep patient information safe by engaging in several key information security practices.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Banking and Payment Card Industries</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Banking institutions are one of the soft targets and primary victims of cyber crimes. This is because the networks of these firms hold an immense amount of financial and banking information of both individuals and businesses. In addition to this, there is always a threat to the payment card industry with the risk of it being exploited by cybercriminals.</p>
<p>To combat these threats, several payment card companies came together to form the Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council (PCS SSC) and created the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). In essence, the PCI DSS is a comprehensive security standard meant to help banks, payment card companies, and consumers stay secure and safe from fraud and cyberattacks.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Cloud Computing Industry</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The cloud computing industry has exploded over the last decade as this technology has allowed organizations the ability to experience more convenience when it comes to storing, processing, and transmitting data online. Unfortunately, given the large amount of data held in the cloud, cloud computing is an industry constantly being compromised by cybercriminals.</p>
<p>Some common attacks on the cloud computing industry include data breaches, in-house employee threats, and accounts being hijacked. So, to ensure that organizations using the cloud have secured their infrastructure several security best practices, industry standards and regulations have been introduced. Regulations and Standards such as GDPR, CPRA, PCI DSS, etc were developed to address these security issues and call organizations to implement best security practices.</p>
<h3><strong>Final Thought</strong></h3>
<p>As cybercriminals have evolved in their techniques of committing cybercrimes and become more adept at exploiting vulnerabilities, it has become increasingly important for businesses to upgrade their security standards and technique. This is to stay ahead in the industry and secure business against any potential threat. That said, it is important to note that attempting a one-size-fits-all approach for cybersecurity can leave your business exposed and unprotected in many ways.</p>
<p>Businesses will have to analyze and accordingly build a strong compliance program that meets various industry standards and requirements concerning the security of their business assets. For this, it is important to conduct a thorough audit and review your existing cybersecurity programs and measures to ensure that you are tailoring efforts to your specific business and industry.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5157"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Guide to Cybersecurity Compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/a-complete-guide-to-cybersecurity-compliance/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5147</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Cybersecurity has become a top priority for organizations across all &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/a-complete-guide-to-cybersecurity-compliance/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity has become a top priority for organizations across all industries and sizes. To safeguard their sensitive data and assets from the ever-evolving threats of cyberattacks and data breaches, businesses must take a proactive approach. Adherence to industry-specific cybersecurity regulations and frameworks is a critical component in building a robust and comprehensive cybersecurity program.</p>
<p>A recent study conducted by the Ponemon Institute revealed that the average cost of a data breach in <strong>2020</strong> amounted to an astounding<strong> $3.86 million.</strong> However, the study also found that companies that had established cybersecurity frameworks and regularly performed risk assessments and compliance audits were able to reduce their data breach costs by an average of <strong>$283,000.</strong></p>
<p>These statistics emphasize the significance of complying with cybersecurity measures and the potential cost savings that can be achieved through the implementation of a solid cybersecurity program.</p>
<p>In addition to the potential cost savings that can be achieved through the implementation of a solid cybersecurity program, there are several other noteworthy statistics and facts that further underscore the importance of cybersecurity.</p>
<ul>
<li>The World Economic Forum reports that a staggering <strong>95%</strong> of all cybersecurity breaches can be attributed to human error.</li>
<li>Fortune Business Insights predicts that by <strong>2028</strong>, the global market for information security will reach an impressive<strong> $366.1 billion</strong>.</li>
<li>The threat of cyberattacks is not limited to any one country or region. In fact, according to <strong>Microsoft</strong>, in 2020 alone, the United States was the target of <strong>46%</strong> of all cyberattacks &#8211; more than double that of any other country.</li>
</ul>
<p>These in-depth statistics underscore the <a href="https://www.exigent.net/managed-it-services-denver/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">exigent</a> need for businesses to place cybersecurity at the forefront of their priorities and take decisive action to safeguard their confidential data and resources.</p>
<p>In light of the critical need for businesses to prioritize cybersecurity and take proactive measures to protect their sensitive information and assets, this guide aims to provide a comprehensive overview of cybersecurity compliance. It covers various topics, including regulatory mandates, frameworks, and practical steps businesses can take to achieve compliance. This guide gives valuable insights into how businesses can stay ahead of the curve and maintain compliance in an ever-changing landscape.  But before getting into the nitty-gritty of the topic, let us first understand  cybersecurity compliance briefly.</p>
<h3><strong>What Is Cybersecurity Compliance?</strong></h3>
<p>Compliance typically means following rules and fulfilling requirements. In cybersecurity, this involves creating a program that uses risk-based controls to safeguard the integrity, confidentiality, and accessibility of information. However, various industries have different standards or regulations for cybersecurity compliance.</p>
<p>For example, healthcare providers need to meet HIPAA requirements. However, they may also have to comply with PCI DSS requirements if they accept payments through a POS device. This electronic system records and tracks sales transactions in retail or hospitality settings. Additionally, companies that conduct business with individuals in the EU must adhere to GDPR regulations, while those that meet specific criteria and have customers in California must comply with CCPA.</p>
<p>Cybersecurity compliance is a critical concern for organizations of all sizes and industries. At its core, cybersecurity compliance ensures that an organization hewed to regulatory requirements and standards by implementing robust controls, policies, and procedures to protect against cyber threats. Failure to comply with these standards can result in significant financial and reputational damage.</p>
<p>In short, cybersecurity compliance is not just a regulatory requirement but a critical component of any organization’s overall cybersecurity strategy. Now that we have a better understanding of what cybersecurity compliance entails, let’s delve into why it is so important for organizations to prioritize compliance in their overall cybersecurity strategy.</p>
<h3><strong>Why Is Compliance Important in Cybersecurity?</strong></h3>
<p>Since 2020, there has been an ongoing series of high-profile cybersecurity breaches. Despite technological advances, security teams continue to struggle with the same vulnerabilities that have plagued the industry for years. The recent cyberattacks on Colonial Pipeline, JBS, and Solar Winds are not fundamentally different from those we have seen over the past two decades.</p>
<p>Cybercriminals have not needed to alter their methods to exploit companies. Ransomware threats are widespread and critical infrastructure is vulnerable. The number of cyberattacks on critical infrastructure and government computer systems has reached unprecedented levels. For corporations, ransomware attacks have become a significant expense. What steps can be taken to address this issue?</p>
<p>This is where cybersecurity compliance comes in. Compliance with cybersecurity helps organizations protect their reputation, maintain customer trust, and improve their security posture. It is a driving force behind an organization’s success and defends against cyberattacks. No organization is immune from cyberattacks, so compliance with standards and regulations is paramount for success and security.</p>
<p>However, To mitigate these risks, it is essential for organizations to take a proactive approach to cybersecurity compliance. Mitigating risk includes conducting regular risk assessments, ongoing monitoring, and making timely updates to their cybersecurity programs. By staying compliant, organizations can safeguard their sensitive data and systems from cyber threats while maintaining their customers&#8217; trust.</p>
<h3><strong>Cybersecurity Regulatory Landscape and Framework:</strong></h3>
<p>The cybersecurity landscape is complex and constantly evolving. Some multiple international regulatory frameworks and standards have been introduced to protect sensitive information and prevent costly penalties. These regulations were introduced to govern the measures that organizations must take to protect themselves, their data, and their customers from cyber threats and data breaches:</p>
<h4><strong>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>The European Union introduced the GDPR in 2018 to protect the privacy and personal data of EU citizens.</li>
<li>It applies to any organization that processes or stores the personal data of EU citizens, regardless of location.</li>
<li>Non-compliance can result in significant fines, with a maximum penalty of 4% of a company’s annual global revenue or €20 million (whichever is greater).</li>
<li>Since its implementation in May 2018, there have been over 160,000 breach notifications across Europe, and the largest fine to date was €50 million.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA):</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>The California Privacy Rights Act (CPRA) went into effect in 2020 to protect California residents&#8217; privacy and personal data.</li>
<li>It applies to any organization that processes or stores the personal data of California residents, regardless of location.</li>
<li>The CPRA establishes data protection and privacy requirements, including the right to know what personal information is being collected, the right to request deletion of personal information, and the right to opt out of the sale of personal information.</li>
<li>The CPRA was approved by voters in November 2020 and officially became law on December 16, 2020.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA):</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) is a regulation that applies to healthcare organizations that handle protected health information (PHI).</li>
<li>HIPAA establishes requirements for protecting PHI, including physical, administrative, and technical safeguards, to ensure PHI&#8217;s confidentiality, integrity, and availability.</li>
<li>Between October 21, 2009, and December 31, 2022. Around 5,150 data breaches were reported to the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rights (OCR).</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS):</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) is a regulation that applies to organizations that handle payment card information, such as credit card numbers.</li>
<li>PCI DSS establishes requirements for protecting payment card information, including secure storage, transmission, and processing of payment card data.</li>
<li>Non-compliance with PCI DSS can result in fines, other penalties, and damage to the organization&#8217;s reputation.</li>
<li>PCI DSS compliance has increased by 167% since 2012.</li>
<li>In a 2020 study from SecurityMetrics, only 43% of PCI DSS requirements were met at the time of a data breach.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>System and Organization Controls 2 (SOC2):</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>SOC2 is a security framework developed by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA) that specifies how organizations should protect customer data from unauthorized access, security incidents, and other vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>The framework is based on five Trust Services Criteria: security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy.</li>
<li>SOC2 has become the de facto standard for businesses in all industries to build trust and unlock sales.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST):</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The NIST promotes innovation, industry competitiveness, and quality of life through advancements in standards and technology.</li>
<li>NIST 800-53 is a Risk Management Framework that provides guidelines for managing information security systems.</li>
<li>Initially used for U.S. defense and contractors, enterprises have implemented NIST.</li>
<li>NIST 800-161 provides standards for assessing and reducing information and communications technology supply chain risks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>International Organization for Standardization (ISO 27001):</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>ISO 27001 specifies the requirements for establishing, implementing, maintaining, and continually improving an ISMS.</li>
<li>The standard requires organizations to examine their security risks, considering threats, vulnerabilities systematically, and impacts.</li>
<li>ISO 27001 helps organizations secure information, including paper-based, cloud-based, and digital data.</li>
<li>Implementing ISO 27001 can help organizations increase their cyber-attack resilience.</li>
<li>Organizations can choose to get certified to ISO 27001 to demonstrate their compliance with the standard.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>9 Steps to Achieve Cyber Security Compliance:</strong></h3>
<p>Achieving and maintaining cybersecurity compliance can be a challenging and complex task for organizations. It is not a one-time effort but rather an ongoing process that requires regular tracking and monitoring to ensure that the organization remains compliant with the relevant standards and regulations. To help organizations navigate this process, we have outlined some effective steps that can be taken to achieve and maintain compliance.</p>
<p>These steps include implementing risk-based controls to protect sensitive information, regularly assessing and updating security measures, and staying up-to-date with the latest regulations and industry standards.</p>
<p>By following these steps, organizations can work towards achieving and maintaining compliance in an ever-changing cybersecurity landscape.</p>
<h4><strong>1.  </strong><strong>Understand the Regulatory Landscape:</strong></h4>
<p>To achieve compliance in cybersecurity, organizations must determine which regulations apply to them. They must carry out a detailed review of the applicable laws and regulations and consult with legal and compliance specialists to gain a comprehensive understanding of the specific requirements they need to meet.</p>
<h4><strong>2. </strong><strong>Conduct a Risk Assessment:</strong></h4>
<p>Organizations can conduct a risk assessment to pinpoint and prioritize their cybersecurity risks. This entails assessing both internal and external threats and vulnerabilities, as well as the potential repercussions of a cybersecurity incident.</p>
<h4><strong>3.</strong><strong>Develop a Cybersecurity Program:</strong></h4>
<p>After completing a risk assessment, organizations should create a detailed cybersecurity program that meets all applicable regulatory requirements. This program should include technical measures, policies and procedures, employee training, and plans for responding to cybersecurity incidents.</p>
<h4><strong>4.</strong><strong>Implement Technical Controls:</strong></h4>
<p>Once a risk assessment has been completed, organizations must develop a comprehensive cybersecurity program that fulfills all relevant regulatory requirements. This program should encompass technical measures, policies and procedures, employee training, and strategies for responding to cybersecurity incidents.</p>
<h4><strong>5.</strong><strong>Establish Policies and Procedures:</strong></h4>
<p>Policies and procedures instruct employees on properly handling sensitive data and the appropriate response to cybersecurity incidents. Organizations must update them regularly to stay current with changes in regulations and emerging threats.</p>
<h4><strong>6.</strong><strong>Train Employees:</strong></h4>
<p>Employees can often represent the most vulnerable aspect of an organization’s cybersecurity defenses. As such, it is crucial to provide them with regular training on best practices in cybersecurity. This training may cover such issues as recognizing phishing attempts, managing passwords effectively, and responding appropriately to cybersecurity incidents.</p>
<h4><strong>7.</strong><strong>Regularly Assess and Update the Cybersecurity Program:</strong></h4>
<p>As cybersecurity threats are multiplying, it is essential for organizations to regularly review and update their cybersecurity programs to address new risks. This may entail conducting periodic risk assessments, conducting penetration testing, and evaluating their ability to respond effectively to cybersecurity incidents.</p>
<h4><strong>8.</strong><strong>Engage Third-Party Vendors:</strong></h4>
<p>When organizations collaborate with third-party vendors, they may expose themselves to additional cybersecurity risks. To mitigate these risks, organizations must ensure that their vendors comply with the relevant cybersecurity regulations and incorporate cybersecurity requirements into their contracts.</p>
<h4><strong>9.</strong><strong>Monitor and Report on Compliance:</strong></h4>
<p>Organizations often work with third-party vendors, which can introduce additional challenges and cybersecurity risks. So, to address these risks, organizations should make sure their vendors comply with relevant cybersecurity regulations. This can be achieved by developing and implementing necessary policies and procedures. In addition to this, organizations must also develop a contract that clearly states the vendor’s roles and responsibilities toward achieving and maintaining compliance with various cybersecurity requirements.</p>
<p>By following these steps, organizations can establish and maintain effective cybersecurity programs that comply with applicable regulations and protect against cyber threats. Organizations must take a proactive and ongoing approach to cybersecurity compliance to ensure the security of their sensitive data and protect against reputational and financial damage.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h2>
<p><em>In conclusion, cybersecurity compliance is essential for protecting your organization’s sensitive data and assets from cyber threats. Compliance ensures that your security measures are effective and meet industry standards. With the ever-evolving regulatory landscape and frameworks, staying current and taking the necessary steps to achieve compliance is crucial. Achieving and maintaining compliance is an ongoing process that requires diligence and commitment. If your organization needs assistance developing a robust cybersecurity compliance program, VISTA InfoSec is here to help. As a renowned cybersecurity consulting firm, our certified and experienced professionals can guide you through your compliance journey and help you build an effective cybersecurity program. By partnering with us, your organization can enjoy a hassle-free compliance journey.</em></p>
<p><em>We hope this guide has provided you with valuable insights into the world of cybersecurity compliance. Remember to stay informed about the latest developments in the field to safeguard your organization against cyber threats. Thank you for reading, and we wish you all the best on your cybersecurity compliance journey!</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5147"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks of credit and debit card Fraud: Why PCI DSS is Essential?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/risks-of-credit-and-debit-card-fraud-why-pci-dss-is-essential/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 11:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PCI DSS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5140</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The Advancement in technology and online payment transaction has offered &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/risks-of-credit-and-debit-card-fraud-why-pci-dss-is-essential/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Advancement in technology and online payment transaction has offered an immense amount of convenience to both consumers and businesses. The ease and widespread acceptance of online payment including the credit/debit card transaction has streamlined business processes and payment transactions greatly. Globally, it was observed that credit card transactions increased by <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/261327/number-of-per-card-credit-card-transactions-worldwide-by-brand-as-of-2011/">roughly 6% between 2020 and 2019</a>, and roughly 188 billion purchase transactions were made worldwide using Visa payment cards in 2020 (an increase by 1.3%).</p>
<p>Further, the number of payment cards in circulation worldwide grew by over <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1080756/number-payment-cards-in-circulation-worldwide/">two billion between 2019 and 2021</a> and is forecast to further increase. However, with such progress in online payment transactions, it has also increased the incidents and cases of scams, frauds, and cyber-attacks.</p>
<p>Since the boom of the online payment industry, it has become an easy and soft target for attackers. Payment methods such as credit/debit card transactions are a huge target for hackers to perform their malicious crimes. This has in turn compelled businesses and industry regulators to establish stringent standards and frameworks that ensure the security and privacy of sensitive data and assets.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5141" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Common-Types-of-Online-Scams-and-Frauds.jpg" alt="Common Types of Online Scams and Frauds" width="1920" height="1080" /></p>
<h3><strong><u>Global Statistics of Payment Card Fraud (2020-2021)</u></strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Payment card fraud losses worldwide exceeded <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2022/12/22/2578877/0/en/Payment-Card-Fraud-Losses-Reach-32-34-Billion.html">$32 billion in 2021</a>, of which nearly $12 billion was in the US.</li>
<li>Losses to fraud worldwide increased by <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2022/12/22/2578877/0/en/Payment-Card-Fraud-Losses-Reach-32-34-Billion.html">14% in 2021</a>.</li>
<li>Over the next 10 years, the industry is projected <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2022/12/22/2578877/0/en/Payment-Card-Fraud-Losses-Reach-32-34-Billion.html">to lose an accumulated $397 billion worldwide</a>, with $165 billion coming from the US</li>
<li>The US accounted for 37% of worldwide losses to card fraud in 2021.</li>
<li>Card fraud netted criminals nearly $4 billion more in 2021 than in 2020.</li>
<li>Issuers, merchants, and acquirers of merchant and ATM transactions collectively <a href="https://nilsonreport.com/upload/content_promo/NilsonReport_Issue1209.pdf">lost $28.58 billion</a> to card fraud in 2020.</li>
</ul>
<h3><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5142" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Common-Types-of-Payment-Card-Fraud.jpg" alt="Common Types of Payment Card Fraud" width="1920" height="1080" /></h3>
<h3><strong><u>Advent of PCI DSS Standard</u></strong></h3>
<p>In order to effectively address credit card fraud, payment card brands such as Visa and MasterCard first created a security program for their credit cards ( Visa introduced their Visa Cardholder Information Security Program and MasterCard introduced their MasterCard’s Site Data Protection). Similarly, other payment brands followed the suit and introduced such security programs for their credit cards.</p>
<p>Such security programs were introduced with the aim to protect card issuers and cardholders against various credit card frauds. However, this made it confusing for Merchants and Service Providers to meet the requirements of multiple payment brands. The challenge of not having a uniform security standard and approach to security requirements resulted in merchants struggling to meet the compliance requirement of various payment card brands.</p>
<p>This is when major payment brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express, Discover Financial Services, and JCB International came together to establish a uniform payment security standard. The initiative of creating a uniform security payment standard was to standardize and regulate card transactions and processing among all merchants and service providers. These 5 major payment brands came together and formed a Payment Card Industry Security Standard Council (PCI SSC) and further established the <strong>Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS).</strong></p>
<h2><strong><u>PCI DSS Standard </u></strong></h2>
<p>PCI DSS Standard was first introduced in the year 2004, thereafter we have seen the standard constantly evolving over the years, till the recent version which is the <strong>PCI DSS 4.0</strong> which was updated in the year 2022. The industry has constantly witnessed the evolution of this international payment security standard to keep up with the evolving and sophisticated threat landscape. The latest version was introduced to enhance the security of payment card account data and also deal with evolving and emerging security threats.</p>
<p>PCI DSS is a benchmark standard for all merchants and service providers to meet the technical security requirements for protecting sensitive account data. The latest version of <strong>PCI DSS 4.0v</strong> provides guidance and flexibility in the implementation of high-level security measures while also allowing customization in the implementation of security solutions. This is to meet the industry&#8217;s best security standard requirements and attain a maximum level of security for payment card account data.</p>
<p>PCI DSS Standard is a comprehensive set of high-level security rules and requirements. It is defined and established to ensure and maintain a maximum level of security by merchants and service providers in the payment card industry. The standard is a mandate for all Merchants and Service Providers who process and store cardholder data. They are expected to meet the industry&#8217;s best practices and follow the set of rules and guidelines of PCI DSS in order to work and be a part of the payment card industry. Every business dealing with payment card data is accountable and obliged to meet the standard requirements and further verify this with a Qualified Security Assessor (QSA) whether or not the business is compliant. Further, businesses are expected to undergo an audit every year in order to attain the certification of Compliance with PCI DSS.</p>
<p>Failure to comply with the standard can have significant implications in terms of hefty penalties, lawsuits, payment brands placing restrictions on card processing, losing license of payment brands with complete termination of services, and tarnished brand reputation. Due to such obligations and significant repercussions, businesses are bound to prioritize security in their business operations and processes.</p>
<p>This in turn helps businesses build a shield against the evolving security threats and risks of data breaches and cybercrimes in the payment industry. Ultimately the whole purpose of PCI DSS is to protect card data from hackers and thieves. By following the standard, businesses can keep the data secure, and prevent a data breach. This way, the level of accountability established in the industry, helps in keeping the checks and balances in place when it comes to implementing and ensuring safe payment transactions in the industry.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-5143 size-large" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--1024x576.jpg" alt="Benefits Of PCI DSS Compliance" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--400x225.jpg 400w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--24x14.jpg 24w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--36x20.jpg 36w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance--48x27.jpg 48w, https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Benefits-of-PCI-DSS-Compliance-.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><strong><u>Conclusion </u></strong></p>
<p>PCI DSS may not seem necessary as it isn’t a mandate by law. Yet it is important to comply with the standard, in order to ensure secure business and safe payment transactions. PCI DSS is an industry best security practice that must be followed if you are a business handling sensitive and valuable payment card information of customers.</p>
<p>This is because even a single incident of a data breach will have repercussions beyond just simple theft.  So, taking that extra time and effort to make sure your business is complying with the PCI DSS standard is important. By doing so, you are not just protecting your business but also acting responsibly and protecting your client as well.</p>
<p>So, we strongly recommend businesses aim for PCI DSS Compliance if they are a part of the payment card industry and the standard applies to their business. You can always consult our compliance expert at VISTA InfoSec for assistance and guidance in achieving PCI DSS Compliance. We are a qualified PCI QSA, PCI QPA &amp; PCI SSFA, having the industry knowledge and expertise in PCI DSS Compliance &amp; Audit.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5140"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VI Achieves  SOC2 -Type1 Certification For Managed Security Services</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vi-achieves-soc2-type1-certification-for-managed-security-services/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[VISTA InfoSec Announcement]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5133</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[VodafoneIdea Limited, a leading Indian Telecom Operator has successfully achieved SOC2 &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/vi-achieves-soc2-type1-certification-for-managed-security-services/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>VodafoneIdea Limited, a leading Indian Telecom Operator has successfully achieved SOC2 Attestation. After undergoing a rigorous auditing process, VodafoneIdea achieved SOC2 Attestation from VISTA InfoSec, a well-known Global Cybersecurity Consulting, and Certification organization. The SOC2 Audit and Attestation is an assessment of internal controls and security practices conducted by the independent auditors of VISTA InfoSec.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Achieving the SOC2 Attestation is a milestone for the organization as it demonstrates their commitment to high-level security and operational resilience. The Attestation is a documented evidence that VodafoneIdea has successfully met all the requirements and implemented security controls in alignment with SOC2 Requirements.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>“Performing the SOC2 Audit was a deliberate decision by our management to prove our commitment towards the security of sensitive data. We were adamant to test and ensure the efficiency of our established processes and internal controls within our organization”</em></strong> <strong>said<em> <u>Mathan K Babu, CTSO</u>, </em></strong><strong><em><u>VodafoneIdea Limited</u></em></strong><em><u>.</u></em> With the successful completion of the<a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/soc2-audit-attestation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> SOC2 Audit</a> and the achievement of SOC2 Attestation, it confirms that VodafoneIdea Limited has all the necessary internal controls in place. <strong>“<em>The Management and the entire team of </em></strong><strong><em>VodafoneIdea Limited were truly dedicated and proactive in ensuring an efficient conduct of the audit process,” </em></strong><strong>said, <u>Narendra Sahoo, Founder &amp; Director of VISTA InfoSec.</u></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The SOC2 Audit performed is based on the AICPA’s Trust Services Criteria. The Audit report focuses on Vodafone’s non-financial reporting controls related to the Security and Availability, of their systems and internal controls relevant to their Managed DDOS Protection Services. The audit report provided by VISTA InfoSec verifies the suitability of the design and operating effectiveness of controls that are in alignment with the AICPA’s standards and <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/choosing-soc-2-principles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trust Services Criteria</a> (TSC).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>SOC2 is an international auditing standard and the industry&#8217;s best data security practice in the US. Achieving a SOC2 Attestation demonstrates that VodafoneIdea Limited is committed to securing sensitive data and for which they have established a robust security program within the organization.</p>
<p>The Attestation suggests that VodafoneIdea Limited delivers secure services and solutions to their clients, and the audit report is an assurance of their commitment to the security and reliability of their internal controls.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Note-The SOC2 Audit report and findings are only available to the clients and stakeholders of VodafoneIdea Limited for review, based on request.</em></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5133"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 0px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <span class="kksr-muted">Rating</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDPR Compliance for Email Marketing and Cold-Callings</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/gdpr-compliance-for-email-marketing-and-cold-callings/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 11:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[EU GDPR]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5121</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Cold calling and emailing have always been popular and effective &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/gdpr-compliance-for-email-marketing-and-cold-callings/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cold calling and emailing have always been popular and effective techniques of sales and communication with prospective clients. It is a way how brands can reach out to potential clients who may not be aware of your service or product offerings. It is a technique of creating brand awareness and lead generation. However, many customers see these activities as spamming.  This sales technique has earned a bad reputation for simply exploiting or misusing the personal data of individuals under the pretext of business.</p>
<p>People are often bombarded with irrelevant emails and sales calls that were of no interest to customers. This led to the practice of cold emailing and calling being seen as spam. Recognizing the growing misuse of personal data, the GDPR Regulation established strong measures to ensure the protection and privacy of people’s private data. Covering the requirements of GDPR, we have explained whether or not email and cold calling is allowed under GDPR and how organizations can ensure compliance while conducting such actives.</p>
<h3><strong>Are cold email marketing and cold calling allowed under GDPR?</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/key-requirements-of-gdpr-regulation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GDPR Regulation</a> was established to protect and preserve the rights of individuals and secure their personal data. That said, the regulation sets certain guidelines to ensure the private data of individuals are not misused in the pretext of business. But it is important to note and understand that the GDPR regulation does not stop email marketing or cold emails. However, the guidelines outlined does discourage the misuse of personal data.</p>
<p>The regulation is about protecting personal data and ending unethical digital marketing practices to protect individuals’ privacy. So, to simply put cold calling and cold email marketing activities are allowed under GDPR, provided appropriate guidelines are followed by the organization. However, anyone violating the rules will have to pay a hefty price for it. So, it is just that the businesses have to be a bit more careful about the methods they adopt to gather, manage, store and use the personal data of citizens of the EU.</p>
<h3><strong>What does the GDPR Regulation say about email marketing and cold-calling activities?</strong></h3>
<p>Organizations must follow certain guidelines as outlined in the GDPR Regulation to ensure compliance in their sales activity like cold emailing or calls. GDPR clearly states that the processing of personal data is only allowed if either the <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/guide-on-gdpr-personal-data-and-data-subject/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data subject</a> has provided consent or there is a legal basis or legitimate interest of the organization (controller) to send e-mails.</p>
<p>Recital 47 of the GDPR states that the law also applies to the processing of personal data used for direct marketing as a legitimate interest of the controller. However, it is important to note that e-mail marketing is allowed without consent for existing customers. But in case the customers wish to not receive any further information by newsletter or e-mail, the customer can object to processing for marketing purposes.</p>
<p>According to Article 21(2), (3) GDPR, the data subject always has the right to object to the processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes. If the data subject objects, the controller has to stop the processing for marketing purposes. But they can continue to process the data for performing their contract.</p>
<p>It is also important to understand that the legitimate interest of the controller to process data for marketing purposes cannot overweigh the objection of the data subject. Regardless of whether the organization involves in the activity of cold calling or cold emailing, based on its legitimate interest or consent, they are required to adhere to the data subject’s right to be informed.</p>
<h3><strong>How can organizations ensure compliance while sending cold emails or in cold calling?</strong></h3>
<p>While it is clear that organizations are allowed to use the technique of cold calling or cold emailing for sales, but they are required to follow certain rules and ensure that the activities are GDPR compliant. So, here are some ways how businesses can ensure compliance with GDPR when sending cold emails or in cold calling.</p>
<h3><strong>Legit reason and targeted prospects</strong></h3>
<p>Organizations should have a legit reason for processing personal data. They should have a legal basis or legitimate interest to send e-mails. Also, organizations must ensure that the data they collect and use should be only if it is strictly necessary for business. So, for instance, if your business plans to simply just send mails then avoid collecting additional data like address and phone numbers. Plus ensure that you only approach well-targeted prospects. So, in this scenario, people sharing views on products similar to what your business offers can be your potential clients and so be considered as target prospects.</p>
<p>Businesses are allowed to contact only those prospects who are likely interested in their products and service offerings and likely to purchase or avail them. If the prospects are not relevant then you might be breaching the GDPR. Businesses are required to be very selective about the data they collect and the prospects they choose to communicate. If this is done right businesses will definitely not get penalized by the GDPR.</p>
<h3><strong>Explain how the prospect’s email was acquired</strong></h3>
<p>To cover all grounds of GDPR the organization must know how and from where they acquired the emails. Even if it is a list of emails bought from a third party, organizations must ensure that the database was collected and used in a GDPR compliant manner. Businesses are required to keep a record of how all the data was collected and is processed. It is also important to note that organizations must have in place measures to ensure that if a data subject demands deletion of their data or objects the processing of data, then it must be done immediately. Simply providing an unsubscribe link is not enough but the data must be immediately deleted.</p>
<h4><strong>GDPR Requirements</strong></h4>
<p>Organizations can process personal data under the following circumstances as outlined in the GDPR</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Consent-</strong>When the organization gets appropriate consent from the prospect to process their personal data.</li>
<li><strong>Contract-</strong>When there is an official and legit contract established between the organizations (controller) and the prospect that requires the processing of the personal data.</li>
<li><strong>Legal obligation- </strong>When the organization has a legal obligation and by law is required to process the personal data of prospect.</li>
<li><strong>Public Interest- </strong>When there is a need to process personal data which is in the public interest, an organization can process personal data.</li>
<li><strong>Protect vital interest:</strong> When there is a vital mutual interest to protect and requires data processing organizations can process personal data.</li>
<li><strong>Legitimate interest:</strong>When there is a legitimate interest and where both the parties will benefit, an organization can process personal data.</li>
</ul>
<p>Whatever be the reason for contacting prospects and processing their data, it is important that the organization informs and communicates the same to the prospect their emails. This is an essential step in the process of <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/gdpr-compliance-consulting-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GDPR Compliance.</a></p>
<h4><strong>Explain Legal Interest in the Email</strong></h4>
<p>Legal interest is one of the six lawful data processing reasons outlined in the GDPR. Whenever the processing of personal data is not a lawful obligation but for the benefit of both the prospect and organization, then it must be justified and communicated to the prospect in the mail accordingly. Organizations need to prove that there is a legitimate interest in contacting the prospect and that may include-</p>
<ul>
<li>The product and service offerings of the organization are of the prospect&#8217;s interest and support their need.</li>
<li>The prospect asked for information or searched for details related to your product and service.</li>
<li>The prospect is up for expansion in an area that is relevant to your product or service.</li>
<li>The prospect is your existing or previous client from the same industry.</li>
<li>The business got to know about the prospect from your network.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>The products and services offered, support the prospects of investment and growth.</li>
</ul>
<p>It is important to note that the term legal interest for processing data can only be legal if the interest also accounts for the person’s right to privacy. Again an organization cannot hold personal data longer than needed. When an organization collects personal data like an email address, they need to inform the individual that the data has been stored for future marketing purposes and also provide a legitimate interest in storing and processing the data. The email should include a copy of</p>
<ul>
<li>A statement informing the prospect how their data was collected and will be processed.</li>
<li>Provide a time frame or retention period for storing their data.</li>
<li>Provide a brief explanation of why the data is processed.</li>
<li>Step-by-step guidelines to the receiver for changing or objecting to the processing or deletion of their data.</li>
<li>Provide a copy of the Disclaimer for the cold email.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Process of Unsubscribing</strong></h4>
<p>If the organization is up from sending cold emails, they also need to provide the recipients an option to opt-out of the emailing list.  Organizations are required to provide an easy, quick unsubscribe option with an ‘unsubscribe link’ added at the bottom of your email to ensure compliance.  This is the fundamental element and right of the recipient in the cold email. The organization should even provide a guide for those who wish to delete their personal data from the records. So, if the receiver asks you to delete their data, then it is easily deleted from your records, backups, and other places of storage. Organizations must ensure that the information provided must be clear and steps to opt-out must be easy.</p>
<h4><strong>Frequently Update the Database</strong></h4>
<p>GDPR also requires organizations to keep their database updated and delete any data that is no longer required or in use. This simply means that organizations should have in place a data retention policy to regularly update their database and prevent storing of personal data longer than required. So, businesses must not hold any leads for a long time or incorrect contact details. This is one of the most essential and core components to ensure cold emails are GDPR compliant.</p>
<p>CRM database must be regular, up-to-date, and should be traceable in terms of how the personal data was collected, processed, and stored. So, remove the leads that are no longer require and replace them with active contacts with correct contact details. An organization must also secure its database by taking necessary measures for security. Measures such as having in place physical access controls, data access controls, system access controls, input controls, transmission control, and segregation of data, backups, are some measures that will help to secure the data.</p>
<h4><strong>Strong Data Security</strong></h4>
<p>The purpose of the GDPR Regulation is mainly to ensure data protection and privacy of personal data. So, that said, when sending cold emails organizations must ensure systems applications, and networks used for mailing and storing of data must be GDPR Compliant. The data collected and processed should be encrypted and the ones that are stored should be retained for only as long as when necessary. Organizations must also keep a record of the data collected, processed, and used while establishing a level of authorization<strong> for every activity. </strong></p>
<h4><strong>Prompt Response to Request/Queries</strong></h4>
<p>When organizations run a cold email campaign it is natural that the recipient will have queries regarding your mails or may possibly even request for an unsubscribe or deletion of their data or even ask for their information or correction of their data. So, organizations are required to have in place a system that facilitates prompt response to any such request or queries. The GDPR Regulation gives the citizen of the EU the right to information, right to access, right to rectification, right to deletion, right to restrict processing, right to data portability, right object, and even right to prevent automated decision making. So, with such right given to the citizens, organizations are required to oblige to their request and respond to it at the earliest</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>The aim to establish GDPR is to not just simply abolish the cold calling and emailing strategy but to ensure that the organizations appropriately secure the data. The regulation was not designed to limit the way business generates leads, but to ensure appropriate measures are taken to communicate with prospects and prevent misuse of personal data.  With GDPR in place, gone are the days of spamming people with random business advertisements.</p>
<p>GDPR is more focused on protecting and preserving the rights of citizens of the EU. The GDPR regulation encourages businesses to build genuine connections with people who may be interested in the business offering. This adds more accuracy and relevance to the emailing process.</p>
<p>The regulation should be seen as an effort to secure and preserve the rights of people and also for quality lead generation. GDPR compliant cold emails will eventually help organizations close deals faster as the list of prospects will be more relevant and accurate when purchased while ensuring compliance.</p>
<h2></h2>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5121"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does VPN Security help in Data Security &amp; Privacy?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-does-vpn-security-help-in-data-security-privacy/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 10:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5107</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Today in a technology-driven business world, network security is an &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-does-vpn-security-help-in-data-security-privacy/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today in a technology-driven business world, network security is an utmost priority for all businesses, especially for those dealing with sensitive data. More so, in an organization that works in a hybrid environment wherein information and critical data are accessed remotely, the need for securing such data and network is important. This has led to a paradigm shift in the approach of establishing a robust security program and security implementations within the organization. So, for addressing the growing concerns of network and data security threats, technology such as the VPN is now in growing demand.</p>
<p>A Virtual Private Network is a technology that secures not just the network but also the data stored, transmitted, and processed in the network. It is a technology that secures the network and ensures only authorized access to the data stored or transferred within the network. Covering about the VPN technology in detail, we have explained how <a href="https://surfshark.com/download">VPN Download</a> Security helps in Data Security &amp; Privacy in a technologically driven world of business operations. But before that let us first quickly understand the concept of the VPN  technology before diving into the benefits of the technology.</p>
<h3><strong>What is VPN?</strong></h3>
<p>Virtual Private Network is a technology that facilitates secure and private browsing for internet users, allowing only authorized access to critical data on that network. The technology helps secure connection over the untrusted network by using encryption and access control techniques. This technology is important, especially when using an open public network to prevent an unauthorized individual from spying on a user’s online activity and for securing the data shared on that network.</p>
<p>VPN creates a secure private network between the user’s computer and the VPN server, thereby preventing their Internet Service Provider (ISP) or any potential hacker from tracking the users browsing activity and location. This facilitates high-level online privacy by hiding browsing information and preventing snooping on users. Further, the encryption technique adds an extra layer of security in terms of securing the data transmitted through the network.</p>
<p>So now that we know about VPN technology let&#8217;s move a step ahead in understanding how the technology helps in data security and privacy.</p>
<h3><strong>How does VPN Security help in Data Security &amp; Privacy?</strong></h3>
<p>Currently with businesses handling huge amounts of sensitive data, securing such data becomes a daunting task for most organizations. These organizations come under the intense pressure of managing the security and privacy of sensitive data, especially in the prevailing cyber threat landscape. So, with the increasing demand for technologies that facilitate data security and privacy, VPN is one such technique that fits perfectly well to address these issues. In fact, VPN technology serves different purposes, including securing the data through the encryption process and ensuring the privacy of online activities by hiding IP addresses and maintaining the privacy of data through controlling access to sensitive data. Explaining more on this in detail we have described how VPN technology helps in data security and privacy.</p>
<h4><strong><u>VPN for Data Security</u></strong></h4>
<p>A Virtual Private Network (VPN) is an exceptionally well-designed and robust Internet Security Solution that allows internet users to access the internet securely via a private network. Given below are some ways how VPN ensures data security.</p>
<h5>         <strong>1.Secures Network</strong></h5>
<p>VPN facilitates high-level network security. The primary objective of VPN technology is to hide the IP address from your Internet Service Provider (ISP) and other third parties. This in turn allows secure transmission of data which includes sending and receiving sensitive data online without the risk of unauthorized access to the data. Further, the technology also prevents the possibility of leaving any trace in terms of search history and cookies, thereby ensuring maximum security of the internet user’s data. Talking about the use of encryption techniques, it helps prevent third-party or unauthorized individuals from accessing critical and confidential information such as personal and financial data online.</p>
<h5 style="text-align: left;">       <strong>2. Secures Data Transmission</strong></h5>
<p>Now that we know VPN technology facilitates secure networks, it is also worth noting that all the data transmitted through the network is through a secure encrypted virtual tunnel. This ensures not just the disguising of the IP address and location but securing of the entire connection and the data on it against any kind of external threat or attack.</p>
<p>The VPN technology uses end-to-end encryption techniques to ensure maximum security and privacy of the data and network. Since the data transmitted on the network is routed via an encrypted tunnel the data is secured against various cyber threats and risk of data exposure or leakage. So, even if a hacker manages to intercept the private network, they would still be unable to view the data and ensure its security.</p>
<h5>     <strong> 3.Secures Data Access</strong></h5>
<p>VPN facilitates data security through access control features wherein only authorized individuals can access data via a secure encrypted virtual tunnel.  This is especially useful for organizations that allow remote working and access to employees who may need to avail critical data over an unsecured or public network. Encrypted and secure access control ensures not just a secure network connection but also secure data access. This way the organization need not worry about unauthorized data access and data leakage or exposure over an unsecured public network.</p>
<h5>     <strong>4.Limits Data Access</strong></h5>
<p>VPN facilitates point of access to data stored in an organization’s servers. So here, by connecting the VPN to the organization&#8217;s private network and database, your organization can grant secure access to only relevant employees within the organization. Since it adds a layer of security in terms of only authorized access, the exposure to data leakage and unauthorized access is limited. This simply means the data access will be limited to only those employees with special access rights to VPN. Limiting access to sensitive data is crucial for organizations especially obligated to ensure the security and privacy of the data.</p>
<h4><strong><u>VPN for Data Privacy </u></strong></h4>
<p>VPN is the most effective way to ensure the privacy of the network and data. It prevents tracking and tracing of the internet user’s activity by hiding the web browsing details and location. This ensures privacy and further enhances the confidentiality of the data searched or fed online by the user. Given below are some ways how VPN ensures data privacy.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h5><strong> Facilitates Privacy on Public Networks </strong></h5>
</li>
</ol>
<p>VPN is popular among organizations that work remotely as it offers high-level privacy. Even on an unsecured network, VPN protects data hiding the browsing history, and encrypting sensitive data such as financial information, and details that are stored and transmitted through the open network. So, this way the technology does not just ensure the security but also the privacy of the data by facilitating access via a private encrypted network.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<h5><strong> Hides IP Address </strong></h5>
</li>
</ol>
<p>VPNs is an excellent and popular technique for protecting IP address. The technique ensures that the online activities of internet users are virtually untraceable. As mentioned earlier, since VPN hides the IP address, there is a high level of privacy maintained. This prevents the possibility of any kind of data exposure and the risk of a hack by an attacker.<strong>  </strong></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<h5><strong> Privacy from the Internet Service Provider</strong></h5>
</li>
</ol>
<p>When a person accesses sensitive and confidential data remotely from home, they are less likely to be attacked by a hacker in comparison to the risk they hold when connecting to a public network. However, the data still stands to be vulnerable as your online activity and the sensitive data accessed will still be visible to the Internet Service Provider. This is equally dangerous, especially if the data falls in the wrong hands in an event of a data breach. However, with the implementation of a VPN, the IP address can be disguised and secured from the visibility of your ISP. So, this way VPN is an excellent way of maintaining security and privacy from the Internet Service Provider.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<h5><strong> Privacy from Third-party Service Providers </strong></h5>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The privacy of your data is not just at risk from your ISP but also from any other third-party service provider whose services you avail online. But with VPN technology in place, it helps prevent any third-party apps, websites, or service providers from accessing your confidential data and tracing your activities online. VPN hides your IP address, location, browsing history, cookies, account details, and even passwords that are confidential and prevent any kind of disclosure to a third party. It prevents apps and websites from accessing and storing any information thereby ensuring maximum privacy against even third-party service providers.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<h5><strong> Enhances Online Browsing Privacy </strong></h5>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Today maintaining browsing privacy is the need of the hour, especially in an age of online shopping which involves using sensitive data for online financial transactions. In the business age where everything is digital and data-driven, apps, and social media platforms are constantly collecting and analyzing data of internet users, based on their browsing history. The information collected through these channels is then used for targeted marketing and sales. However, VPN provides the required privacy by ensuring such data isn’t traced, collected, or even stored in the most effective way. VPN hides your browsing history and cached data thereby enhancing your browsing privacy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>Final Thought </strong></h3>
<p>VPN as a technology serves both internet users and businesses online. While it provides security and privacy to internet users in terms of their data exposure, it also helps businesses stay compliant with various data security and privacy compliance and regulatory requirements, including GDPR, HIPAA, PCI DSS, MAS TRM, CPRA, ISO27001, etc. to name a few. As we just learnt, technology can greatly increase data security and provide an effective solution to the growing concerns of data security and privacy in the prevailing dynamic cyber-threat landscape. Although there are certain downsides to the use of this technology, however, the benefits definitely outweigh the downside of VPN technology.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5107"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Threat Intelligence Matters To Your Organization?</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-threat-intelligence-matters-to-your-organization/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 09:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5102</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Technological advancements have revolutionized the world’s cultural and economic institutions &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/why-threat-intelligence-matters-to-your-organization/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Technological advancements have revolutionized the world’s cultural and economic institutions in almost every aspect. Unfortunately, they have also brought risks in the form of cyber threats. While there are various ways to mitigate such threats, paying importance to threat intelligence can make a difference to your organization.</p>
<h3><strong>What Is Threat Intelligence?</strong></h3>
<p>Threat intelligence is evidence-based knowledge that allows organizations to mitigate or prevent cyber-attacks. It provides context, implications, indicators, and mechanisms you can use to make well-informed decisions about your company’s security.</p>
<p>Organizations can access this information through &#8216;threat feeds,&#8217; which provide detection updates. These feeds can be community-based, vendor-based, or public-based. They can also be maintained and generated internally in a proprietary fashion.</p>
<p>Threat intelligence and other <a href="http://fusioncomputing.ca/cyber-security-toronto/">cyber security services in Toronto</a> not only help prevent cyber threats but also help in recovering from the damages in case of attacks. If you’re in doubt about threat intelligence, here are the reasons it matters to your organization:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Helps Prevent Financial Loss</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Security breaches can be expensive. More often than not, they can include investigations, lawsuits, and fines that cost millions of dollars. With threat intelligence, you can help your incident response team to make informed and timely decisions to prevent downtime, protect your assets, save your company’s customers and reputation, and avoid data theft.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Helps Gather Actionable Data</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Threat intelligence helps gather actionable data for your business and provides insights about cyber-attack indicators. Such threat indicators include email addresses, servers, and web addresses used in cyber-attacks.</p>
<p>All these can be scanned and actionable for your infrastructure, enabling you to develop <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cybersecurity-best-practices-for-small-organizations/">cybersecurity best practices</a>. Together with your incident response teams, the gathered actionable data can strengthen your defenses, preventing the likelihood of cyber-attacks.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Maximizes Staffing Efficiency</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Threat intelligence makes your security team less prone to burnout due to alert fatigue, allowing them to be more efficient. Manually correlating and validating threat intelligence is resource-intensive and time-consuming.</p>
<p>Leveraging threat intelligence solutions that use security automation and artificial intelligence can help your business correlate and collect data about threats. This way, you can lessen your security response times and minimize false positives to let your security teams focus on what matters.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Reduces Loss Of Data</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Since threat intelligence can help block malicious domains and website addresses belonging to cyber criminals, it can prevent threats from penetrating your infrastructure. As a result, attackers won’t be able to steal your sensitive data, improving your data security and minimizing the chances of data loss.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Secures Network Infrastructure</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When cybercriminals find an entry point in your infrastructure, they may crawl through your entire system, using siphoning and lateral movement for financial or sensitive data. Threat intelligence can help scan for compromise indicators and block them in your infrastructure. This way, you can immediately secure your network’s infrastructure and prevent threats from proceeding if they have entered your system.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Helps Your Business Maintain Pace With The Constantly Evolving Attacks</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Another reason threat intelligence matters to an organization are that it helps your business maintain pace with the constantly evolving attacks. For example, many attacks these days occur through phishing emails.</p>
<p>Threat intelligence can be used to close any entry point for attackers. In the case of phishing, businesses can have various employee awareness programs to block possible cyber-attacks.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Evaluates Your Organization’s Security Posture</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Threat intelligence can help assess your infrastructure’s security posture. It provides data on exploiting vulnerabilities found in different applications, software, and tools.</p>
<p>With threat intelligence, you can constantly check on what new vulnerabilities are exploited or discovered and check which assets are at risk. As a result, you can apply timely updates or patches to your critical assets as soon as cybersecurity specialists fix any bugs or vulnerabilities.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Provides In-Depth Cyber Threat Analysis</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Threat intelligence provides you with an in-depth analysis of all cyber threats. Therefore, it can help your organization analyze the different methods attackers can use. If your current cybersecurity defense strategy can’t protect your network, you can improve your network’s security with threat intelligence. Doing so can help protect your system from possible vulnerabilities.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>It Offers Collaborative Knowledge</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Threat intelligence offers collaborative knowledge that may benefit your entire organization. It shares essential cybersecurity information and practices that your employees may not be aware of. Since it’s somewhat challenging to keep up with zero-day threats or new vulnerabilities, threat intelligence can be advantageous for your organization, allowing you to defend yourself against cyber threats and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2022/09/23/getting-ahead-of-attackers/">get ahead of the attackers</a>.</p>
<h3><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<p>Those are many reasons threat intelligence is essential for any organization. It not only enhances your organization’s security posture but also alerts you about possible threats coming your way. With such insights, you can strengthen your cybersecurity technique, effectively mitigating cyber-attacks.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5102"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Developing Your Ransomware Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/tips-for-developing-your-ransomware-strategy/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 08:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5095</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Ransomware attacks continue to make headlines and cause havoc on &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/tips-for-developing-your-ransomware-strategy/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ransomware attacks continue to make headlines and cause havoc on organizations on an international scale. Unfortunately, we should expect that ransomware attacks will persist as one of the primary threats to organizations. Ransomware attacks have grown 350% in recent years, and while the best strategy is to prevent attacks from happening in the first place, there is no guarantee your data won’t be compromised. Instead of turning a blind eye to the possibility of a <a href="https://guardiandigital.com/resources/blog/ransomware" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ransomware</a> attack, your organization should develop a <a href="https://guardiandigital.com/resources/blog/ransomware-recovery-basics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ransomware prevention and recovery strategy</a> that will help your organization recover from the situation of a ransomware attack.</p>
<h3><strong>Importance of a Ransomware Recovery Plan</strong></h3>
<p>If your business lacks a ransomware recovery plan, you run the risk of serious consequences. A successful ransomware attack affects not only your productivity and reputation but also comes with a hefty price tag. Research studies and reports suggest that the average ransom paid by victim organizations of ransomware attacks, where their data was encrypted, has increased to $812,360</p>
<p>Implementing a cybersecurity strategy can save your organization time, money, and sensitive data when facing a ransomware attack. An in-depth cybersecurity strategy includes a comprehensive, multi-security response strategy that is designed to prevent such threats and enable stability to minimize downtime.</p>
<p>When developing your strategy, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) recommends that you follow the Cyber Security Framework (CSF), with five essential roles including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Identify:</strong> Identify key assets (data, applications, etc) that your business needs for continued operations.</li>
<li><strong>Protect: </strong>Automate data protection for your key assets and the backup environment.</li>
<li><strong>Detect:</strong> Early threat detection is critical for mitigating ransomware threats.</li>
<li><strong>Respond: </strong>Have a Disaster Response Strategy in place to address the ongoing attack and prevent escalation of threats.</li>
<li><strong>Recover: </strong>Establish a Disaster Recovery Plan including recovery options and backups that reduce impacts on business.</li>
</ul>
<p>Deciding on the right ransomware recovery solution is crucial to ensure that your organization has a stable and effective defense plan in place. This is essential to reduce the impact of ransomware or malware.</p>
<h3><strong>Ransomware Incident Response Plan</strong></h3>
<p>Response Plans will vary, but they should address the different types of data that are at risk. This should include the backup tools, processes the team has in place, and available resources for responding to ransomware attacks. A typical Ransomware Response Plan should look like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Assessing the Attack Impact:</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When responding to a ransomware attack, the first step you should take is to assess how much of the data has been affected, and how many systems were breached. This is essential for implementing the next plan of action to address and mitigate the risk and further minimize the risk impact.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Disable Affected Systems</strong>:</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Once the affected systems have been identified, the next step is to disable them immediately. This is to prevent further escalation of the attack. You can disable them by shutting them down or disconnecting them from the network. Regardless of the route you take, you must act in a controlled manner, as opposed to making quick and rash decisions. In your plan, specify which systems will be disabled first, how they will be disabled, and which steps must be taken during disabling to ensure that the data isn’t damaged when your systems go offline.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Assess the Damage</strong>:</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you have addressed the attack and taken appropriate measures to neutralize the attack, you must then determine the extent of damage caused by the attack. Determine how much of your data was held for ransom, whether backups are available, and how recent they are. Your Ransomware Response Plan should assess if recovery plans exist for any backup data in hand. Ideally, you will have specific data recovery plans already in place that you can run quickly to recover the data.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Disclose the Attack</strong>:</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In some cases, there are compliance regulations that require you to disclose the attack. An example of this would be ransomware attacks that impact data and are defined as sensitive and require mandatory disclosure of the attacks, regardless of how much of the data is affected. Data that is not considered personal or sensitive generally does not require the disclosure of a breach. If it is required, follow the steps specified by the relevant regulatory framework to disclose the attack. Disclosure typically involves notifying the appropriate government authorities and individuals whose personal data was breached.</p>
<h3><strong>Tips for Preventing Ransomware Attack</strong></h3>
<p>Cybercriminals are finding new and more sophisticated ways of exploiting vulnerabilities and breaking into their systems. Because of this, it is important businesses take these basic steps to help avoid ransomware:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Never Open Suspicious Links</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Avoid clicking on links in spam messages or on unknown websites. Clicking malicious links may compromise your device by launching an application or infecting it, sometimes without you even knowing.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Avoid Disclosing Personal Information</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you receive a message, whether it be via text, call, or email, from an untrusted source requesting personal information, do not engage. Cybercriminals planning a ransomware attack may try to compromise your personal information in advance, which they will then use to tailor phishing messages specifically to you. If you have any reason to believe that the message is fake, contact the sender directly.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Do Not Open Suspicious Email Attachments</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Ransomware can also find its way to your device through email attachments so you should avoid opening any suspicious attachments. Ensuring the email is trustworthy by paying attention to the sender and checking that the address is correct.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Never Use Unknown USB Drives</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Never connect USB drives or any other storage media to your device if you are not sure where they came from. They may have been infected by cybercriminals and then left it in a public place to coerce someone into using it.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Keep Programs and Operating Systems Updated</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Updating programs and operating systems frequently will help to protect you from malware. When performing updates, take note of the latest security patches and make sure they are to your benefit. This makes it more difficult for cybercriminals to exploit vulnerabilities in your programs.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Use Only Trusted Download Sources</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>To minimize the risk of downloading ransomware, never download software or media files unless they are verified and trustworthy for download. Websites like this can be identified by trust seals. Make sure that the page you are visiting uses &#8220;HTTPS&#8221; instead of &#8220;HTTP&#8221;, or look for a shield or lock symbol in the address bar to also indicate it’s secure. Exercise caution when downloading anything to your mobile device outside of the Google Play Store or the Apple App Store.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Use A VPN on Public Wi-Fi Networks</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Try to avoid using public Wi-Fi networks altogether, but if you have no alternative, using a VPN is a protective measure against ransomware. Your device is more vulnerable to attacks when using a public Wi-Fi network.</p>
<h3><strong>Bottom Line</strong></h3>
<p>Securing sensitive information is the need of the hour for every business. An organization needs to establish appropriate security measures to prevent cyber-attacks like ransomware attacks. Be it any size business or industry, cyber-attacks are a huge threat and concern for all businesses. Even the most thorough strategy can’t guarantee that your data won’t be compromised by cyber threats like ransomware attacks.</p>
<p>Protecting the business requires that you follow <a href="https://guardiandigital.com/email-security-tips" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best practices</a> for prevention and designing a robust Ransomware Response Plan. Having a plan in place helps to respond quickly and effectively should ransomware strike. A strong Ransomware Response Plan in place will go a long way in ensuring secure data and better business continuity in the industry.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5095"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 144px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">4</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Advantages of Continuous Cybersecurity Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/the-advantages-of-continuous-cybersecurity-monitoring/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 11:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5073</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The advancement of digital technology benefits many individuals and businesses, &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/the-advantages-of-continuous-cybersecurity-monitoring/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The advancement of digital technology benefits many individuals and businesses, making communication, collaboration, and processes faster and more accessible. However, the biggest risk of using digital technology has something to do with cybersecurity.  Cyber-attacks, such as identity theft, ransomware, and malware, can be disruptive. For this reason, many individuals and companies install safety features in computer devices and software systems. But, cybersecurity isn&#8217;t just a one-time process and investment. The Cybersecurity process involves continuous monitoring and updating based on the evolved threat landscape.  Elaborating on this in detail below given are some reasons why continuous cybersecurity monitoring is essential and the benefits of it that are discussed below-</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Proactive Measures in an Evolving Threat Landscape</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Cybercriminals use sophisticated tools and tactics to lure their next prey. They use automation, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and data analytics to access business systems and security controls. When enterprises are not seen taking proactive security measures, cyber-attack is imminent.  The best way for enterprises to remain secure is to take proactive measures to strengthen security defenses by anticipating and preparing for potential cybersecurity vulnerabilities and attacks. Examples of these proactive cybersecurity measures include regularly monitoring business systems, identifying vulnerabilities, and preventing data and security breaches. <a href="https://netsurit.com/en-za/cape-town-cyber-security-services/">Netsurit&#8217;s cape town cyber security services</a> and other highly-trained IT security professionals can perform these advanced data protection services.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Detects Anomalies</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Continuous cybersecurity monitoring helps enterprises detect any kind of anomaly. Analyzing systems and data to define baseline security, determine deviations, and investigate inaccurate and inconsistent data and potential threats goes a long way in preventing a cyber-attack and data breach. Cybersecurity experts must constantly test and monitor processes to detect possible anomalies using data observability tools, leveraging artificial intelligence and machine learning to detect unexpected dataset changes.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Compliance with Regulations</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Cybersecurity experts are required to ensure that business systems comply with various data security, data privacy, and cybersecurity laws. For this, it requires constant monitoring of systems and networks on a real-time basis. Further, enterprises must also work towards building a system for alerts and notifications to stay ahead of potential cyber hackers and cyber threats. Constant testing of networks, executing strong access control measures, and establishing a comprehensive Information Security Policy not only helps comply with regulations but also prevent the possibility of breach and violation of regulations.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Improves Decision-Making Capability</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>A highly secure business has a better decision-making capability. Constant Monitoring helps identify the risk exposure to an enterprise. It helps in the decision-making when it comes to building a strong cybersecurity program for the enterprise. This also helps in preventing costly breaches and facing non-compliance penalties.  Even in terms of conducting training programs for employees and investing in secure IT Infrastructure, decision-making becomes a lot easier, when the organization is constantly monitoring and tracking systems, infrastructure, and the overall performance of employees.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Facilitates Resource Allocation</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>When it comes to resource allocation for building strong security systems, decision-making can be quite challenging. But with constant monitoring and tracking of systems and networks, and further classifying critical systems can make the resource allocation process easy.</p>
<p>Continuous cybersecurity monitoring helps facilitate proper resource allocation. Businesses will be much more confident in their decision-making when they are aware of their risk exposure and security status. Constant monitoring and tracking will help them build a robust cybersecurity program and also comply with various regulatory mandates. Further, it also gives the enterprise the confidence to allocate and focus their resources on their core business activities including production, sales, marketing, and customer service.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Avoids Business Delays and Disruptions</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If your business data is compromised, you run a huge risk of losing many customers. Many people don&#8217;t want to deal with companies that have reported <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/everything-you-need-to-know-about-gdpr-data-breach-fines-penalties/">data breach</a>es and have cyber-security problems. Businesses would face huge challenges in terms of delays and disruptions when this occurs.  However, to tackle these issues businesses need to develop and establish Business Continuity Plan which requires constant monitoring and training. Continuous cybersecurity monitoring entails being prepared to recover missing, lost, or damaged data to avoid business interruptions. It helps create and execute the backup plan and further prevents business delays and disruption in operations if the risks are detected and addressed in time.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Maintains Business Continuity</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>With the rapid shift from in-office to remote work settings, many companies invest in digital technology to automate processes for higher employee productivity and revenue. These businesses use project management systems for remote task assignments, third-party communication apps for virtual meetings, customer relationship management systems, and similar technologies.</p>
<p>Investing in relevant cybersecurity technologies, such as cloud security solutions, to maintain a remote or hybrid workplace for your company is essential. With robust and continuous cybersecurity monitoring, you can secure your apps, website, application programming interface (API), and infrastructure.  This further helps maintain business continuity.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Provides Peace of Mind</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Maintaining secure software programs can be challenging if you don&#8217;t have an IT security professional to perform continuous cybersecurity monitoring. Cybercriminals can easily target your company once they find your network and data security flaws. They can introduce malware into your business system to steal and trade your data and commit fraud.</p>
<p>Continuous cybersecurity monitoring can help detect immediate and adjacent threats that expose your business data to unauthorized people or entities. If you have a comprehensive and holistic cybersecurity solution in place, you will have assurance knowing that your network and data are safe and secure even after business hours.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong>Saves Time and Money </strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Ransomware attacks have become more prevalent. But only a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/edwardsegal/2022/10/14/only-30-of-surveyed-organizations-have-plans-for-responding-to-ransomware-crisis/?sh=3aca9a0a1db9">small percentage of surveyed organizations</a> have plans to respond to ransomware crises. This data is very alarming, considering the damage ransomware can cause to a company. Cybercriminals can ask for thousands or millions of dollars for a ransomware event. Victims are forced to pay a ransom to recover important data or business system operations. In the worst case, paying the money doesn&#8217;t assure companies that they&#8217;ll recover their data.</p>
<p>Before a similar situation happens to your business, it&#8217;s time to strengthen your network and data security through continuous monitoring. As cybercriminals have become more advanced in their tricks to lure their next prey, you must also enforce more stringent and intuitive security systems to stay ahead of your cybersecurity. Hire advanced cybersecurity services that can offer 24/7 cybersecurity monitoring using state-of-the-art tools and equipment. This step will help you prevent losing money or, in the worst case, bankruptcy or business closure.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<p>Cybersecurity monitoring plays a vital role in long-term data security and business continuity. Businesses can protect their network and data round the clock to avoid breaches and undue cyberattack exposure. Hiring the services of a cybersecurity company is crucial to ensure a continuous level of security protection for the entire business.  Establishing constant monitoring will not just help maintain a strong cybersecurity infrastructure but also help businesses evolve and build robust measures to deal with the evolving threat landscape.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5073"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 0px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <span class="kksr-muted">Rating</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important Trends in Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/important-trends-in-cybersecurity/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 08:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5065</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The cybersecurity industry is an ever-evolving landscape wherein businesses struggle &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/important-trends-in-cybersecurity/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The cybersecurity industry is an ever-evolving landscape wherein businesses struggle to keep up with the dynamic security and cyber-threat landscape. Due to unprecedented events such as the COVID-19 pandemic, evolving IoT landscape, and the newly evolved techniques of sophisticated cybercrimes, businesses are grappling to deal with the growing cyber threats.</p>
<p>This especially stands to be true, particularly in recent years, where we have witnessed significant alterations introduced by businesses in the <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/infrastructure-audit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IT infrastructure</a> in an effort to address the dynamic threat landscape. Threat actors and hackers often take advantage of such changes in the environment, and uncertainty of events. Targeting attacks, the hackers exploit vulnerabilities in the newly adopted security strategies, remote access, and cloud computing operations.</p>
<p>It definitely works out to be a daunting task for the security team to keep up with the growing attacks that are new and sophisticated in technique. Threats such as Ransomware, IoT threats, Supply Chain Attacks, Cloud Vulnerabilities, and Multi-vector Attacks have been increasingly impacting millions of businesses including large-scale businesses like Nvidia, Toyota Suppliers, Accenture, Acer, Apple, and Amazon to name a few. Today, we see a huge spike in the number of attacks and severity of cyber crimes prevailing in the industry.</p>
<p>Experts are predicting that global cybercrimes are going to increase and the cost for it is said to reach $10.5 trillion by 2025 which would be nearly up by 15% from $3 trillion in 2015. Being a part of this industry for more than two decades I strongly believe, understanding the evolving threats and proactively adapting to situations, and building strong measures is the key to preventing cyber-attacks. Covering more of this in detail, we have today in this article discussed some latest trends in the cybersecurity industry including the<a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/5-key-cybersecurity-threats-to-cloud-computing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> cybersecurity threats</a>, the latest technology, measures, and challenges in 2022.</p>
<h2><strong>Top Cybersecurity Threats in 2022</strong></h2>
<p>Cyber-attack is a series of malicious activities performed by threat actors or hackers with the intention to gain access to confidential and sensitive data or launch an attack with the intention to compromise systems and networks. Hackers adopt various techniques such as phishing, ransomware, malware, and/or social engineering tactics to commit cybercrime. Speaking of the year 2022, the below-given list of threats, top the rank when we list out the top cybersecurity threats in the year 2022.</p>
<h3><strong>      1.IoT Threats</strong></h3>
<p>Speaking of the IoT industry, there are no security standards or regulation that governs the way any developer or manufacturer builds a robust security measure around the device and/or network through which they access the cloud. While there are security best practices for secure usage of IoT, yet with no binding regulatory forces in place, there is no assured implementation of best practices and measures to prevent IoT threats. So, Cyber Attacks that are targeted toward an IoT device or network can be considered IoT threats.</p>
<p>The most common IoT threats that have been on the rise and should be addressed include IoT botnets, IoT ransomware, DNS threats, shadow IoT devices, and IoT physical security are some of the rising IoT threats in the industry that should be addressed. Exploiting the vulnerabilities in the IoT devices and network, the hacker can steal data or even infect the network to execute DoS or DDoS attacks.</p>
<h3><strong>   2.Ransomware Threat</strong></h3>
<p>The ransomware threat is probably the most common cyber threat prevailing in the industry. It is malware that either exposes or limits access to data or systems by encrypting the data or system functionality in general. While there are many strains of ransomware malware, some of the popular ones that have had a global impact include WannaCry, Cerber, Locky, Ryuk, Petya, NotPetya, and Cryptolocker to name a few. Cybercriminals often demand for monetary benefits in exchange for releasing systems or data with limited access.</p>
<h3><strong>  3.Supply Chain Attacks</strong></h3>
<p>Supply chain attack which is also known as a third-party software attack or value chain attack which is a kind of cyber-attack performed on an organization’s suppliers or third-party vendors. This is done to gain unauthorized access to the organization’s systems or data using malicious code to infiltrate an organization’s systems, and compromise systems and data. The industry has recently seen a huge spike in the growth of such attacks.</p>
<h3><strong>  4.Cloud Vulnerabilities</strong></h3>
<p>Businesses are increasingly moving towards adopting cloud and cloud-based services. So, this becomes the primary attack vector for an initial infiltration into an organization. Some of the most common cloud vulnerabilities or threats include the compromise of cloud consoles, compromise of cloud servers, container exploit by exploiting misconfiguration, and hybrid or multi-cloud attacks to name a few.</p>
<p>Since most organizations have yet not mastered and are still struggling to learn ways to secure all aspects of the cloud infrastructure. This learning phase has resulted in a huge spike of security gaps in storage, and console that has further resulted in compromise and maliciously establishing a presence in the target cloud infrastructure.</p>
<h3><strong>  5.API Threats</strong></h3>
<p>Application Programming Interface (API) is slowly gaining mainstream popularity in the software industry. However, the use of insecure API is resulting in attackers exploiting and leveraging the vulnerability. Threat actors are exploiting API vulnerabilities and configuration weaknesses that facilitate bypassing all security controls are resulting in the compromise and hacking of systems.</p>
<h3><strong> 6.Remote Service Threats</strong></h3>
<p>Remote service threats are attacks wherein the hacker exploits vulnerabilities in external remote services like Microsoft’s Remote Desktop Protocol (RDP) or Windows Server Message Block (SMB). Such services are usually vulnerable in a way that they are often misconfigured or not updated which provides an opportunity for criminals to exploit. Criminals get direct access to networks and systems that can be compromised. These types of attacks are rapidly growing and are also predicted to continue growing over the coming years.</p>
<h3><strong> 7.AI Threats</strong></h3>
<p>With AI now taking the mainstream in most industries and businesses, there is also a growing threat of increased AI threats staring at the industry. Some high-level risks and threats of AI technology include lack of privacy, lack of transparency, lack of security governance and mandates, biased algorithms, etc. all of which can have a huge impact on business and pose a huge cyber threat in the industry. Currently, the poorly regulated use of AI is a major threat to the industry from a security standpoint as there is no governance and regulation to implement security measures in the design and use of technology.</p>
<h2><strong>Top Trends in Cybersecurity 2022</strong></h2>
<h3><strong> 1.Multi-Factor Authentication</strong></h3>
<p>Multi-Factor Authentication is an added layer of security to any system and network. Currently, the industry is witnessing an increasing level of adoption of this security technique in most organizations. In fact, this technique is also outlined as security best practice in various international regulatory and payment standards like PCI DSS, GDPR, HIPAA, etc. MFA ensures organizations can enhance data security and control access.</p>
<h3><strong>2.Least Access Privilege Technique</strong></h3>
<p>Least Access Privilege is another popular and growing strategy adopted by most businesses that are bound by various regulatory and compliance standards. Often excessive privileges granted are seen as a huge security threat to organizations. Administrator-level permissions granted which include unrestricted access and potentially privileged accounts often result in unauthorized access which is a huge threat to an organization. These excessive permissions results in security incidents and breach. So, the least access privilege strategy is adopted by most of organizations as a best security practice and also as a mandate in most regulatory and compliance requirements that have also resulted in the development of the concept of the zero trust security model.</p>
<h3><strong>3.Cloud-Native Application Protection Platform (CNAPP)</strong></h3>
<p>Cloud-based infrastructure poses new and high-level security challenges for organizations. This requires organizations to focus on the implementation of cloud-based security solutions like Cloud Service Network Security (CSNS), Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM), and Cloud Workload Protection Platform (CWPP) solutions that facilitates an effective and efficient level of cloud security.</p>
<p>The Cloud-Native Application Protection Platforms (CNAPPs) are an integration of all of the cloud securities into a single holistic native cloud solution. With this, the organization can secure cloud-native applications across the entire application lifecycle. Organizations can implement this solution to address the cloud security and visible gaps, and simplify cloud security architectures.</p>
<h3><strong>4.AI in Cybersecurity</strong></h3>
<p>AI is now being increasingly adopted in the cybersecurity industry for tracing patterns, behaviour, and predictive activities within systems and networks to detect anomalies in systems and applications. The technology is harnessed to protect systems and establish security within the IT infrastructure of an organization. While we have witnessed the use of AI in financial services for fraud detection, it is now slowly being adopted in the cybersecurity industry for building a robust security solution for tracking monitoring, and altering unauthorized access, compromise, and other such anomalies in processes and operations within the IT Infrastructure.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>IT Infrastructure is a significant and integral part of an organization’s systems and business operations, so organizations must gear up to tackle the growing and evolving cyber threats in the industry. With the increasing sophistication of cybercrimes, organizations should plan and strategize robust preventive measures to tackle the growing threats in the industry.</p>
<p>For this, being abreast with the latest technology, cyber security trends and cyber threats is important for all businesses. Moreover, following the best security practices and IT hygiene is also crucial. With infrastructure security being so significant for an organization today, it is strongly recommended that organizations have in place a team of skilled and experienced cybersecurity professionals to address cybersecurity concerns. Further, we also strongly recommend investing in the best technology to build a stringent security system within the organization and ramp up the security game.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5065"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/open-source-intelligence/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Vulnerability Assessment]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5029</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[What is Open Source Intelligence? The term “open source” refers in particular to records this &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/open-source-intelligence/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong>What is Open Source Intelligence?</strong></h3>
<p>The term “open source” refers in particular to records this is publically available. A huge part of the internet cannot be found using major search engines. This is called as “Deep Web”. Deep Web is a mass of websites, databases, files, and more that cannot be indexed by Google, Bing, Yahoo, or any other search engine. Despite this, much of the content of the dark web can be considered open source because it is easily available to the public.</p>
<p>There is plenty of information available online that can be found using online tools other than regular search engines. Tools like Shodan can be used to find IP addresses, open ports, CCTV, printers, and everything else that is connected to the internet.</p>
<p>Information can be considered open source if it is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Published or broadcasted for a public audience like news</li>
<li>Available to the public by request for eg. census data</li>
<li>Available to the public by subscription or purchase</li>
<li>Could be seen or heard by any casual observer</li>
<li>Made available at a meeting open to the public</li>
<li>Obtained by visiting any place or attending any event that is open to the public</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>How is the Open Source Intelligence Used?</strong></h3>
<p>OSINT is widely used in:</p>
<h4><strong>      1.Ethical Hacking &amp; Penetration Testing</strong></h4>
<p>Security professionals use open-source intelligence to identify weaknesses in networks so that they can be remediated before they are exploited by hackers. Commonly found weaknesses include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Accidental leaks of sensitive information, like through <a href="https://www.recordedfuture.com/social-media-threat-intelligence/">social media</a></li>
<li>Open ports or unsecured internet-connected devices</li>
<li>Unpatched software, such as websites running old versions of CMS</li>
<li>Leaked or exposed assets<b>.</b></li>
</ul>
<h4>     <strong>2</strong>.<strong>Identifying External Threats</strong></h4>
<p>From identifying which new vulnerabilities are being actively exploited to intercepting threat actors about an upcoming attack, open source intelligence enables security professionals to prioritize their time to address the most significant current threats.</p>
<p>The fact that open-source intelligence is frequently combined with other intelligence categories, is one of the most crucial things to comprehend about. Open-source intelligence is frequently filtered and verified using information from closed sources like external intelligence-sharing forums and closed dark web communities. Analysts can carry out these tasks with the use of a variety of instruments.</p>
<h3><strong>The Dark Side of Open Source Intelligence</strong></h3>
<p>If security analysts can access everything, threat actors can do the same with ease. Threat actors use open-source intelligence tools and tactics to identify potential targets and exploit weaknesses in target networks. Attackers attempt to exploit a weakness once it has been identified to breach the target.</p>
<p>This procedure is the main cause of the high number of attacks on small and medium-sized businesses. It is not because threat actors target particular businesses; rather, it is because open-source intelligence tools can spot design flaws in a company&#8217;s network or website. Additionally, threat actors look for data about people and organizations that can be used to support complex social engineering campaigns utilizing <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/social-engineering-how-to-recognize-phishing-emails/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">phishing (email</a>), vishing (phone or voicemail), and Smishing (SMS). Sensitive information often published on social networks and blogs can be used to create social engineering campaigns that are very persuasive to convince individuals to compromise the network or assets of their company.</p>
<p>This is why it is crucial to use open-source intelligence for security objectives. It provides you a chance to identify and address network vulnerabilities in your company and delete critical data before threat actors utilize the same tools and strategies to take advantage of them.</p>
<h3><strong>Open Source Intelligence Techniques</strong></h3>
<p>The methodology to perform OSINT falls under two categories: Passive OSINT &amp; Active OSINT.</p>
<p><strong>Passive OSINT</strong> Threat Intelligence Platforms (TIPs) are frequently used in passive OSINT to aggregate several threat feeds into one convenient location. This issue is resolved by more sophisticated threat intelligence solutions, which automate the process of prioritizing and ignoring warnings in accordance with the unique requirements of a company. These solutions use artificial intelligence, machine learning, and natural language processing. Similar to this, organized threat groups frequently employ botnets to gather crucial data using methods like traffic sniffing and keylogging.</p>
<p><strong>Active OSINT</strong> is the use of a variety of techniques to search for specific insights or information. For security professionals, this type of collection work is usually done for one of two reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>A passively collected alert has highlighted a potential threat and further insight is required.</li>
<li>Used in <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/types-of-penetration-test/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Penetration Testing</a> exercise.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Open Source Intelligence Tools</strong></h3>
<p>While there are numerous free and practical tools available to security experts and threat actors alike search engines like Google are among the most often utilized open-source intelligence tools.</p>
<p>The frequency with which common, well-intentioned people unintentionally leave important assets and information exposed to the internet is one of the largest problems encountered by security experts. The data and assets they reveal can be found using a set of sophisticated search techniques known as &#8220;Google Dork&#8221; queries.</p>
<p>The Public Intelligence website offers a <a href="https://publicintelligence.net/feds-google-dorking/">more thorough rundown of Google dork queries</a>, below is an example of what a google dork query looks like:</p>
<p><strong><em><u>“sensitive but unclassified” filetype: txt publicintelligence.net”</u></em></strong></p>
<p>If you type this search term into a search engine, it returns only <strong>TXT documents</strong> from the Public Intelligence website that contain the words “<strong>sensitive but unclassified</strong>” somewhere in the document text. As you can imagine, with hundreds of commands at their disposal, security professionals and threat actors can use similar techniques to search for almost anything.</p>
<p>Beyond search engines, literally hundreds of technologies are available for locating network <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/types-of-vulnerability-assessment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vulnerabilities</a> or exposed assets.</p>
<p>There are a ton of free and paid programs with common features that may be used to search and analyze open-source data, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Metadata search</li>
<li>Code search</li>
<li>People and identity investigation</li>
<li>Phone number research</li>
<li>Email search and verification</li>
<li>Linking social media accounts</li>
<li>Image analysis</li>
<li>Geospatial research and mapping</li>
<li>Wireless network detection and packet analysis</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>WRAP UP!</strong></h3>
<p>All security disciplines can benefit greatly from open-source intelligence. It will take some time and some trial and error to find the best set of tools and methods for your particular needs. The tools and methods required to locate unsecured assets differ from those that will enable you to act on a threat alert. The presence of a clear strategy is the most crucial element in the success of any open-source intelligence endeavor. Once goals have been stated and objectives are clear, it will be much easier to find the best tools and methodologies.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5029"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 165px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">4.7</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">3</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things You Should Know About Your Privacy Online</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/things-you-should-know-about-your-privacy-online/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 11:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=5011</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Surveillance is becoming an increasingly standard component of modern life, &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/things-you-should-know-about-your-privacy-online/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surveillance is becoming an increasingly standard component of modern life, posing a threat to the idea that people have a <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/stories/2013/10/right-privacy-digital-age">right to privacy</a>. In many situations, we unwittingly provide companies with information about our preferences, routines, and interests.</p>
<p>In this age of digital era, you must not rely on evolving surveillance regulations and vendors to keep your personal information and security intact. From mobile devices to your online surfing and the IoT products installed in your homes potentially erode your privacy and personal security.</p>
<p>This includes the potential for your privacy to be sold to third parties for marketing purposes. At every step in the data lifecycle—from collection to storage to analysis—users are always concerned about protecting their personal information. Furthermore, most people do not trust businesses to manage the personal information they obtain responsibly.</p>
<p>The concern of sharing information applies to various online websites and services, including paying bills online, checking in at the airport, joining a club, and so on. A significant amount of your personal information is already in circulation, and there is no guarantee that it will always be utilized in the most honest, ethical, or legal manner possible.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s walk you through some vital aspects you need to know about your privacy online.</p>
<h3>Privacy online: 5 Things you must know</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5012" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/How-to-Protect-Your-Privacy-V2.png" alt="How to protect your privacy" width="1954" height="1139" /></p>
<p><a href="https://bloom.co/blog/how-to-protect-your-privacy-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source</a></p>
<p>You are in charge of taking all necessary steps to protect the privacy of your personal information. Raising awareness is the first step toward <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/top-6-internet-safety-rules-what-not-to-do-online/">safety</a>, even though it is a complex topic.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s look more into the nature of the information about you that circulates online, how others access this information, and the measures you must take to protect it.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">1. Why do you need to care about online privacy laws?</h3>
<p>Consumers are subjected to data breaches and invasions of privacy regularly. There is so much private data that is already in circulation and isn&#8217;t necessarily utilized in the most open and accountable manner.</p>
<p>Most people admit that they are not constantly vigilant about paying attention to the privacy rules and terms of service they often see, even while the public expresses concern about various digital privacy issues. Your information is being saved continuously and probably used for undesirable purposes. It is possible to deduce a lot about you based on apparently unimportant data, including the places you like and the things you buy.</p>
<p>Many businesses benefit by tracking the online activities of their consumers and clients. Consumers must know the ins and outs of data collection, processing, and dissemination to make educated choices and appreciate data for its worth.</p>
<p>Although stricter privacy settings are helpful, they are not a substitute for the protections afforded by law—several states in the US have enacted legislation relating to online privacy. California has been leading among states in ensuring citizen privacy for some time now. California took the lead in enforcing policies to protect user privacy in the early days of the modern internet when many sites still used sneaky methods to gather information without informing users beforehand. <a href="http://www.osano.com/articles/california-privacy-laws-ccpa-cpra">Osano explains the CPRA</a> (California privacy rights act)—which put the state at the forefront of efforts to give consumers more say over the corporations&#8217; use of their personal information.</p>
<h3>2. What Personal Information about you is Easily Accessible Online?</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5013" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/personal-information.jpg" alt="Personal Information" width="429" height="280" /></p>
<p><a href="https://feelbeautiful.com/about/privacy-policy/">Source</a></p>
<p>The information accessible online that service providers, websites, and retailers collect from users is mainly categorized into two kinds.</p>
<p><strong>Personally Identifiable Information (PII)</strong>—Your name, address, banking credentials, and even the physical location from which you use the internet—on your home computer, a tablet, or smartphone, are all examples of personally identifiable information (PII).</p>
<p><strong>Non-Personally-Identifiable Information (NPII)</strong> — this data is collected when A website counts how many visitors it attracts daily or what site content users click on the most. The website in question is concerned not with its members&#8217; activities but with how they behave as a group. This information is less ominous.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. How is privacy impacted?</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5016" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/privacy-impacted.png" alt="privacy impacted" width="720" height="236" /></p>
<p><a href="https://medium.com/@cre8tivemediaservices/how-the-digital-age-is-impacting-our-personal-privacy-695326dd1455">Source</a></p>
<p>Our privacy is compromised in several ways while we are online. A few of them here include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Theft of Individual Identity</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Fraudsters impersonate someone else by using their private details and information. Someone is creating fake accounts on your behalf and using them to perpetrate fraud or damage your reputation. Identity theft is now the most pressing issue in terms of privacy protection.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Spying and snooping</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Spying, or snooping, refers to secretly acquiring information about another person. Spy agencies now have an easier time tracking our digital footprint because of the explosion of social networking sites. Because of our insatiable curiosity about social media, we tend to share private information about ourselves.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Dangers of data privacy and information mishandling</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The internet is often used to disseminate and collect information from various sources. One reason is the ease and speed with which information is transferred through the internet. When we connect to a network and exchange data, we do it according to a predetermined set of protocols.</p>
<p>Snoopers intercept our data in transit without adequate network security and relay it to the intended destination, unmodified and unencrypted. Many of the data and information they access will be misused by these individuals. This leads to a breach of privacy when sensitive information is improperly managed.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Website monitoring</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Multiple online platforms facilitate the completion of our tasks—you&#8217;ve probably noticed that certain websites need you to have cookies enabled to access their content. A cookie is a small text file used by websites to remember information about the user—such as the user&#8217;s preferences or authentication details. Some websites are authentic, while others are fraudulent or legitimate but use the information they acquire fraudulently or legitimately. Because of this, personal information is exposed.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">4. Types of online privacy invasion threats</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5017" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/online-privacy-threats.jpg" alt="Online Privacy Threats" width="480" height="320" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.hotspotshield.com/blog/the-6-biggest-online-privacy-threats/">Source</a></p>
<p>Online privacy is often compromised with small and big negligence. The most common negligence is easy to determine. Let&#8217;s delve into the most common problems.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Web surfing without security</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When you click on a link or conduct a search online, your default browser establishes a connection to the World Wide Web—occasionally, you even save credentials there.</p>
<p>Malicious add-ons, advertisements, and other forms of cyber assault are prevalent. There is often an overlap between security and privacy issues. Companies and scammers learn a lot about you through your browsing habits.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Poor password practices</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>One of the vital risks to your privacy is creating simple and easy-to-guess passwords—the most common reason for large-scale data breaches is the careless reuse of old, insecure passwords. This is because it makes it easier for hackers to get into many accounts simultaneously and commit financial or identity fraud.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Cyber-attacks</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Passwords and settings that are too easy to crack are prime targets for hackers. Hackers will use technical and psychological means to take advantage of your preferences and routines. They steal your personal information by sending you deceptive emails, texts, and phone calls. Most of their assaults use malware specifically designed to intercept sensitive information. Then they&#8217;ll come back later—either steal your money, hack your account, or otherwise harm you differently.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Oversharing</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The proliferation of online and social media platforms has simplified meeting new people and broadening one&#8217;s social circle—its unintended consequence is often overlooked.  Predators will locate you if you provide too much personal information online. Potential attackers get insight into your habits, relationships, and assets if you publicly share recordings of your possessions or information about your journey plans.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Easy steps to protect your privacy online</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5018" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/How-to-Maintain-Your-Privacy-Online.png" alt="Maintain Your privacy online" width="1000" height="573" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/how-to-maintain-your-privacy-online/">Source</a></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Create a strong password</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Avoid using your birthdate or other easily-accessible passwords. Pick a combination of lowercase and uppercase letters, numerals, and symbols and change them regularly.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Check site security</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Check your browser with an &#8220;HTTPS&#8221; URL and a lock symbol while entering personal information. The website&#8217;s privacy policy, contact information, or a &#8220;certified secure&#8221; logo indicates trustworthiness.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Avoid fake posts</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Don&#8217;t open links in unsolicited emails offering surveys, work-from-home employment, or money-making opportunities. Search for the company name or the person&#8217;s name plus the word &#8220;scam&#8221;—if it&#8217;s a scam, someone must have likely reported it.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Use legitimate browsers</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Use browsers like Safari, Firefox, or Chrome that have a private surfing mode. When you enable private browsing, your browser won&#8217;t record or send any of your activity to third-party sites or services.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Use added protections</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Use an anti-virus, firewall, and anti-spyware software to keep your data safe. Never provide your home address or credit card details online unless you are sure the site is safe and encrypted. Cyber insurance is something to think about—it protects you and your loved ones in the event of a <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/cyber-attack-vectors-and-how-to-avoid-them/">cyberattack</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Regularly update your OS, browser, etc.</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Always use the latest versions of your preferred web browser, operating system, and mobile device software. Updated software often includes solutions for known issues and improved security measures. Attackers and hackers have found several ways to circumvent the security of earlier releases.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Wrapping up</h3>
<p>There are several factors to consider regarding privacy online. Privacy breaches happen, but most websites gather data to enhance user experience and grow commerce, not to trick you.</p>
<p>Now that you thoroughly understand your privacy online and its dangers, you must <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/how-to-protect-yourself-and-detect-credit-card-fraud/">protect yourself</a> against fraud by taking measures that let you manage your online privacy and personal data. Even performing the basics—using a reputable anti-virus, upgrading your browser and OS, strengthening your passwords, and turning on two-factor authentication—will make your accounts safer.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="5011"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 0px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <span class="kksr-muted">Rating</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthen Your SaaS Security with SaaS Ops</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/strengthen-your-saas-security-with-saas-ops/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4985</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[What exactly is SaaS Security? Many organizations have multi-cloud setups, &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/strengthen-your-saas-security-with-saas-ops/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><b>What exactly is SaaS Security?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many organizations have multi-cloud setups, with the average corporation employing services from at least five cloud providers. Compatibility problems, contract breaches, non-secured APIs, and misconfigurations are among the security hazards cloud computing brings, which is popular.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS configurations are an attractive target for cybercriminals because they store a large amount of sensitive data, such as payment card details and personal information. Consequently, enterprises need to emphasize the importance of SaaS security. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS security includes techniques companies use to secure their assets while employing SaaS architecture. According to the </span><a href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UK&#8217;s National Cyber Security Centre </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">(NCSC), SaaS security rules, the client and the service provider or software distributor must share security responsibilities. Moreover, service providers offer SaaS Security Posture Management (SSPM) solutions that automate and manage SaaS security.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As SaaS usage and adoption continue to increase, so does the</span><a href="https://www.vendr.com/blog/saas-security"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> SaaS security</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> problem. The top SaaS security issues are misconfigurations, access management, compliance, data storage, retention, privacy and data breaches, and disaster recovery.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is easy to believe that protecting SaaS only prevents users from accessing the internet. However, securing SaaS usage is far more challenging than it initially appears.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact is that there is no universal, all-encompassing SaaS security checklist. Businesses vary; they perform distinct tasks, operate differently, and have specific needs. </span><a href="https://www.zluri.com/blog/saas-operations/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Check out this article by Zluri</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h3><b>Why is SaaS Security a priority?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many firms are familiar with IaaS and PaaS security threats. IT and security teams frequently communicate through linked business processes and applications. IaaS and PaaS management and security technologies are also widespread.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.leanix.net/en/wiki/saas/saas-security"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS security can safeguard</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a corporation from cyberattacks and data leaks. Any SaaS company should take security precautions to secure its data, assets, and reputation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS programs work differently and provide advantages to businesses. However, they can be more difficult to administer from a security standpoint:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The design of SaaS applications supports a range of teams inside a business. For example, Record systems are utilized for client data by sales teams, source code by development teams, and HR information by HR teams. Such SaaS apps are typically used regularly by many end-users with varying degrees of technical expertise. </span><a href="https://www.zluri.com/blog/saas-management-challenges"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS apps are challenging to understand due to their volume and complexity.</span></a></p>
<h4><b>Communication:</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is limited communication between security teams and the business administrators who pick and manage new SaaS technology. Limited team contact makes it more challenging for security teams to identify the breadth of use and related dangers when fully operating apps.</span></p>
<h4><b>Collaboration:</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The internal teams supporting SaaS services typically lack the requisite advice to safeguard them. Constant communication is necessary for balancing business and security requirements. To maintain consistency, enterprises should invest more resources and effort in identifying and addressing security issues and treat SaaS like bare metal, IaaS, PaaS, and endpoint security. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">The security problems that SaaS users face</span></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/risk-and-resilience/our-insights/securing-software-as-a-service"><span style="font-weight: 400;">McKinsey surveyed cybersecurity specialists</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from over 60 firms to understand how they handled SaaS security concerns. Most respondents said they had increased their attention on SaaS security, highlighting their and their providers&#8217; security offerings.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As expected, Chief Information Security Officers (CISOs) were frustrated by suppliers&#8217; security deficiencies. They complained about contractual and implementation delays and customer-centric security. They wanted SaaS companies to enable security experts to understand product security and set up and integrate them more simply.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most respondents used SaaS for IT service management and office automation. But, given the dangers, several CISOs said their firms weren&#8217;t ready for SaaS in essential areas. Resource planning software was deemed too risky since downtime may cripple the company. Due to data confidentiality, companies hesitated to utilize SaaS for health-related or mergers-and acquisitions applications.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With more complex technologies like AI, cyberattacks become more sophisticated. For this reason, you must regularly review your SaaS security procedures. Listed here are the eight most prevalent SaaS security concerns, in case you are unfamiliar with them. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Management of Identity and Access</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A CISO establishing a SaaS application security strategy must include access management as one of the fundamental foundations. However, if not done precisely, it can create a security hole that allows an attacker to enter. </span></p>
<p><strong>Single Sign-On</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Examples of successful &#8216;Identity and Access Management (IAM) strategies implemented by SaaS companies include Single Sign-On (SSO) and Secure Web Gateways (SWG). With SSO, the user must log in once to access all linked services inside a single ecosystem. However, if the provider has a secure access mechanism, SSO might introduce SaaS security problems, as it enables simple tracking of ID and password and access to multiple services. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Virtualization</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most SaaS services utilize </span><a href="https://www.ibm.com/cloud/blog/5-benefits-of-virtualization"><span style="font-weight: 400;">virtualization</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because it provides more uptime than conventional computers. Nonetheless, if a single virtual machine is hacked, numerous parties may have problems since data is copied across servers. Virtualization has substantially improved mobile app security over the years, but there are still vulnerabilities that hackers are likely to exploit. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Obscurity</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The SaaS model concentrates on application and business continuity while the service providers make infrastructure and architecture decisions. Occasionally, these suppliers withhold crucial back-end information, a significant red flag. CISOs should hold one-on-one meetings with service providers and inquire about their security measures. Remember that you must select a service that can provide adequate responses on data security.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Accessibility</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Suitable SaaS applications are available from any location. This benefit, however, might soon become negative if the devices accessing the application are infested with viruses and malware. In addition, if the user accesses the application over a public WiFi network or VPN, it might pose a security risk to your infrastructure. Therefore, CISOs should prioritize safeguarding all endpoints to prevent such threats. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, the NHS (National Health Service) is a publicly financed healthcare institution established in the United Kingdom. The system contains voluminous sensitive data, such as patients&#8217; health information, physicians&#8217; information, pharmaceutical data, etc. Therefore, protecting every endpoint was essential. The university then cooperated with Cisco, which helped build the SecureX unified security platform. This technology protects the NHS&#8217;s highly targeted PII (Personally Identifiable Information) against internet thieves. It also allows users to protect data from phishing attempts, ransomware, data exfiltration, etc. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Data Control</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With SaaS, all data is stored and managed on the cloud, leaving you little control over data storage and management. If you have a problem, you are relying on the service providers. Before signing a contract, ask the SaaS provider about data storage patterns, security measures, and disaster recovery processes. After receiving positive responses, you can form a partnership with the supplier. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">6. Misconfigurations</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS apps are renowned for incorporating several complex features into a single solution. However, they add complexity to the code and increase the likelihood of misconfigurations. Even a little coding error might influence the availability of your cloud services. In one of the most disastrous misconfigurations of 2008, a Pakistani Telecom application attempted to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> restrict YouTube </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">for legal reasons. However, in trying to block YouTube, they established a dummy route that resulted in misconfigurations, resulting in YouTube being unavailable worldwide for two hours. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Disaster Restoration</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless of the security procedures, you employ to protect your application, server, infrastructure, and data; there is always the possibility of a disaster since the future is unpredictable. CISOs should ask suppliers of SaaS security solutions: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the event of a catastrophe, what happens to all cloud-stored data?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you ensure complete data recovery?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you include catastrophe recovery in your service-level agreement?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How long will it require to retrieve and restore the data? </span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">5 Ways to Strengthen your SaaS Security with SaaS Ops</span></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4986" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/SaaS-security.png" alt=" SaaS Security with SaaS Ops" width="1200" height="627" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.simform.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/SaaS-security.png"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source</span></a></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Develop Real-time Security Observability and Ongoing System Monitoring</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to the dynamic infrastructure, changes in SaaS settings tend to occur often, and this has instantaneous effects, and influence on many resources. Running a SaaS infrastructure without real-time security monitoring and observability is equivalent to flying blind. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">     2.Configure and Constantly Monitor Configuration Settings</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The SaaS landscape is constantly evolving. Since services are frequently launched and withdrawn in real time, configuring them correctly and monitoring settings can help you secure your customers&#8217; data. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">    3.Utilize Operations Theory for Security</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practical operations principles may address tech sprawl, lack of integration between tool sets, lack of visibility, and operations running at the speed of business without security checks. Remember, &#8220;Great ops = great security.&#8221; </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">    4.Protect Data</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Storing unencrypted data on the cloud might expose your business to reputational harm, revenue loss, and customer loss. Encryption is one of the simplest and the most effective methods for securing client information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obtain</span><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Compliance &amp; Regulatory Consulting Services</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> IT Audits, Risk &amp; Security Management solutions, and training programs that meet the industry&#8217;s Regulatory Compliance and Information Security problems.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">   5.Measure &amp; Enhance Performance</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a method for measuring performance, you can examine the impact of infrastructure modifications. Consequently, you may accomplish the constant security and performance enhancements essential for enhancing client relationships.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that you have a better grasp of the SaaS data security landscape, let&#8217;s examine the measures you can take to secure this at your organization: </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Document your Data Processing Actions</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regarding SaaS data security, RoPA is only one starting point. RoPA stands for Record of your Processing Activities, a requirement of the GDPR. You are compelled by law to comply with this requirement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider this an overview of all of your data processing procedures. It is a single document detailing your company&#8217;s data processing activities. Some examples of personal information processing activities include marketing, human resources, and third-party operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is vital not just because the GDPR needs it but also because it assists organizations with self-auditing. If you keep track of and comprehend your data processing operations, you will be in the greatest position to implement data security.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After all, you cannot manage risks without first identifying them, correct? </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Establish Authentication Methods and Necessitate a Formidable Password</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Implementing appropriate access controls is one of the most critical measures to reduce the likelihood of a data breach. The first line of defense in this regard is a </span><a href="https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32040?hl=en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">strong password.</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whenever a user establishes an account, you must ensure that they choose a secure and effective password, which should contain a combination of uppercase and lowercase letters, numbers, and special characters. Do not permit the use of clearly identifiable terms as passwords.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Verify that you do not depend solely on passwords to grant access to an individual&#8217;s account. Multi-factor authentication necessitates completing more than one step before admittance is granted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Several more alternatives are available, such as requiring the user to enter a code provided to their cell phone or doing facial verification. It depends on the software you give and the individuals utilizing it. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Educate both your Consumers and your Staff</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Education is essential for data security. You must do all your power to ensure that everyone using your program has the security expertise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that 94% of businesses have had an insider data breach? While a few of these incidents may have been caused by malevolent employees, the great majority have been the consequence of unintended employee acts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If they had received training on data security, this event might never have occurred.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The issue is that many companies are only concerned with the expense and resources associated with training. Nonetheless, it is crucial to calculate how much money you would lose if you were the victim of a data breach.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition, you must ensure that you are simultaneously teaching your clients. According to Gartner, customers will be accountable for</span><a href="https://www.gartner.com/smarterwithgartner/why-cloud-security-is-everyones-business"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 95%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of cloud security breaches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether releasing critical upgrades to existing clients or onboarding new ones, you must actively inform them how their activities affect security.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A growing number of SaaS companies are transitioning to cloud-based infrastructures. The great majority of customers are unaware of the ramifications of this decision. Educating your customers on how to secure their data is essential to reduce the likelihood of a security breach. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Continuously Monitor User Responsibilities and Access</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to the topics we&#8217;ve already discussed, you must continue to monitor division of duties (SOD) infractions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SaaS applications are developed using initialized roles. However, as time passes, these roles and the users may get confused, leading to SOD violations, and it can be a significant compliance burden.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To prevent SOD breaches, you must regularly monitor people and their assigned roles. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Employ a Cybersecurity Company</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are having trouble with SaaS data security, you should contact a </span><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cybersecurity company</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with experience in this field. Security is a challenging subject to master. On the other hand, you cannot afford to cut shortcuts since doing so might result in your company suffering a data breach, which could cost you hundreds or millions of dollars!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A good cybersecurity company can do a vulnerability assessment and even provide services such as penetration testing. This is ethical hacking if you have never heard the term before. It suggests that someone with good intentions will hack into your system before someone with malicious purpose. This will notify you of any software vulnerabilities so that you may make the necessary modifications.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Numerous aspects must be considered while searching for a reputable cybersecurity company. You want a corporation with a solid reputation and extensive industry expertise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Concerning experience, you should not only seek a company with a substantial number of years under its belt, but you should also ensure that they have extensive expertise dealing with SaaS organizations.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4987" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Principles-of-SaaS-Security.png" alt="Principles of saas security" width="1434" height="924" /></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tips for SaaS security</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> These</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> strategies can protect SaaS environments and assets.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.Authentication Strengthening</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud providers handle authentication differently, making it challenging to decide how customers should access SaaS applications. Some manufacturers support customer-managed identity providers like Active Directory (AD) with SAML, OpenID Connect, and Open Authorization. Some providers allow multifactor authentication. Some don&#8217;t.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The security team must know which services are used and the alternatives each service supports to manage SaaS products. This context allows administrators to choose the proper authentication method(s).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the SaaS provider supports it, a single sign-on (SSO) connected to AD ensures that account and password policies match the application&#8217;s services.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Encryption of Data</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The channels that interface with SaaS apps use Transport Layer Security (TLS) to secure data in transit. Some SaaS suppliers offer data-at-rest encryption. This feature may be defaulted or activated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investigate each SaaS service&#8217;s security procedures to discover if data encryption is possible and activate it if so. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.Oversight and Vetting</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Review and examine any prospective SaaS provider (as you would with other vendors). Make sure you know how the service is used, its security model, and any extra security precautions. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.Discovery and Inventory</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tracking all SaaS usage is essential as usage patterns might be unpredictable, especially when apps are quickly launched. Ensure you hunt for fresh, untracked SaaS use and be watchful for changes. When possible, combine human and automatic data collection to keep up with growing SaaS consumption and maintain a reliable, up-to-date inventory of services and users. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Cloud Access Protection Broker (CASB) tools</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider employing a CASB solution when the SaaS provider does not provide enough security. CASB allows organizations to build SaaS-unique controls. Examine the SaaS provider&#8217;s security issues. You should also know the CASB deployment choices so you may choose the suitable configuration (API or proxy-based) for your organization&#8217;s architecture. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Situational Awareness</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Review data from CASBs and the SaaS provider&#8217;s data and logs to monitor SaaS consumption. IT and security directors must treat SaaS products differently from conventional websites since they are complex tools requiring the same degree of protection as any business application.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adopting SaaS security best practices with systematic risk management provides consumer and enterprise SaaS security. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Utilize SaaS Security Posture Management (SSPM)</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SSPM ensures SaaS apps remain secure. An SSPM system monitors SaaS applications for gaps between declared security policy and actual security posture, allowing you to automatically detect and repair security vulnerabilities in SaaS assets and prioritize risk severity.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4988" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/SaaS-Security-Posture-Management.png" alt="SaaS Security Posture Management" width="1434" height="1076" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.simform.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/SaaS-Security-Posture-Management.png"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To summarize, we can say that </span><a href="https://www.zluri.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">many businesses rely on SaaS applications to perform mission-critical operations.</span> </a><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hence they must give the security measures around SaaS the same level of importance as those surrounding other technologies. It is possible to maintain the security of your data and the seamless operation of your business by continuously monitoring your SaaS environment, fixing misconfigurations as soon as they are discovered, and maintaining a tight check on third-party access to your systems.</span></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4985"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">2</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PCI DSS Readiness Assessment</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-readiness-assessment/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 10:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[PCI DSS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4971</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The PCI Council has set a robust framework comprising a &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/pci-dss-readiness-assessment/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The PCI Council has set a robust framework comprising a comprehensive set of requirements for enhancing the security of payment card data. So, prior to performing the final PCI DSS Audit, most Level 1 Merchants conduct a PCI Readiness Assessment. This is to validate the effectiveness of their security implementation and the readiness for the final audit. In fact, Level 2-4 Merchants who are required to fill out a Self-Assessment Questionnaire (PCI SAQ) are also recommended to conduct a Readiness Assessment.</p>
<p>Performing a PCI DSS Readiness Assessment helps build a baseline for organizations like you to ensure your efforts are well aligned for achieving compliance. The process uncovers the weak cyber defenses and helps your organization know whether you are ready for a full <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/pci-dss-audit-certification-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS Audit</a> or Self-Assessment.</p>
<p>Covering more on this in detail, we have shared some reasons why we consider PCI DSS Readiness Assessment important. But, before that let us understand what PCI DSS Readiness Assessment is and the other details related to the assessment process.</p>
<h3><strong>What is PCI DSS Readiness Assessment?</strong></h3>
<p>PCI DSS Readiness Assessment is a kind of gap analysis that is often performed just prior to undergoing the final PCI DSS Compliance Audit. The Readiness Assessment is an evaluation process wherein the auditor tests and verifies whether or not all the processes and implementation of PCI DSS Requirements are in place. The assessment helps your organization determine gaps in the systems, and processes concerning PCI DSS Compliance. The report of the assessment further recommends the implementation of appropriate controls to meet the PCI Requirements. Performing a PCI DSS Readiness Assessment is a proactive way of improving the compliance standard and implementation process.</p>
<p>The assessment helps your organization understand the key areas of weakness and respond to rapidly evolving security compliance obligations. Further, such assessment helps your team in the decision-making in terms of developing a strategy and planning out the process of implementing necessary requirements in alignment with PCI DSS Compliance. So, to put it simply the PCI DSS Readiness Assessment is an effective method for determining and fixing compliance gaps. The assessment goes a long way in simplifying the compliance process and reducing the long terms expenses relating to non-compliance.</p>
<h3><strong>Importance of PCI DSS Readiness Assessment</strong></h3>
<p>Every organization that handles cardholder data is expected to comply with PCI DSS. So, organizations are strongly recommended that prior to the final PCI DSS Audit they run a quick Readiness Assessment to check whether or not the necessary requirements of compliance are met.  This is usually seen as a proactive initiative and a standard of best practice for organizations who plan for PCI DSS Compliance. Given below are some of the benefits of performing a readiness assessment before a formal PCI DSS Audit.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Strengthens Security</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>PCI DSS Readiness Assessment helps identify weaknesses in systems and processes. This allows your organization to fix the gaps and improve their security measures. So, with this step in place, your organization also has better chances of reducing the potential risk of security breaches. So, PCI DSS Readiness Assessment will not just ensure PCI Compliance but also help strengthen the security systems and measures within your organization.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Reduces the Possibility of Breach</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>PCI DSS was designed to protect payment cardholder data and secure the business process of payment transactions. So, achieving PCI DSS compliance reduces the possibility of a data breach. Although it is important to understand that achieving and maintaining PCI compliance does not guarantee the prevention of data breaches.</p>
<p>But it definitely helps to substantially decrease the risk. Performing the Readiness Assessment allows your organization to evaluate and verify whether or not they can achieve PCI DSS Compliance. So, considering PCI DSS Readiness assessment is essential to ensure your organization achieves PCI DSS Compliance.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Prevents Hefty Fines</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>PCI Readiness Assessment lets your organization know whether or not you are compliant and your security implementation is in alignment with the PCI requirements. It allows your organization to fix gaps and meet compliance requirements before the final PCI audit.</p>
<p>This way the assessment prevents your organization from being non-compliant and reduces the possibility of fines and penalties for not complying with PCI DSS Standard. Generally speaking, if you do not meet the PCI requirements, your business will be liable for paying considerable fines and penalties for non-compliance. Further, in case of a data breach, the penalty may quickly add up for you causing substantial financial loss in terms of the cost of investigation and expenses for the loss of customers due to the event of a breach.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Improved Customer Relationship</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Performing the Readiness Assessment helps your organizations meet the PCI Requirements and clear the final audit for achieving PCI DSS Compliance. Further, achieving compliance will not just help your organization tick off your obligation towards meeting the <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/12-requirements-of-pci-dss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI requirements</a>, but also help you in building a sense of confidence among customers.</p>
<p>Knowing that your organization is PCI DSS Compliant, it definitely boosts the customer confidence in your business. It shows that your organization is committed to safeguarding your sensitive card data and personal data by taking proactive measures to protect them. This definitely goes a long way in building credibility for your business in the market and improving customer relationships.</p>
<h4><strong>Compliance with other Regulation</strong></h4>
<p>Complying with PCI requirements by implementing necessary security measures does not just ensure compliance with PCI DSS but also prepares your business to comply with other regulations as well. This way your organization will also be able to identify ways to improve the <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/infrastructure-audit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IT infrastructure</a> and enhance its security.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/book-free-compliance-consultation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-4915 size-full" src="https://www.vistainfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Unlock-the-key-to-a-successful-POPUP-AD-6-06-2.png" alt="pci dss readiness assessment" width="1070" height="543" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>How does PCI Readiness Assessment help organizations in the PCI DSS Audit?</strong></h3>
<p>PCI DSS Readiness Assessment can benefit your organization if you are planning to undergo the final PCI Audit. The assessment ensures a smooth audit and compliance process for your organization. Elaborating more on this here are some ways how the readiness assessment can help your organizations in their PCI DSS Audit.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Compliance Strategy &amp; Decision Making</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>PCI Readiness Assessment reports help your organizations in their decision-making process related to <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/pci-dss-audit-certification-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCI DSS compliance</a>. The assessment highlights the key areas that need to be addressed and recommendations to fix those gaps. So, those planning to undergo the final PCI DSS Audit must surely consider undergoing the readiness assessment to evaluate and take the right decision concerning compliance.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Verifies the Effectiveness of Systems, Processes &amp; Controls</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The effectiveness of Systems, Processes &amp; Controls plays a key role in achieving PCI DSS Compliance. The Readiness Assessment allows your organization to evaluate and verify the effectiveness of the existing controls established and highlight areas that need to be fixed. Based on the outcome of the assessment, your organization can improve the existing process and controls to meet the requirements.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Identifies Weaknesses in Systems &amp; Processes</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>More than often organizations fail in their PCI DSS Audit due to the gaps identified in systems, processes, and controls. There is always a possibility of certain gaps being overlooked by the internal audit team during the internal audit assessment.</p>
<p>Such gaps can result in failure of the PCI DSS audit and compliance. For these reasons, organizations are recommended to conduct a quick readiness assessment to identify such gaps and fix them before the final audit. Depending on the outcome of the assessment and the weakness highlighted in the report, organizations can implement additional controls as per the PCI requirements and fix the gaps accordingly.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Recommendations to Fix Gaps</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Recommendation to fix the gaps in systems and processes is a critical aspect of the Readiness Assessment Report. Based on the risk exposure and gaps identified, auditors provide a list of recommendations to address the issue in the report. These reports and recommendations work as a guide for organizations to improve their systems, processes, and implementation and additionally fix the identified compliance gaps.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4><strong>Prevents PCI DSS Audit Failure</strong></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>PCI DSS Audit failure can be an expensive affair for your business. Non-compliance to PCI DSS will not just attract hefty fines from banks, but also in case of a data breach, it may result in the canceling of license for card transactions by the credit card brand, especially if the impact of the breach is significant. So, just to prevent the consequences of such audit failures, organizations are recommended to perform a readiness assessment prior to the final PCI DSS Audit. The Readiness Assessment verifies whether or not the organization meets the 12 requirements of PCI DSS compliance. This in turn helps the organization fix the gaps identified and prevents the possibility of an audit failure.</p>
<h3><strong>Key Takeaway </strong></h3>
<p>Complying with standards like PCI DSS can be expensive, tedious, and time-consuming. But to make the process easy, we strongly recommend you conduct PCI DSS Readiness Assessment. This makes your compliance journey much easier and more efficient. It helps your organization make an informed decision in your compliance process and implementation.</p>
<p>The assessment streamlines the process and makes your organization compliance-ready.  So, before you plan to undergo the final PCI Audit consider performing a readiness assessment by an experienced auditor like us (VISTA InfoSec) to guide you through the process and help you stay ahead in the journey of PCI compliance proactively.</p>
<p>VISTA InfoSec is a global <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cyber security consulting firm</a> and a PCI Council qualified PCI QSA, PCI QPA offering end-to-end PCI DSS solution. For any doubts or queries pertaining to PCI DSS Readiness Assessment, you can contact us or drop us a mail at <strong>askus[@]vistainfosec.com</strong></p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4971"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to Hire a Red Team Assessor for the IT Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/reasons-to-hire-a-red-team-assessor-for-the-it-infrastructure/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Narendra Sahoo]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 05:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Red Team Assessment]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4962</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Red team assessors are professional hackers who are hired to &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/reasons-to-hire-a-red-team-assessor-for-the-it-infrastructure/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Red team assessors are professional hackers who are hired to assess the IT Infrastructure of an organization. They are hired to evaluate and perform hacks on systems in a way a malicious hacker would perform an attack and break in into the systems. They basically simulate an attack to exploit gaps in the organization’s IT Infrastructure.</p>
<p>This is precisely the way how a <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/red-team-assessment-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">red team assessor</a> evaluates the effectiveness of an organization’s security controls in place. Compared to the penetration test, the red team assessment is broader in scope involving a full-scale attack on the IT Infrastructure which lasts for hours, days, or even weeks.</p>
<p>This type of hack provides insightful data on how and for how long a hacker managed to maintain access within their systems and network. Such assessments help organizations improve and strengthen their cyber security posture. Covering more of this in detail we have today shared the top 5 reasons why we believe organizations must hire red team assessors.</p>
<h3><strong>Top 5 reasons to hire a red team assessor</strong></h3>
<h4><strong style="font-size: 16px;">1) Identify Gaps in the IT Infrastructure</strong></h4>
<p>Red Team Assessors are often hired by IT firms and businesses to help them identify potential gaps in the systems. More than often the internal team fails to identify gaps, vulnerabilities, or weaknesses in systems that a hacker would possibly find. Such loopholes and gaps are essential to be identified and fixed immediately to prevent incidents of breaches and hacks.</p>
<p>The exercise is performed for finding gaps in terms of operational disruptions, coding errors, misconfigured patches, insider threats, and weaknesses in processes, workflows, technology, and negligence of people involved such as employees, suppliers, and business vendors. So, for these reasons, it is recommended that organizations annually perform a thorough red team assessment to identify such gaps and remediate vulnerabilities in systems. After all, even the best of defense can fall prey to attacks by hackers, given the dynamics of the evolving cybersecurity industry.</p>
<h4><strong>2) Evaluate the Effectiveness of Security Controls</strong></h4>
<p>Evaluating the effectiveness of security controls is crucial for a business looking to strengthen its cyber security posture. So, Red team assessment is one of the best ways of evaluating the effectiveness and performance of security controls established within the organization. Although internal assessment of security controls and systems may suggest strong security in place, yet a third-party assessment may suggest otherwise.</p>
<p>This is because internal teams may tend to overlook certain things that a third party may detect. So, in that sense, the Red team assessment is a perfect exercise as it gives the organizations a third-party perspective of their cybersecurity posture. Further, their assessment and reports give more credibility to the stakeholders of the organizations.</p>
<p>Moreover, the red team assessment exposes vulnerabilities and weaknesses in the infrastructure and verifies the effectiveness of the security control implemented in the organization. This helps the organization fix gaps and improve the security controls while also allowing the organization to strengthen the overall cybersecurity posture in the industry.</p>
<h4><strong>3.Risk Exposure &amp; Impact</strong></h4>
<p>Performing red team assessment involves simulating a real attack on systems and infrastructure. This helps the organization understand the risk exposure to the organization and the potential impact of a security breach or compromise on business.</p>
<p>The assessment demonstrates different ways and means by which a hacker can stage an attack on systems and IT infrastructure. It also demonstrates the amount of damage that the attack could have on the organization and the extent of data leakage in case of a compromise.</p>
<p>Not just that, the assessment also helps an organization understand and prioritize their resources on assets and processes that need immediate attention. This is especially for those assets that are highly exposed to risk. Overall, the assessment conducted by the red team assessor highlights the vulnerabilities and their implications on the<a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/service/infrastructure-audit/"> IT infrastructure</a> and operations.</p>
<h4><strong>4.Effectiveness of Security Team</strong></h4>
<p>Simulation of real attacks allows the organization to test the effectiveness of not just the security controls but also the effectiveness of the security team within the organization. The assessment will help organizations evaluate how well the security team is equipped to deal with situations of data breach and how quickly can they address the issue. Incidents of data leakage and compromise need to be neutralized at the earliest to prevent further damage. For this, the security team should be well equipped and undergo regular training. So, this way red team assessment will ensure the effectiveness of not just the controls in place but also the effectiveness of the security team.</p>
<h4><strong>5.Effectiveness of Incident Response Plans</strong></h4>
<p>Red Team Assessment also provides an opportunity for the organization, to test the effectiveness of its incident response plans. The test evaluates the security controls and the real-time incident response of an organization in case of an incident. This process demonstrates the preparedness of the organization in terms of responding to incidents and, strategies for mitigating the risk. The entire process also works as a guide for organizations to improve their Incident Response plans and establish a strong cybersecurity program within the organization.</p>
<h3><strong>Final Thought</strong></h3>
<p>Red Team Assessors are professional hackers having the skills, experience, and expertise of finding gaps and security flaws like a real-world hacker would, in a given scenario. So, talking about hiring a read team assessor, it would definitely be considered as a good decision for it helps find vulnerabilities and also test the effectiveness of controls in place.</p>
<p>Their dynamic approach and multi-layered, thorough assessment process bring out the accuracy in the evaluation process and test the effectiveness of the organization’s security controls. So, organizations looking to strengthen their cybersecurity programs and ensure the effectiveness of their security controls must definitely consider hiring a red team assessor for performing the exercise.</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4962"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">1</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            vote        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Network Assessment or Wi-Fi Hacking</title>
      <link>https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/wireless-network-assessment-or-wi-fi-hacking/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Swapnesh Chogle]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 11:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[CyberSecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.vistainfosec.com/?p=4943</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Wireless network technology is widely used but at the same &#8230; <a href="https://www.vistainfosec.com/blog/wireless-network-assessment-or-wi-fi-hacking/">Read More</a>]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wireless network technology is widely used but at the same time, it has many security weaknesses. Several reports have explained weaknesses in the Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP) &amp; Wi-Fi Protected Setup (WPS) to encrypt wireless data. Before understanding the benefits of Wireless Network Assessment it is necessary to know what it is, why it is needed, how the service works and what you get from the service.</p>
<h3><strong>Let’s understand what is known as wireless assessment</strong></h3>
<p>Wireless Assessment is an analysis of the current wireless installation that looks at the specific environmental, architectural, and configuration factors that impact the performance and functionality of the system.</p>
<h3><strong>In Wireless Assessment following items are considered:</strong></h3>
<p>The Wireless Assessment provides tactical analysis and strategic assessment of the risks of your wireless implementations. Security Consultants utilize the same techniques the hackers use and provide a realistic view of your susceptibility to network attacks. It helps in determining if the systems, data, and wireless users are being protected. Further, it also improves Wireless Network Security and mitigates possible threats. Wireless Assessment or Wi-Fi hacking involves different attacks like weak encryption, evil twin attacks, Deauth attacks, etc.</p>
<h3><strong>Why is the Wireless Assessment essential?</strong></h3>
<p>The Wireless Assessment is necessary because it uncovers specific configurations or components that are affecting the performance of the system. It provides insight into the system and highlights weaknesses or gaps that require remediation to improve the overall health of the system.</p>
<h2><strong>Wireless Encryption Types:</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>WEP (Wired Equivalent Privacy)</li>
<li>WPS (WiFi Protected Setup)</li>
<li>WPA (WiFi Protected Access)</li>
<li>WPA2 (WiFi Protected Access v2)</li>
<li>WPA3 (WiFi Protected Access v3)</li>
</ul>
<h4> a) <strong>Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP)</strong></h4>
<p>The main issue with WEP is that while sending data from our computer, it only utilises one static key. When WEP first appeared, this wasn&#8217;t a problem, but over time, hackers were able to decipher the secret code hidden in the keys. As a result, if a hacker obtains the key to your Wi-Fi connectivity, they can decrypt the data you&#8217;re sending and read it. Of course, a hacker can&#8217;t just apply a key and hope for the best, our computer can choose from a variety of WEP keys. Hackers can, however, observe patterns in the encryption and keep an eye on the packets. They then determine which key matches the profile and decipher the code.</p>
<h4>b) <strong>Wi-Fi Protected Setup (WPS)</strong></h4>
<p>WPS is a built-in feature of many routers that makes it easier to connect Wi-Fi-enabled devices to a secure wireless network. This information is provided to help connect your TV or other supported home video products to a wireless network using WPS. A router with WPS enabled is at a risk of getting hacked. A successful attack on your router&#8217;s WPS function will reveal your network password in a matter of hours – regardless of how strong that password is. Again, there is no point in putting a strong password on a weak network.</p>
<h4>c) <strong>Wi-Fi Protected Access (WPA)</strong></h4>
<p>WPA improves upon the security feature of WEP by using Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP) to secure network access and Temporal Key Integrity Protocol (TKIP) encryption method to secure data transmissions. Temporary Key Integrity Protocol (TKIP), a 128-bit dynamic key that makes WPA distinct and difficult to crack, is what gives it its security. Because it was designed for WEP-enabled devices, WPA&#8217;s main components were much the same as those of WEP, which was one obvious drawback.</p>
<h4>d) <strong>Wi-Fi Protected Access Version 2 (WPA2)</strong></h4>
<p>Only users with your network password can access the data broadcast or received over your wireless network thanks to WPA2. The Advanced Encryption Technology (AES), which replaced the more exposed TKIP system used in the original WPA protocol, was one advantage of the WPA2 system.</p>
<h4>e)<strong> Wi-Fi Protected Access Version 3 (WPA3)</strong></h4>
<p>The newest security encryption, the WPA3 Protocol, is rising in popularity. WPA3 provides excellent security and hinders illegal access. This degree of security is impenetrable to unauthenticated or unauthorised users. Due to its automatic encryption, WPA3 is the preferred security protocol for public networks.Further, WPA3 security uses GCMP-256 encryption, which is way better than previously used 128-bit encryption.</p>
<h2><strong>Types of wireless attacks.</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fake authentication Attack</li>
<li>Deauthentication Attack</li>
<li>Hirte Attack</li>
<li>Fragmentation Attack</li>
<li>Chop-Chop Attack</li>
<li>Evil twin Attack</li>
</ul>
<h4>a)<strong> Fake Authentication Attack</strong></h4>
<p>In Fake Authentication attacks, attacker tries to authenticate to the access points in the disguise of an authenticated client. Fake authentication attacks work with conjunction to deauthentication attack.</p>
<h4>b)<strong> De-authentication Attack</strong></h4>
<p>A Wi-Fi De-authentication attack is a type of denial-of-service attack that targets communication between a user and a Wi-Fi wireless access point. De-authentication attacks represent fraudulent requests that interfere with the communication between routers and devices. The strategy attacks 802.11-based wireless networks, as they require De-authentication frames whenever users terminate connections.</p>
<h4>c)<strong> Hirte Attacks</strong></h4>
<p>Hirte is a form of assault that aims to crack the WEP key of wi-fi networks that aren&#8217;t available however the client device (laptop, mobile, etc.) is withinside the vicinity of the attacker. This can be accomplished due to the fact the WEP key and the configuration info are nevertheless saved in the wi-fi device.</p>
<h4>d)<strong> Fragmentation Attacks</strong></h4>
<p>A Fragmentation attack does one of the two things: It captures visitors passing via unsecured networks, mimics it, and then impersonates servers. It injects the community visitors with malicious plaintext frames that resemble handshake messages.</p>
<h4>e)<strong> Chop-Chop Attack</strong></h4>
<p>It targets the WEP encrypted Wi-Fi Network. This attack determines the pre-shared key (PSK) through trial and error, rather than mathematically or cryptographically. The WEP key or WPA/WPA2 pre-shared key/passphrase is not the same as the password for the access point. The WEP key or WPA/WPA2 pre-shared key/passphrase allows printers and computers to join your wireless network.</p>
<h4>f) <strong>Evil Twin Attack</strong></h4>
<p>An evil twin attack is a spoofing cyber-attack that works by tricking users into connecting to a fake Wi-Fi access point that mimics a legitimate network.</p>
<h3><strong>What is the expected outcome of the Wireless Assessment?</strong></h3>
<p>Post conducting the Wireless Assessment, the assessment engineer and your account executive will deliver a detailed report comprising the data gathered during the engagement. The Wireless Assessment report includes an overall summary of the assessment and its findings.  The Wireless Assessment report provides a list of findings that the assessment engineer found concerning the wireless system.</p>
<p>These findings are analyzed individually and prioritized to specifically address concerns. The Wireless Assessment report provides a list of recommendations for remediating the items that were of concern from the findings section of the report. The recommendations are very specific about what changes are needed, why they are needed, and how they will improve the performance of the system.</p>
<h3><strong>Protecting Wireless Networks &#8211; Best Practices</strong></h3>
<h4> a)<strong> Update router firmware</strong></h4>
<p>It is recommended to update the firmware of the router whenever an update is released. Updating the firmware will minimize the risk of getting hacked as it will remove most of the vulnerabilities.</p>
<h4> b) <strong>Make use of Strong Passwords</strong></h4>
<p>A strong password is at least eight characters long and includes a mix of upper- and lower-case letters, numbers, and symbols. It is recommended to change the passwords frequently.</p>
<h4> c) <strong>Using MAC Filtering</strong></h4>
<p>By allowing only devices with specific MAC addresses to connect to the network, you can prevent unauthorized access. MAC filtering can be implemented by accessing the wireless router&#8217;s configuration page and adding the MAC addresses of devices that are allowed to connect to the network.</p>
<h4> d) <strong>Enable WPA3 Security</strong></h4>
<p>It is recommended to make use of WPA3 encryption as it provides stronger protection than WPA2</p>
<div style="display: none;"
    class="kk-star-ratings kksr-valign-bottom kksr-align-left "
    data-id="4943"
    data-slug="">
    <div class="kksr-stars">
    <div class="kksr-stars-inactive">
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="1">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="2">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="3">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="4">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star" data-star="5">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="kksr-stars-active" style="width: 180px;">
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
            <div class="kksr-star">
            <div class="kksr-icon" style="width: 30px; height: 30px;"></div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
    <div class="kksr-legend">
            <strong class="kksr-score">5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">/</span>
        <strong>5</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">(</span>
        <strong class="kksr-count">4</strong>
        <span class="kksr-muted">
            votes        </span>
        <span class="kksr-muted">)</span>
    </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>