<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu security notices</title>
    <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/rss.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ubuntu security notices</description>
    <atom:link href="https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/rss.xml" rel="self" />
    <copyright>2023 Canonical Ltd. Ubuntu and Canonical are registered trademarks of Canonical Ltd.</copyright>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>USN-6003-1: Emacs vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6003-1</link>
      <description>Xi Lu discovered that Emacs did not properly handle certain
inputs. An attacker could possibly use this issue to execute
arbitrary commands.
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6003-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 16:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-6001-1: Linux kernel (AWS) vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6001-1</link>
      <description>
Xuewei Feng, Chuanpu Fu, Qi Li, Kun Sun, and Ke Xu discovered that the TCP
implementation in the Linux kernel did not properly handle IPID assignment.
A remote attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (connection
termination) or inject forged data. (CVE-2020-36516)

Ke Sun, Alyssa Milburn, Henrique Kawakami, Emma Benoit, Igor Chervatyuk,
Lisa Aichele, and Thais Moreira Hamasaki discovered that the Spectre
Variant 2 mitigations for AMD processors on Linux were insufficient in some
situations. A local attacker could possibly use this to expose sensitive
information. (CVE-2021-26401)

Jürgen Groß discovered that the Xen subsystem within the Linux kernel did
not adequately limit the number of events driver domains (unprivileged PV
backends) could send to other guest VMs. An attacker in a driver domain
could use this to cause a denial of service in other guest VMs.
(CVE-2021-28712, CVE-2021-28713)

Wolfgang Frisch discovered that the ext4 file system implementation in the
Linux kernel contained an integer overflow when handling metadata inode
extents. An attacker could use this to construct a malicious ext4 file
system image that, when mounted, could cause a denial of service (system
crash). (CVE-2021-3428)

It was discovered that the IEEE 802.15.4 wireless network subsystem in the
Linux kernel did not properly handle certain error conditions, leading to a
null pointer dereference vulnerability. A local attacker could possibly use
this to cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2021-3659)

It was discovered that the System V IPC implementation in the Linux kernel
did not properly handle large shared memory counts. A local attacker could
use this to cause a denial of service (memory exhaustion). (CVE-2021-3669)

Alois Wohlschlager discovered that the overlay file system in the Linux
kernel did not restrict private clones in some situations. An attacker
could use this to expose sensitive information. (CVE-2021-3732)

It was discovered that the SCTP protocol implementation in the Linux kernel
did not properly verify VTAGs in some situations. A remote attacker could
possibly use this to cause a denial of service (connection disassociation).
(CVE-2021-3772)

It was discovered that the btrfs file system implementation in the Linux
kernel did not properly handle locking in certain error conditions. A local
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (kernel deadlock).
(CVE-2021-4149)

Jann Horn discovered that the socket subsystem in the Linux kernel
contained a race condition when handling listen() and connect() operations,
leading to a read-after-free vulnerability. A local attacker could use this
to cause a denial of service (system crash) or possibly expose sensitive
information. (CVE-2021-4203)

It was discovered that the file system quotas implementation in the Linux
kernel did not properly validate the quota block number. An attacker could
use this to construct a malicious file system image that, when mounted and
operated on, could cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2021-45868)

Zhihua Yao discovered that the MOXART SD/MMC driver in the Linux kernel did
not properly handle device removal, leading to a use-after-free
vulnerability. A physically proximate attacker could possibly use this to
cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-0487)

It was discovered that the block layer subsystem in the Linux kernel did
not properly initialize memory in some situations. A privileged local
attacker could use this to expose sensitive information (kernel memory).
(CVE-2022-0494)

It was discovered that the UDF file system implementation in the Linux
kernel could attempt to dereference a null pointer in some situations. An
attacker could use this to construct a malicious UDF image that, when
mounted and operated on, could cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-0617)

David Bouman discovered that the netfilter subsystem in the Linux kernel
did not initialize memory in some situations. A local attacker could use
this to expose sensitive information (kernel memory). (CVE-2022-1016)

It was discovered that the implementation of the 6pack and mkiss protocols
in the Linux kernel did not handle detach events properly in some
situations, leading to a use-after-free vulnerability. A local attacker
could possibly use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-1195)

Duoming Zhou discovered race conditions in the AX.25 amateur radio protocol
implementation in the Linux kernel, leading to use-after-free
vulnerabilities. A local attacker could possibly use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-1205)

It was discovered that the tty subsystem in the Linux kernel contained a
race condition in certain situations, leading to an out-of-bounds read
vulnerability. A local attacker could possibly use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or expose sensitive information. (CVE-2022-1462)

It was discovered that the implementation of X.25 network protocols in the
Linux kernel did not terminate link layer sessions properly. A local
attacker could possibly use this to cause a denial of service (system
crash). (CVE-2022-1516)

Duoming Zhou discovered a race condition in the NFC subsystem in the Linux
kernel, leading to a use-after-free vulnerability. A privileged local
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash) or
possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-1974)

Duoming Zhou discovered that the NFC subsystem in the Linux kernel did not
properly prevent context switches from occurring during certain atomic
context operations. A privileged local attacker could use this to cause a
denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-1975)

It was discovered that the HID subsystem in the Linux kernel did not
properly validate inputs in certain conditions. A local attacker with
physical access could plug in a specially crafted USB device to expose
sensitive information. (CVE-2022-20132)

It was discovered that the device-mapper verity (dm-verity) driver in the
Linux kernel did not properly verify targets being loaded into the device-
mapper table. A privileged attacker could use this to cause a denial of
service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-20572,
CVE-2022-2503)

Duoming Zhou discovered that race conditions existed in the timer handling
implementation of the Linux kernel's Rose X.25 protocol layer, resulting in
use-after-free vulnerabilities. A local attacker could use this to cause a
denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-2318)

Zheyu Ma discovered that the Silicon Motion SM712 framebuffer driver in the
Linux kernel did not properly handle very small reads. A local attacker
could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-2380)

David Leadbeater discovered that the netfilter IRC protocol tracking
implementation in the Linux Kernel incorrectly handled certain message
payloads in some situations. A remote attacker could possibly use this to
cause a denial of service or bypass firewall filtering. (CVE-2022-2663)

Lucas Leong discovered that the LightNVM subsystem in the Linux kernel did
not properly handle data lengths in certain situations. A privileged
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash) or
possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-2991)

It was discovered that the Intel 740 frame buffer driver in the Linux
kernel contained a divide by zero vulnerability. A local attacker could use
this to cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-3061)

Jiasheng Jiang discovered that the wm8350 charger driver in the Linux
kernel did not properly deallocate memory, leading to a null pointer
dereference vulnerability. A local attacker could use this to cause a
denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-3111)

It was discovered that the sound subsystem in the Linux kernel contained a
race condition in some situations. A local attacker could use this to cause
a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-3303)

It was discovered that the Broadcom FullMAC USB WiFi driver in the Linux
kernel did not properly perform bounds checking in some situations. A
physically proximate attacker could use this to craft a malicious USB
device that when inserted, could cause a denial of service (system crash)
or possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-3628)

Ziming Zhang discovered that the VMware Virtual GPU DRM driver in the Linux
kernel contained an out-of-bounds write vulnerability. A local attacker
could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-36280)

It was discovered that the NILFS2 file system implementation in the Linux
kernel did not properly deallocate memory in certain error conditions. An
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (memory exhaustion).
(CVE-2022-3646)

It was discovered that the Netlink Transformation (XFRM) subsystem in the
Linux kernel contained a reference counting error. A local attacker could
use this to cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-36879)

It was discovered that the infrared transceiver USB driver did not properly
handle USB control messages. A local attacker with physical access could
plug in a specially crafted USB device to cause a denial of service (memory
exhaustion). (CVE-2022-3903)

Jann Horn discovered a race condition existed in the Linux kernel when
unmapping VMAs in certain situations, resulting in possible use-after-free
vulnerabilities. A local attacker could possibly use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-39188)

Hyunwoo Kim discovered that the DVB Core driver in the Linux kernel did not
properly perform reference counting in some situations, leading to a use-
after-free vulnerability. A local attacker could use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2022-41218)

It was discovered that a race condition existed in the SMSC UFX USB driver
implementation in the Linux kernel, leading to a use-after-free
vulnerability. A physically proximate attacker could use this to cause a
denial of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2022-41849)

It was discovered that a race condition existed in the Roccat HID driver in
the Linux kernel, leading to a use-after-free vulnerability. A local
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash) or
possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-41850)

It was discovered that the USB core subsystem in the Linux kernel did not
properly handle nested reset events. A local attacker with physical access
could plug in a specially crafted USB device to cause a denial of service
(kernel deadlock). (CVE-2022-4662)

It was discovered that the network queuing discipline implementation in the
Linux kernel contained a null pointer dereference in some situations. A
local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-47929)

Kyle Zeng discovered that the IPv6 implementation in the Linux kernel
contained a NULL pointer dereference vulnerability in certain situations. A
local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2023-0394)

It was discovered that a memory leak existed in the SCTP protocol
implementation in the Linux kernel. A local attacker could use this to
cause a denial of service (memory exhaustion). (CVE-2023-1074)

Mingi Cho discovered that the netfilter subsystem in the Linux kernel did
not properly initialize a data structure, leading to a null pointer
dereference vulnerability. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of
service (system crash). (CVE-2023-1095)

Kyle Zeng discovered that the ATM VC queuing discipline implementation in
the Linux kernel contained a type confusion vulnerability in some
situations. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system
crash). (CVE-2023-23455)

Lianhui Tang discovered that the MPLS implementation in the Linux kernel
did not properly handle certain sysctl allocation failure conditions,
leading to a double-free vulnerability. An attacker could use this to cause
a denial of service or possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2023-26545)

It was discovered that the NTFS file system implementation in the Linux
kernel did not properly validate attributes in certain situations, leading
to an out-of-bounds read vulnerability. A local attacker could possibly use
this to expose sensitive information (kernel memory). (CVE-2023-26607)

Duoming Zhou discovered that a race condition existed in the infrared
receiver/transceiver driver in the Linux kernel, leading to a use-after-
free vulnerability. A privileged attacker could use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2023-1118)

</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6001-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-6000-1: Linux kernel (BlueField) vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6000-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that the Upper Level Protocol (ULP) subsystem in the
Linux kernel did not properly handle sockets entering the LISTEN state in
certain protocols, leading to a use-after-free vulnerability. A local
attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash) or
possibly execute arbitrary code. (CVE-2023-0461)

It was discovered that the NVMe driver in the Linux kernel did not properly
handle reset events in some situations. A local attacker could use this to
cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-3169)

It was discovered that a use-after-free vulnerability existed in the SGI
GRU driver in the Linux kernel. A local attacker could possibly use this to
cause a denial of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary
code. (CVE-2022-3424)

Gwangun Jung discovered a race condition in the IPv4 implementation in the
Linux kernel when deleting multipath routes, resulting in an out-of-bounds
read. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system
crash) or possibly expose sensitive information (kernel memory).
(CVE-2022-3435)

It was discovered that a race condition existed in the Kernel Connection
Multiplexor (KCM) socket implementation in the Linux kernel when releasing
sockets in certain situations. A local attacker could use this to cause a
denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2022-3521)

It was discovered that the Netronome Ethernet driver in the Linux kernel
contained a use-after-free vulnerability. A local attacker could use this
to cause a denial of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary
code. (CVE-2022-3545)

It was discovered that the hugetlb implementation in the Linux kernel
contained a race condition in some situations. A local attacker could use
this to cause a denial of service (system crash) or expose sensitive
information (kernel memory). (CVE-2022-3623)

Ziming Zhang discovered that the VMware Virtual GPU DRM driver in the Linux
kernel contained an out-of-bounds write vulnerability. A local attacker
could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-36280)

Hyunwoo Kim discovered that the DVB Core driver in the Linux kernel did not
properly perform reference counting in some situations, leading to a use-
after-free vulnerability. A local attacker could use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2022-41218)

It was discovered that the Intel i915 graphics driver in the Linux kernel
did not perform a GPU TLB flush in some situations. A local attacker could
use this to cause a denial of service or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2022-4139)

It was discovered that a race condition existed in the Xen network backend
driver in the Linux kernel when handling dropped packets in certain
circumstances. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service
(kernel deadlock). (CVE-2022-42328, CVE-2022-42329)

It was discovered that the Atmel WILC1000 driver in the Linux kernel did
not properly validate offsets, leading to an out-of-bounds read
vulnerability. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service
(system crash). (CVE-2022-47520)

It was discovered that the network queuing discipline implementation in the
Linux kernel contained a null pointer dereference in some situations. A
local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2022-47929)

José Oliveira and Rodrigo Branco discovered that the prctl syscall
implementation in the Linux kernel did not properly protect against
indirect branch prediction attacks in some situations. A local attacker
could possibly use this to expose sensitive information. (CVE-2023-0045)

It was discovered that a use-after-free vulnerability existed in the
Advanced Linux Sound Architecture (ALSA) subsystem. A local attacker could
use this to cause a denial of service (system crash). (CVE-2023-0266)

Kyle Zeng discovered that the IPv6 implementation in the Linux kernel
contained a NULL pointer dereference vulnerability in certain situations. A
local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system crash).
(CVE-2023-0394)

Wei Chen discovered that a race condition existed in the TIPC protocol
implementation in the Linux kernel, leading to a null pointer dereference
vulnerability. A local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service
(system crash). (CVE-2023-1382)

It was discovered that the Android Binder IPC subsystem in the Linux kernel
did not properly validate inputs in some situations, leading to a use-
after-free vulnerability. A local attacker could use this to cause a denial
of service (system crash) or possibly execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2023-20938)

Kyle Zeng discovered that the class-based queuing discipline implementation
in the Linux kernel contained a type confusion vulnerability in some
situations. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system
crash). (CVE-2023-23454)

Kyle Zeng discovered that the ATM VC queuing discipline implementation in
the Linux kernel contained a type confusion vulnerability in some
situations. An attacker could use this to cause a denial of service (system
crash). (CVE-2023-23455)

It was discovered that the NTFS file system implementation in the Linux
kernel did not properly validate attributes in certain situations, leading
to an out-of-bounds read vulnerability. A local attacker could possibly use
this to expose sensitive information (kernel memory). (CVE-2023-26607)

Wei Chen discovered that the DVB USB AZ6027 driver in the Linux kernel
contained a null pointer dereference when handling certain messages from
user space. A local attacker could use this to cause a denial of service
(system crash). (CVE-2023-28328)

</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-6000-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 22:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5998-1: Apache Log4j vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5998-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that the SocketServer component of Apache Log4j 1.2
incorrectly handled deserialization. An attacker could possibly use this issue
to execute arbitrary code. This issue only affected Ubuntu 16.04 ESM.
(CVE-2019-17571)

It was discovered that the JMSSink component of Apache Log4j 1.2 incorrectly
handled deserialization. An attacker could possibly use this issue to execute
arbitrary code. (CVE-2022-23302)

It was discovered that Apache Log4j 1.2 incorrectly handled certain SQL
statements. A remote attacker could possibly use this issue to perform an SQL
injection attack and alter the database. This issue was only fixed in Ubuntu
18.04 LTS and Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. (CVE-2022-23305)

It was discovered that the Chainsaw component of Apache Log4j 1.2 incorrectly
handled deserialization. An attacker could possibly use this issue to execute
arbitrary code. This issue was only fixed in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS and Ubuntu 20.04
LTS. (CVE-2022-23307)
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5998-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 21:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5999-1: trim-newlines vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5999-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that trim-newlines incorrectly handled certain inputs. If a
user or an automated system were tricked into opening a specially crafted
input file, a remote attacker could possibly use this issue to cause a
denial of service. (CVE-2021-33623)
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5999-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 10:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5997-1: IPMItool vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5997-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that IPMItool was not properly checking the data received
from a remote LAN party. A remote attacker could possibly use this issue to
to cause a crash or arbitrary code execution.
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5997-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5996-1: Liblouis vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5996-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that Liblouis incorrectly handled certain files.
An attacker could possibly use this issue to cause a denial of service.
(CVE-2023-26767, CVE-2023-26768, CVE-2023-26769)
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5996-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 10:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5995-1: Vim vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5995-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that Vim incorrectly handled memory when opening certain
files. If an attacker could trick a user into opening a specially crafted
file, it could cause Vim to crash, or possible execute arbitrary code. This
issue only affected Ubuntu 14.04 ESM, Ubuntu 18.04 LTS, Ubuntu 20.04 LTS,
and Ubuntu 22.04 LTS. (CVE-2022-0413, CVE-2022-1629, CVE-2022-1674,
CVE-2022-1733, CVE-2022-1735, CVE-2022-1785, CVE-2022-1796, CVE-2022-1851,
CVE-2022-1898, CVE-2022-1942, CVE-2022-1968, CVE-2022-2124, CVE-2022-2125,
CVE-2022-2126, CVE-2022-2129, CVE-2022-2175, CVE-2022-2183, CVE-2022-2206,
CVE-2022-2304, CVE-2022-2345, CVE-2022-2581)

It was discovered that Vim incorrectly handled memory when opening certain
files. If an attacker could trick a user into opening a specially crafted
file, it could cause Vim to crash, or possible execute arbitrary code. This
issue only affected Ubuntu 18.04 LTS, Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, and Ubuntu 22.04
LTS. (CVE-2022-1720, CVE-2022-2571, CVE-2022-2845, CVE-2022-2849,
CVE-2022-2923)

It was discovered that Vim incorrectly handled memory when opening certain
files. If an attacker could trick a user into opening a specially crafted
file, it could cause Vim to crash, or possible execute arbitrary code. This
issue only affected Ubuntu 20.04 LTS and Ubuntu 22.04 LTS. (CVE-2022-1927,
CVE-2022-2344)

It was discovered that Vim incorrectly handled memory when opening certain
files. If an attacker could trick a user into opening a specially crafted
file, it could cause Vim to crash, or possible execute arbitrary code. This
issue only affected Ubuntu 18.04 LTS, Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, Ubuntu 22.04 LTS,
and Ubuntu 22.10. (CVE-2022-2946)

It was discovered that Vim incorrectly handled memory when opening certain
files. If an attacker could trick a user into opening a specially crafted
file, it could cause Vim to crash, or possible execute arbitrary code. This
issue only affected Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, and Ubuntu 22.10.
(CVE-2022-2980)
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5995-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 08:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5994-1: HAProxy vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5994-1</link>
      <description>It was discovered that HAProxy incorrectly initialized certain connection
buffers. A remote attacker could possibly use this issue to obtain
sensitive information.
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5994-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 13:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USN-5993-1: Samba vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5993-1</link>
      <description>Demi Marie Obenour discovered that the Samba LDAP server incorrectly
handled certain confidential attribute values. A remote authenticated
attacker could possibly use this issue to obtain certain sensitive
information. (CVE-2023-0614)

Andrew Bartlett discovered that the Samba AD DC admin tool incorrectly
sent passwords in cleartext. A remote attacker could possibly use this
issue to obtain sensitive information. (CVE-2023-0922)
</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ubuntu.com/security/notices/USN-5993-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 13:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>