<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
    <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
    <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 08:27:16 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <image>
      <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
      <url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
      <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
    </image>
    <description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-pill-at-center-of-escalating-us-court-battle-3930374]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[US Abortion Pill Ruling: What Happened And What's Next?]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abortion-pill-at-center-of-escalating-us-court-battle-3930374]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 07:33:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Federal judges in Texas and Washington on Friday issued dueling rulings that intensified the legal battle over abortion and a commonly used medical abortion drug.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Federal judges in Texas and Washington on Friday issued dueling rulings that intensified the legal battle over abortion and a commonly used medical abortion drug.</p>

<p>The legal battle over the pill mifepristone has grown more intense since the US Supreme Court last year tossed out the federal right to the procedure.</p>

<p>The abortion pill was at the center of two conflicting federal court rulings on Friday.</p>

<p>In one ruling, a federal judge in Texas halted Food and Drug Administration approval of the abortion pill, pending a seven-day window to give the Justice Department time to appeal.</p>

<p>Then Friday night, in a dramatic lurch in a different legal direction, a federal judge in Washington state said that the FDA must keep the abortion pill available in at least 12 liberal states.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here is background on the abortion pill and its use.</p>

<p><strong>How widespread is abortion pill use?</strong></p>

<p>According to the Guttmacher Institute, the pill accounted for more than half -- 53 percent -- of the 930,160 abortions documented by the reproductive health research and policy organization in the United States in 2020.</p>

<p>That was up from 17 percent in 2008 and 39 percent in 2017.</p>

<p>While the number of so-called medication abortions has gone up dramatically in the United States in recent years, it is still not as prevalent as in several European nations.</p>

<p>In France, for example, medication abortions represented 70 percent of the total number of abortions in 2020.</p>

<p><strong>How does it work?</strong></p>

<p>The abortion pill is different from the "morning after" pill, which is taken by a woman after sexual intercourse to prevent becoming pregnant.</p>

<p>The abortion pill is taken to induce an abortion once a woman confirms that she is pregnant.</p>

<p>It in fact involves more than one pill. The first, mifepristone, also known as RU 486, stops a pregnancy from proceeding normally by blocking production of the hormone progesterone.</p>

<p>Another drug, misoprostol, is taken up to 48 hours later and causes cramps, bleeding and the emptying of the uterus.</p>

<p>Abortion pills can be used at home and a medical setting is not required.</p>

<p><strong>When was the abortion pill approved?</strong></p>

<p>The US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) gave the green light to mifepristone and misoprostol in 2000.</p>

<p>It is approved for use up to 10 weeks of pregnancy, after which a woman would need to undergo an abortion through another means such as vacuum aspiration.</p>

<p>The average cost of a medication abortion at Planned Parenthood is $580 but it can cost up to $800.</p>

<p><strong>Is it safe and effective?</strong></p>

<p>Use of the abortion pill during the specified time period is considered to be safe and effective by medical experts.</p>

<p>Pregnancies are successfully terminated in more than 95 percent of cases where the pill is used, according to studies.</p>

<p>Serious complications -- excessive bleeding, fever, infection or allergic reaction -- which require a medical consult, are rare.</p>

<p>The abortion pill does not work for ectopic pregnancies, which account for around two percent of all pregnancies and where a fertilized egg grows outside the uterus.</p>

<p><strong>Where is the pill available?</strong></p>

<p>At least 13 US states have banned most abortions, including medication abortions, since the Supreme Court's ruling in June overturning the constitutional right to an abortion.</p>

<p>Despite the bans, a number of organizations have mobilized to provide abortion pills to women in states where abortion is restricted.</p>

<p>The extent of their efforts is difficult to evaluate.</p>

<p>In the states where abortion is legal, the FDA recently loosened restrictions surrounding mifepristone, allowing it to be sent through the mail with a prescription or to be sold directly in pharmacies like any other drug.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-05/en2sf2m8_us-abortion-protests_625x300_06_May_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The abortion pill is taken to induce an abortion once a woman confirms that she is pregnant.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-announces-drills-around-taiwan-after-us-speaker-meeting-3930338]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[China Announces Drills Around Taiwan After US Speaker Meeting]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-announces-drills-around-taiwan-after-us-speaker-meeting-3930338]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 06:40:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[China will hold three days of military exercises around Taiwan starting from Saturday, the People's Liberation Army's Eastern Theatre Command announced, the day after Taiwan President Tsai Ing-wen returned from a trip to the United States.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China will hold three days of military exercises around Taiwan starting from Saturday, the People's Liberation Army's Eastern Theatre Command announced, the day after Taiwan President Tsai Ing-wen returned from a trip to the United States.</p>

<p>China will hold "combat readiness patrols" and exercises around in the Taiwan Strait and to the north, south and east of Taiwan "as planned", it added in a brief statement without offering other details.</p>

<p>Tsai met U.S. House Speaker Kevin McCarthy while in Los Angeles in Wednesday, angering Beijing which views Taiwan as its own territory.</p>

<p>There was no immediate response from Taiwan's government.</p>

<p>China had threatened unspecified retaliation if the meeting took place, having staged war games around Taiwan including live fire missile launches in August after then-House Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taipei.</p>

<p>Taiwanese officials had expected a less severe reaction to the McCarthy meeting given it took place in the United States, but nonetheless had also said they could not rule out the possibility of China staging more drills.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/b6t3g4kg_china-flag-reuters_625x300_13_June_21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[China had threatened unspecified retaliation if the meeting took place.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-mobilises-army-police-after-deadly-attacks-in-west-bank-tel-aviv-3930333]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Israel Mobilises Army, Police After Deadly Attacks In West Bank, Tel Aviv]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-mobilises-army-police-after-deadly-attacks-in-west-bank-tel-aviv-3930333]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 06:18:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu mobilised police and army reserves Friday after separate attacks killed three people, including an Italian tourist, in the West Bank and Tel Aviv, in the latest escalation of deadly violence.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu mobilised police and army reserves Friday after separate attacks killed three people, including an Italian tourist, in the West Bank and Tel Aviv, in the latest escalation of deadly violence.</p>

<p>Despite appeals for restraint, violence has surged since Israeli police clashed with Palestinians Wednesday inside Jerusalem's Al-Aqsa mosque, with Israel bombarding both Gaza and Lebanon following rocket fire by Palestinian militants.</p>

<p>The latest flare-up in tensions comes during what is both the Jewish Passover and the Muslim holy month of Ramadan.</p>

<p>Earlier on Friday, two British-Israeli sisters aged 16 and 20 were killed, and their mother seriously wounded in a shooting attack in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>Israel's army said it had launched a manhunt for the perpetrators.</p>

<p>Later, in central Tel Aviv, one man was killed and seven people aged between 17 and 74 wounded when a car rammed into people walking on a cycling path along the seafront, and flipped over, Israeli rescue services and police said.</p>

<p>"All the victims were tourists," the Magen David Adom emergency service said.</p>

<p>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni identified the deceased as 36-year-old Alessandro Parini.</p>

<p>The Ichilov hospital in Tel Aviv said it had received three injured Britons and one wounded Italian.</p>

<p>A police spokesman told AFP that "the terrorist was neutralised, it was a terror attack against civilians, a car ramming attack".</p>

<p>Shortly afterwards, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu "instructed the Israel Police to mobilise all reserve border police units and has directed the IDF to mobilise additional forces", his office said.</p>

<p>Oded Revivi, mayor of the illegal settlement of Efrat, confirmed that the dead in the West Bank shooting were Israeli sisters aged 16 and 20, and that the wounded woman was their mother.</p>

<p>A British diplomat later confirmed that the two also held UK passports, while calling for "all parties... to de-escalate tensions".</p>

<p><strong>- Cross-border strikes -</strong></p>

<p>Friday's attacks came after Israel launched air strikes and an artillery bombardment before dawn in response to rocket fire from the Gaza Strip and Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel "struck targets, including terror infrastructures, belonging to the Hamas terrorist organisation in southern Lebanon", the army said.</p>

<p>AFP journalists heard explosions in Lebanon's Tyre region as well as in Gaza, where Israeli air raids began before midnight.</p>

<p>The Lebanese army said it had found and dismantled a multiple rocket launcher in an olive grove in the Marjayoun area near the border, still loaded with six primed rockets.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said it had hit two tunnels and "two weapon manufacturing sites" belonging to Hamas in Gaza "as a response to the security violations of Hamas".</p>

<p>It said air defences had intercepted 25 rockets on Thursday, while five had hit Israeli territory.</p>

<p>Israel "will not allow the Hamas terrorist organisation to operate from within Lebanon", it added.</p>

<p>On Friday, Hezbollah deputy chief Naim Qassem said "the threats and intimidation of the Zionist leaders will lead nowhere".</p>

<p>Army spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Richard Hecht had blamed Palestinian militants for the rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>The United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL), which patrols the area along the border, urged restraint, adding: "Both sides have said they do not want a war."</p>

<p>On Friday evening, the army said it had shot down a drone that had entered Israel's airspace from Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry had earlier reported "partial damage" to the Al-Dorra children's hospital in Gaza City. Hecht said Israel was investigating.</p>

<p>Hamas condemned the "appalling Israeli aggression" and said it held Israel "fully responsible for the consequences".</p>

<p><strong>- Mosque raid -</strong></p>

<p>A Qatari official on Friday said Doha was mediating between Israel and the Palestinians.</p>

<p>Doha -- which has previously mediated between Israel and Hamas -- "is working to deescalate the situation on all sides, with the latest contact being noon today," the official said, speaking on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>Israeli riot police stormed the prayer hall of Al-Aqsa mosque in a pre-dawn Wednesday raid aiming to dislodge "law-breaking youths and masked agitators" they said had barricaded themselves inside.</p>

<p>The violence sparked an exchange of rockets and air strikes with militants in Gaza.</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres has urged "all actors to exercise maximum restraint".</p>

<p>The United States on Friday voiced solidarity with Israel after the Tel Aviv attack, saying that "the targeting of innocent civilians of any nationality is unconscionable", according to State Department spokesman Vedant Patel.</p>

<p>France vowed "unwavering" support for "Israel's security and Lebanon's stability and sovereignty", while an Iranian foreign ministry spokesperson "strongly condemned the attacks of the aggressor Zionist regime" and Russia called for a "lasting ceasefire".</p>

<p>Hamas and Islamic Jihad told Egypt, a longstanding mediator between Israel and the Palestinians, that rocket fire would continue "if Israel continues its aggressions and air strikes but, if these aggressions stop, they will cease fire," Palestinian sources said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/bac1gvqc_west-bank-attack_625x300_08_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[At least 3 killed and several injured in the latest escalation of deadly violence in Israel on Friday.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-stands-with-israel-after-unconscionable-attacks-3930325]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[US Says Stands With Israel After "Unconscionable" Attacks]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-stands-with-israel-after-unconscionable-attacks-3930325]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:56:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[The United States on Friday voiced solidarity with ally Israel which mobilized police and army reserves after deadly attacks following a surge in tension in Jerusalem.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Friday voiced solidarity with ally Israel which mobilized police and army reserves after deadly attacks following a surge in tension in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>"The targeting of innocent civilians of any nationality is unconscionable. The United States stands with the government and people of Israel," State Department spokesman Vedant Patel said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/p579c7u_vedant-patel_625x300_27_January_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The US on Friday voiced solidarity with ally Israel amid violence in Jerusalem.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-court-suspends-government-approval-of-abortion-pill-3930322]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[US Court Suspends Government Approval Of Abortion Pill]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-court-suspends-government-approval-of-abortion-pill-3930322]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:43:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[A conservative federal judge in the state of Texas halted US approval of the abortion pill mifepristone on Friday, but paused implementation for a week to give federal authorities time to appeal.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A conservative federal judge in the state of Texas halted US approval of the abortion pill mifepristone on Friday, but paused implementation for a week to give federal authorities time to appeal.</p>

<p>The suit against the Food and Drug Administration is the latest step in the campaign to win a total ban on abortion following a landmark Supreme Court ruling last year. It takes aim at a pill involved in 53 percent of all abortions in the United States, or more than half a million every year.</p>

<p>"FDA's approval of mifepristone is hereby STAYED," Judge Matthew Kacsmaryk wrote in his decision, adding that the court was also halting "applicability of this opinion and order for seven (7) days."</p>

<p>While the FDA has never been challenged like this before on its approval of a drug that has proven safe and effective, the plaintiffs -- a coalition of anti-abortion groups --&nbsp; counted on being able to win a national freeze on distribution of mifepristone.</p>

<p>Presiding over the case in federal court in Amarillo, Texas is Kacsmaryk, who was appointed to the bench by Republican former president Donald Trump and confirmed by the Senate in 2019.</p>

<p>The judge is a conservative Christian with a personal history of opposition to abortion and a court record of favoring right-wing causes.</p>

<p>The case landed in his court via what critics call "judge-shopping," in which plaintiffs take legal action in a district where the judge has a history of rulings that support their case.</p>

<p>Federal judges in the United States have a right to issue rulings that carry national legal force.</p>

<p>Democratic politicians were quick to react on social media.</p>

<p>"This ruling opens a new door to politicizing medicine," New York Governor Kathy Hochul posted on Twitter. "Extremists will not stop at stripping away abortion rights."</p>

<p>Massachusetts Senator Elizabeth Warren posted that "because of today's lawless ruling, women could lose access to a safe and legal medication they've relied on for decades."</p>

<p>One component of a two-drug regimen used for medication abortion, mifepristone can be used in the United States through the first 10 weeks of pregnancy.</p>

<p>It has a long safety record, and the FDA estimates 5.6 million Americans have used it to terminate pregnancies since it was approved.</p>

<p>While abortion care has halted in more than a dozen states after the Supreme Court overturned the long-established constitutional right last June, it is still legal in dozens more.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/kpriagks_pills-generic_625x300_22_May_19.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Texas court halted US approval of the abortion pill mifepristone on Friday.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-governments-actions-making-mockery-of-country-imran-khan-3930315]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pak Government's Actions Making Mockery Of Country Abroad: Imran Khan]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pak-governments-actions-making-mockery-of-country-imran-khan-3930315]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:14:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) chairman and former prime minister Imran Khan on Friday expressed his concern about the government's actions, stating that they are making a mockery of Pakistan abroad.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) chairman and former prime minister Imran Khan on Friday expressed his concern about the government's actions, stating that they are making a mockery of Pakistan abroad.</p>

<p>"The dangerous ruling buffoons don't realise the damage they are doing to Pak's image abroad by sham FIRs &amp; absurd sedition charges against a former PM for using terms 'Dirty Harry' &amp; 'psycopath'! They are making a mockery of Pakistan," tweeted Khan.</p>

<p>He also warned that foreign investors may be getting a troubling message after the Pakistani government's decision to not accept the Supreme Court's decision in the Punjab polls delay case.</p>

<p>"Also, what msg is being sent to foreign investors when govt itself is not accepting SC decisions? Investors need security of contracts &amp; that means faith in judicial system. What confidence can they have when govt itself casting aside SC orders? This happens in a banana republic," he tweeted.</p>

<p>Khan's comments came after the federal government demanded that Chief Justice of Pakistan (CJP) Umar Ata Bandial step down, claiming that his position had become "controversial" after Justice Athar Minallah's note in the case.</p>

<p>Justice Minallah stated that the Supreme Court's suo motu notice over the delay in the announcement of provincial assembly elections was dismissed by a majority 4-3 ruling.</p>

<p>A three-member SC bench comprising Chief Justice of Pakistan Umar Ata Bandial, Justice Ijazul Ahsan, and Justice Munib Akhtar had announced the verdict on the PTI's petition challenging the Election Commission of Pakistan's (ECP) move to postpone the Punjab Assembly polls till October 8.</p>

<p>This ruling was rejected by the government, who labeled it a "minority verdict", with the National Assembly also passing a resolution against the top court.</p>

<p>The government's refusal to accept the Supreme Court's decision has raised concerns about the state of country's democracy and judicial system.</p>

<p>The PTI chief also claimed that the sedition cases filed against him and the imprisonment of senior party leader Ali Amin Gandapur are attempts to undermine their party's ability to contest elections.</p>

<p>"Sedition cases against me - this is 144th case against me- and our senior ldr Ali Amin along with his imprisonment, are simply attempts to undermine our Party's ability to fight elections. This is all part of London Plan in which Nawaz Sharif was given assurances that PTI would be crushed before elections through fake cases &amp; imprisonment of its leadership," he tweeted.</p>

<p>Imran Khan has been pushing for assembly elections in Punjab and Khyber-Pakhtunkhwa provinces as part of a campaign to force an early general election that he has waged since being forced from office a year ago after losing a vote of confidence, reported The Express Tribune.</p>

<p>However, Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has rejected Imran Khan's call for an early general election and his government had backed the Election Commission of Pakistan (ECP) delay in the votes in the two provinces to Oct 8.</p>

<p>The commission cited a lack of resources and the government agreed, saying it was not possible to organise the provincial elections while the country was struggling with an economic crisis and with a general election due around early October anyway.</p>

<p>But the Supreme Court ruled that the delay was illegal and voting in the two provinces should be held between April 30 and May 15, reported The Express Tribune.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/ia818iug_imran-khan-afp_625x300_19_March_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Ex-Pak PM Imran Khan said that Sharuf givernment is making a mockery of Pakistan abroad.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-spying-charges-against-reporter-categorically-false-wall-street-journal-3930314]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Russia Spying Charges Against Reporter "Unjustified": Wall Street Journal]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-spying-charges-against-reporter-categorically-false-wall-street-journal-3930314]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 04:55:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Russia's charges of spying filed Friday against Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich are "categorically false," the newspaper said.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's charges of spying filed Friday against Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich are "categorically false," the newspaper said.</p>

<p>"We've seen media reports indicating Evan has been charged. As we've said from the beginning, these charges are categorically false and unjustified, and we continue to demand Evan's immediate release," The Wall Street Journal said in a statement.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/etgd98qo_evan-gershkovich_625x300_30_March_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal slammed Russia over spy charges against its journalist Evan Gershkovich.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-announces-all-out-anti-terror-operation-against-banned-outfits-3930302]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Announces All-Out Anti-Terror Operation Against Banned Outfits]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-announces-all-out-anti-terror-operation-against-banned-outfits-3930302]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 04:10:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[To root out terrorism from the country, Pakistan on Friday announced an all-out anti-terror operation against banned outfits, reported Geo News.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To root out terrorism from the country, Pakistan on Friday announced an all-out anti-terror operation against banned outfits, reported Geo News.</p>

<p>The development came after a two-hour-long National Security Committee (NSC) meeting comprising the country's top civil and military leadership -- with Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif in the chair, a statement from the PM's Office said.</p>

<p>The recent spurt in clashes between terrorists and the police in Pakistan after the failure of a ceasefire with the outlawed Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) reflects the precarious security situation in the country.</p>

<p>This all-around and comprehensive operation to eliminate the scourge of terrorism in all its forms from Pakistan will also include efforts at the political, diplomatic, security, economic, and social levels.</p>

<p>Chief of Army Staff General Asim Munir, Chairman Joint Chiefs of Staff Committee General Shamshad Mirza, federal ministers for defence, finance and information, and senior military leadership were in attendance, reported Geo News.</p>

<p>"The meeting agreed to launch an all-out comprehensive operation -- with renewed vigour and determination -- with the [help] of the entire nation and the government, which will rid the country of the menace of terrorism," the statement mentioned.</p>

<p>The committee termed the recent spate of terrorism a result of a soft corner for and reckless policy with the Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan (TTP), which was completely contrary to public expectations and aspirations, reported Geo News.</p>

<p>From January to March of this year, various attacks in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa (KP) have resulted in the death of 127 police officers, reported The News International.</p>

<p>According to an official, 116 of them were killed in January, two in February and nine in March. At least four deputy superintendents of police (DSPs) and some junior officers were among those killed in attacks during the first quarter of 2023.</p>

<p>Comparatively, 36 policemen were attacked in 2017, 30 in 2018, 38 in 2019, 28 in 2020, and 59 in 2021. However, the number of casualties by policemen increased to over 120 in 2022, and the death toll in the first quarter of 2023 has already surpassed the numbers in the previous year.</p>

<p>The police posts in several areas have been coming under attack with grenades and heavy weapons for the last couple of years.</p>

<p>The most recent incident this year occurred in Lakki Marwat, when DSP Iqbal Momand and three other police officers were killed after their armoured personnel carrier was damaged by a roadside improvised explosive device, reported The News International.</p>

<p>The worst attack on police during the current year was in January when a suicide bomber detonated explosives around his vest in the mosque of the Peshawar Police Lines during the Zuhr prayers.</p>

<p>Regarding the casualties in the incident, some senior officials put the exact death toll at 100 and 96 were policemen some of whom died at the hospital, reported The News International.</p>

<p>Terrorism in Pakistan has been rearing its head again. Over the past few months, the law and order situation in the country -- especially in Khyber-Pakhtunkhwa and Balochistan has worsened -- with terrorist groups executing attacks with near impunity across the country.</p>

<p>Since the talks with the Tehrik-i-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) broke down in November, the terrorist group has intensified its attacks, particularly targeting the police in KP and areas bordering Afghanistan. Insurgents in Balochistan have also stepped up their violent activities and formalized a nexus with the outlawed TTP, reported Dawn.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/66abjdp8_shehbaz-sharif-pakistan-pm-afp_625x300_21_September_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The decision took in National Security Committee (NSC) meeting, the Pak PMO office said.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-carried-out-nuclear-capable-underwater-weapon-test-3930296]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[North Korea Says It Carried Out Nuclear-Capable Underwater Weapon Test]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-carried-out-nuclear-capable-underwater-weapon-test-3930296]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 03:39:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[North Korea carried out an underwater strategic weapon system test from April 4 to April 7, state media KCNA said on Saturday.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea carried out an underwater strategic weapon system test from April 4 to April 7, state media KCNA said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The country tested another kind of a nuclear-capable unmanned underwater attack weapon called "Haeil-2", after it disclosed a new underwater drone system designed to make sneak attacks in enemy waters.</p>

<p>"The test perfectly proved the reliability of the underwater strategic weapon system and its fatal attack ability," the North's state news agency said.</p>

<p>North Korea has ramped up its military activities in recent weeks in a show of force against the United States and South Korea that conduct joint military drills.</p>

<p>It unveiled new, smaller nuclear warheads and fired an intercontinental ballistic missile capable of striking anywhere in the United States.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/85c1dul_north-korea-reuters_625x300_30_June_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[North Korea has ramped up its military activities in recent weeks amid US-South Korea military drills.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrested-us-wall-street-journal-journalist-evan-gershkovich-charged-with-spying-in-russia-3930278]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Arrested US Journalist Charged With Spying In Russia]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrested-us-wall-street-journal-journalist-evan-gershkovich-charged-with-spying-in-russia-3930278]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 02:14:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Moscow has formally charged US journalist Evan Gershkovich with espionage, Russian news agencies reported Friday, adding that he had denied the accusations.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Moscow has formally charged US journalist Evan Gershkovich with espionage, Russian news agencies reported Friday, adding that he had denied the accusations.</p>

<p>The arrest of Wall Street Journal correspondent Evan Gershkovich prompted an outcry from media outlets and rights groups, as well as government officials in Washington.</p>

<p>"FSB investigators charged Gershkovich with espionage in the interests of his country," Russian state-run agency TASS said, citing a law enforcement source.</p>

<p>"He categorically denied all accusations and stated that he was engaged in journalistic activities in Russia," TASS said.</p>

<p>Gershkovich's arrest is seen as a serious escalation of Moscow's crackdown on the media.</p>

<p>His publication, one of the most prestigious in the United States, "vehemently denies the allegations" against its "trusted and dedicated reporter".</p>

<p>The case has been classified as secret, limiting the amount of information available.</p>

<p>His arrest also comes as Moscow's relationship with Washington has been severely downgraded because of the Ukraine offensive.</p>

<p>Washington has long accused Moscow of arbitrarily arresting Americans in order to secure the release of detained Russians.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden called for Gershkovich's release on Friday, the White House describing the accusations against him as "ridiculous".</p>

<p>The Democratic and Republican leaders of the US Senate also denounced his arrest.</p>

<p>"We strongly condemn the wrongful detention of US citizen and Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich, and demand the immediate release of this internationally known and respected independent journalist," Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer and Republican Leader Mitch McConnell said in a rare joint statement.</p>

<p>"Let there be no mistake: journalism is not a crime," the Senate leaders wrote. "We demand the baseless, fabricated charges against Mr. Gershkovich be dropped and he be immediately released."</p>

<p>Schumer and McConnell also reiterated their "condemnation of the Russian government's continued attempts to intimidate, repress, and punish independent journalists and civil society voices."</p>

<p>But Russia said on Thursday it was "pointless" to try to pressure Moscow over the case.</p>

<p>Gershkovich worked for AFP in Russia before taking a job with the Journal.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/etgd98qo_evan-gershkovich_625x300_30_March_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Evan Gershkovich's arrest is seen as a serious escalation of Moscow's crackdown on the media.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-shootout-between-two-armed-groups-in-bangladesh-cops-3930262]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[8 Killed In Shootout Between Two Armed Groups In Bangladesh: Cops]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-killed-in-shootout-between-two-armed-groups-in-bangladesh-cops-3930262]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:57:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups at Rowangchhari upazila in Bandarban on Thursday night, said police, reported Dhaka Tribune.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups at Rowangchhari upazila in Bandarban on Thursday night, said police, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Officials suspect the United People's Democratic Front (Democratic) and Kuki-Chin National Army, the military wing of Kuki-Chin National Front (KNF), were engaged in the gunbattle.</p>

<p>Abdul Mannan, officer-in-charge (OC) of Rowangchhari police station, said the bullet-riddled bodies were taken to the Bandarban Zila Sadar Hospital morgue. The bodies will be handed over to their families after the autopsy, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>Locals said they heard on-and-off gunshots from Thursday evening till Friday morning. They claimed the gunfight took place between KNF and United People's Democratic Front (UPDF-reformist).</p>

<p>Based on an inspection of their clothes, the deceased are believed to be members of the Kuki Chin National Army (KNA), the armed wing of the KNF. It is suspected that the opposition armed group took heavy weapons that the deceased were carrying.</p>

<p>The KNF in a social media post claimed that just seven people were killed in the gunfight. They blamed a reformist group for the incident, without mentioning any name, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>While the KNF is the armed wing of the Kuki Chin National Front, that harbours separatist demands, the original UPDF under Prasit Khisa has in the past stated 'full autonomy' for the CHT districts as its principal demand. Its official position on the CHT Accord signed between the government of Bangladesh and the PCJSS in 1997, has been 'skeptical'.</p>

<p>UPDF (Democratic) has never clarified its position or distanced itself from the original founding principles. Their reasons for splintering are thought to be personality-based.</p>

<p>The deaths reported on Thursday are the highest in an armed incident in the area since the July 2020 incident, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>On March 12 this year, a senior army warrant officer was killed and two other soldiers suffered injuries when members of KNA opened fire on a patrol team in Rowangchhari upazila of Bandarban.</p>

<p>On March 15, KNF members abducted nine people, including Sergeant (Retd) Anwar Hossain, while they were working on the road in the Longthasi Jhiri area of Ruma.</p>

<p>In a message on March 18, the KNF claimed that 30 people from the Bom community were detained by the joint forces from September 9 till March, and demanded their release, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>After Thursday's incident, some 175 families in the neighbourhood have taken refuge in Rowangchhari Government High School.</p>

<p>Manik Khiang, a shopkeeper in the Khamtam neighbourhood, said: "There was a shooting incident between two groups on Thursday evening. At that time, many people left their homes in fear. So far, I have learned that more than 50 families have left their homes. Many of them have taken refuge in nearby educational institutions."</p>

<p>Since November 15 last year, at least 548 people from 132 families have taken refuge in Mizoram. On January 28, some 140 Marma women, men and children took refuge in Ruma Sadar from Mulpi Para, but they returned to their homes on February 5, reported Dhaka Tribune.</p>

<p>On March 10, around 220 people of 56 families from Barathli 4 Union of Rangamati's Bilaichhari took shelter in Tangchangya Reichha and Rowangchhari Sadar Upazila in fear of the armed activities by KNF members.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-01/k0915tug_gun-generic-pixabay-650_625x300_31_January_19.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Eight people were killed during a "shootout" between two armed groups In Bandarban. (Representational)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-4-injured-in-terror-attack-in-israels-tel-aviv-3930253]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[1 Killed, 5 Injured In Terror Attack In Israel's Tel Aviv]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-4-injured-in-terror-attack-in-israels-tel-aviv-3930253]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:35:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[One man was killed and four people were wounded in an attack Friday in central Tel Aviv, Israeli rescue services said, updating a previous casualty toll of two injured.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu mobilised police and army reserves late Friday after one man was killed and five people were wounded in a car-ramming attack in central Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>The Magen David Adom emergency service said in a statement a man aged about 30 had been declared dead and five others were taken to hospital with moderate injuries after the attack.</p>

<p>"All the victims were tourists," it added, without providing details on their nationalities.</p>

<p>Three of them, including a 17-year-old, were moderately injured, while two had light injuries, the rescue service added.</p>

<p>A police spokesman meanwhile told AFP "the terrorist was neutralised, it was a terror attack against civilians, a car ramming attack".</p>

<p>Netanyahu ordered the mobilisation of police and army reserves following the attack, his office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Earlier Friday, two British-Israeli sisters aged 16 and 20 were killed and their mother seriously wounded in a shooting attack in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim of responsibility for either attack.</p>

<p>The attacks came hours after Israel bombarded Lebanon following rocket fire from there that the army blamed on Palestinian militants.</p>

<p>The violence comes amid an upsurge in tensions during Jewish, Muslim and Christian religious holidays.</p>

<p>It follows the storming early Wednesday by Israeli riot police of the Al-Aqsa mosque in Jerusalem, Islam's third holiest site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-03/police-generic-international-afp_650x400_41520126059.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Israeli police said that it was a terrorist attack. (Representational)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-hosts-iftar-slams-russian-repression-of-crimea-muslims-3930251]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Hosts Iftar, Slams Russian "Repression" Of Crimea Muslims]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/volodymyr-zelensky-hosts-iftar-slams-russian-repression-of-crimea-muslims-3930251]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 08 Apr 2023 01:19:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority Tatar community in Kremlin-controlled Crimea and vowed to recapture the peninsula from Russia during a first official state iftar.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority Tatar community in Kremlin-controlled Crimea and vowed to recapture the peninsula from Russia during a first official state iftar.</p>

<p>Russia wrested control of the Black Sea territory from Ukraine in 2014 and pushed through a referendum on the annexation that was condemned as fraudulent and illegitimate by Ukraine and its Western allies.</p>

<p>"Russia's attempt to enslave Ukraine ... began exactly with the occupation of Crimea, exactly with repressions against Crimean, Ukrainian and Crimean Tatar freedom and of Crimean Muslims," he told Ukrainian Muslim leaders and ambassadors from Muslim countries.</p>

<p>The Tatar community, which accounted for 12-15 percent of the two million Crimea residents, largely boycotted the 2014 vote.</p>

<p>Moscow then banned the Mejlis -- the traditional assembly of the Tatar Muslim minority in Crimea -- declaring it an extremist organisation and has jailed members of the community since, citing security concerns.</p>

<p>"There is no alternative for Ukraine, or for the world, other than the de-occupation of Crimea. We will return to Crimea," Zelensky said, before handing out awards to several Muslim Ukrainian servicemen.</p>

<p>Zelensky, speaking at a mosque outside the centre of the capital, announced that Ukraine was beginning a new tradition of hosting an official iftar, the meal breaking the daily fast during the holy month of Ramadan.</p>

<p>"Ukraine is grateful to the Muslims of our country and to everyone in the Muslim community of the world who, like us, longs for peace and protection from evil," he added.</p>

<p>Several Muslim-majority countries, including Turkey and Saudi Arabia, have positioned themselves as mediators in the conflict in Ukraine, brokering agreements between Kyiv and Moscow on grain exports or prisoner exchanges.</p>

<p>Russia has a large Muslim minority from southern regions, including Chechnya and Dagestan, many of whom are fighting for Moscow in Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/l7ul8h9g_zelensky-reuters_625x300_12_December_22.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Zelensky criticised Russia's treatment of the Muslim-minority in Russian-controlled Crimea.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/spaniards-were-consuming-drugs-3-000-years-ago-study-finds-3930102]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Spaniards Were Consuming Drugs 3,000 Years Ago, Study Finds]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/spaniards-were-consuming-drugs-3-000-years-ago-study-finds-3930102]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:06:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[After examining Bronze Age hair fragments discovered in the Es Carritx cave on the Spanish island of Menorca, researchers made the finding.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ancient humans were using hallucinogenic chemicals to get high during cave ceremonies 3,000 years ago, according to a recent study by researchers studying ancient human civilizations.</p>

<p>The finding of hairs from a burial site in Menorca, Spain, by specialists demonstrates that drugs originating from plants and bushes were utilised by prehistoric human civilizations.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-65211722" target="_blank"><em>The BBC</em></a>, the findings, published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-31064-2" target="_blank"><em>Scientific Reports</em></a>, showed signs of human activity at the Es Carritx cave, on the south-western side of Menorca. The cave houses more than 200 human graves and is believed to have served as a ritual and funerary site for about 600 years, until 800 BCE.</p>

<p>The authors of the study explained that "as early as the Palaeolithic period, humans came across the non-food properties of certain plants." The results presented here indicate that several alkaloid-bearing plants were consumed by Bronze Age people from Menorca (although Solanaceae and Ephedra were not the only ones to have been consumed)."</p>

<p>"Interestingly, the psychoactive substances detected in this study are not suitable for alleviating the pain involved in severe palaeopathological conditions attested in the population buried in the cave of Es Carritx, such as periapical abscesses, severe caries, and arthropathies."</p>

<p>"Considering the potential toxicity of the alkaloids found in the hair, their handling, use, and applications represented highly specialised knowledge. This knowledge was typically possessed by shamans, who were capable of controlling the side effects of the plant drugs through an ecstasy that made diagnosis or divination possible."</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/qlq2f2lo_bronzeage-people-took-hallucinogenic-drugs-in-menorca-study-reveals_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The study found psychoactive substances on hair strands.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-maid-jailed-for-six-months-for-biting-baby-who-refused-to-sleep-3930057]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Singapore Maid Jailed For Six Months For Biting Baby Who Refused To Sleep]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapore-maid-jailed-for-six-months-for-biting-baby-who-refused-to-sleep-3930057]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:47:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[A 33-year-old maid in Singapore who was hired to care for twin babies bit one of them out of frustration when the toddler refused to go to sleep, and now she is serving jail time.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 33-year-old maid in Singapore who was hired to care for twin babies bit one of them out of frustration when the toddler refused to go to sleep, and now she is serving jail time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The domestic help, identified as Masita Khoridaturochmah, was sentenced to six months' jail on Tuesday for one charge of ill-treating the one-year-old girl by willfully causing her unnecessary physical pain, <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/courts-crime/6-months-jail-for-maid-who-bit-forearm-of-baby-under-her-care" target="_blank"><em>The Straits Times </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A court in Singapore heard that Ms Masita, an Indonesian national, started working for the victim's mother in 2021. Her primary duties included taking care of her employer's twin babies, as well as household chores.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On May 26, 2022, Ms Masita's employer left home to pick up her older daughter from preschool. Ms Masita was left at home with the twin infants, who were aged 14 months at the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is when the maid attempted to put them to sleep, however, after about a half-hour, she lost patience with one of the babies because she thought the victim was keeping her from preparing dinner. Ms Masita then bit the little girl once on her left forearm, leaving a bruise.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When the child's mother returned home about half an hour later, she went to cook dinner for her children and fed them. While preparing the baby girl for bed, the mother saw a bruise in the shape of a bite mark on the baby's arm. The woman suspected that Ms Masita had bitten the little girl and questioned her about it.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/canadian-man-chronicles-his-weight-loss-journey-it-started-after-a-conversation-with-daughter-3929897" target="_self">Canadian Man Chronicles His Weight Loss Journey. It Started After A Conversation With Daughter</a></strong></p>

<p>The 33-year-old initially denied doing so but eventually acknowledged her behaviour. According to The Straits Times, Ms Masita even knelt down and apologised to her employer, but the child's mother reported the matter to the police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The prosecutor claimed that the victim was particularly vulnerable and especially young, and Ms Masita had abused the position of trust she was placed in. According to him, Ms Masita hurt the victim "willfully," and the offence was committed because she was upset that the victim wasn't nodding off as quickly as she would have liked.</p>

<p>District Judge Tan Jen Tse also observed that Ms Masita had committed the offence out of annoyance in a singular instance of abuse involving a single act and had shown regret shortly after. The judge agreed to Ms Masita's request to postpone her sentence for a week so she could put her affairs in order, including contacting her family in Indonesia over arrangements for her return after her imprisonment.</p>

<p>The 33-year-old is now expected to surrender herself at the State Courts on Tuesday in order to begin serving her sentence.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/it8dmhbo_baby-generic_625x300_09_June_21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The maid is expected to surrender herself at the State Courts on Tuesday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-organisations-sanctioned-by-china-for-hosting-taiwan-president-3930006]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[American Organisations Sanctioned By China For Hosting Taiwan President]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/american-organisations-sanctioned-by-china-for-hosting-taiwan-president-3930006]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:27:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[China on Friday slapped sanctions on two American organisations that hosted Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen during her visit to the US and her meeting with the House Speaker.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Friday slapped sanctions on two American organisations that hosted Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen during her visit to the US and her meeting with the House Speaker, a day after President Xi Jinping said it is "wishful thinking" to expect Beijing to "compromise" on its stand on the self-ruled island.</p>

<p>Ms Tsai's meeting with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy - the third most senior official in the US - on Thursday took place against the backdrop of repeated warnings from Beijing to Washington that the meeting should not happen. It was the first time a Taiwan president had met a US Speaker on American soil.</p>

<p>China views any official exchanges between foreign governments and Taiwan as an infringement on Beijing's claims of sovereignty over the island.</p>

<p>China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs announced that the Washington-based think tank Hudson Institute and the Ronald Reagan Presidential Library in California would be banned from any cooperation, exchange or transaction with institutions and individuals in China.</p>

<p>The Ronald Reagan Presidential Library in Simi Valley was the site where Tsai met McCarthy and a bipartisan group of congressional leaders. It was the second high-profile meeting between an American official and Taiwan's president.</p>

<p>China also sanctioned the Hudson Institute, which hosted an event and presented Tsai with its global leadership award on March 30.</p>

<p>The sanctioned groups included Asia-based groups --The Prospect Foundation and the Council of Asian Liberals and Democrats for their involvement in promoting Taiwan's independence.</p>

<p>"[The] Taiwan issue is the core of China's core interests. The Chinese government and Chinese people will never agree to anyone making a fuss about the one-China issue," President Xi told European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen during a meeting in Beijing on Thursday.</p>

<p>It was his first comment after the US House Speaker McCarthy met Tsai, which Beijing sharply criticised.</p>

<p>"Anyone who expects China to compromise on the Taiwan question could only be wishful thinking and self-defeating," Xi was quoted as saying by the state-run Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters after the meeting, von der Leyen said the Taiwan issue had been discussed and she had told Xi that "the threat to use force to change the status quo is unacceptable. It is important that some of the tensions that might occur should be resolved through dialogue", Hong Kong-based South China Morning Post reported.</p>

<p>On Friday's sanctions, the foreign ministry in Beijing said that both American institutions were banned from having exchanges, cooperation, and other activities with any individuals, universities or institutions in China.</p>

<p>"We want to stress China will take resolute measures to safeguard its sovereignty and territorial integrity," Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said at a media briefing.</p>

<p>She also sought to dismiss a question on how Beijing can integrate Taiwan, which follows a multiple-party democratic system with that of China's one-party rule headed by the ruling Communist Party.</p>

<p>The Taiwan question is not about democracy but about China's territorial integrity and reunification and Taiwan is an inalienable part of China's territory, Mao said.</p>

<p>"The sovereignty and territory of China have never been divided and will never be divided," she asserted.</p>

<p>"Some countries support Taiwan in the name of democracy and use the Taiwan question to contain China. This move is dangerous and gets nowhere. Taiwan's future lies in the development of cross-strait relations and reunification with the mainland," she added.</p>

<p>The difference in systems is not a barrier to reunification or an excuse for division, Mao said and advocated the 'one country-two systems' formula which Beijing sought to apply to Hong Kong.</p>

<p>Peaceful reunification and the 'one country two systems' take Taiwan's realities into full account and help to achieve peace and stability after re-unification, she said.</p>

<p>"It is the basic principle to resolving the Taiwan question and the best way for realising reunification," she said.</p>

<p>The sanctions came a day after China vowed reprisals against Taiwan.</p>

<p>China and the US also flexed their naval might by deploying aircraft carriers in a rare showdown in the Taiwan Strait.</p>

<p>Under its longstanding "One China" policy, the US acknowledges China's position that Taiwan is part of China, but has never officially recognised Beijing's claim to the island of 23 million. Under the Taiwan Relations Act, it is also bound by law to provide the democratic island with the means to defend itself.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Taiwan's foreign ministry on Friday said the head of state of the Republic of China (Taiwan) exercises a basic right of a sovereign nation when travelling to other countries to engage in diplomatic activities. China has no right to intervene.</p>

<p>"China is overreacting when it uses this as a pretext to further suppress Taiwan's international space and impose so-called sanctions on related individuals and organisations. Such irrational behaviour not only increases the Taiwanese people's antipathy to China but also exposes the erratic and absurd nature of the communist regime," Taiwan's foreign ministry said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/0nobu66_tsai-ing-wenkevin-mccarthy_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Taiwan President met with US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy on Thursday]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-needs-to-repay-77-billion-debt-to-china-saudi-arabia-by-2026-report-3929817]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pak Needs To Repay $77 Billion Debt To China, Saudi Arabia By 2026: Report]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-needs-to-repay-77-billion-debt-to-china-saudi-arabia-by-2026-report-3929817]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 21:13:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Pakistan, currently tackling a major economic crisis, is grappling with high external debt, a weak local currency and dwindling foreign exchange reserves.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan needs to repay a whopping USD 77.5 billion in external debt from April 2023 to June 2026 and the cash-strapped country may face "disruptive effects" if it ultimately defaults, a prominent US think tank has warned.</p>

<p>The analysis published on Thursday by the United States Institute of Peace (USIP) warned that amid skyrocketing inflation, political conflicts, and rising terrorism, Pakistan is facing the risk of a default due to its massive external debt obligations, the Geo News reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Pakistan, currently tackling a major economic crisis, is grappling with high external debt, a weak local currency and dwindling foreign exchange reserves.</p>

<p>The USIP report called the USD 77.5 billion that Pakistan needs to repay in external debt from April 2023 to June 2026 a "hefty amount" for a USD 350 billion economy.</p>

<p>It stated that if Pakistan ultimately defaults, there will be a "cascade of disruptive effects".</p>

<p>In the next three years, the debt-struck country has to make major repayments to Chinese financial institutions, private creditors and Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>From April to June 2023, Pakistan faces near-term debt repayment pressure as the external debt servicing burden is USD 4.5 billion, the report said.</p>

<p>According to the report, substantial repayments are due in June, when a USD 1 billion Chinese SAFE deposit and a roughly USD 1.4 billion Chinese commercial loan would mature.</p>

<p>Pakistani authorities hope to convince the Chinese to refinance and roll over both debts, the report said, noting that the Chinese government and commercial banks have done so in the past.</p>

<p>Even if Pakistan manages to meet these obligations, the next fiscal year will be more challenging as the debt servicing will rise to nearly USD 25 billion, the report said.</p>

<p>Pakistan is awaiting a much-needed USD 1.1 billion tranche of funding from the International Monetary Fund, originally due to be disbursed in November last year.</p>

<p>The funds are part of a USD 6.5 billion bailout package the IMF approved in 2019, which analysts say is critical if Pakistan is to avoid defaulting on external debt obligations.</p>

<p>The IMF programme, signed in 2019, will expire on June 30, 2023, and under the set guidelines, the programme cannot be extended beyond the deadline.</p>

<p>Pakistan and the IMF have been negotiating the programme's resumption for months but have yet to reach an agreement.</p>

<p>There is no easy solution available to fix the ailing economy of Pakistan, and the government is of the view that they have taken all the tough decisions for reviving the stalled IMF programme.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/jqlsd7mk_pakistan-rupee-generic-pkr-generic-istock_625x300_04_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Pakistan is awaiting a much-needed USD 1.1 billion tranche of funding from IMF.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pope-francis-to-skip-good-friday-procession-due-to-cold-weather-3929557]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Pope Francis To Skip Good Friday Procession Due To Cold Weather]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pope-francis-to-skip-good-friday-procession-due-to-cold-weather-3929557]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 19:39:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis, who left hospital last weekend following a bout of bronchitis, will skip Friday's outdoor "Way of the Cross" procession due to cold weather, the Vatican said in a statement.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pope Francis, who left hospital last weekend following a bout of bronchitis, will skip Friday's outdoor "Way of the Cross" procession due to cold weather, the Vatican said in a statement.</p>

<p>The 86-year-old pontiff will still attend an indoor Good Friday service earlier in St. Peter's Basilica, Vatican spokesman Matteo Bruni said in response to a question from Reuters.</p>

<p>It is the first time the pope will not preside at the "Via Crucis" service at Rome's Colosseum since he was elected in 2013.</p>

<p>The Vatican said he would follow it from his residence.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/cja2600g_pope-francis_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[The Vatican said the Pope would follow it from his residence. (File)]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-stop-exchanges-with-the-world-taiwan-president-after-us-visit-3929421]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA["Will Not Stop Exchanges With The World": Taiwan President After US Visit]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-stop-exchanges-with-the-world-taiwan-president-after-us-visit-3929421]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:54:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Taiwan will not be stopped from engaging with the world and will not give in to pressure, President Tsai Ing-wen said on Friday as she arrived back from a trip to Central America and United States, where she met US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan will not be stopped from engaging with the world and will not give in to pressure, President Tsai Ing-wen said on Friday as she arrived back from a trip to Central America and United States, where she met US House Speaker Kevin McCarthy.</p>

<p>China, which claims democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, reacted with anger to the McCarthy meeting having demanded it not take place, though so far has held off ratcheting up military tensions to show its displeasure.</p>

<p>Speaking after stepping off her flight, Tsai said her enthusiastic welcome overseas was a powerful message.</p>

<p>"We showed the international community that in the face of pressure and threats Taiwan will be even more united and will absolutely not yield to suppression, nor due to obstructions stop exchanges with the world," she said at Taiwan's main international airport at Taoyuan outside of Taipei.</p>

<p>China staged war games around Taiwan last August following a visit to Taipei by then-House Speaker Nancy Pelosi.</p>

<p>While Taiwan has reported a Chinese aircraft carrier group far off its eastern coast, it has not reported any other unusual military movements.</p>

<p>China's Taiwan Affairs Office, in a statement released shortly after Tsai's flight landed, reiterated its opposition to her US trip, technically billed as a "transit" though in reality where her most important meetings took place.</p>

<p>"The so-called 'transit' is just an excuse, but it is actually a provocation, relying on the United States to seek independence," it said.</p>

<p>However, the statement did not announce any specific retaliatory steps.</p>

<p>But underscoring the sensitivity of Tsai's return, Taiwan's Defence Ministry denied, around 30 minutes before touchdown, a Taiwanese media report that her flight had been subjected to "unknown interference", saying this was not true.</p>

<p>It did say, though, that a special military task force was deployed to "control the whole process", using naval and air forces to stand guard.</p>

<p>Tsai travelled on an A350 specially chartered from Taiwan's China Airlines.</p>

<p>Tsai and her government reject China's sovereignty claims, saying only Taiwan's people can decide their future. She has repeatedly offered talks with China but been rebuffed, with Beijing viewing her as a separatist.</p>

<p>China has never renounced the use of force to bring Taiwan under its control.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/g8e01ov8_tsai-ingwen_625x300_07_April_23.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Taiwan President Tsai Ing-wen said her enthusiastic welcome overseas was a powerful message]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="true"><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-developed-a-new-recyclable-plastic-that-isnt-derived-from-crude-oil-3929357]]></guid>
      <title><![CDATA[Researchers Make New Recyclable Plastic That Isn't Derived From Crude Oil]]></title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-developed-a-new-recyclable-plastic-that-isnt-derived-from-crude-oil-3929357]]></link>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:31:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[The poly(ethyl cyanoacrylate), or PECA, that serves as the basis for the new recyclable plastic is created from the same monomer as Super Glue.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every area of human life has been contaminated by plastic, including medical devices, educational materials, and, arguably, every occupation and way of life on the world. The packaging for daily-use products is not even imaginable without plastic wrapping. An environmental crisis has been brought on by years of excessive use and a rise in single-use, disposable plastics.</p>

<p>Researchers, developers, and scientists have been attempting to create new eco-friendly and simple processes for producing plastic. In the quest for solutions, recent research has achieved a breakthrough.</p>

<p>A new type of plastic has just been created by researchers at <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adg2295" target="_blank">Boise State University</a> in the US that, unlike other plastics, is not made from crude oil and its byproducts.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2365324-recyclable-plastic-made-from-super-glue-could-replace-polystyrene/" target="_blank"><em>New Scientist</em>, </a>Allison Christy and Scott Phillips at Boise State University in Idaho used ethyl cyanoacrylate-the main ingredient in super glue-to create a plastic that could replace polystyrene, which is commonly used in yoghurt pots, disposable cups, and cutlery and accounts for 6 percent of plastic waste.</p>

<p>The scientists explained the process, saying ethyl cyanoacrylate can be made from formaldehyde, which in turn can be made from carbon dioxide. When super glue is exposed to moisture, ethyl cyanoacrylate molecules bond to form polymer chains, but the reaction is so fast that you only get short chains. The researchers created a way to slow that process down in order to form longer polymer chains and therefore a stronger material, known as poly(ethyl cyanoacrylate), or PECA.</p>

<p>According to the <a href="https://www.un.org/pga/73/plastics/" target="_blank">United Nations</a>, up to 12 million tonnes of plastic are being swept into the oceans annually, and gyres, or so-called 'islands of plastic', are blossoming. While most plastics are expected to remain intact for decades or centuries after use, those that do erode end up as micro-plastics, which are consumed by fish and other marine wildlife and quickly make their way into the global food chain. Indeed, micro-plastics have been found everywhere, from the Arctic to the Swiss mountains, in tap water, and in human faeces.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <media:content url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/0pour1r8_plasticafp_625x300_13_October_21.jpg" type="image/jpeg" expression="full" width="538" height="190">
        <media:description type="plain"><![CDATA[Superglue-based recyclable plastic could take the place of polystyrene.]]></media:description>
      </media:content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>