<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>CBNNews.com</title>
    <link>http://www.cbn.com/cbnnews/feed/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[CBNNews.com Feed]]></description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright><![CDATA[Copyright 2011. The Christian Broadcasting Network, Inc.]]></copyright>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[BIBLICAL SCHOLAR: The Resurrection of Jesus Points to His Deity]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Unquestionably, Jesus' resurrection from the dead stands at the very center of the Christian faith, as the Apostle Paul reminded us vigorously in 1 Corinthians 15:11-22. Without it, there is no salvation. With it, there is a&nbsp;glorious eternity for those who commit themselves to Jesus Christ's truth is based on His resurrection.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/easter-empty-tomb_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/april/biblical-scholar-the-resurrection-of-jesus-points-to-his-deity</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-07T12:50:23-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA['Mayflower Church' Refugees from China Find Safe Haven in US After 3-Year Ordeal]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[All 63 members of a Chinese church who are fleeing persecution from the communist regime are on their way to the United States.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/mayflowerchurch2ap_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/april/mayflower-church-refugees-from-china-find-safe-haven-in-us-after-3-year-ordeal</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-07T11:11:39-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Russia Threatens to Retaliate Against Finland for Joining NATO]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Russia is threatening military and other measures after Finland joined NATO this week. Vladimir Putin is nervous because it ends Finland's era of military non-alignment and doubles the length of NATO's shared border with Russia.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/finlandrussiaas_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/april/russia-threatens-to-retaliate-against-finland-for-joining-nato</link>
      <isVideoArticle>true</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-06T09:13:13-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[McCarthy Meeting with Taiwanese President, China Threatens to 'Fight Back']]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[As the president of Taiwan wraps up her trip to North and Central America, she's finishing off with a high-profile meeting with House Speaker Kevin McCarthy (R) and a bipartisan group of members of Congress. China has been issuing warnings about the meeting, with a promise to "fight back" if it happens.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/taiwansupportap.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/april/mccarthy-meeting-with-taiwanese-president-china-threatens-to-fight-back</link>
      <isVideoArticle>true</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-05T10:18:09-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Members of Exiled Chinese 'Mayflower Church' Detained in Thailand]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[More than 60 exiled members of a Chinese Christian church were detained in Thailand on Saturday, uncertain about their legal status amid fears they would be deported against their will to their home country, where they face persecution.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/mayflowerchurchap_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/april/members-of-exiled-chinese-mayflower-church-detained-in-thailand</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-04T16:04:56-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Finland Officially Joins NATO in Major Blow to Russia Over Ukraine War]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Finland joined the NATO military alliance Tuesday, dealing a major blow to Russian President Vladimir Putin with a historic realignment of Europe's post-Cold War security landscape triggered by Moscow’s invasion of Ukraine.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/finlandnatoap.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/april/finland-officially-joins-nato-in-major-nbsp-blow-to-russia-over-ukraine-war</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-04T15:43:37-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[War-Crimes Warrant for Putin Could Complicate Ukraine Peace]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[An international arrest warrant for President Vladimir Putin raises the prospect of justice for the man whose country invaded Ukraine but complicates efforts to end that war in peace talks. Both justice and peace appear to be only remote possibilities today, but the conflicting relationship between the two is a quandary at the heart of the March 17 decision by the International Criminal Court.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23090707483075.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/april/war-crimes-warrant-for-putin-could-complicate-ukraine-peace</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-03T02:36:02-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA['God Never Changes': Ray Comfort on What It Really Means to 'Fear God']]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Evangelist Ray Comfort believes the “fear of the Lord is key to entering God’s holy presence and receiving his blessings” and the pathway to gaining true wisdom.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/praise.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/april/god-never-changes-ray-comfort-on-what-it-really-means-to-fear-god</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-04-02T12:23:40-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Ex-Gay Man Could Go to Jail After Sharing Testimony of Finding God: 'I Don't Have to Wear That Label Anymore']]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[An ex-LGBT activist reportedly faces&nbsp;potential prison time&nbsp;after sharing his testimony of leaving behind a gay lifestyle to follow Christ.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/matthewgrech_si_0.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/2023/march/ex-gay-man-could-go-to-jail-after-sharing-testimony-of-finding-god-i-dont-have-to-wear-that-label-anymore</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-31T11:33:40-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Turkey's Parliament Ratifies Finland's Membership in NATO]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Turkey’s parliament has ratified Finland’s application to join NATO, lifting the last hurdle to the Nordic country’s long-delayed accession into the Western military alliance. All 276 lawmakers present voted in favor of Finland’s bid Thursday, days after Hungary’s parliament also endorsed Helsinki’s accession. Alarmed by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine a year ago, Finland and Sweden abandoned their decades-long policy of nonalignment and applied to join the alliance.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23089789675781.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/turkeys-parliament-ratifies-finlands-membership-in-nato</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-31T01:19:17-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Russia Arrests Wall Street Journal Reporter on Spying Charge]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Russia’s security service has arrested an American reporter for The Wall Street Journal on espionage charges. It's the first time a U.S. correspondent has been detained on spying accusations since the Cold War. The newspaper denied the allegations and demanded his release. Thirty-one-year-old Evan Gershkovich was detained in Yekaterinburg, Russia’s fourth-largest city, about 1,670 kilometers (1,035 miles) east of Moscow. Russia’s Federal Security Service accused him of trying to obtain classified information.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23089452037695_1.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/russia-arrests-wall-street-journal-reporter-on-spying-charge</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-31T01:01:14-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Russia Stops Sharing Missile Test Info with US, Opens Drills]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A Russian diplomat says Moscow has suspended sharing any information about its nuclear forces with the U.S., including notifications about missile tests as envisioned by a U.S.-Russian treaty that the Kremlin has suspended. Deputy foreign minister Sergei Ryabkov told Russian news agencies that Moscow had halted all information exchanges with Washington,&nbsp;as its military rolled missile launchers across Siberia in a show of the country’s massive nuclear capability amid fighting in Ukraine.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23088362233183.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/russia-stops-sharing-missile-test-info-with-us-opens-drills</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-30T01:07:50-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Vatican: Pope to be Hospitalized for Days for Lung Infection]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Pope Francis was hospitalized with a lung infection Wednesday after experiencing difficulty breathing in recent days and will remain in the hospital for several days of treatment, the Vatican said.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/popefranciscane_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/march/vatican-pope-to-be-hospitalized-for-days-for-lung-infection</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-29T15:08:39-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[38 Dead in Mexico Fire after Guards Didn't Let Migrants Out]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[When smoke began billowing out of a migrant detention center in the Mexican border city of Ciudad Juarez, Venezuelan migrant Viangly Infante Padrón was terrified because she knew her husband was still inside. The father of her three children had been picked up by immigration agents earlier in the day, part of a recent crackdown that netted 67 other migrants, many of whom were asking for handouts or washing car windows at stoplights in this city across from El Paso, Texas.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23087517656090.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/38-dead-in-mexico-fire-after-guards-didnt-let-migrants-out</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-29T03:12:25-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why Does Russia Want Tactical Nuclear Weapons in Belarus?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin has announced that he intends to deploy tactical nuclear weapons on the territory of Belarus. The move appears to be another attempt by Putin to raise the stakes in the conflict in Ukraine. It follows statements by the Russian leader and his top lieutenants that Moscow is ready to use “all available means” to protect its territory.&nbsp;
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/ap23086631540665.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/why-does-russia-want-tactical-nuclear-weapons-in-belarus</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-28T01:27:37-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[UK Preacher Reported as Terrorist After 'Disturbing' 'Misgendering' Arrest Wins BIG After Legal Nightmare]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A Christian pastor in the U.K. arrested and found guilty of harassing and “misgendering” an individual who identifies as transgender recently saw his conviction overturned nearly two years after his legal nightmare began.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/arrest.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/uk-preacher-reported-as-terrorist-after-disturbing-misgendering-arrest-wins-big-after-legal-nightmare</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-26T11:06:17-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[DR. DAVID JEREMIAH: Is the Devil in the Details, or Is God?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The late co-founder and CEO of Apple, Steve Jobs, was well-known (some would say notorious) for his attention to detail when it came to the design of Apple products.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/biblewordofgod_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/march/dr-david-jeremiah-is-the-devil-in-the-details-or-is-god</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-26T10:56:31-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA['Gateways to the Demonic': Pastor Breaks Down Possession, Spiritual Healing, and Biblical Truths About Devil's Most Dangerous Tricks]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[What does it mean to open the door to evil — and what do demonic possession, exorcism, and spiritual healing look like in the modern era?
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/slider/images/fireman.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/cwn/2023/march/gateways-to-the-demonic-pastor-breaks-down-possession-spiritual-healing-and-biblical-truths-about-devils-most-dangerous-tricks</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-26T10:52:32-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[World Athletics Council Bans Transgender Athletes From Competing in Female Sports]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Track and field banned transgender athletes from international competition Thursday, while adopting new regulations that could keep Caster Semenya and other athletes with differences in sex development from competing.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/cbu1032transgender_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/world-athletics-council-bans-transgender-athletes-from-track-and-field</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-23T14:48:52-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Operation Blessing Medical Team Helping in Turkey: 'It's Only Possible Because of Our Donors']]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The government in Turkey is working hard to meet the needs of millions of earthquake victims. Sadly, some victims are falling through the cracks. That's where CBN's Operation Blessing comes in.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/operationblessingturkey2_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/world/2023/march/operation-blessing-medical-team-helping-in-turkey-its-only-possible-because-of-our-donors</link>
      <isVideoArticle>false</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-22T16:34:47-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[US Navy Intel Chief Warns China's 'Messianic' Totalitarian Leader Planning a Taiwan War with USA]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The tiny island of Taiwan is in Beijing's crosshairs with increasing signs of a possible Chinese invasion. The&nbsp;head of U.S. Naval Intelligence warns the communist regime is preparing for a real war against the U.S., and the U.S. is now deploying additional troops to Taiwan.
]]></description>
      <thumbnail><![CDATA[https://www1.cbn.com/sites/default/files/media/standard/images/gtr1127tawancrisis_si.jpg]]></thumbnail>
      <link>http://www.cbn.com/api/urlredirect.aspx?u=http://www1.cbn.com/cbnnews/us/2023/march/us-navy-intel-chief-warns-chinas-messianic-totalitarian-leader-planning-a-taiwan-war-with-usa</link>
      <isVideoArticle>true</isVideoArticle>
      <pubDate>2023-03-22T13:18:14-04:00</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>