<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Vox -  World</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52517/voxv.png</icon>
  <updated>2022-05-04T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.vox.com/rss/world/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world" rel="alternate" />
  <entry>
    <published>2022-05-04T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-04T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Are sanctions against Russia working?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SAq3yALomMLGOvG_GF8SxcEySKE=/0x0:2667x2000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70830260/GettyImages_1239986034_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A McDonald’s restaurant seen closed in Belaya Dacha, outside of Moscow, on April 14. The company has temporarily closed all its restaurants in Russia. | Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The unprecedented penalties are dismantling the Russian economy, even as Moscow tries to find ways to ease the pain. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="K0XufD"&gt;The United States and its allies imposed &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/24/22949324/russia-ukraine-war-sanctions-sberbank-oligarchs"&gt;unprecedented economic sanctions&lt;/a&gt; on Russia in the wake of its full-scale &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/russia-invasion-ukraine"&gt;invasion of Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. The swiftness and intensity of the penalties &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/02/27/world/europe/ruble-russia-stock-market.html"&gt;crashed the ruble&lt;/a&gt;, forced the &lt;a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/russian-stock-market-moex-index-51648063294"&gt;Russian stock market to close&lt;/a&gt;, and sent &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/video/long-lines-at-atms-in-russia-as-ruble-collapses/AB57C6F8-49DD-4C05-88AB-B75CD2EC3A0A.html"&gt;Russians to line up at ATMs &lt;/a&gt;to withdraw dollars from their bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pb52vy"&gt;The Russian economy was in free fall. Until it wasn’t, exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vf6KRI"&gt;The country’s central bank responded by &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/02/28/russia-central-bank-hikes-interest-rates-to-20percent-from-9point5percent-to-bolster-ruble.html"&gt;sharply hiking interest rates to 20 percent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-says-capital-controls-were-tit-for-tat-move-after-reserves-were-frozen-2022-03-25/"&gt;imposing strict capital controls&lt;/a&gt;. Those interventions, along with Russia’s still-intact ability to &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/22/1092591767/despite-u-s-sanctions-oil-traders-help-russian-oil-reach-global-markets#:~:text=Russia%20has%20earned%20more%20than,revenues%20from%20it%2C%20remains%20strong."&gt;sell its oil and gas abroad&lt;/a&gt;, helped create a buffer against the economic chaos&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;after the initial sanctions shock. The measures were “straight out of the country’s economic crisis playbook,” said Adam Smith, a partner at Gibson, Dunn &amp;amp; Crutcher, who worked on sanctions during the Obama administration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yUbLxi"&gt;The economic crisis playbook did its job, and calmed the immediate crisis. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/russian-rouble-hits-more-than-2-year-high-vs-euro-before-steadying-near-77-2022-04-26/"&gt;The ruble stabilized&lt;/a&gt;. That allowed Russia to declare victory over the sanctions onslaught. “The strategy of the economic blitz has failed,” Russian President Vladimir Putin &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/4/18/putin-says-wests-sanctions-blitz-has-failed"&gt;said in April&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZkQml"&gt;At least, that is what Russia would like to claim. Russia’s efforts to shore up its currency mask the profound economic disruptions and transformations that sanctions are unleashing within Russia right now. The West’s sanctions are isolating Russia, cutting it off from key imports that it needs for commercial goods and its own&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;manufacturing to make its economy work. That means high-tech imports like microchips, to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chip-sanctions-challenge-russias-tech-ambitions-11647682202"&gt;develop advanced weaponry&lt;/a&gt;. But&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;it also means &lt;a href="https://interfax.com/newsroom/top-stories/78455/"&gt;buttons for shirts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LDP5Xn"&gt;Right now, there is “this false sense of stability,” said Maria Shagina, a visiting fellow at the Finnish Institute of International Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDONJf"&gt;Russia is facing a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/08/russia-heading-for-worst-recession-since-end-of-cold-war-says-uk"&gt;deep recession&lt;/a&gt;, one the Bank of Russia says will be &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-22/russia-faces-reverse-industrialization-in-sanctions-squeeze"&gt;“of a transformational, structural nature.”&lt;/a&gt; The Finance Ministry &lt;a href="https://www.vedomosti.ru/economics/articles/2022/04/27/919912-parametri-obnovlennogo-makroprognoza"&gt;has predicted the Russian GDP will shrink by about 8.8 percent&lt;/a&gt; in 2022. Inflation is expected to clock in &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/russian-central-bank-lowers-key-rate-14-flags-more-cuts-2022-04-29/#:~:text=(Reuters)%20%2D%20Russia's%20central%20bank,shrinking%20economy%20and%20soaring%20inflation."&gt;as high as 23 percent&lt;/a&gt; this year. Russia is &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/16/business/russia-debt-default.html"&gt;looking at a looming debt default&lt;/a&gt;. All of this will mean hardship for ordinary Russians, &lt;a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/04/28/russians-wartime-disposable-income-drops-inflation-highest-since-1999-a77517"&gt;who are already seeing their real incomes shrink&lt;/a&gt;. Some tens of thousands have tried to flee, &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-putin-immigration-kazakhstan-technology-c041eb0b7472668087bb94207de2f71d"&gt;especially those in tech&lt;/a&gt;, prompting a potential “brain drain.” And these are the things we know; &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/amp/articles/russia-blocks-economic-data-hiding-effect-of-western-sanctions-11650677765"&gt;Russia will cease publishing a lot of economic data&lt;/a&gt;, a tactic, experts said, Moscow has used before to obscure the effects of sanctions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bq2ZY2"&gt;These sanctions, said Yakov Feygin, a political economy expert at the Berggruen Institute, are pushing Russia — a modern economy, integrated around the globe — back decades and decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nnHIgt"&gt;“They’ve stabilized it, they’ve taken emergency measures. That was to be expected. But that’s not going to help them in the long run,” Feygin said of Russia. “You’re not going to see people queuing for food for quite a bit. But with the current course of things, it’s still very possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DlWdnd"&gt;The US and European allies have continued to pile on more penalties, refining and sharpening the sanctions, all in an effort to ratchet up the pressure on Moscow. The EU has proposed a phase-out of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/05/04/world/ukraine-russia-war-news?campaign_id=60&amp;amp;emc=edit_na_20220504&amp;amp;instance_id=0&amp;amp;nl=breaking-news&amp;amp;ref=cta&amp;amp;regi_id=86419414&amp;amp;segment_id=91193&amp;amp;user_id=72df3a03b331f442d9ef463ea0eac169#eu-russia-oil-ban"&gt;Russian oil products&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and depending on the final details, that might further erode the Kremlin’s lifeline. And the US could take additional steps, like threatening secondary sanctions that go after countries like China or India, to deter them from buying cheap Russian energy. That &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22916773/russia-ukraine-sanctions-putin"&gt;comes at a cost&lt;/a&gt;, and not just for Russia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7PmOGC"&gt;Even without more escalation, the sanctions regime against Russia is one of the most aggressive in history, untested on an economy of Russia’s size and as entangled in the global financial system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beexu5"&gt;Whether the sanctions are “working,” then, depends on what they are intended to achieve. One thing is clear:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Over time, these sanctions will likely make it harder for Russia to rebuild its tanks, manufacture cruise missiles, and finance a war. It will also make it harder to produce food and make cars. And it still may not &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/22/23034480/russia-donbas-new-phase-war-ukraine-explained"&gt;stop Russia from pursuing its campaign against Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;, all with unpredictable consequences for the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ji13BI"&gt;What Russia did (and what the West didn’t) to deal with the sanctions shock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oHcFFt"&gt;The US and allies &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22916773/russia-ukraine-sanctions-putin"&gt;threatened&lt;/a&gt; sanctions against Russia should it invade Ukraine. It was always a question of how far the West might go, largely because of concerns on how some of the pain might rebound, economically and politically, onto &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22916773/russia-ukraine-sanctions-putin"&gt;the US and its allies&lt;/a&gt;. But the West moved swiftly and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22968949/russia-sanctions-swift-economy-mcdonalds"&gt;more forcefully&lt;/a&gt; than many expected, a reaction to the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/4/3/23009048/russian-troops-retreat-in-ukraine-civilian-deaths-discovered"&gt;brutality of Moscow’s assault&lt;/a&gt;, the ferocity of Ukraine’s resistance, and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/zelenskyys-personal-plea-helped-accelerate-eu-aid/"&gt;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy’s pointed pleas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lV26QS"&gt;After the US and EU &lt;a href="https://2009-2017.state.gov/e/eb/tfs/spi/ukrainerussia/index.htm"&gt;put targeted sanctions on Russia in 2014 after its Crimea annexation and Donbas invasion&lt;/a&gt;, the Russian government took measures to sanction-proof-ish its economy — &lt;a href="https://www.bne.eu/russia-s-reserves-ended-2021-at-an-all-time-high-of-630-5bn-230680/?source=russia"&gt;like building up some $640 billion in gold and foreign reserves&lt;/a&gt;. Yet the intensity of these latest Ukraine sanctions rattled Russia’s &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/energy/how-is-russias-fortress-economy-really-faring/2022/04/18/0ea37ee2-beef-11ec-b5df-1fba61a66c75_story.html"&gt;“fortress”&lt;/a&gt; economy. And in some cases, the West’s measures directly targeted Russia’s backup plan; sanctions on Russia’s central bank, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/russia-admits-it-cant-access-nearly-half-foreign-currency-reserves-2022-3"&gt;prevented Russia from accessing about half of those foreign reserves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i8i9H7"&gt;Even so, Russia reacted aggressively once those sanctions hit. “They have done textbook defensive policies to retain capital and stabilize the currency and avoid a financial crisis,” said Rachel Ziemba, an economic and political risk expert and adjunct senior fellow at the Center for a New American Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1I7DBM"&gt;Take the ruble, which President Joe Biden declared reduced to &lt;a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/mocked-rubble-biden-russia-ruble-193615066.html"&gt;“rubble.”&lt;/a&gt; In the aftermath of sanctions, its value crashed. It suddenly took a lot more rubles to buy, say, one US dollar. You really&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;wouldn’t want rubles, then, because you wouldn’t have as much purchasing power. So the Russian central bank sought to create demand for rubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qqaxlw"&gt;The central bank did so through a series of &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/russias-response-western-sanctions-over-ukraine-2022-03-02/"&gt;measures&lt;/a&gt;. That included raising interest rates, an incentive for Russians to save their money. The bank implemented a series of capital controls that targeted Russian businesses and individuals. For example, companies that export things or do business abroad &lt;a href="https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-ruble-weakens-sharply/31797010.html"&gt;had to convert 80 percent of their foreign exchange revenues to rubles&lt;/a&gt;. It also limited the amount of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/russia-ukraine-latest-news-2022-03-09/card/moscow-limits-foreign-currency-trading-to-shore-up-struggling-ruble-dgTDTQdEOkO3wgoFyC3I"&gt;money Russians could transfer abroad&lt;/a&gt; or remove from foreign bank accounts — currently no more than $10,000 over the next six months. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KsIQwV7NcBsUlqtwBiw_JiZglYI=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23433802/Screen_Shot_2022_05_02_at_5.07.17_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.google.com/finance/quote/RUB-USD?hl=en&amp;amp;window=6M" target="_blank"&gt;Google Finance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Russian ruble to USD exchange rate over the past six months.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AfqMxA"&gt;Those are policies the Russian central bank engineered, but Russia has also benefited from the fact that it &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-01/putin-may-collect-321-billion-windfall-if-oil-gas-keep-flowing"&gt;is still exporting a lot of oil and gas&lt;/a&gt;, including to places like Europe, &lt;a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/europe-grapples-with-2-crises-connected-to-gas-war-warming/#:~:text=Under%20the%20agreement%2C%20the%20European,Europe%20currently%20imports%20from%20Russia."&gt;which gets more than one-third of its natural gas imports from Russia.&lt;/a&gt; That money — &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/03/23/putin-wants-unfriendly-countries-to-pay-for-russian-gas-in-roubles.html"&gt;hundreds of millions per day from the European Union alone&lt;/a&gt; — is coming into the Kremlin’s coffers, and their ability to replenish funds gives the economy a cushion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UBuEjr"&gt;This is partly why Putin started demanding “unfriendly countries” &lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/russia-demands-natural-gas-payments-in-rubles-leaves-a-loophole"&gt;pay for natural gas in rubles&lt;/a&gt;, as it would help prop up Russia’s currency. But it’s also why, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/26/energy/poland-russia-gas/index.html"&gt;until his shutoff to Poland and Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/germany-top-buyer-of-russian-energy-since-ukraine-invasion-began-report/a-61616274"&gt;who are far from the biggest consumers of Russian gas&lt;/a&gt;), Putin wasn’t enforcing it because it might &lt;a href="https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-putin-ruble-gas-payments/31774413.html"&gt;require contract renegotiations&lt;/a&gt;, and that might incentivize EU countries to start the process of weaning themselves off Russian hydrocarbons altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y3aRpr"&gt;Neither sophisticated Russian central bankers nor energy can fully save the Russian economy in the long run. As Smith said, this is the economic crisis playbook. “The problem with that playbook, of course, is that it runs a course,” Smith said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kw3puZ"&gt;These measures are painful, which makes them harder to sustain. Russia has slightly eased some of its interventions, inching down interest rates &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-29/bank-of-russia-delivers-another-big-rate-cut-with-eye-on-economy"&gt;to a (still high) 14 percent&lt;/a&gt;. It also loosened some capital controls, but that also &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/rouble-falls-sharply-russia-relaxes-some-capital-controls-2022-04-11/"&gt;knocked the value of the ruble&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QXUIj"&gt;Oil and gas revenues help, &lt;a href="https://qz.com/2160717/a-total-european-ban-on-russian-oil-is-coming/"&gt;but if sanctions against energy tighten&lt;/a&gt;, as with with the EU’s proposal for a gradual oil ban,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;or Russia is forced to sell its gas on the cheap — or if the threat of running afoul of sanctions &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/russia-tried-to-sell-a-huge-slug-of-oil-nobody-wanted-it-11650995897"&gt;deters even the bargain hunters&lt;/a&gt; — the safety net frays over time. Russia has already said &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/exclusive-russia-sees-its-oil-output-falling-by-up-17-2022-document-2022-04-27/#:~:text=Oil%20exports%20are%20seen%20declining,231%20million%20tonnes%20in%202021."&gt;oil output is expected to decline&lt;/a&gt; as sanctions hinder investments and trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mSCcAu"&gt;“There was an initial shock,” Feygin said. “It’s over, but it’s not better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="oRk5cI"&gt;The toll of Russian sanctions, so far&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="QopNm6"&gt;Russia wants everyone to want rubles. But there isn’t much Russia can do with all those rubles because sanctions block those transactions or make them way too expensive. “The money itself matters, but also how you can use it — both in terms of who your counterparts are, and physically, how you can move it around — matters much more,” said Edoardo Saravalle, a sanctions researcher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jFspv9"&gt;Moscow can’t buy some foreign goods because of&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;controls on critical items like microchips. Those restrictions&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will directly undermine Russia’s technology and defense sectors, making it difficult to continue developing weaponry or tools like artificial intelligence, or even &lt;a href="https://kyivindependent.com/uncategorized/russian-companies-specializing-in-tank-repair-suspend-operations-due-to-supply-shortages/"&gt;repair damaged tanks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ke92Fx"&gt;Even if items are not explicitly banned, the web of financial sanctions can make it difficult to do transactions, and often it’s easier for Western companies to self-sanction to avoid running afoul of any possible penalties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6EC9xG"&gt;And sanctions&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;have revealed how reliant Russia is on imported goods and products, not just for the things the country’s populace buys, but for the things it needs for the products it makes and sells at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhFsoq"&gt;All of that means Russia’s economy will become more isolated over time.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Data from other countries has shown that it is already beginning to happen, as imports to Russia are crashing. For example, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/sanctions-hit-trade-harder-than-soviet-collapse-finnish-customs-says-2022-03-23/"&gt;Finland’s exports to Russia&lt;/a&gt; are down 60 percent; &lt;a href="https://theovershoot.co/p/korean-exports-to-russia-have-collapsed?s=r"&gt;South Korea’s are down&lt;/a&gt; about 62 percent&lt;a href="https://theovershoot.co/p/korean-exports-to-russia-have-collapsed?s=r"&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OjWReu"&gt;Russian planes &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/us-cracks-down-russian-airlines-after-flights-violated-export-controls-2022-04-07/"&gt;are now mostly limited to domestic flights&lt;/a&gt; because of sanctions, but because a lot of the jets in Russia are made by Western companies like Boeing, Russia can’t get spare parts or maintenance, leaving it to &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/03/13/1086219973/sanctions-may-ground-russias-planes-but-the-firms-that-own-them-cant-get-them-ba"&gt;recycle parts from grounded planes&lt;/a&gt; or cut back the flights it still has. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-official-says-export-curbs-russia-hit-car-production-tank-building-2022-03-30/"&gt;Car companies can’t get parts&lt;/a&gt;, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7zY6Wo"&gt;Companies can’t get &lt;a href="https://interfax.com/newsroom/top-stories/76646/"&gt;bleaching reagents for paper&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2022/3/23/russia-looks-for-baby-food-packaging-suppliers-as-sanctions-bite"&gt;packaging for baby food&lt;/a&gt;. One report from a Russian business outlet said that 90 percent of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/b_nishanov/status/1515272029137776640?s=20&amp;amp;t=1lPkkifwrYt_x9V4eEUGrA"&gt;Russian bread makers rely on parts from Europe&lt;/a&gt;; their current replacements will only last months. Russia’s garment industry got a lot of buttons from the European Union. As &lt;a href="https://interfax.com/newsroom/top-stories/78455/"&gt;Elvira Nabiullina, the governor of Russia’s central bank&lt;/a&gt;, said, finding new buttons is possible, it just takes time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W8ld77"&gt;All of this cascades across the economy. If a car company can’t get parts, it may have to temporarily shutter and its employees will lose income. If the bakers can’t fix their mixers, it may mean bread shortages. If Russia can’t get semiconductors or chips for computers or communications systems, it will have to make equipment that is less technologically and economically efficient. A report from the Bank of Russia called what Russia is facing &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-22/russia-faces-reverse-industrialization-in-sanctions-squeeze"&gt;“reverse industrialization.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtiX03"&gt;The US and its allies also keep adding more sanctions. So far, they are not as sweeping as what happened in the early days of the war, but instead are more incremental, building on what was already in place. For example, after the discoveries of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/04/world/europe/bucha-ukraine-bodies.html"&gt;the Bucha massacre&lt;/a&gt;, the US closed a loophole on &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/22/1094240449/russia-could-default-on-its-foreign-debt-for-the-first-time-in-a-century"&gt;Russia’s sovereign debt payment&lt;/a&gt; that might now force Russia to default on its foreign debt for the first time in more than a century. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/germany-drops-opposition-to-russian-oil-embargo-11651155915"&gt;Europe is reportedly ready to move on a gradual oil embargo&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a cumulative tightening that gives Russia fewer and fewer options out of the catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r084Z3"&gt;Ordinary Russians, too, have fewer options. They are the ones who will feel the real crush of sanctions. Overall, experts said, Russians are likely worse off than they were two months ago. “People are seeing a squeeze on their real incomes, that’s the main effect that ordinary Russians are feeling,” said Jacob Nell, former chief Russia economist and head of European economics at Morgan Stanley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZ90TA"&gt;Ziemba said, at the outset, relatively well-off Muscovites might have felt the shock of sanctions most sharply — &lt;a href="https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-it-workers-brain-drain/31783558.html"&gt;like those who worked in tech&lt;/a&gt; or who had a nice chunk of change in a foreign bank account. This is partly what prompted tens of thousands of people to flee, a &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-60697763"&gt;“brain drain” depleting Russia&lt;/a&gt; of those who might be best able to help Russia recover, whenever that might be. Still, the sanctions have now made it even harder for those people to leave. There are few planes to take you anywhere, and Russians can’t take out more than $10,000 in foreign money from their accounts, making it hard to start a new life, wherever you might go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7XMSKt"&gt;Yet many of those middle- and upper-class Russians — with resources at the start of this crisis — are the people best able to withstand sustained sanctions pressure in the longer term. Russia’s most vulnerable will feel the sanctions’ pain most acutely, watching their incomes shrink, struggling to pay for goods, and seeing services fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XxdW6D"&gt;As Shagina said, those on Russia’s periphery were always an afterthought, and they will be the ones who suffer the most. “If you look at the people who were sent to fight the war in Ukraine, and they’re from the Far East. And because they were poor, I think their situation will be even worse,” she said. That is, the Russians who have the least power may be punished the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1OMqZx"&gt;So are Russian sanctions working? Well, it depends on the goal.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PN67LG"&gt;The longer sanctions stay in place, the worse it will be. “We’re ultimately looking at an economy that is shrinking, is turning more inward,” Ziemba said.&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B5YebW"&gt;Russia may figure out how to navigate as a permanently state-sanctioned economy — like an Iran or a North Korea. “These economies, they don’t just stop, they kind of slow down and stumble,” Saravalle said. “But often, I think in the popular perception, there was this point where the economy just collapses — and there isn’t necessarily. Past sanctions programs haven’t had these types of collapses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZuT6Dt"&gt;Russia will find &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/russia-legalizes-shady-imports-of-amd-intel-and-apple-goods-to-dodge-sanctions"&gt;workarounds where it can&lt;/a&gt;. It will substitute for supply chains, many of which will be murky, and help fuel a dark economy. Living standards may erode to levels not seen in decades, and the things Russians buy may be more poorly made and harder to get. “Cuba refurbishes old cars for a reason,” Feygin said. In early April, after the Biden administration tightened sanctions, a senior Biden administration official told reporters that, at this rate, Russia “will go back to Soviet-style standards from the 1980s.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u7wXlr"&gt;That will not likely happen in the immediate future, but it is the course Russia is on, for as long as the West keeps it there. But the question is: What does the West actually want to achieve by doing this? Before the invasion, the Biden administration &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/blinken-sanctioning-russia-41450155-7aa7-4f87-a336-fdc83bd33209.html"&gt;framed the threat of sanctions as a way to deter Russia from invading Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. It did not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sSbn4m"&gt;In the wake of the invasion, the goal was framed as “inflicting pain on Russia and supporting the people of Ukraine,” which is how Biden put it in his &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/03/01/joe-biden-state-of-the-union-address-live-updates.html"&gt;State of the Union.&lt;/a&gt; He also talked about depleting Russia’s military, making it harder to wage war in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VaN5Jq"&gt;The Biden administration has also indicated that certain sanctions are trying to squeeze Russia, eroding its ability to &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/fact-sheet-united-states-g7-and-eu-impose-severe-and-immediate-costs-on-russia/"&gt;finance its war in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. This month, Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said that the US “wants to see Russia weakened to the degree that it &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/27/1094970683/u-s-war-aims-shift-in-ukraine-and-bring-additional-risks"&gt;can’t do the kinds of things that it has done in invading Ukraine.”&lt;/a&gt; The administration hopes to accomplish that through a combination of sanctions on Russia and aid for Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O0X8Q2"&gt;But it’s less clear what a “weakened” Russia means, and what the United States and allies would do with it. Are they using the pressure to get Russia to the negotiating table? Are they trying to stop the war by getting Russia to withdraw or surrender? Or to defeat it? And what are the consequences of that? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JscsbG"&gt;If this is an indefinite effort to weaken Russia, it may get harder to keep up the intensity. The US and its allies acted in cohesion and got enormous buy-in from other partners, including in Asia. But as the war drags on and sanctions continue, that coalition may fracture, especially if the economic costs mount beyond Russia’s borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nCHoxw"&gt;Poorer countries will experience the shock of these economic sanctions, without having much say at all in whether or not they will support these policies. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/global-ukraine-agriculture/feature-as-ukraine-war-hikes-prices-global-south-farmers-struggle-to-find-fertilizer-idUSL5N2VV599"&gt;Farmers in Brazil&lt;/a&gt; need fertilizer from Russia, &lt;a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/make-in-india-iaf-mi-17-choppers-russia-1938341-2022-04-16"&gt;countries that depend on Russian arms exports&lt;/a&gt; all of a sudden won’t have parts or equipment for themselves, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkL9Fq"&gt;As experts said, the United States and its allies may also need to mitigate the pain for these countries, promising to help replace arms at a discount or offer food aid. The US’s latest request to Congress for $33 billion in supplemental aid to Ukraine partially acknowledged this, including funding for global food assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7mwa7X"&gt;The sanctions on Russia are unraveling its economy. But this act of extreme economic pressure will have consequences beyond Russia. “It’s a form of economic war,” Saravalle said. “But it’s also very much like we’re reshaping the global economy.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/23049187/russia-sanctions-ukraine-ruble" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/23049187/russia-sanctions-ukraine-ruble</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jen Kirby</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-05-01T17:24:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-01T17:24:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Was Russia’s decision to cut off natural gas exports a mistake?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vladimir Putin, Narendra Modi, and Xi Jinping stand together with hands linked in front of a row of flags." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Up8qecVFiZY5_fz_PIDBtD14FU=/0x0:3369x2527/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70819961/1152483138.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin links hands with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping at the G20 Osaka Summit in 2019. | Mikhail Svetlov/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Despite Western sanctions, the country still maintains powerful friends — for now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="2K007S"&gt;Last week, Russia announced it would cut off natural gas deliveries to Poland and Bulgaria after both countries refused to comply with its request to perform export payments in rubles, Russia’s national currency. It is the latest maneuver off the battlefield to hit back against Western efforts to weaken the country even as its armed forces &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/videos/news/world/2022/04/30/russian-troops-slowed-down-ukrainian-defense-donbas-region/9598036002/"&gt;continue to be slowed&lt;/a&gt; by Ukrainian troops in the embattled &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/22/23034480/russia-donbas-new-phase-war-ukraine-explained"&gt;eastern territory of Donbas&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FxB6px"&gt;Russia has largely been able to maintain diplomatic relationships in the Asia-Pacific region with China and India, its biggest partners, despite Western sanctions. But its decision to cut off energy exports has strengthened Europe’s alliance with the US, particularly as Europe continues deliberations over added sanctions against Russia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9D4os6"&gt;The Kremlin &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/28/1095113387/what-russia-cutting-off-energy-to-poland-and-bulgaria-means-for-the-world"&gt;defended&lt;/a&gt; the move as a necessary measure to protect Russia’s financial reserves following heavy sanctions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhEJRp"&gt;“They blocked our accounts, or — to put in Russian — they ‘stole’ a significant portion of our reserves,” Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov told the media during a press call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUSGOo"&gt;Europe imports a third of its oil and gas from Russia but that has not deterred it from using sanctions as a tool to stop the country’s aggression in Ukraine. The European Union has already put out five rounds of economic sanctions against Russia and is expected to introduce more penalties in the upcoming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9tkmi"&gt;Russia’s decision to cut off gas exports to Poland and Bulgaria — the latter of which had remained undecided in its stance regarding Russia up until the recent ban — is a risky move meant to act as a warning to other European countries. But some experts have written off the move as a miscalculation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0V5cL3"&gt;According to Yoshiko Herrera, a professor of political science at the University of Wisconsin-Madison specializing in Eurasian politics, it may have the opposite intended effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqx5th"&gt;“One of the key arguments for people who are for the additional energy sanctions is to say, Russia is an untrustworthy partner, that they’re using energy as a political tool,” said Herrera. “So by cutting off gas to Poland and Bulgaria, they’re kind of making the case that they are an unreliable partner.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGmPAG"&gt;Although no formal proposals have been put forth, Bloomberg &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-30/eu-to-propose-phasing-out-russian-oil-by-the-end-of-the-year"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; the EU will likely introduce a ban on Russian oil by the end of the year, gradually limiting its imports until then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="18KZCQ"&gt;“Full European energy sanctions would really hurt [Russia’s] economy and hurt their ability to wage war because they will run out of money. So that, I think, is something Russia has to be worried about,” Herrera said. “Their continued bad behavior in Ukraine, the atrocities are what is I think pushing Europe to quite radically change positions on things, on energy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="H3eNbj"&gt;Russia has maintained some global support since its invasion of Ukraine&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Large black screens hovering above crowds show white text with the UN vote to remove Russia from Human Rights Council." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bDafYmogtoHT-ggmNMlcU3C30fY=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23430957/1239809346.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Screens show passage of the UN’s resolution to remove Russia from the UN Human Rights Council following a vote by the General Assembly on April 7, 2022.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="15gN3z"&gt;Despite Western powers’ broad condemnation of and efforts to isolate Russia, the country has managed to maintain ties and partnerships elsewhere around the world. In April, the UN General Assembly voted on a resolution to suspend Russia from the Human Rights Council over its invasion of Ukraine. The resolution succeeded after it &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/04/1115782"&gt;received&lt;/a&gt; a two-thirds majority of votes from member states with 93 nations voting in favor of Russia’s suspension from the body. But 24 of the body’s members voted against the action while 58 members abstained from the vote altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0nWW0"&gt;Results of the UN vote signify the complexities of real-world diplomacy even in the face of war. Countries in Africa, South America, and Asia have increasingly sought to resist taking sides as the Russia-Ukraine war threatens to shape the world into political factions. But the West’s waning influence in other parts of the globe, combined with economic and political interests at stake, has resulted in many nations &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/24/world/asia/cold-war-ukraine.html"&gt;opting to maintain their independence&lt;/a&gt; when it comes to relations with Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5IGyGI"&gt;In Asia, where growing vigilance over China’s increasing influence is shared across borders, nations in the southeast and the south of the continent have &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/ukraine-response-asia-us-russia-china-rcna17976"&gt;expressed&lt;/a&gt; their intentions to remain on good terms with Russia in spite of the situation with Ukraine. Among Russia’s most loyal partners is India, with whom it has maintained a strong relationship since the Soviet Union’s backing of India during the 1971 war with Pakistan, even as India remained officially non-aligned during the Cold War. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vd0qGb"&gt;Another factor behind their continued friendship is India’s &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6c52b083-d38a-40c9-9e23-2747c913065f"&gt;reliance&lt;/a&gt; on Russia as a military arms supplier — from the 1950s to now the country has received &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6c52b083-d38a-40c9-9e23-2747c913065f"&gt;an estimated 65 percent&lt;/a&gt; of firearms exports from the Soviet Union or Russia, according to the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute. India’s border disputes in the Himalayas with China, which triggered a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/07/18/world/asia/china-india-border-conflict.html"&gt;bloody clash&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, is another motivating factor for India as Russia has functioned as an important mediator in the conflict with China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMIuQr"&gt;China, another key Russian partner, has refrained from condemning Russia outright, instead asking for the warring countries to reach a peaceful resolution. In a March virtual meeting with France and Germany, President Xi Jinping &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/3/9/chinas-xi-beijing-supports-peace-talks-between-russia-ukraine"&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; for “maximum restraint” on the issue and expressed concerns over the broader impact of sanctions on Russia. But some, like Herrera, doubt how far China will continue to toe the line if the situation worsens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rJ7laA"&gt;“China has not said they would not abide by the sanctions and they are so far going along with the sanctions against Russia,” Herrera said. A potential turning point, she said, could be Europe’s next sanctions, particularly any secondary sanctions it puts out, which will be “a big crossroads for China to decide whether to participate with those.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XjsZGF"&gt;But its ties with Russia could still end up serving China economically. President Vladimir Putin has &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/60571253"&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; Russia will “redirect” its energy exports to “rapidly growing markets” elsewhere to help buttress against sanctions, perhaps an effort to maintain support from its key ally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="j7rgeH"&gt;Russian forces continue to face military hurdles in Ukraine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7qoDcU"&gt;After two months of conflict, tensions on the war front between Russia and Ukraine have shown no signs of de-escalating. Russian armed forces have shifted focus in recent weeks to &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/ukraine-kyiv-police-find-bound-men-in-bucha-as-russia-continues-eastern-assault-as-it-happened/a-61643081"&gt;take control of eastern Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;, referred to as the Donbas territory, where fighting between Ukraine troops and Russia-backed separatists had been ongoing since 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4P48CO"&gt;Russia has also continued its advance on Kyiv, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/29/russia-carries-out-airstrike-on-kyiv-during-un-chief-visit-ukraine-antonio-guterres"&gt;launching an airstrike&lt;/a&gt; on the capital city last week during a diplomatic visit by UN Secretary-General António Guterres. The attack drew wide condemnation as an unnecessary act of aggression by Russian forces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bCcomr"&gt;Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy, who met with Guterres during his capital visit, accused Russia of deliberately trying to humiliate the UN. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6ZFRb"&gt;“It says a lot about Russia’s true attitude to global institutions, about the efforts of the Russian leadership to humiliate the UN and everything that the organization represents. It requires a strong response,” Zelenskyy &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/29/russia-carries-out-airstrike-on-kyiv-during-un-chief-visit-ukraine-antonio-guterres"&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; in a public address following the airstrike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IWEpXZ"&gt;Former UN Deputy Secretary-General Mark Malloch-Brown said the international community “will recognize they cannot have their UN secretary-general treated in this disrespectful, casual and frankly, dangerous way, by Putin.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hGMMl"&gt;As the conflict shows no signs of relenting, last week US President Joe Biden &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/28/politics/biden-ukraine-congress/index.html"&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; Congress to send another $33 billion in military aid to support Ukraine’s military defenses. Biden’s proposal, which includes strategies to potentially use seized funds from Russian oligarchs to fund Ukraine’s military operations, is more than twice as much as the $13.6 billion worth of military and humanitarian aid already approved by Congress last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwTGeN"&gt;Herrera believes that extra boost could be extremely helpful to Ukraine, both strategically and physically, even this far into the war. Combined with energy sanctions by Europe, she said Russia could be looking at significant roadblocks to achieving its objectives since “that would make a big difference in Russia’s ability to fight the war.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZQQLr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, May 2, 11:50 am:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; A previous version of this article misstated Russia’s relationship with China and India. They maintain close partnerships and have bilateral friendship and cooperation agreements but do not have official military alliances.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Vy1sw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/5/1/23051868/russias-natural-gas-exports-india-china-ukraine" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/5/1/23051868/russias-natural-gas-exports-india-china-ukraine</id>
    <author>
      <name>Natasha Ishak</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-30T17:04:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T17:04:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>The economic crisis in Sri Lanka, explained</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VMrEnfEqzAFGTPb4kwBjfME5Orw=/317x0:5384x3800/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70816907/1240346996.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Protesters take part in an anti-government demonstration near the president’s office in Colombo, Sri Lanka, on April 30, demanding President Gotabaya Rajapaksa’s resignation over the country’s crippling economic crisis. | Ishara S. Kodikara/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A mountain of foreign debt has led the country to default on loans for the first time since its 1948 independence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="lNqYJ3"&gt;After a month of intense civilian-led protests over Sri Lanka’s deteriorating economy, President Gotabaya Rajapaksa agreed to appoint a new council on Friday to lead the formation of an interim government. The resolution would create a coalition made up of all parties in Parliament and would remove the grip of the Rajapaksa family dynasty currently ruling the country. At issue is the country’s economic future, which is in shambles after defaulting on payments on its mountain of foreign loans — estimated to be worth $50 billion — &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-international-monetary-fund-sri-lanka-foreign-debt-f48b3cfb388c3a11af5d2d8a3d1a4391"&gt;for the first time&lt;/a&gt; since the country gained independence from the British in 1948.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwUNv0"&gt;Signs of Sri Lanka’s impending economic crisis became increasingly apparent over the last two years of the Covid-19 pandemic as &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/25/world/asia/sri-lanka-economic-crisis.html"&gt;food prices soared and power blackouts&lt;/a&gt; increased in frequency. Sri Lanka currently has about $7 billion in total debt due this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oPiftU"&gt;Many attribute Sri Lanka’s economic crisis to the mishandling of its finances by successive governments through mounting foreign debt and continued infrastructure investments. The Rajapaksa administration also implemented &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/b6b96849ebe74c8dbeac461ff8418c28"&gt;sweeping tax cuts in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, slashing the value-added tax (VAT) rate — the tax applied to imports and domestic supplies — from 15 percent to 8 percent, which contributed to a decrease in the country’s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5AeRD"&gt;The president’s older brother, Mahinda Rajapaksa, is expected to be removed as prime minister as part of an agreement brokered by former President Maithripala Sirisena, who defected with dozens of other members of the incumbent president’s governing party in April in protest of the Rajapaksas’ poor governing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5vuOLd"&gt;But the country’s power struggle may have sown discord between the two brothers which could exacerbate its political impasse. On Friday, the Associated Press &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-biden-cabinet-sri-lanka-maithripala-sirisena-bc8ed130537eb090b9bc648b1b470d76"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; a spokesperson for the prime minister did not immediately confirm the elder Rajapaksa’s removal, saying that any such decisions would be announced by the prime minister in due time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="SXJypo"&gt;The country continued to mount foreign debt without sufficient revenue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4JSlaL"&gt;A big part of Sri Lanka’s economic woes is its ballooning foreign debt, namely to fund its aggressive turn to infrastructure development under former President Mahinda Rajapaksa, the elder Rajapaksa sibling and two-time prime minister. With its finances already bleeding, Sri Lanka took out major investment loans from state-owned Chinese banks to fund its infrastructure projects including a controversial port development in the Hambantota district. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xd1AD7"&gt;The Sri Lankan government justified the Hambantota project as a way to grow its economy as a bustling trade hub comparable to Singapore. However, the project was riddled with corruption and stalled, and Sri Lanka eventually &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/world/asia/china-sri-lanka-port.html"&gt;handed over the port’s control&lt;/a&gt; to China as collateral after it was unable to pay back its loans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EfRhuy"&gt;Over the last decade, Sri Lanka amassed &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/25/world/asia/china-sri-lanka-port.html"&gt;a debt of $5 billion to China&lt;/a&gt; alone, making up a large portion of its overall foreign debt, according to the New York Times. Sri Lanka’s bloated debt to China and the Hambantota project failure are often held up as an example of the “debtbook diplomacy” that China has pursued in the last couple of decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RETbob"&gt;Some believe China has expanded that monetary diplomacy approach through its ambitious Belt and Road Initiative (BRI), a global infrastructure project involving Chinese investment in infrastructure developments in parts of Asia, Africa, and Europe, as part of China’s bid to increase global influence as a growing economic power. The number of countries that have signed onto China’s BRI project is unclear, but is somewhere between &lt;a href="https://www.cfr.org/blog/countries-chinas-belt-and-road-initiative-whos-and-whos-out"&gt;139&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://greenfdc.org/countries-of-the-belt-and-road-initiative-bri/"&gt;146&lt;/a&gt;, including Sri Lanka. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GwVAuU"&gt;While an infrastructure project on such a global scale may provide some economic benefits to the participating countries, the BRI has become a strategic way for China to gain political leverage with economically vulnerable countries across the Asia-Pacific region. At least 16 countries involved in the BRI project have been saddled with billions of dollars of debt which China then has leveraged, according to an &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/may/15/warning-sounded-over-chinas-debtbook-diplomacy"&gt;independent analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Harvard Kennedy School for the US State Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ijWy8"&gt;About &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/04/01/india-tries-to-pry-sri-lanka-loose-from-chinas-embrace.html"&gt;22 percent of Sri Lanka’s debt&lt;/a&gt; is owed to bilateral creditors — institutional investors from foreign governments — according to CNBC. Neighboring India has sought to grow its bilateral cooperation with Sri Lanka partly as an attempt to secure its influence in South Asia over China. India recently &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/exclusive-sri-lanka-seeks-additional-1-billion-credit-line-india-sources-2022-03-28/"&gt;gave Sri Lanka a $1.5 billion credit line&lt;/a&gt; to tide over the country’s fuel crisis in addition to another $2.4 billion through a currency swap and loan deferment since January. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KPd5aL"&gt;As the country amassed foreign debt, its tourism sector — previously &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/sri-lanka-tourism-plummets-after-bombings/4904347.html"&gt;a $4.4 billion industry&lt;/a&gt; and a primary revenue source for the island — took successive hits. In 2019, tourism suffered after &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/interactive/2019/04/world/sri-lanka-attacks/"&gt;a series of church bombings&lt;/a&gt; that killed nearly 300 people, including some foreign nationals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XC8Biv"&gt;The next year, the Covid-19 pandemic halted tourism and other major sectors, spurring a global economic downturn. Although Sri Lanka saw some increase in its number of foreign visitors last year, the ongoing pandemic combined with Russia’s invasion of Ukraine — both nations &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/4/6/crisis-hit-sri-lanka-is-hosting-thousands-of-stranded-ukrainians"&gt;leading sources of tourism&lt;/a&gt; for Sri Lanka before the conflict — continued to slow the industry’s recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DjBh4o"&gt;A worsening crisis triggered mass protests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="W4vs3u"&gt;The country’s issues escalated in March when the Sri Lankan government &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/3/31/sri-lanka-crisis-forces-13-hour-blackouts-hospitals-stop-surgery"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a 13-hour daily power cut as a way to save energy amid the ongoing crisis. Without sufficient power, many were unable to do their jobs as the economic crisis continued, prompting mass unrest. Thousands of Sri Lankans took to the streets in the weeks following the power cuts to protest the country’s growing crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXdNi0"&gt;On April 1, President Rajapaksa declared an emergency as growing unrest&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;saw protesters clash with police. The entire Sri Lankan government Cabinet &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/04/1090753152/sri-lanka-offers-resignations-as-public-anger-grows-over-economic-crisis"&gt;resigned in protest&lt;/a&gt; not long after the emergency law was implemented, causing Rajapaksa to revoke the law. Among those who resigned was Sports Minister Namal Rajapaksa, another member of the Rajapaksa family and the president’s nephew. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cgk2gZ"&gt;With growing political unrest and no resolution in sight, Rajapaksa’s rivals began calls for a no-confidence vote against his administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wvaDYa"&gt;“We are confident we have the numbers and we will bring the motion at the appropriate time,” opposition lawmaker Harsha de Silva &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/04/18/sri-lankan-opposition-to-table-no-confidence-vote-against-government-.html"&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; CNBC. Hoping to placate critics, President Rajapaksa sought to form a new unity coalition under his leadership but failed to gain support. In April, the government also announced it would temporarily suspend foreign debt payments, marking the first time Sri Lanka had defaulted on foreign loans since its independence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bNWTGc"&gt;Experts had been warning of a potentially dire situation for the country’s finances for some time. When the country defaulted, the government had been &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-61145854"&gt;negotiating a bailout plan&lt;/a&gt; with the International Monetary Fund, which had assessed its accumulated debt as unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RpffQy"&gt;“The government intends to pursue its discussions with the IMF as expeditiously as possible with a view to formulating and presenting to the country’s creditors a comprehensive plan for restoring Sri Lanka’s external public debt to a fully sustainable position,” the Finance Ministry said in a &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-international-monetary-fund-sri-lanka-foreign-debt-f48b3cfb388c3a11af5d2d8a3d1a4391"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FVqMeG"&gt;In a meeting with Cabinet officials a week later, President Rajapaksa &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-biden-cabinet-sri-lanka-mahinda-rajapaksa-c85718a88d4ff03d2a72f969eb595afa"&gt;acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; his government’s role in the country’s declining economy. Specifically, the president said the government should have approached the IMF earlier for support in tackling its unruly foreign debt and that they should have avoided a ban on imported chemical fertilizers, which was meant to preserve Sri Lanka’s foreign exchange holdings but instead hurt its agricultural production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYRGeu"&gt;“During the last two and a half years we have had vast challenges. The Covid-19 pandemic, as well as the debt burden, and some mistakes on our part,” Rajapaksa said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ips2BN"&gt;Now, Sri Lanka’s future rests on whether the president’s proposed government changes will placate his growing opposition long enough for a solution to come through from the IMF. The Sri Lankan central bank chief, Nandalal Weerasinghe, has stated that such a hoped-for deal could &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20220429-crisis-hit-sri-lanka-says-imf-bailout-three-months-away"&gt;still be months away&lt;/a&gt;, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LTG5eH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, May 1, 4:55 pm: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A previous version of this story misstated the value of Sri Lanka’s tourism sector. It was a $4.4 billion industry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4FiEy9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, May 2, 6:45 pm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; A previous version of this story misstated the number of Belt and Road Initiative countries; the correct range is between 139 and 146.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/4/30/23050242/sri-lanka-50-billion-debt-protests-loan-default-china-india-imf" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/4/30/23050242/sri-lanka-50-billion-debt-protests-loan-default-china-india-imf</id>
    <author>
      <name>Natasha Ishak</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-28T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-28T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ron DeSantis is following a trail blazed by a Hungarian authoritarian</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xawrQnXT4AqtqbFGq2IMngUMqag=/186x0:1537x1013/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70804103/orban_desantis_board_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Christina Animashaun/Vox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The Florida governor isn’t doing “competent Trumpism.” He’s inventing American Orbánism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="1650644850.526219"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DZi58"&gt;In June of last year, Hungary’s far-right government passed a law cracking down on LGBTQ rights, including a provision prohibiting instruction on &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22547228/hungary-orban-lgbt-law-pedophilia-authoritarian"&gt;LGBTQ topics in sex education classes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EDH9Tx"&gt;About nine months later, Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis (R) signed the so-called “Don’t Say Gay” bill &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/03/28/1089221657/dont-say-gay-florida-desantis"&gt;banning&lt;/a&gt; “classroom instruction by school personnel or third parties on sexual orientation or gender identity” up through third grade. According to some knowledgeable observers on the right, these two bills were closely connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQ3mqC"&gt;“About the Don’t Say Gay law, it was in fact modeled in part on what Hungary did last summer,” Rod Dreher, a senior editor at the American Conservative magazine, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kG1tEZjRvLk"&gt;said during a panel interview in Budapest&lt;/a&gt;. “I was told this by a conservative reporter who ... said he talked to the press secretary of Governor Ron DeSantis of Florida and she said, ‘Oh yeah, we were watching the Hungarians, so yay Hungary.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ijt9S"&gt;(When I asked DeSantis press secretary Christina Pushaw about a possible connection, she initially denied knowing of Hungarian inspiration for Florida’s law. After I showed her the quote from Dreher, she did not respond further. Dreher did not reply to two requests for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nFr2H5"&gt;It’s easy to see the connections between the bills — in both provisions and justifications. Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orbán described his country’s anti-LGBTQ law as &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/hungary-approves-law-banning-lgbtq-content-for-minors/a-57909844"&gt;an effort to prevent gay people from preying on children&lt;/a&gt;; Pushaw described Florida’s law as an “anti-grooming bill” on Twitter, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChristinaPushaw/status/1500651333480849419"&gt;adding that&lt;/a&gt; “if you’re against the Anti-Grooming Bill, you are probably a groomer” — meaning a person preparing children to become targets of sexual abuse, a slur targeting LGBTQ people and their supporters that’s &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23025505/leftist-groomers-homophobia-satanic-panic-explained"&gt;becoming increasingly common on the right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LkNhsP"&gt;This is not a one-off example. DeSantis, who has built a profile as a pugilistic culture warrior with eyes on the presidency, has steadily put together a policy agenda with strong echoes of Orbán’s governing ethos — one in which an allegedly existential cultural threat from the left justifies aggressive uses of state power against the right’s enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7bBIWr"&gt;Most recently, there was &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2022/04/ron-desantis-disney-dont-say-gay-banana-republic-florida-authoritarian.html"&gt;DeSantis’s crackdown&lt;/a&gt; on Disney’s special tax exemption; using regulatory powers to punish opposing political speech is &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump"&gt;one of Orbán’s signature moves&lt;/a&gt;. On issues ranging from &lt;a href="https://www.the74million.org/article/with-last-minute-changes-floridas-stop-woke-bill-establishes-limits-on-classroom-instruction-some-experts-call-flatly-unconstitutional/"&gt;higher education&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/7/1/22558980/florida-social-media-law-injunction-desantis"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/04/22/florida-quickly-sued-over-new-map-that-gives-big-wins-to-republicans-00027203"&gt;gerrymandering&lt;/a&gt;, DeSantis has followed a trail blazed by Orbán, turning policy into a tool for targeting outgroups while entrenching his party’s hold on power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LrJyWh"&gt;Orbán has recently emerged &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/8/5/22607465/tucker-carlson-hungary-orban-authoritarianism-democracy-backsliding"&gt;as an aspirational model&lt;/a&gt; for many on the Trump-friendly right. During his presidency, many observers on both sides of the aisle compared Trump to the Hungarian autocrat — and not without some justification. But &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump"&gt;after a 2018 visit to Hungary&lt;/a&gt;, I concluded that Trump was not competent or disciplined enough to implement Orbán-style authoritarianism in America on his own. The real worry, I argued, was a GOP that took on features of Orbán’s Fidesz party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2nHrRf"&gt;DeSantis’s agenda in Florida is evidence that the Republican shift in this direction is continuing, maybe even accelerating. He has shown little interest in moderation or consensus-building instead centering his governing philosophy on using policy to own the libs. While Trump may have been &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/6/15/22522504/republicans-authoritarianism-trump-competitive"&gt;an ideological catalyst&lt;/a&gt; for the GOP’s authoritarian lurch, DeSantis is showing how it could actually be implemented in practice. The consequences for democracy in Florida, and America in general, could be dire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nqWAuc"&gt;The many places where DeSantis and Orbán meet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="f7heup"&gt;There is no doubt that Hungary, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump"&gt;an authoritarian state in all but name&lt;/a&gt;, is becoming &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/8/5/22607465/tucker-carlson-hungary-orban-authoritarianism-democracy-backsliding"&gt;more and more important&lt;/a&gt; in the American right-wing imagination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DzlOK"&gt;Tucker Carlson, the most influential media figure in today’s GOP, is at the forefront of this effort. In January, Carlson released a “documentary” on Orbán’s government &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22904444/tucker-carlson-hungary-soros-fox-nation-documentary-special"&gt;lionizing his regime&lt;/a&gt; and encouraging Republicans to emulate it. That same month, Donald Trump &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/03/us/politics/trump-endorses-viktor-orban-hungary.html"&gt;endorsed Orbán for reelection&lt;/a&gt;, calling him a “strong leader” who has “done a powerful and wonderful job in protecting Hungary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oPZ7T0msyAz4igj8tsUDDkft47o=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23420780/AP22093760950896.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Petr David Josek/AP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orbán addresses cheering supporters during an election night rally in Budapest, Hungary, on April 3. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zij3tg"&gt;This makes the echoes between DeSantis’s agenda and Orbán’s especially notable — with the “Don’t Say Gay” law, and the ensuing fight with Disney, being the most glaring examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlXgkS"&gt;Orbán’s political model has frequently employed &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22547228/hungary-orban-lgbt-law-pedophilia-authoritarian"&gt;a demagogic two-step&lt;/a&gt;: Stand up a feared or marginalized group as an enemy then use the supposed need to combat this group’s influence to justify punitive policies that also happen to expand his regime’s power. Targets have included Muslim immigrants, Jewish financier George Soros, and most recently LGBTQ Hungarians. Hungary’s version of the “Don’t Say Gay” law — which the government labeled an anti-pedophilia bill — &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22547228/hungary-orban-lgbt-law-pedophilia-authoritarian"&gt;expanded&lt;/a&gt; both government control over curricula and its powers to regulate programming on Hungary’s airwaves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PKrFVy"&gt;You see a similar logic in DeSantis’s Florida. Alleging that classroom education on LGBTQ topics somehow threatens children, the governor and his allies pushed through &lt;a href="https://pen.org/these-4-florida-bills-censor-classroom-subjects-and-ideas/"&gt;a vague and broadly worded bill&lt;/a&gt; that empowers both the state and private citizens to go after schools that teach about LGBTQ identity. A moral panic about alleged LGBTQ “grooming” serves to justify the imposition of ideological controls on public education — and the speech rights of progressive and LGBTQ teachers. (Relatedly, both Orbán and DeSantis have &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/new-school-curriculum-raises-eyebrows-in-orbans-hungary/a-52964617"&gt;taken&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.yahoo.com/florida-education-department-explains-ban-192710206.html"&gt;aim&lt;/a&gt; at curricula and textbooks used in K-12 schools on expressly political-cultural grounds.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W7VapF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22545125/republicans-corporate-america-education-polarization"&gt;Predictably&lt;/a&gt;, the Florida bill provoked a backlash from corporate America — which DeSantis used as a justification to engage in even more Orbán-like behavior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IBLCNy"&gt;After Disney put out a statement criticizing the “Don’t Say Gay” bill, DeSantis moved to strip the corporation of its special tax status in a 40-square-mile area around Disney World. In this area, called the Reedy Creek Improvement District, Florida allows the mega-corporation to essentially function as a local government, giving it the power to, for example, collect taxes (from itself) and build roads. These privileges, first granted by the state in 1967, are hugely beneficial for the company — and, on Friday, DeSantis &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/04/22/florida-gov-desantis-signs-bill-revoking-disneys-special-district-status.html"&gt;signed a bill revoking them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xc4pzw"&gt;In doing so, he was very explicit about his reasoning: This move was &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/23036427/ron-desantis-disney-first-amendment-constitution-supreme-court"&gt;direct punishment&lt;/a&gt; for Disney’s stance on the “Don’t Say Gay” law. In a fundraising email, DeSantis wrote that “Disney and other woke corporations won’t get away with peddling their &lt;a href="https://www.kcra.com/article/disney-world-self-government-explained/39786585#"&gt;unchecked pressure campaigns any longer&lt;/a&gt;.” In an appearance &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/justinbaragona/status/1517245466433527809?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1517245466433527809%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vox.com%2F23036427%2Fron-desantis-disney-first-amendment-constitution-supreme-court"&gt;on Newsmax&lt;/a&gt;, Lt. Gov. Jeanette Nunez noted that Disney had “changed what they really espouse,” lambasting the company’s “very public agenda to indoctrinate our children.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLhcHD"&gt;This use of regulatory power to punish political opponents is right out of Orbán’s playbook. In 2015, Lajos Simicska — an extremely wealthy Hungarian businessman and longtime Orbán ally — turned on his patron, &lt;a href="https://www.economist.com/europe/2015/02/09/curse-like-an-oligarch"&gt;using a vulgar term&lt;/a&gt; to describe the prime minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NzfoRW"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/5/21/21256324/viktor-orban-hungary-american-conservatives"&gt;In retaliation&lt;/a&gt;, the government cut its advertising in Simicska’s media outlets and shifted contracts away from his construction companies. After Fidesz’s 2018 election, Simicska sold his corporate holdings (mostly to pro-government figures). He moved to an isolated village in western Hungary; his last remaining business interest was an agricultural firm owned by his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sn6kJ3"&gt;DeSantis isn’t the first Republican to follow Orbán here. Trump tried this kind of move &lt;a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/donald-trumps-re-election-is-a-dire?s=r"&gt;a few times&lt;/a&gt;, most notably attempting to block AT&amp;amp;T’s purchase of Time Warner because he hated CNN’s coverage of his campaign and administration, &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/03/11/the-making-of-the-fox-news-white-house"&gt;according to Jane Mayer’s reporting&lt;/a&gt; in the New Yorker. But he failed to follow through, whereas DeSantis actually made good on his threats (&lt;a href="https://news.bloombergtax.com/tax-insights-and-commentary/the-contractual-impossibility-of-unwinding-disneys-reedy-creek?context=search&amp;amp;index=1"&gt;at least for now&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUe47q"&gt;Higher education is another area where DeSantis, like Orban, has taken special aim. On April 22, DeSantis signed the “&lt;a href="https://www.tallahassee.com/story/news/politics/2022/04/22/florida-governor-desantis-stop-woke-act-race-bill-law-sign-discussions-republicans/7403239001/"&gt;Stop WOKE Act”&lt;/a&gt;, a bill that, among other things, expressly regulates what professors are allowed to teach about race and gender in college courses. In &lt;a href="https://www.thefire.org/fire-letter-to-florida-state-university-regarding-house-bill-7/"&gt;a letter to Florida State University&lt;/a&gt;, the free speech advocacy group FIRE argued that the bill (also known as HB 7) was so obviously an unconstitutional abridgment of speech that administrators might simply “refuse to enforce” the bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qcfggRpPYkZvf6wLfYj5HdvtR_A=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23420737/GettyImages_1240219409.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Daniel A. Varela/Miami Herald/Tribune News Service via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis poses for a photo after signing HB 7, the “Stop WOKE Act,” at a school in Hialeah Gardens, Florida, on April 22.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SOj8AU"&gt;“By barring any ‘instruction’ that ‘espouses,’ ‘promotes,’ or ‘advances’ a prohibited concept, HB7 chills vast swaths of academic discussion and inquiry protected by the First Amendment,” FIRE writes. “Florida’s new prohibition will silence discussions on (among other topics) systemic racism, the gender pay gap, affirmative action, [and] reparations for slavery or indigenous peoples.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2maODj"&gt;Orbán’s assault on higher ed has been even more striking. In 2018, his government issued a decree removing accreditation for Hungarian gender studies degrees, a move that &lt;a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/quicktakes/2018/10/17/hungary-officially-ends-gender-studies-programs"&gt;effectively banned Hungarian universities&lt;/a&gt; from teaching the subject. Later that year, his government forced Budapest’s Central European University — a widely respected liberal arts college founded by Orbán’s foil, George Soros — &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2018/12/4/18123754/hungary-ceu-orban-soros-authoritarianism"&gt;to leave the country altogether&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldi7bh"&gt;For both men, the focus on academia is unsurprising: Universities are places where cultural liberal views flourish, and a forceful conservative agenda should take the fight to them. Conservatives believe state power can and should be wielded to prevent professors from “indoctrinating” students into a left-wing worldview (which &lt;a href="https://medium.com/arc-digital/no-professors-are-not-brainwashing-their-students-d4694522f413"&gt;doesn’t actually happen&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="byWtUW"&gt;On another hot-button culture-war issue, social media, DeSantis has actually outstripped Orbán.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e5Z2Yu"&gt;In February 2021, Hungarian Justice Minister Judit Varga &lt;a href="https://www.euractiv.com/section/politics/short_news/hungary-to-regulate-digital-damaging-of-tech-giants/"&gt;proposed a bill&lt;/a&gt; to regulate “the Hungarian operations of large tech companies” to counteract &lt;a href="https://www.euractiv.com/section/digital/news/hungary-raises-concerns-about-shadow-banning-of-online-speech/"&gt;what she earlier called&lt;/a&gt; their alleged restrictions on “Christian, conservative, right-wing opinions.” While Varga’s bill never passed, a version of it &lt;a href="https://www.wfla.com/news/politics/breaking-it-down-florida-big-tech-accountability-bill-signed-into-law/"&gt;became law in Florida&lt;/a&gt; just three months after her proposal. Florida Senate Bill 7072 gave state regulators the power to fine social media companies if state authorities determined they improperly “deplatformed” a political candidate for office. (Shortly after its enactment, a court ruled that the bill &lt;a href="https://www.wlf.org/2021/09/23/publishing/social-media-and-common-carriage-lessons-from-the-litigation-over-floridas-sb-7072/"&gt;violated the First Amendment&lt;/a&gt;; oral arguments for Florida’s appeal &lt;a href="https://news.wfsu.org/state-news/2022-02-14/arguments-are-set-for-may-in-a-battle-over-floridas-law-regulating-social-media-platforms"&gt;are set for mid-May&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L8eOQ4"&gt;Finally, the Hungarian and Florida governments share a penchant for extreme gerrymandering (as, to be fair, do quite a few other &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22961590/redistricting-gerrymandering-house-2022-midterms"&gt;Democratic and Republican state governments&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ct6e5g"&gt;Shortly after its initial victory in 2010, Fidesz created a new set of single-member districts that gave its supporters outsize representation in the country’s parliament. In the 2022 election, Fidesz won &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/hungarians-vote-orbans-12-year-rule-tight-ballot-overshadowed-by-ukraine-war-2022-04-03/"&gt;53 percent of the vote nationally&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://telex.hu/english/2022/04/04/viktor-orbans-fourth-two-thirds-majority-a-disaster-for-the-opposition-coalition-key-election-results"&gt;83 percent of the seats&lt;/a&gt; in single-member districts — including a whopping 98 percent of seats in districts outside of Budapest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7FpkTB"&gt;During the current redistricting cycle, DeSantis &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/03/29/politics/desantis-vetoes-florida-congressional-map/index.html"&gt;rejected a congressional map&lt;/a&gt; drawn by Florida’s Republican legislature, instead insisting on new maps that would give the party a substantially larger leg up in House elections. The statehouse complied, producing new maps that are so biased that, by one estimate, they could swing the &lt;em&gt;national &lt;/em&gt;House bias &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22961590/redistricting-gerrymandering-house-2022-midterms"&gt;a full point in the GOP’s direction&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="uRwOOn"&gt;Why DeSantis and Orbán have converged&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tHupSt"&gt;These similarities reflect a certain ideological convergence between the post-Trump Republican Party and Fidesz: a belief in the central importance of cultural war and the need to wage it using state power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YyXnBC"&gt;Broadly speaking, both Orbán and DeSantis characterize themselves as standing for ordinary citizens against a corrupt and immoral left-wing cosmopolitan elite. These factions are so powerful, in their telling, that aggressive steps must be taken to defeat their influence and defend traditional values. University professors, the LGBTQ community, “woke” corporations, &lt;a href="https://www.mvtimes.com/2021/12/15/desantis-cites-marthas-vineyard-immigration-destination/"&gt;undocumented immigrants&lt;/a&gt;, opposition political parties — these are not merely rivals or constituents in a democratic political system, but threats to a traditional way of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iknYy7I6tfatxvozy-VOo6lrdr0=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23420815/GettyImages_1372618288.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A poster of Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis declares “America needs a new generation of leaders,” alongside a poster of former President Donald Trump, at the Conservative Political Action Conference in Orlando, Florida, on February 24.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xao26e"&gt;In such an existential struggle, the old norms of tolerance and limited government need to be adjusted, tailored to a world where the left controls the commanding heights of culture. Since the left can’t be beaten in that realm, government must be seized and wielded in service of a right-wing cultural agenda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZcHDU"&gt;These ideas are not exclusive to these two political figures: They are widely shared among far-right thinkers and parties across the Western world. You can find versions of them in factions ranging from Poland’s ruling Law and Justice party to former Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s Likud party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FH5SD0"&gt;In the United States, Trump was supposed to be the avatar of this far-right thinking — which, in this country, is broadly associated with a loose group of intellectuals and writers called “&lt;a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/164408/young-intellectuals-illiberal-revolution-conservatism"&gt;the New Right&lt;/a&gt;.” But it turned out he was too self-absorbed and haphazard to successfully implement a New Right agenda. Trump’s most notable legislative achievement? A tax cut written by old-school, pro-business conservatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UjlNmS"&gt;DeSantis is actually walking the New Right walk. His policy agenda has been described as “&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/10/us/politics/ron-desantis-republican-trump.html"&gt;competent Trumpism&lt;/a&gt;,” but that’s a bit misleading. Trumpism was never a coherent intellectual doctrine, because the person whose name it bore did not have a coherent ideology. What DeSantis is doing is taking far-right ideas and making them into policy reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="notMvQ"&gt;“There are important parallels [between Orbán and DeSantis], although I think they’re less exclusive to Orbán than they are indicative of a broader shift in right-wing parties across the West,” Nate Hochman, a writer at National Review affiliated with the New Right, tells me. “DeSantis and Orbán do share a much starker view of politics than the traditional, laissez-faire, business-friendly Republican approach to politics, which is much more willing to draw sharp lines between political friends and enemies.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MsKlyc"&gt;That starker view of politics, and the foregrounding of the culture wars it entails, threatens to further undermine the status and security of marginalized groups. It also serves as a vehicle for maintaining and expanding Orbán’s and DeSantis’s own power and influence — at democracy’s expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NlQwwI"&gt;Democracy in Hungary — and in Florida&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vCtbvZ"&gt;Any politics that puts emphasis on punishing political and cultural enemies tends toward illiberal and anti-democratic practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sie6b4"&gt;In the Hungarian case, this was a feature rather than a bug: Orbán designed &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump"&gt;his ideological message&lt;/a&gt; around his desire to create a “&lt;a href="https://www.nybooks.com/articles/2018/04/05/homo-orbanicus-hungary/"&gt;central political forcefield&lt;/a&gt;” that would dominate the country. The culture war was more of a means than an end, a legitimating tactic for policies explicitly designed to undermine Hungarian democracy, weaken political rivals, and strengthen Fidesz’s grip on power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O4auLm"&gt;Today, the Hungarian political system is best described as a form of “&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2021/6/15/22522504/republicans-authoritarianism-trump-competitive"&gt;competitive authoritarianism&lt;/a&gt;”: a system where leaders do not ban elections or nakedly stuff ballot boxes, but instead hold contests under profoundly unfair background conditions — pervasive state control of the media, for example. By combining repressive tools with a culture-war message that genuinely resonates in Hungary’s conservative countryside, the government can maintain a near-absolute hammerlock on power without needing to resort to the most obvious forms of electoral cheating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i3T27e"&gt;This model has been proven effective. Orbán has been in power since 2010 and has won three separate reelection bids — in 2014, 2018, and April 2022 — on an increasingly uneven playing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kUhmRcmZ_FsHayf7u10-ZVuFvPA=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23420852/GettyImages_1372590695.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Gov. Ron DeSantis arrives to speak at CPAC in Orlando, Florida, on February 24.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WygW1F"&gt;DeSantis is operating in a very different context. His goal is not to establish a permanent DeSantis regime in Florida but rather to improve his status in the national Republican Party in order to launch &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/02/25/ron-desantis-republicans-wait-your-turn-00012024"&gt;an eventual presidential bid&lt;/a&gt;. Bare-knuckles culture warring in Florida is also constrained by national politics and a legal system his party doesn’t (entirely) control. It is &lt;a href="https://newsletters.theatlantic.com/the-third-rail/6261f9a29881d90020642c9d/florida-ron-de-santis-disney-status/"&gt;very plausible&lt;/a&gt; that some of his signature legislation, like the revocation of Disney’s tax status, will be struck down on constitutional grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUKVNY"&gt;But that is cold comfort. The American federal system delegates huge amounts of power to state governments, enough to severely undermine democracy within a state’s boundaries. The United States has a long history of state-level authoritarianism: Jim Crow laws, in addition to being a form of racial apartheid, were also designed to guarantee indefinite Democratic control over Southern states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTXIOW"&gt;In this political context, any diffusion of Hungarian-style culture-war authoritarianism to the state governments is extremely disturbing — potentially accelerating &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/4/5/22358325/study-republican-control-state-government-bad-for-democracy"&gt;a decade-plus process of democratic decline in Republican-governed states&lt;/a&gt;. If DeSantis is in fact creating a blueprint for American Orbánism that Republicans across the country choose to follow, the implications for American democracy could well be disastrous.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/28/23037788/ron-desantis-florida-viktor-orban-hungary-right-authoritarian" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/28/23037788/ron-desantis-florida-viktor-orban-hungary-right-authoritarian</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-28T07:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-28T07:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>An expert on why wars start, and how to prevent them</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kJfTkI90hhvQ1NJGwPohFnj3Ojw=/295x0:5132x3628/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70803697/1240098294.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Ukrainian soldiers patrol a village destroyed by Russian shelling in Mykolaiv Oblast. | Celestino Arce/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The key to understanding war: It’s the exception, not the rule.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="DALuJ0"&gt;War is a stupid idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSqKCC"&gt;Fighting is a bad way to resolve disagreements. If two countries want the same land, it is almost always less costly to each side to split it than to fight. The same is true if they are arguing over a shared natural resource, like oil. Fighting costs lives and money, with an incredibly uncertain payoff when the dust settles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZIQpE"&gt;And yet wars persist, both within nations and, as appallingly demonstrated by Russia’s devastation of Ukraine, between them. Why? Why do governments and private armed groups still resort to violence when it’s so often mutually destructive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="poEGXg"&gt;That’s the question Chris Blattman’s new book, &lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/636263/why-we-fight-by-christopher-blattman/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why We Fight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, seeks to answer. Blattman is an economist and political scientist at the University of Chicago, and he has studied the roots of violence in many different contexts. In academic work, Blattman and his coauthors have examined the roots of &lt;a href="https://chrisblattman.com/documents/research/2010.Consequences.RESTAT.pdf"&gt;child soldiering&lt;/a&gt; in Uganda, the potential of &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2015/04/15/jobs-and-jail-might-not-keep-young-men-out-of-crime-but-how-about-therapy/"&gt;cognitive behavioral therapy to prevent violence&lt;/a&gt; in post-war Liberia, and the policy choices of &lt;a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/5nyqs/"&gt;drug gangs who govern neighborhoods&lt;/a&gt; in Medellín, Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2Yn9a"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why We Fight&lt;/em&gt; is an effort to summarize what he and other social scientists have learned about violent conflict, both between and within states: where it comes from; if it can be prevented; and how to stop it once it’s begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mXDTd"&gt;Blattman and I spoke for this week’s episode of the Vox podcast &lt;em&gt;The Weeds&lt;/em&gt;. A transcript, edited for length and clarity, follows. Note that our conversation occurred on April 7, so we didn’t cover the past couple weeks of developments in Ukraine. As always, there’s much more in the full podcast, so listen and follow &lt;em&gt;The Weeds&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-weeds/id1042433083"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhld2VlZHM"&gt;Google Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1vSUO6Bg4abtjRF7fnGpT1"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/show/voxs-the-weeds"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;, or wherever you listen to podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZgrcQr"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 152px; position: relative;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/6tC2NJ1WaMO4MlYi3zdEuX?utm_source=oembed" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ngeSdd"&gt;Dylan Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LFC4fl"&gt;You start from a standpoint that is kind of surprising for a book about war, which is that war usually is a bad idea, it usually isn’t in anybody’s best interests, and most conflicts are resolved peaceably. Can you explain that organizing framework and why you think that’s important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="o4HtRq"&gt;Chris Blattman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="v5bwJ9"&gt;It is kind of amazing how much attention we pay to violence. We want doctors to pay a lot of attention to sick people, but then we don’t want them to forget that most people are healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uSuVlM"&gt;For example, two weeks into Russia’s invasion of the Ukraine, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/12/world/asia/india-pakistan-missile.html"&gt;India accidentally lobbed a cruise missile at Pakistan&lt;/a&gt; and nothing came of it, and we shouldn’t be surprised at that. Likewise, schoolchildren will learn about the US invasion of Afghanistan for decades, [but] very few kids will be taught about the &lt;a href="https://time.com/5682135/haiti-military-anniversary/"&gt;US invasion of Haiti in 1994&lt;/a&gt;, which ended before it began. Colin Powell went to the coup leader [Raoul Cédras] who ousted a democratically elected president, showed him a video of US troops loading into planes and taking off and said, “This isn’t live. This happened two hours ago,” and he sort of surrendered right there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OoNeVt"&gt;All of these things are happening all the time. And they’re happening for a pretty simple reason. If you’re Pakistan [after India’s missile launch], it’s just going to be ruinous if you go to war over this, even if you think it might not have been an accident. And this military leader in Haiti … It wasn’t just that the US was strong and Haiti was weak. That was part of it, but we know that weak parties can mount insurgencies. I think he just looked at [the situation] and he said, this isn’t going to be worth it, because I can basically use whatever bargaining power I have to get some kind of deal. [The US government wound up &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1994-10-14-mn-50281-story.html"&gt;giving the coup leader over $1 million&lt;/a&gt; to leave.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bx2x8j"&gt;That’s just the normal everyday business of what happens, precisely because war is so costly. Peace has this gravitational pull, from all the costs of war. So war only happens because some other force yanked it out of that orbit, which is actually pretty hard to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nmyzaM"&gt;Dylan Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="1cA6YB"&gt;You list five explanations for war, which are all explanations of how bargaining breaks down and why people can’t reach agreements peaceably. Could you walk through those five?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tdAxhl"&gt;Chris Blattman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="WAhDBK"&gt;I call them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="xAC9We"&gt;Unchecked leaders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Qx3DKr"&gt;Intangible incentives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eKg8Id"&gt;Misperceptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Vruuvt"&gt;Uncertainty, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mSIUFU"&gt;Commitment problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p id="CAzd24"&gt;Three of them are more strategic in nature, and then two are more psychological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8cMuRi"&gt;Let me just start with a couple examples that I think are the most intuitive. We live in a world with a lot of autocrats, and even if they’re not autocrats, we live in a world where leaders are not totally constrained by their people, which means they don’t have to do the thing that’s in the interest of their group. This especially matters for someone who is completely unaccountable, like a &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/order-from-chaos/2017/03/23/the-rise-of-personalist-rule/"&gt;personalized dictator&lt;/a&gt;, which Vladimir Putin has increasingly become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ClfEuh"&gt;If you’re a personalized dictator, you don’t have to consider all these costs of war. You consider some of them, but you consider a much narrower range, so you’re much more ready to use violence. Sometimes leaders, particularly dictators, have a special incentive to invade or attack that their group doesn’t share. In Liberia, maybe the warlord Charles Taylor thinks he’s going to get more diamond profits by keeping the war going. Or maybe Putin thinks that too — to keep his regime of control the war needs to keep going. That’s one example of a very powerful thing that can yank us out of that peaceful orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="svTyYc"&gt;Another, which is related, I call intangible incentives. What if the group or a leader — or in particular the dictatorial, personalized ruler — is seeking some ethereal benefits, something they value? That gives them a strong incentive to go to war. It’s not a material incentive like diamonds or something strategic, like “I need to gain this territory in Ukraine or exterminate democracy there because it’s going to threaten me.” Rather, it’s this nationalist ideal of a unified Russia. Or, in Charles Taylor’s case, a nationalist ideal of a unified West African Republic that, by the way, he would rule. It could be personal glory, like wanting to be the next Catherine the Great. It could be the desire to exterminate a heretic, or in service of some kind of religious or ethnic ideal. If you value this thing that only war can bring you, it’s going to yank you out of the peaceful orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V6pzfV"&gt;“Misperceptions” includes all the ways war happens by mistake. Uncertainty is about times when we don’t know the strength of our opponent, we don’t know their resolve, so it seems like the optimal choice to fight. Commitment problems are mostly cases where there’s some way we can avert our opponent from being strong in the future. It actually pays to invade now to lock in our advantage forever. That can overcome the costs of war. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="8srsKT"&gt;Dylan Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="iCTlYQ"&gt;We’re having this conversation as a war in Ukraine rages. Just before the war broke out, you wrote a &lt;a href="https://chrisblattman.com/blog/2022/02/15/when-we-focus-on-russian-aggression-and-motives-are-we-asking-the-wrong-questions/"&gt;short post&lt;/a&gt; asking the question of why diplomacy didn’t work, why the countries hadn’t been able to come to a deal. Looking back, how do you think about that question? How do you apply some of the lessons in this book to that context?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xNXGda"&gt;Chris Blattman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0erqp3"&gt;I know exactly how to apply each of the lessons in the book. What I don’t know is which ones are correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIRFoV"&gt;What it comes down to is you either think Putin and his cabal are being strategic, or they’re not. I always lean on this side of [strategy]; fundamentally they’re not bonkers. Certainly in week four, they’ve woken up and they’re becoming strategic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O6oje6"&gt;But at many lunch hours, I knock on the door of my colleague &lt;a href="https://harris.uchicago.edu/directory/konstantin-sonin"&gt;Konstantin Sonin&lt;/a&gt;, who &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/09/opinion/masha-gessen-putin-and-his-new-years-resolutions.html"&gt;used to be the provost&lt;/a&gt; of one of the most major universities in Moscow. He’s a game theorist, so he’s the kind of person who’s biased to think that everything is strategic, and he thinks it’s completely non-strategic. He thinks [Putin’s] inner circle has basically gone downhill in quality of thought and quality of individuals and experience, and that they’re both mass-deluded and ideological. He puts in the misperceptions and the intangible incentives, and that’s enough for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vLz3N"&gt;I lean more towards the strategic camp. We can all understand Konstantin’s point of view because it’s what we read in the paper every day. I’m always suspicious of it because it gives those people very little agency. It denigrates them. It makes us feel superior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6Znr0"&gt;I think it comes down to Putin’s unchecked-ness: the fact that he is not responsible for the costs [of the war], and he has some private incentives, in terms of the preservation of his regime, to exterminate democracy in Ukraine. There’s uncertainty; he got bad draws and Ukraine got good draws. There’s maybe a little bit of a commitment problem, where he could see a point where [Ukraine] is more democratic, closer to the West, maybe even armed with long-range missiles by the West and thus impossible to invade, and so the window of opportunity is closing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K880P0"&gt;I think those are really important to understanding the war. But for the record, Konstantin totally disagrees with me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l1jJWm"&gt;Dylan Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ACpPwY"&gt;The US is still processing &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22217039/capitol-attack-trump-rally-election-biden-explained"&gt;what happened on January 6th&lt;/a&gt; last year. On the extreme end, your colleague Barbara Walter has a &lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/624156/how-civil-wars-start-by-barbara-f-walter/"&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; raising the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/22814025/democracy-trump-january-6-capitol-riot-election-violence"&gt;possibility of widespread political violence&lt;/a&gt; in the US. Even if not a Liberia-style civil war, then widespread terrorism and street violence. I’m curious how you think about that question, especially because I left your book oddly hopeful about our odds of finding peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="RfknKg"&gt;Chris Blattman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rEZAxM"&gt;Barbara’s not the extreme end — there’s people who think there &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be full-scale civil war. Barbara’s more like, “At worst this is probably going to look like the Irish troubles, and that’s not assured.” She’s definitely more pessimistic than I am. I agree with a lot of what she says. We just have very different probabilities. We can all look at the same evidence and disagree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBhWqk"&gt;Again, it comes down to these costs [of war]. These costs are very high and we have a lot of institutions that have not been politicized and are very good at internalizing these costs, and therefore will work very hard to avoid them. The thing that would push me to be as pessimistic as Barbara is if those institutions, like our military and our Supreme Court and police forces, were more split, or more unaccountable, and thus were not internalizing these costs of violence. But I actually have found those institutions to be amazingly resilient in a polarized age. I draw some optimism from that. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/4/28/23041726/chris-blattman-why-we-fight-war-peace" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/4/28/23041726/chris-blattman-why-we-fight-war-peace</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan Matthews</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-25T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is fracturing the delicate peace in the Arctic </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vu0VrAtYFnNISP8-jTDLrWh_0II=/119x0:2819x2025/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70789514/GettyImages_1235114294.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Russian “50 Years of Victory” nuclear-powered icebreaker is seen at the North Pole on August 18, 2021.  | Ekaterina Anisimova/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Arctic was once an oasis of international cooperation. Russia’s invasion brought it to a halt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="HSRhnY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JnJCtV"&gt;Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is rippling throughout the world, and some of the strongest waves are crashing in the far north. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zOSosf"&gt;There, Russia’s aggression has led to the suspension of the Arctic Council, the main international forum for cooperation in the Arctic, which Russia, awkwardly, was &lt;a href="https://oaarchive.arctic-council.org/bitstream/handle/11374/2646/%d0%90%d1%80%d0%ba%d1%82%d0%b8%d0%ba%d0%b0%20%d0%bf%d1%80%d0%b8%d0%be%d1%80%d0%b8%d1%82%d0%b5%d1%82%d1%8b_%d0%b0%d0%bd%d0%b3%d0%bb_21.06.2021.pdf?sequence=11&amp;amp;isAllowed=y"&gt;slated to chair&lt;/a&gt; until 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UFy4C4"&gt;For decades, the Arctic in general — and the council in particular — was something of an oasis from tense and raucous international relations, working on trade, environmental, and scientific issues while carefully eschewing security concerns. The council continued to operate after Russia’s invasion of Crimea in 2014, for instance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UIcBBs"&gt;But the latest invasion was a bridge too far, posing “grave impediments to international cooperation,” according to a &lt;a href="https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-on-arctic-council-cooperation-following-russias-invasion-of-ukraine/"&gt;joint statement&lt;/a&gt; from the other seven Arctic Council members in March. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGnGAC"&gt;That’s left what had been a unified group of nations adrift in a critical time for the Arctic: Climate change is quickly altering the Arctic landscape, creating new economic opportunities, more headaches for infrastructure on land, and new friction points between countries. The confluence of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and climate change stand to alter balance of trade and security in the Arctic irrevocably, and a region that once avoided the troubles of the rest of the world is now being confronted by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sYWTaR"&gt;Russia’s invasion of Ukraine fractured the delicate peace in the Arctic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ZViv3v"&gt;Despite the recent tensions, countries in the far north have long aspired for “&lt;a href="https://www.thearcticinstitute.org/regional-order-arctic-negotiated-exceptionalism/"&gt;Arctic exceptionalism&lt;/a&gt;,” the idea that the region would remain immune from political wrangling and conflicts brewing in other parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zXLhr3"&gt;“The Soviet Union is in favor of a radical lowering of the level of military confrontation in the region,” said Soviet leader &lt;a href="https://www.thearcticinstitute.org/regional-order-arctic-negotiated-exceptionalism/"&gt;Mikhail Gorbachev in a speech in 1987&lt;/a&gt;.  “Let the North of the globe, the Arctic, become a zone of peace. Let the North Pole be a pole of peace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49ISDS"&gt;Since then, Arctic exceptionalism has largely held, with countries in the region trying to work together and overlook their differences in other areas. In 1996, Arctic nations founded the Arctic Council. Until Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, it was composed of eight states: Canada, Denmark (via Greenland), Finland, Iceland, Norway, Russia, Sweden, and the United States. The council also includes six permanent groups representing Indigenous people in the Arctic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n8usXD"&gt;Over the years, the group established agreements on scientific research, protecting fisheries, conducting search and rescue operations, developing environmental rules, and defending the rights of Indigenous people. The council, however, explicitly does not deal with military issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9283d"&gt;Countries have also pursued their own economic interests in the Arctic outside of the council. Russia, the country with the longest Arctic coastline, has vastly expanded its footprint in the Arctic in recent decades, building roads, airports, power plants, and &lt;a href="https://www.arctictoday.com/russias-newest-nuclear-powered-icebreaker-arrives-in-murmansk/"&gt;nuclear-powered ice breakers&lt;/a&gt;, leaning into fossil fuel extraction to boost its economy. Oil and gas provide &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20211115-climate-change-can-russia-leave-fossil-fuels-behind"&gt;40 percent of Russia’s federal budget&lt;/a&gt; and account for 60 percent of its exports. Overall, it generates about 20 percent of its gross domestic product above the Arctic Circle, mainly from oil and gas, but also from &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2017/3/29/vladimir-putin-visits-arctic-to-reaffirm-russias-claim"&gt;mining minerals and metals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9AZay"&gt;“Russia is hell-bent on developing Arctic oil and gas resources because it has no other choice,” said &lt;a href="https://www.thearcticinstitute.org/experts/malte-humpert/"&gt;Malte Humpert&lt;/a&gt;, founder and a senior fellow at the Arctic Institute think tank. “Purely from a logistical and technical aspect, what Russia has achieved in the Arctic is really, really impressive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CAY329"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="It's time to draw borders on the Arctic Ocean|32919" data-volume-uuid="8e95cea31" data-volume-id="32919" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-380" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2rBP7"&gt;Russia is establishing new shipping routes through the Arctic as well. And to protect all this economic development, Russia’s expanded its military presence in the region, with new bases, hardware, and troops. It’s also conducting &lt;a href="https://www.19fortyfive.com/2021/07/russias-most-powerful-bombers-are-training-for-war-in-the-arctic/"&gt;long-range bomber flights&lt;/a&gt;. “Over the next 30 years, the Arctic will be critical for Russian economic survival,” according to a &lt;a href="https://api.army.mil/e2/c/downloads/2021/03/15/9944046e/regaining-arctic-dominance-us-army-in-the-arctic-19-january-2021-unclassified.pdf"&gt;2021 US Army strategic plan&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SutU4c"&gt;“The question has always been, where do legitimate security interests end and where does militarization of the Arctic begin?” Humpert said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bkjwyi"&gt;That question makes some other countries uneasy, particularly given that they have stakes in the Arctic too. China has become a major customer for Russian fuels from the Arctic and is now the second-largest shipper in the region. The US Army report said that Russia and China could “seek to use military and economic power to gain and maintain access to the region at the expense of US interests.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ia7tYX"&gt;Russian militarization, and its invasion, have spurred other countries to step up their military activities in the region. NATO forces are now &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-calls-increased-nato-military-activity-arctic-worrying-warns-unintended-2022-04-17/"&gt;conducting exercises in the Arctic&lt;/a&gt;, which Russia has warned could lead to “unintended incidents.” The US has &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/27/us/army-alaska-arctic-russia.html"&gt;deployed F-35 fighter jets to Alaska&lt;/a&gt; and is conducting its own drills in the area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Hgjuyv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Russia’s war in Ukraine, explained ","url":"https://www.vox.com/2022/2/23/22948534/russia-ukraine-war-putin-explosions-invasion-explained"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="3DTQtF"&gt;At the moment, all that’s happened are drills. But having so much military might in a place that was supposed to be “a zone of peace,” has some experts concerned. “We’re basically back to the Cold War in terms of level of activity,” said &lt;a href="https://poli.ucalgary.ca/profiles/robert-huebert"&gt;Robert Huebert&lt;/a&gt;, an associate professor of political science at the University of Calgary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hk7Sfs"&gt;The Arctic Council was never meant to delve into military matters. But the hope was that the cooperation it fostered in other areas would minimize the chances of aggression. However, the invasion may end up excluding Russia from the Arctic Council for good, according to Huebert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BHbpcR"&gt;For one thing, Russian President Vladimir Putin is looking to build a &lt;a href="https://thebarentsobserver.com/en/arctic/2022/02/russia-and-china-deepen-cooperation-arctic"&gt;new polar organization with China&lt;/a&gt;. “If in fact he’s successful in doing this, I don’t see how the Russians can be brought back,” Huebert said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BQ1FD2"&gt;Sweden and Finland are also &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/12/europe/putin-finland-sweden-nato-backfire-cmd-intl/index.html"&gt;considering joining NATO&lt;/a&gt;, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, as a result of Russia’s invasion. That could become a permanent wedge between Arctic nations. The prospect of NATO expanding its membership was a big reason &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/23/22948534/russia-ukraine-war-putin-explosions-invasion-explained"&gt;why Russia invaded Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; to begin with. “The moment Finland and Sweden join NATO, I just don’t ever see the Russians coming back to the Arctic Council,” Huebert said.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/knWDe3eqAGmPxGBeRJS6hWwZkiw=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23410257/AP21138030656605.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Alexander Zemlianichenko/AP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Russian officers talk to each other at a base called the “Arctic Trefoil” on the island of Alexandra Land, Russia, on May 17, 2021. Once a desolate home mostly to polar bears, Russia’s northernmost military outpost is bristling with missiles and radar and its extended runway can handle all types of aircraft, including nuclear-capable strategic bombers.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="w6ccUm"&gt;Climate change is creating new opportunities and flashpoints in the Arctic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="EJS0hc"&gt;The Arctic itself is rapidly changing. It’s warming more than twice as fast as the global average, reshaping the icy ocean and the lands around it. Arctic sea ice is &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2017/12/12/16767152/arctic-sea-ice-extent-chart"&gt;declining at its fastest rate in 1,500 years&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MVrlWI"&gt;But while the Arctic is warming quickly, the effects are not equal across the region. “One of the things that climate change has really illustrated is that there’s more than one Arctic,” Huebert said. Rising temperatures play out differently depending on whether it’s on Alaskan permafrost, Finnish tundra, or Greenland’s ice sheet. Even within the Arctic, some places are heating up more than others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgAPqz"&gt;Since 1900, the Arctic has warmed on average by &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/arctic-ocean-atlantic-warming-climate-study-e0aaaba3-3f2f-4202-8350-acaa36c2787a.html"&gt;2 degrees Celsius&lt;/a&gt;, 3.6 degrees Fahrenheit, fueled by the heat-trapping gasses from burning fossil fuels. That’s playing out several key ways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HruoTO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.climate.gov/news-features/featured-images/warming-waters-shift-fish-communities-northward-arctic"&gt;Fish stocks are moving further north&lt;/a&gt; as species like cod and redfish seek cold refuge from warming oceans. Many Arctic nations count on fishing, but right now, there is a &lt;a href="https://thebarentsobserver.com/en/arctic/2021/06/central-arctic-ocean-fishing-moratorium-comes-effect#:~:text=An%20international%20agreement%20banning%20commercial,countries%2C%20plus%20the%20European%20Union."&gt;moratorium on fishing in the Arctic&lt;/a&gt; for at least 15 years. After that, the waters could become a lot more crowded than they are now: “I think the boats will follow eventually if that moratorium is lifted,” said &lt;a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/canada/people/mia-moy-bennett/"&gt;Mia Bennett&lt;/a&gt;, an assistant professor of geography at the University of Washington.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ewQlEx"&gt;Shipping has already become easier. Arctic sea ice is not just &lt;a href="https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/arctic-sea-ice/"&gt;retreating to record lows&lt;/a&gt;, but the ice that remains is also often thinner, allowing icebreakers to more readily guide vessels through frigid waters. In 2016, the &lt;a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/2908883/crystal-serenitys-journey-through-northwest-passage-draws-excitement-climate-change-fears/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crystal Serenity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; became the first cruise ship to transit the Northwest Passage. Warming is also facilitating &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-23/arctic-oil-and-gas-exploration-is-booming-despite-climate-fears"&gt;offshore oil and gas drilling&lt;/a&gt; in the Arctic. The &lt;a href="https://pubs.usgs.gov/fs/2008/3049/fs2008-3049.pdf"&gt;US Geological Survey&lt;/a&gt; estimated the Arctic holds 13 percent of the world’s undiscovered oil and 30 percent of undiscovered natural gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IOcQeD"&gt;But warming is also making life more difficult in other ways. “It’s actually getting much trickier on land to build stable terrestrial infrastructure,” Bennett said. Higher temperatures means the permafrost isn’t so permanent. The softer ground is causing roads to buckle and buildings to list. The Pentagon recently warned that &lt;a href="https://www.militarytimes.com/news/pentagon-congress/2022/04/17/climate-change-damaging-us-military-bases-in-the-arctic-report-warns/"&gt;US military installations&lt;/a&gt; in the Arctic are being damaged by the effects of warming. Onshore drillers have even had to &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2020/oct/19/oil-alaska-arctic-global-heating-local-cooling"&gt;chill the ground under their rigs&lt;/a&gt; in order to stabilize them and continue drilling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EGLeUL"&gt;Shorter and warmer winters mean the ground doesn’t harden back up as much and rivers don’t freeze over, making it more difficult to maintain ice roads to bring in supplies. Wildfires have also &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/7/24/17607722/wildfires-greece-sweden-arctic-circle-heat-wave"&gt;ignited in the Arctic Circle&lt;/a&gt; as climate change has fueled heat waves and extended fire seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3jWz9r"&gt;Russia has faced some of the worst of it. Massive wildfires in Siberia blanketed the country in smoke in recent years. The fires this year are already spreading at an &lt;a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/04/20/public-outrage-mounts-as-siberia-forest-fires-spread-at-unprecedented-rate-a77419"&gt;unprecedented rate&lt;/a&gt;.   On June 20, 2020, the Russian town of &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/arctic-record-siberia-100-degree-heat-climate-change-alarm-bells-un/"&gt;Verkhoyansk&lt;/a&gt; recorded a temperature of 100.4 degrees Fahrenheit, the hottest temperature ever recorded north of the Arctic Circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b6Iz91"&gt;“All this is largely connected to the climate change — both global and in our country,” &lt;a href="https://tass.com/society/1323113"&gt;Putin said in August&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AV7xkc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A very early start of 2022 wildfire season in Russia, with massive fires raging across vast spaces of Western, Central, Southern and Eastern Siberia. Video below is from Omsk region, Western Siberia  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/wildfires2022Russia?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#wildfires2022Russia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/QYj8o5XQOI"&gt;pic.twitter.com/QYj8o5XQOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— The Siberian Times (@siberian_times) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/siberian_times/status/1516454999085109249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MlgHeu"&gt;While climate change is an omnipresent factor in the Arctic, Huebert cautioned that it’s not necessarily the “cause” of many of the recent developments in the region. Russia has faced strong economic pressure to exploit more of its natural resources and would likely be expanding its footprint even if the Arctic hadn’t warmed. And despite the changes in the climate seen so far, the Arctic remains a difficult place to work and live. “It’s being definitely facilitated by climate change, it’s making it easier, but it’s not making it easy,” Huebert said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="edz1F0"&gt;Still, climate change is acting as an accelerant for activity in the region. Those activities, particularly fossil fuel extraction, in turn are speeding up the transformation of the Arctic. And all this new bustle in a once frigid and desolate part of the world, coupled with climate change, could then spark more conflict. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="epyynm"&gt;The future of the Arctic is on thin ice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="F23hJb"&gt;Intelligence agencies are now trying to anticipate future disruptions in the Arctic and have identified some potential ignition points. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgYcW6"&gt;“We assess that Arctic and non-Arctic states almost certainly will increase their competitive activities as the region becomes more accessible because of warming temperatures and reduced ice,” reads an October 2021 report from the &lt;a href="https://www.dni.gov/files/ODNI/documents/assessments/NIE_Climate_Change_and_National_Security.pdf"&gt;National Intelligence Council&lt;/a&gt;. “Competition will be largely economic but the risk of miscalculation will increase modestly by 2040 as commercial and military activity grows and opportunities are more contested.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWMboy"&gt;One looming concern is how countries will claim territory in the newly revealed Arctic ocean. Countries currently control the water stretching 200 nautical miles from their shorelines as exclusive economic zones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cTPGI"&gt;Claims beyond that maritime border depend on the boundaries of the &lt;a href="https://www.thearcticinstitute.org/continental-shelf-claims-arctic-infographic/"&gt;continental shelf&lt;/a&gt;, where a country’s land mass extends out underwater before dropping off into the deep ocean. Arctic nations have been mapping their shelves underwater with tools like probes and submarines to establish their claims. However, some claims overlap, particularly between Canada, Russia, and Denmark, and with the suspension of the Arctic Council, they may not get resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Map showing Arctic continental shelf claims" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R84-In0QHJgiV5eSSxnlKONEACY=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23409940/Screen_Shot_2022_04_22_at_3.22.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Tolpa Studios/Arctic Institute&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Canada, Denmark, and Russia have overlapping continental shelf claims in the Arctic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yKIrxC"&gt;“That simply will be postponed,” Huebert said. If more than one country tries to claim these disputed regions, that could ignite a political — or even military — conflagration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5gmIM"&gt;Friction&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;may also build up around shipping. Russia is aiming to expand its shipping capacity to &lt;a href="https://thebarentsobserver.com/en/arctic/2021/07/moscows-big-plan-trans-arctic-shipping-2000-percent-growth-10-years"&gt;80 million tons per year&lt;/a&gt; by 2024, up from just over 1 million tons today. “[T]he decreasing amount of sea ice will lead to new routes opening in the future and may become an area of contention as Arctic nations attempt to exert control over key sea lanes,” the US Army report warned.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1rBy3i"&gt;And while Russia’s oil and gas could get hit with sanctions from Europe, it will likely still have plenty of other buyers, namely India and China. Mining and drilling can cost &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=4650"&gt;50 to 100 percent more in the Arctic&lt;/a&gt; than they cost at lower latitudes, but with global fuel prices rising, there’s ample demand, so maritime traffic will continue to grow for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0Cn7c"&gt;On the US side, some are pushing for the country to establish a stronger diplomatic presence in the region, particularly as tensions rise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1VcpCm"&gt;“I have directly asked President Joe Biden to consider expanding America’s Arctic leadership across the executive branch, within both the State and Defense Departments, on the National Security Council and beyond,” wrote Alaska Sen. Lisa Murkowski last year in the &lt;a href="https://afsa.org/arctic-exceptionalism"&gt;Foreign Service Journal&lt;/a&gt;. “The United States is one of the only Arctic countries without an Arctic ambassador — a diplomatic post that even many non-Arctic countries have.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hstxvt"&gt;Efforts to address climate change stand to suffer the greatest effects of Arctic instability. As the fastest warming region, it’s a critical area for scientific research. Changes in the Arctic can alter weather patterns around the world. And the &lt;a href="https://nsidc.org/cryosphere/arctic-meteorology/arctic-people.html"&gt;4 million people living in the Arctic Circle&lt;/a&gt; are on the front lines of some of the most radical shifts in ecosystems, from animal extinctions to &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK562756/"&gt;emerging diseases&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DuY5Hv"&gt;Without collaboration at the North Pole, the world loses a window into a region with consequences for the whole planet, according to Humpert. “If we cannot cooperate in the Arctic with regards to climate change and the challenges that brings, then where can we?”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/22993194/russia-ukraine-invasion-arctic-council-climate-change" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/22993194/russia-ukraine-invasion-arctic-council-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umair Irfan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-23T17:38:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-23T17:38:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Deadly attacks on Afghan minorities show the Taliban isn’t keeping its promises</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lx0qiZRINnR6yBp7AmEqrxAZDIg=/187x0:2714x1895/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70785409/1240084122.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Relatives search for loved ones outside a hospital in Kabul following an attack at a boys’ school in a Shiite Hazara neighborhood that killed at least 6 people on April 19 — just one of a series of attacks that have devastated the country as of late. | Wakil Kohsar/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A week of deadly attacks targeted Afghan minorities — and the Taliban has done little to respond.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="hGZGon"&gt;A spate of attacks this week all over Afghanistan killed at least 77 people, including children. At least one — and likely most — of the attacks were carried out by ISIS Khorasan (ISIS-K), the Islamic State affiliate active mostly in Afghanistan and Pakistan. The devastating attacks are further destabilizing a nation already in economic free fall and further increase doubt that the Taliban can protect the Afghan people — especially minorities — from violence and terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7m3eB"&gt;The attacks started Tuesday, with double bombings at the Abdul Rahim Shaheed High School and in the vicinity of the Mumtaz Education Center, both in the capital Kabul. There were at least six deaths and 17 injuries at the Abdul Rahim Shaheed High School in the predominantly Shia and Hazara Dasht-e-Barchi neighborhood, &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/4/19/kabul-boys-school-rocked-by-blasts-casualties-feared"&gt;Al Jazeera&lt;/a&gt; reported Tuesday. While no group has yet claimed responsibility for the attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/19/afghanistan-kabul-school-bomb-blast/"&gt;ISIS-K has been known to target Dasht-e-Barchi in the past.&lt;/a&gt; Government workers in Kunduz province were targeted this week as well — &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/21/world/asia/afghanistan-mosque-bombing.html"&gt;an attack for which ISIS-K claimed credit&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuCLxz"&gt;Attacks continued Thursday, with a bombing at a Shia mosque in Mazar-e-Sharif, in northern Afghanistan. That attack, which ISIS-K claimed credit for on Friday, killed at least 31 people and injured many more, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/22/afghanistan-isis-arrest-attacks-security/"&gt;Pamela Constable reported in the Washington Post Friday&lt;/a&gt;. The Associated Press put the number of dead much lower, at 12, &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/afghanistan-islamic-state-group-religion-kabul-taliban-a13e45ad2660a29f4943258e2b317e24"&gt;in a Saturday report&lt;/a&gt;. In a statement on Friday claiming responsibility for the attack, ISIS-K said that the bomb was in a bag that was left in the Seh Doken mosque; it exploded when the mosque was filled with worshippers. “When the mosque was filled with prayers, the explosives were detonated remotely,” the ISIS-K statement claimed, also alleging that 100 worshippers were injured. Around the same time, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/21/world/asia/afghanistan-mosque-bombing.html?searchResultPosition=3"&gt;the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; reported Friday, ISIS-K attacked a bus in Kunduz province, killing four and injuring 18. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gDPKFI"&gt;After the Taliban government announced it had arrested the “mastermind” of the Mazar-e-Sharif bombing in Balkh province on Friday, an explosion at a mosque in Kunduz province killed at least 30, and a mine went off near a market in Kabul, ending the already-devastating week with even more destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M6mm4Q"&gt;It’s unclear if ISIS-K is behind all of the attacks, but this week’s attacks indicate that the Taliban either doesn’t have as much control over the security situation in Afghanistan as the leadership had indicated it would after US and NATO forces left the country in August, or isn’t particularly interested in providing protection to minorities. It doesn’t help matters that the country is facing destabilization wrought by economic sanctions against Taliban leaders, coupled with the Taliban’s persecution of women, journalists, human rights workers, and other groups. But the Taliban’s inaction does send a strong message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="97Y1Jr"&gt;That’s likely the intention, though, Faiz Zaland, an academic and political analyst in Kabul, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/22/afghanistan-isis-arrest-attacks-security/"&gt;told the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;. “These attackers are trying to build up a momentum of insecurity, to show that even with the Taliban in power, they cannot be stopped,” he said. “They are announcing a spring and summer of destruction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1sDAdT"&gt;Both the Taliban and ISIS-K have attacked minorities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Kc0FRQ"&gt;Both the Taliban and ISIS-K are considered Sunni extremist groups, adhering to a strict interpretation of the sect’s ideology which views Shia Muslims as apostates, or nonbelievers. While the Taliban does have a history of targeting Afghanistan’s Shias, the group agreed in the lead-up to its takeover that minorities would be protected under a new Taliban government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JBM7sg"&gt;The Hazara, an ethnic minority group that mostly practices Shia Islam, has been historically marginalized, with few opportunities for education or employment. They are Afghanistan’s &lt;a href="https://minorityrights.org/country/afghanistan/"&gt;third-largest ethnic group, behind Pashtuns and Tajiks.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lv41EA"&gt;But even before the Taliban took over the Afghan government for a second time this past August, there have been a number of attacks on Shias, and specifically Hazaras. Last May, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/08/world/asia/bombing-school-afghanistan.html"&gt;a vicious attack on a girls’ school&lt;/a&gt; in a predominantly Hazara section of Kabul killed at least 90; the Taliban denied responsibility for the bombing. But even before the Taliban came back into power, minority groups &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2021/08/afghanistan-taliban-responsible-for-brutal-massacre-of-hazara-men-new-investigation/"&gt;lacked protection from the government&lt;/a&gt;; protection that — &lt;a href="https://extremism.gwu.edu/risks-facing-hazaras-taliban-ruled-afghanistan"&gt;despite a history of targeting Shia minorities&lt;/a&gt; during its first period of rule in the 1990s — the Taliban said it would provide, particularly following a number of attacks on Hazara communities by ISIS-K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14POqi"&gt;However, while the Taliban has &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/taliban-reach-out-to-shiite-hazara-minority-seeking-unity-and-iran-ties-11630599286"&gt;said it would not interfere with Shia worship&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2021/10/27/why-the-hazara-people-fear-genocide-in-afghanistan"&gt;will protect all ethnic groups,&lt;/a&gt; the group is responsible for the &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2021/10/afghanistan-13-hazara-killed-by-taliban-fighters-in-daykundi-province-new-investigation/"&gt;deaths of dozens&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2021/08/afghanistan-taliban-responsible-for-brutal-massacre-of-hazara-men-new-investigation/"&gt;Hazara&lt;/a&gt; over the past eight months, as well as mass forced displacements of Hazara people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LiB6Rg"&gt;Not only is the Taliban government directly threatening Hazara people, it’s either unable or unwilling to protect them and other minorities against the attacks of other groups, namely ISIS-K, Asfandyar Mir, a senior expert at the US Institute of Peace focusing on extremism in Afghanistan and Pakistan, told Vox via email. “When the Taliban are pushed on issues of rights and economic well-being of the Afghan people, they push back by touting their ability to provide security for all Afghans, including minorities,” he said. “Yet under the Taliban, vulnerable minorities — in particular the Hazara — continue to be one of the main targets of violence. This is a source of enormous insecurity and raises questions about the Taliban’s ability to provide security in general and against minorities in particular.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpU8hW"&gt;Though the Taliban has instituted a crackdown of sorts on ISIS-K since coming to power, Mir said, “the range of ISIS-K’s violence — from parts of the north to Kabul to eastern border regions — suggests that the Taliban’s months-long crackdown against ISIS-K and supposed sympathizers of the group has not been able to meaningfully curtail the group’s underground activity in most parts of the country where it was based and operational before the Taliban’s takeover.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C94Pjs"&gt;This crackdown — in which the Taliban framed innocent people as ISIS-K members and engaged in targeted repression of the Salafi communities from which many ISIS-K recruits hail — may have actually backfired and pushed people toward ISIS-K, Mir said. And, with no real political alternative to the Taliban, ISIS-K may be the only viable option of belonging or exercising a sense of power to many Afghans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h58JDo"&gt;The ultimate goal is to erode Taliban legitimacy, such as it is&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tQhMkP"&gt;Mir told Vox in a separate phone interview on Saturday that, in his estimation, the attack on the Kunduz mosque was likely the work of ISIS-K as well due to its Sufi-oriented practice of Sunni Islam — the end result is further destabilization. This follows ISIS-K taking responsibility mosque attack in Mazar-e-Sharif, indicating such tragedies have only ramped up since there was a bit of a lull in terror attacks in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="21fq11"&gt;Mir told Vox that was likely a “deliberate decision” on the part of ISIS-K leadership, as they felt out the new government for its security weaknesses. Furthermore, “spring is traditionally fighting season” in Afghanistan, Mir said; this past week’s attacks can be read as an announcement of that, and an indication that there is only more violence to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmath5"&gt;“ISIS-K is likely to go after two sets of targets: One set is of minorities, [that] includes Shia, includes Hazara Shias, and then the ‘wrong’ kind of Sunnis,” like those worshiping at the Khanaqa-e-Malawi Sekandar Sufi mosque and madrassa in Kunduz Friday. The other, Mir said, are high-profile Taliban officials, particularly in the eastern provinces of &lt;a href="https://www.wilsoncenter.org/article/explainer-isis-khorasan-afghanistan"&gt;Kunar and Nangarhar&lt;/a&gt;, where ISIS-K’s base of support is located. “In order to make a big point, my sense is that ISIS-K will try to target someone high up in the Taliban,” he said, hammering home the Taliban’s poor leadership and its inability to protect even its own officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DXkJ7t"&gt;Those attacks, if indeed they are carried out, would further ISIS-K’s possible goal of establishing a branch of the ISIS caliphate in Afghanistan — although that’s presently difficult to imagine, given that &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/what-is-isis-k-two-terrorism-experts-on-the-group-behind-the-deadly-kabul-airport-attack-and-its-rivalry-with-the-taliban-166873"&gt;they didn’t control any significant territory&lt;/a&gt; after the US withdrawal. “The group also wants to topple the Pakistani government, [and] punish the &lt;a href="https://www.newsweek.com/irans-worst-fears-afghanistan-are-coming-true-isis-tests-red-line-1699753"&gt;Iranian government&lt;/a&gt; for being a vanguard of Shias,” he said, hence recent &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/04/world/middleeast/pakistan-peshawar-mosque-explosion.html"&gt;attacks and threats in Pakistan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ruU7vZ"&gt;But the end goal of ISIS-K “is hard to pinpoint,” Mir said. “A closer read of their materials also suggests ISIS-K is obsessed with punishing civilians and those they deem to be non-believers in mass-casualty attacks for their supposed apostasy — almost as an end in of itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6U4muI"&gt;However, the fact remains that they are locked in an ideological battle with the Taliban, and if the point is to use terror to create further instability, chaos, doubt, and violence to delegitimize the Taliban government, the attacks on civilians this past week could certainly have that effect — &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2022/04/14/afghanistan-taliban-violence-women-journalists/"&gt;whether or not they were all perpetrated by ISIS-K&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/4/23/23038561/afghanistan-terror-attacks-targeted-afghan-minorities" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/4/23/23038561/afghanistan-terror-attacks-targeted-afghan-minorities</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-22T12:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-22T12:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Russia’s offensive in the Donbas can’t make up for its failure in Kyiv</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b7PLuu_IjtAo2PCOekGclgt45D0=/167x0:3334x2375/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70781299/GettyImages_1240069549a.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Ukrainian soldiers stand next to their armored personnel carrier in Izyum, southeast of Kharkiv, near the front line with Russian troops on April 18. | Anatolii Stepanov/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;How to understand the new phase in the Ukraine war — and why, in the big picture, Russia has probably already lost.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="MxEDxY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DLAGnk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4mqw2q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4l6Ns"&gt;This week, the new phase of Russia’s war in Ukraine has taken form. It is a war over control of the Donbas, the eastern Ukrainian region where Russia has been supporting a separatist rebellion since 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p3Y1Ar"&gt;Whereas the war — which began with the Russian invasion on February 24 — previously spanned the country, centering on a Russian push to seize Ukraine’s capital and most populous city, Kyiv, its newest offensive is narrowly focused on a region several hundred miles to the east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RwhDAc"&gt;“The Russian troops have begun the battle for the Donbas,” &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/russian-offensive-eastern-ukraine-zelensky/"&gt;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy&lt;/a&gt; announced in a Tuesday address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QLLmMw"&gt;This is, in one sense, a smart move by the Russians. Its attempt to seize Kyiv in the war’s opening days was decisively repulsed, due not only to Russian incompetence but unusually strong Ukrainian resistance that benefited from defending in tricky urban settings. The terrain in the Donbas — fewer suburbs, more open land — affords the defenders fewer advantages. In the east, Russia can concentrate its forces and move toward battles in which their superior artillery and air force can be used to devastating effect. Territorial successes in the Donbas could blunt the narrative of Russian military incompetence and give the Kremlin a more plausible argument that its war has achieved something real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eHeNxQ"&gt;Yet Ukraine has advantages too. The forces it currently has in the Donbas &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/ukraine-the-battle-for-donbas-will-be-protracted-and-bloody-military-expert-180988"&gt;are some of its most battle-hardened fighters&lt;/a&gt;, having spent the past eight years clashing with Russian-backed separatists. It is getting tremendous amounts of Western aid and &lt;a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/04/18/losses-morale-and-counterattacks-stymie-russias-donbas-offensive-a77338"&gt;still has superior morale and logistics&lt;/a&gt; — decisive factors in repulsing Russia’s advances elsewhere. It may numerically match the theoretically much larger Russian army, according to military observers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adGK5Q"&gt;For these reasons, the outcome of the new phase is far from clear, even to leading experts on the Ukraine war. In our conversations, they suggested that possible outcomes ranged from Russia successfully seizing control of the entire Donbas to Ukraine actually clawing territory back. The fighting is likely to be long and bloody, no matter where the lines end up being drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pTEdhu-vXwgZ1UPzntzasPGNQUc=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408423/AP22108714909016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Alexei Alexandrov/AP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Russian military vehicles on a highway in an area controlled by Russian-backed separatist forces near Mariupol, Ukraine, on April 18, 2022. Mariupol, a strategic port on the Sea of Azov, has been besieged by Russian troops and forces from self-proclaimed separatist areas in eastern Ukraine for more than six weeks.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U63kk2"&gt;But the sources I spoke with all agreed on one thing: In the big picture, the outcome in the Donbas might be less important than it may seem. That’s because &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23003689/putin-ukraine-russia-donbas-energy-feint"&gt;Russia’s ultimate aim&lt;/a&gt; — regime change in Kyiv, or at least forcing Ukraine to submit to a Russian-dominated political future — has been out of reach for weeks. Russia can continue to launch missiles at Ukrainian cities in other regions, terrorizing civilians, but it cannot currently threaten to actually seize those population centers or topple President Volodymyr Zelenksyy’s government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DaGKrT"&gt;“Politically, Russia [already] lost the war,” says Michael Kofman, an expert on the Russian military. “When it withdrew from the north, around Kyiv, it eliminated any impetus Ukraine might have for settlement.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baKxL4"&gt;Russia’s offensive in the Donbas, then, is best understood as an effort at limiting the costs of its blunder: a campaign to string together significant enough gains — like &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-putin-kyiv-business-europe-f0e1cd893715eda1e6bef696d9c47db3"&gt;the seizure of Mariupol&lt;/a&gt; — to soften the blow from its overall strategic defeat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ZuyPqp"&gt;Russia is shifting to the Donbas because its initial attack failed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="H4sm0l"&gt;There are good reasons for Russia to focus on the Donbas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZYa2P"&gt;Ukraine’s easternmost region, stretching from Luhansk down to around Mariupol in the south, the Donbas directly borders Russia and Russian-held territory in southern Ukraine. Seizing the region’s south would create a Russian-controlled corridor connecting occupied Crimea to Russia proper, a so-called “land bridge” that would make supplying Crimea somewhat easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5P1qh"&gt;The Donbas’s population has long been more pro-Russian than the rest of Ukraine, though this &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/04/15/russia-ukraine-donbas-donetsk-luhansk-public-opinion/"&gt;can be overstated&lt;/a&gt; and may well have changed since the war began. The region has been at the center of Russia’s war propaganda, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/24/22948944/putin-ukraine-nazi-russia-speech-declare-war"&gt;inventing claims of a “genocide” against ethnic Russians&lt;/a&gt; in the region to justify the invasion. It is rich in natural gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w1OZkT"&gt;And yet, not a single one of these reasons was sufficient to make the Donbas the center of Russia’s initial invasion. That’s because the goal at first was &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23003689/putin-ukraine-russia-donbas-energy-feint"&gt;regime change in Kyiv&lt;/a&gt; — Putin’s now-infamous announcement to seek the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/24/22948944/putin-ukraine-nazi-russia-speech-declare-war"&gt;“de-Nazification” and “de-militarization” of Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3MJ3X7"&gt;The new focus dates back to March 25, when the Russian general staff announced their intention to shift offensive combat operations to the Donbas region. At the time, Russian forces were engaged in fighting across Ukraine’s north, east, and south, as you can see on the following map from the Institute for the Study of War (a Washington-based think tank).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HuiRWqK11xkQWs5LK1KsFJLiFA8=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23406094/ISW_Map_March_25.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-march-25" target="_blank"&gt;Institute for the Study of War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;In late March, Russian forces were fighting on several fronts in Ukraine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HbfcxS"&gt;Over the course of the next month, Russia conducted a strategic withdrawal from much of the battlefront, especially around Kyiv and Chernihiv. By April 20, the ISW map shows a shrunken Russian presence focused primarily on fighting in and around the Donbas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4axkbK0maTApYNNWSSPDr7aB8B0=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23406106/ISW_Map_April_20.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-april-20" target="_blank"&gt;Institute for the Study of War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;By late April, Russia’s troops had shifted almost entirely to the Donbas region in eastern Ukraine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SwfwFz"&gt;This shift, first and foremost, reflects the inability of Russian troops to seize Ukraine’s capital and overthrow its government in one fell swoop. “Putin has really started to rethink the strategic aims in Ukraine after the massive strategic failure in Kyiv,” says Rachel Rizzo, a senior fellow at the Atlantic Council’s Europe Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Q3Mwh"&gt;Understanding the nature of this failure is vital to understanding what’s happening in the Donbas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApdRv9"&gt;In the Kyiv theater, Russia attempted to plunge troops and armor forward rapidly to seize and/or encircle the capital. These pushes assumed light Ukrainian resistance, which did not end up being the case, and they were undercut by poor logistics and a decision to travel on open roads that created easy opportunities for ambushes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="towqpQ"&gt;The Ukrainians took advantage, raiding Russia’s weak supply lines and stymieing the Russians in brutal block-to-block fighting in &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-60959667"&gt;Kyiv suburbs like Irpin&lt;/a&gt;. Russia’s air force, vastly superior to Ukraine’s on paper, was unable to control the skies, allowing Ukrainian drones to wreak havoc on Russian armor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xrB82DQrKmSme9MpyxjsXh6mDUI=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408452/GettyImages_1240059694.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Sergei Chuzavkov/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A Ukrainian flag flies near a destroyed building in a residential area of Borodyanka, northwest of Kyiv and Irpin, on April 17.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9a5oZI"&gt;The war in the Donbas is different. Russia’s main military objective is &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/384d981b-d3da-4fca-b6ab-21b1136bd2ab"&gt;cutting off Ukraine’s army in the region&lt;/a&gt;, known as the Joint Forces, from the rest of Ukraine by seizing territory to the west of its positions. If the Russian effort is successful, the Joint Forces will lose their ability to resupply and ability to keep fighting — which would allow Russia to consolidate control over a vast swath of the Donbas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nNr6Ck"&gt;This plan avoids many of the pitfalls that beset Russian forces in the Kyiv region. It mostly requires seizing open terrain from the Ukrainians rather than engaging in urban environments that favor defenders. It entails fighting in a concentrated area, rather than a series of dispersed fronts, which in theory should create fewer vulnerable supply lines. And Russia currently enjoys &lt;a href="https://rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/russia-likely-has-local-air-superiority-donbas-it-may-not-matter"&gt;a measure of air superiority in the Donbas&lt;/a&gt; that it didn’t elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W0Grtr"&gt;“If they mass forces, which they’re trying to do now, and they mass them in the right place and they use of a lot artillery and air strikes, they can still have tactical success,” says Rob Lee, a senior fellow in the Foreign Policy Research Institute’s Eurasia Program. “That’s why the Donbas plays into the Russian military’s strength and mitigates some of their weaknesses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUiT58"&gt;This is why we should expect a different kind of fighting in the Donbas: fewer raids, more large-scale conflicts between armies. This should favor a Russian force that has always outclassed the Ukrainians in armor, artillery, and aircraft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9erGem"&gt;Ultimately, the Russian objective here, per some analysts, is to take enough territory to be able to sell its own population — and the world — on the idea that their campaign was a success despite the failures around Kyiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1-Ib6FJcdG0f2pK41goqNxEVG3Y=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408571/GettyImages_1239919441.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Anatolii Stepanov/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Ukrainian soldiers keep their position in a trench on the front line with Russian troops in Luhansk on April 11.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5H0LDl"&gt;If Russia can secure its control over the breakaway republics in the area controlled by pro-Russian separatists — the Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics — they can claim to have achieved a pre-war aim of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/24/22948944/putin-ukraine-nazi-russia-speech-declare-war"&gt;stopping “genocide.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fY5NhO"&gt;“They have now put their stake on this being the ‘defense’ of the Donbas,” says Olga Oliker, the International Crisis Group’s program director for Europe and Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="unxCiU"&gt;Ukraine can still win despite Russia’s advantages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="P2JYP2"&gt;If we’ve learned anything in this conflict so far, it’s that theoretical Russian advantages don’t always translate to battlefield success. And there are reasons to think that Ukraine may once again repulse the Russian attack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pzfU7V"&gt;The nature of Russia’s plan pits its army against &lt;a href="https://kyivindependent.com/national/explainer-what-to-expect-from-the-battle-of-donbas-russias-new-offensive/"&gt;the Ukrainian military elite&lt;/a&gt;. The Joint Forces have been fighting in the Donbas since 2014, when Russian-backed separatists rebelled against the government in Kyiv and Russia annexed Crimea. Eight years of war means that they have significant battlefield experience and an understanding of how Russian-trained fighters operate. Given that Russia has made extensive use of untested fighters in this conflict, including &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/conscripts-sent-fight-by-pro-russia-donbas-get-little-training-old-rifles-poor-2022-04-04/"&gt;poorly trained and equipped conscripts&lt;/a&gt;, the Ukrainian advantage in experience could prove decisive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bDm9H4"&gt;We also don’t know if Russia has fixed some of the major problems that plagued their campaigns elsewhere in the country. Incompetent logistics and maintenance led to Russian tanks breaking down on Ukrainian roads, out of gas or stuck in the mud. Russian commanders repeatedly employed baffling tactics, failing to concentrate their forces and creating vulnerabilities Ukraine could exploit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nInAOv"&gt;“The biggest question of this upcoming set of battles ... is whether or not they have sufficiently learned from the failures of the first month of the war, and are going to put together a coherent, properly resourced effort,” says Kofman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lp5JmDZOUNBf7Axpplxkr1MszoQ=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408521/GettyImages_1391789299.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Chris McGrath/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Ukrainian troops walk through rubble after a shopping center and surrounding buildings in Kharkiv were hit by a Russian missile strike on April 16.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Kp3Qpo"&gt;The Ukrainians seem to have two significant and connected advantages: numbers and morale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Thf3hg"&gt;On paper, Russia’s military is significantly larger than Ukraine’s. But analysts believe that Ukraine may well be able to field a larger force than Russia in the battle for the Donbas. This is primarily a matter of policy choices: While Ukraine has called up its reserves and recruited civilians in ad hoc militias, Russia has steadfastly refused to adopt a total war footing (its conscription has, so far, been limited).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kUSDDL"&gt;In military theory, a rule of thumb is that attackers should enjoy &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/ukraine-the-battle-for-donbas-will-be-protracted-and-bloody-military-expert-180988"&gt;a three-to-one advantage&lt;/a&gt; over defenders; Russia won’t even approach that, and may suffer numerical disadvantages in some battles. Experts say it would take time for Russia to mobilize substantial reserves from its larger population — time that they simply don’t have, given that the offensive is starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWhqUf"&gt;“Because they’ve been so stuck in trying to fight a large conventional war as a ‘special military operation,’ they don’t have access to any large manpower reserves,” Kofman explains. “[By contrast], the Ukrainian military has a tremendous amount of manpower — they have a mobilized reserve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pTrv1I"&gt;Part of the reason for this discrepancy is significant Russian losses in the first phase of the war. But another part is that the Ukrainian population is profoundly committed to the war, creating a large pool of willing fighters who perform more effectively than Russian conscripts. “The Ukrainians can get away with putting accountants who used to shoot at beer bottles out at the dacha because they’re defending their territory,” Oliker says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NDxZbD"&gt;While Russian civilians &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/18/1093282038/russia-war-public-opinion-polling"&gt;seem to support the war from afar&lt;/a&gt;, evidence from the battlefield shows a Russian force &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/02/friendly-fire-blunders-confusion-low-morale-why-russias-army-has-stalled"&gt;suffering from consistently low morale&lt;/a&gt;, for reasons ranging from poor training to confusion as to why they’re fighting in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wz2qht"&gt;This gulf in morale has shaped the two sides’ battlefield performance, and will likely continue to do so. Demoralized Russian soldiers are more likely to withdraw when they meet Ukrainian resistance, while the highly motivated Ukrainians are more willing to take risks and lay down their lives to protect their homeland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CLgSYj"&gt;How much does the outcome in the Donbas matter?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="gQQtmF"&gt;Both sides have pretty good reasons to believe that they could emerge triumphant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zbAbVd"&gt;It’s possible Russia successfully pulls Ukraine into a series of pitched battles in which their aircraft and artillery advantages prove decisive, allowing them to encircle the Joint Forces and seize the entire Donbas. It’s possible that the Ukrainians successfully blunt the Russian attack and mount a counteroffensive, leveraging their manpower reserves and more motivated fighting force to retake parts of the region Russia currently controls. It’s possible they end up in a bloody stalemate, a long war of attrition where the two armies wear each other out over the course of months or years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uUJvk5"&gt;Right now, as the fighting is just ramping up, it’s impossible to say which of these scenarios, if any, is the most likely outcome. Too much depends on unpredictable battlefield developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kfLcXH-zR2rXtw6huhtdQ4U3jRU=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408639/AP22107473659606.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Andriy Andriyenko/AP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Andrey and wife Anastasia crouch behind a building with daughters Anna, 2, Nadezhda, 5, and Sofia, 6, after hearing shelling during an evacuation of civilians at a bus station in Kramatorsk on April 17. Russian forces have been advancing to the eastern Ukrainian city from the Donbas.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TfNKwo"&gt;But at the same time, it’s not clear how much the outcome of the battle will actually end up mattering. In my conversations with experts, each and every one of them said that, in the big picture, Russia has suffered an irreversible defeat in this war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhFFNF"&gt;“The Russian special military operation in Ukraine is already a strategic failure,” Oliker says. “What they wanted out of this was a compliant Ukraine run by people friendly to Russia. This does not seem like a plausible outcome — and, aside from that, their forces have proven to be much less capable than almost everyone thought.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qj4dlO"&gt;The initial Russian war aim, as evidenced by its &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23003689/putin-ukraine-russia-donbas-energy-feint"&gt;early statements and troop deployments&lt;/a&gt;, was to inflict a decisive blow on Ukraine that would transform the country’s political institutions: either imposing a Russian puppet regime or forcing the current Ukrainian leadership to surrender on Russian terms. When Russia withdrew from Kyiv — and not just Kyiv, but most of the northern Ukrainian theater — it de facto conceded that its fundamental war aim was outside of its power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BAh2e4"&gt;Even if they do manage to take significant new territory in the Donbas, or impose full control over a bombed-out Mariupol, it’s difficult&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to imagine these gains outweighing the war’s costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WXoTdq"&gt;The Russian economy has been damaged by sanctions, which &lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-closes-in-on-russian-oil-ban-vladimir-putin-ukraine/"&gt;could well escalate&lt;/a&gt; in the coming weeks. Europe has united against Russia, with &lt;a href="https://sanctionsnews.bakermckenzie.com/switzerland-adopts-fifth-comprehensive-sanctions-package-against-russia-imposed-by-the-european-union/"&gt;historically neutral Switzerland&lt;/a&gt; joining the sanctions and both Sweden and Finland &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-inches-closer-nato-after-parliament-expresses-support-military-alignment-2022-04-20/"&gt;moving toward joining NATO&lt;/a&gt;. The war has embarrassed Russia’s military and depleted it materially; any territory they occupy in the Donbas will be home to many citizens who hate them, creating the very real prospect of an insurgency backed by Ukraine and the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="foXTmi"&gt;“Win, lose, or draw — the Russian military is likely to be exhausted for some period of time after this coming set of battles,” Kofman says. “The Russian military is very short on manpower, and that’s been evident since the outset of the war. The more territory they capture, the greater the pull on manpower they have, to occupy the territory they seized.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xja8mk4V6rAUe4Eax45IIJnk3D0=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23408566/GettyImages_1239935156.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Alexander Nemenov/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;People walk down a debris-laden Mariupol avenue on April 12.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iRdcbZ"&gt;In this sense, the fight for the Donbas is less important than it might seem. The highest-stakes issue in the war seems to have been decided, with Russia on the losing end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GjeqC7"&gt;But at the same time, there are real stakes — both in human terms, for the soldiers and civilians who will perish, and also in broader political terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8JYl6"&gt;The more successful the Russian war in the Donbas is, the easier of a time Putin will have selling his war as a victory to Russia’s citizens. The more territory he controls there, the more leverage he will have at the negotiating table — meaning that he’ll be able to extract more significant concessions on issues like NATO membership from Zelenskyy in exchange for giving back territory taken in the Donbas. (In theory, Russia could benefit economically from controlling the Donbas and its gas reserves; in practice, sanctions, the war’s devastation, and a likely insurgency will probably make it more of a burden than a boon.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMMCrf"&gt;By contrast, another humiliating Russian collapse could do serious damage to Russia’s strategic position. Not only would it make Russian threats of force less credible in other places — who could take their military seriously after such a resounding defeat? — but it could&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;also &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22961563/putin-russia-ukraine-coup-revolution-invasion"&gt;raise the odds of a political challenge to Putin at home&lt;/a&gt;. Zelenskyy would have a dominant hand in peace negotiations, and could achieve terms that would allow for more significant Ukrainian security and political integration with the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTG8rd"&gt;So while this round of fighting may be less important than the previous one, the stakes are still high.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/22/23034480/russia-donbas-new-phase-war-ukraine-explained" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/4/22/23034480/russia-donbas-new-phase-war-ukraine-explained</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-22T07:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-22T07:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why is it Macron and Le Pen, again?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U4BeSuRB_A7Flupz7tvBdAoyZng=/400x0:3600x2400/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70779863/GettyImages_1239565594.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A worker puts up posters for French presidential candidates, including incumbent centrist candidate Emmanuel Macron, left, and far-right candidate Marine Le Pen, right, on a wall in Bordeaux, France, on March 28. Macron and Le Pen will face each other in a runoff election on April 24. | Philippe Lopez/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;French presidential runoff elections take place on April 24. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="QuXZKs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZqqaT"&gt;French president Emmanuel Macron will face off against the far-right candidate Marine Le Pen in the country’s &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/4/10/23019045/macron-le-pen-france-presidential-election-first-round"&gt;April 24 presidential runoff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tw8m9q"&gt;It is a rematch of sorts of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2017/5/8/15578338/french-election-2017-macron-le-pen-results"&gt;2017 election&lt;/a&gt;. But the dynamics that gave voters a reprise of the Macron-Le Pen matchup reveal deeper shifts in French politics: a collapse of traditional parties, a mainstreaming of right-wing discourse, and a disunity among the left. All bring &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/french-far-left-consultations-show-majority-will-abstain-vote-blank-presidential-2022-04-17/"&gt;a degree of uncertainty to the election this Sunday&lt;/a&gt;, even if &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/bookmakers-see-frances-macron-easily-winning-sundays-runoff-2022-04-20/"&gt;Macron is now favored to win&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TUT7d0"&gt;Maybe nothing exemplifies this more than the implosion of France’s mainstream center-right and center-left parties &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/4/10/23019045/macron-le-pen-france-presidential-election-first-round"&gt;in the first round of the elections on April 10&lt;/a&gt;. The candidates for the traditionally center-right Republicans finished behind two far-right candidates — Le Pen, of the National Rally, and the more extreme Éric Zemmour and his Reconquête party. The traditionally center-left Socialist candidate was demolished by the left-wing populist, Jean-Luc Mélenchon of La France Insoumise. In both cases, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/10/europe/french-presidential-election-results-intl/index.html"&gt;it was not all that close&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RKv9Gc"&gt;“We are absolutely seeing the collapse of the former mainstream right and former mainstream left in France in a really, really striking way,” said Sarah Wiliarty, an associate professor of government, specializing in Western European politics, at Wesleyan University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZDEiMz"&gt;Macron himself may be the biggest reason for the struggles of the mainstream parties, having captured the political center. He is pro-environment, pro-LGBTQ rights, and pro-European project. But, on the economy, he is much more the pro-business, lower-taxes type. “He stole from the moderates from the left and on the right,” said Rainbow Murray, an expert on French politics at Queen Mary University of London. “And the moderates, of course, are where the average voter is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJPkz5"&gt;This year, Le Pen built off her position in the 2017 runoffs by trying to frame herself as more mainstream. Some experts said the far-right’s ascendance has pulled &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/31/magazine/new-french-right.html"&gt;the entire political discourse rightward in France&lt;/a&gt;. Rim-Sarah Alouane, a researcher in comparative law at Toulouse 1 Capitole University in France,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;said the “normalization” of the far-right has allowed more mainstream parties to absorb versions of their talking points — on issues like immigration and integration into French society. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZrktKh"&gt;But, since 2017, Le Pen has put even more effort into softening the edges of her extremist rhetoric and elevating a populist message that still captures a lot of the right. If you’re a voter who finds a message like Le Pen’s appealing, “do you,” as Wiliarty put it, “go for a watered-down version from the Republicans? Or do you go for the real deal?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nO0OMG"&gt;All of that has combined to help give France another showdown between Macron and Le Pen. Unlike last time, Macron has been tested in office — and at times, &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/europe/20220401-will-france-s-yellow-vests-come-back-to-haunt-macron-on-election-day"&gt;faced real resistance to his agenda&lt;/a&gt;. Though Macron’s lock on a second term &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/16/europe/macron-le-pen-france-election-runoff-intl/index.html"&gt;isn’t as sure&lt;/a&gt; as some experts expected, as Sunday approaches, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-18/macron-s-lead-over-le-pen-widens-slightly-ahead-of-election"&gt;he is building about a 10 percentage-point lead&lt;/a&gt; in polls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUIufa"&gt;A lot will depend on the voters whose candidates didn’t make it through the first round, specifically those who supported Mélenchon, who came in third. The question is who they will support in the runoff — &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-18/macron-s-lead-over-le-pen-widens-slightly-ahead-of-election"&gt;if they support anyone at all&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3lM9uB"&gt;Macron’s agenda has proven to be more right-of-center, which leaves some leftist voters with two less-than-satisfactory choices. &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20220412-macron-softens-on-controversial-pension-reform-as-he-heads-into-tight-run-off"&gt;Macron has tried to broaden his appeal on the left&lt;/a&gt; as April 24 gets closer. But this election may be less about a vote for Macron than about a vote against Le Pen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IDg41qqvthEskvNFnmfOJ9c4hiQ=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23404092/GettyImages_1239898129.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Joel Saget/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;French far-right presidential candidate Marine Le Pen, center, and supporters react after seeing preliminary results during the first round of voting in the French presidential election in Paris on April 10.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xLLNHG"&gt;Sunday’s contest may turn on how many voters make that choice — and whether it will be enough to give Macron a real mandate to govern. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zSL4SF"&gt;“If he’s just the man who could barely beat Le Pen, then that’s going to make it much harder for him to push things through,” Murray said. “So he needs to win. But he needs to win credibly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Sj3fQB"&gt;The headliners are the same as 2017, but the showdown isn’t &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0ZmVjx"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/10/europe/french-presidential-election-results-intl/index.html"&gt;the first round&lt;/a&gt; of France’s presidential elections, on April 10, Macron won just shy of 28 percent of the vote. Le Pen came in second, with a tiny bit more than 23 percent. Mélenchon, the left-wing candidate, fell just short of a spot in the runoff, with 22 percent. Everybody else delivered single-digit results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkdAVL"&gt;The results are maybe not that unexpected. While experts said it’s pretty remarkable that France’s mainstream left and right parties have practically disappeared on the national level (&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/11/french-election-macron-le-pen-politics/"&gt;it’s a little more nuanced in local politics&lt;/a&gt;), political parties are traditionally a bit weaker in France, and party affiliation and organization is less deeply rooted than in other parts of Europe (&lt;a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/eurocrisispress/2021/09/28/fragmentation-germany/"&gt;which have also seen political fragmentation&lt;/a&gt;, if not to the same degree.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQk7jJ"&gt;Macron, after all, created his own party, La République En Marche. In 2018, Le Pen &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/20180601-france-national-front-renamed-national-rally-le-pen-marine"&gt;renamed&lt;/a&gt; the far-right National Front, &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2017/04/21/525110143/marine-le-pens-brutal-upbringing-shaped-her-worldview"&gt;whose leadership she inherited from her even-more-radical father&lt;/a&gt;, to the National Rally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="duX571"&gt;It is a sign that the parties may be mutable, and that the pull comes more from the candidates and their politics. But Le Pen and Macron are not running as exactly the same politicians they were in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qXMegK"&gt;Le Pen learned lessons from 2017, and has &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/07/world/europe/marine-le-pen-french-elections-macron.html"&gt;tried to detoxify some of her party’s politics to appeal to more mainstream voters&lt;/a&gt;. She has emphasized economic issues, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-04-19/le-pen-mixes-hardline-policies-with-social-welfare-to-widen-appeal"&gt;like protecting French workers.&lt;/a&gt; She’s also tried to tweak her most controversial policies. For example, she has shifted from calling for an aggressive curtailing of immigration, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/14/marine-le-pen-presidential-election-2022/"&gt;instead supporting a referendum for France to decide&lt;/a&gt;. She also no longer wants France to leave the EU, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/15/frexit-what-marine-le-pen-win-mean-eu"&gt;but does still want to implement policies to vastly weaken it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9z8wl2"&gt;This &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/13/world/europe/marine-le-pen-national-front-party.html"&gt;“un-demonization”&lt;/a&gt; strategy is a lot more cosmetic than anything else. “The heart, the soul of the far-right is still rotten to the core,” Alouane said. “It’s still the same party, but with a different face. It’s plastic surgery.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dS7efB"&gt;If political plastic surgery was the strategy, Le Pen looked even more mainstream compared to the more radical right-wing party that arose alongside of her, which did push the kind of racist, overly anti-immigrant rhetoric that Le Pen had tried to edit. &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/europe/20220412-how-zemmour-s-storm-in-a-teacup-hijacked-french-campaign-%E2%80%93-and-helped-le-pen"&gt;Zemmour, the candidate to her right, also got a lot of media attention&lt;/a&gt; — which may have helped Le Pen escape some scrutiny. “She was both clever and got lucky,” Wiliarty said. (Zemmour received about 7 percent of the vote in the first round, &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/video/20220411-french-far-right-candidate-zemmour-endorses-le-pen-for-runoff"&gt;and has endorsed Le Pen for the runoff&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5rq8Eg"&gt;Macron also isn’t the same candidate as in 2017. Then, Macron was the “&lt;a href="https://www.barrons.com/news/france-s-macron-tacks-right-in-bid-for-2022-triumph-01620547216"&gt;wunderkind&lt;/a&gt;,” a political &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20220415-ex-president-hollande-calls-for-macron-vote-to-keep-le-pen-out-of-power"&gt;outsider-ish&lt;/a&gt; who managed to be a sort of anti-establishment establishmentarian, promising a pragmatic and anti-populist presidency. He was pro-EU, and pro-Western values in the wake of Brexit and Trump, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/1de1c540-dd7b-11e6-86ac-f253db7791c6"&gt;and he was framed as an antidote to both&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CWmzs7"&gt;Now, he’s got a term in office for voters to scrutinize. “It’s easier for the other candidates to attack him. He’s in a weaker position now than he was in 2017,” said Francesca Vassallo, an associate professor of political science at the University of Southern Maine, who studies French and European politics.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nO8PQr1xHNhbK70CjIKyrmNx12U=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23404109/GettyImages_1239902773.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Ludovic Marin/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;French President and candidate for re-election Emmanuel Macron addresses supporters after the first round of France’s presidential election, in Paris on April 10.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Exosw5"&gt;The populist &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/12/3/18123906/france-protest-macron-paris-riots-yellow-vest-arc"&gt;“yellow vest”&lt;/a&gt; uprising threatened Macron’s presidency early on. The protests began in 2018 over a proposed fuel tax hike, framed as an effort to reduce France’s dependence on fossil fuels, but morphed into larger grievances about France’s economy and Macron as a president for the rich — especially as &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-france-tax/macron-fights-president-of-the-rich-tag-after-ending-wealth-tax-idUSKCN1C82CZ"&gt;Macron took actions like abolishing a wealth tax&lt;/a&gt;. Then, &lt;a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/best-countries/articles/2020-04-28/will-coronavirus-help-re-elect-a-struggling-french-president-emmanuel-macron"&gt;Covid-19 consumed Macron’s presidency&lt;/a&gt;, and now, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-tells-macron-russia-will-achieve-its-goals-ukraine-2022-03-03/"&gt;the crisis in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/tv-shows/france-in-focus/20220128-france-s-price-hikes-households-bearing-the-brunt-of-inflation"&gt;price hikes because of inflation&lt;/a&gt;. Though this may not be surprising from a guy who started his own political party, voters have bristled at &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20220410-macron-centrist-reformer-dogged-by-accusations-of-arrogance"&gt;his perceived arrogance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fMkXOW"&gt;France’s post-Covid-19 economic recovery has been strong, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/08/world/europe/france-presidential-election-macron-economy-le-pen.html"&gt;and Macron has delivered on promises to attract business and tech&lt;/a&gt;. But Macron’s policies of tax cuts and welfare and pension reform have contrasted sharply with the national mood, where French voters are &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/mar/22/people-feel-suffocated-cost-of-living-tops-french-concerns-before-election"&gt;worried about price increases&lt;/a&gt;. As experts said, his policy manifesto looks a lot like what you’d expect from a center-right Republican. “His ideological shift in both economic and social terms has been towards the right,” Murray said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="t1XTsf"&gt;Macron has the middle. But is that enough?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rkgbqk"&gt;Macron, in 2017, trounced Le Pen, &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/887844/french-presidential-election-results/"&gt;winning about two-thirds of the vote&lt;/a&gt;. He appealed to the middle — on the right and the left. But he also was the new guy, who promised an untested vision. Even for many left-wing voters who may not have loved all of his policies, he was a clear alternative to Le Pen’s extremism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHAu31"&gt;The wild card is whether that will hold true in 2022. The fear is that left-wing voters, especially those who opted for Mélenchon, will be disillusioned. “Macron or Le Pen, we’re screwed in any case. For my first election, I’d hoped for better,” an 18-year-old student and Mélenchon voter &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20220413-screwed-either-way-macron-le-pen-presidential-duel-leaves-young-m%C3%A9lenchon-voters-cold"&gt;told France24&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vQJCXI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20220418-in-france-s-unhappy-democracy-voting-for-lesser-evil-is-a-bitter-pill-to-swallow"&gt;About a quarter of French voters&lt;/a&gt; abstained in the first round on April 10, and the fear is that will happen again in the runoff. In particular, Mélenchon’s bloc of voters might abstain, or may even opt for Le Pen, seeing her economic populist message as more appealing than Macron’s technocratic one. Mélenchon, the left-wing candidate, has told his supporters to vote against Le Pen — &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/france/20220417-leftist-party-consultation-shows-majority-will-abstain-vote-blank-in-macron-le-pen-run-off"&gt;but he has also stopped short of backing Macron&lt;/a&gt;. A recent poll showed a pretty even breakdown of Mélenchon voters, splitting into thirds on &lt;a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/international-politics/french-election-2022/2022/04/exclusive-polling-emmanuel-macron-strengthens-his-position-after-the-first-round-of-the-french-election"&gt;whether they will abstain, vote Macron, or vote Le Pen in the second round&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhbjO3"&gt;There was an assumption, likely made by Macron himself, that he could take the left for granted, “and they will support him because they have nowhere else to go,” Murray said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jHO0VU"&gt;“Which is an assumption that’s now being challenged because he’s now facing abstention from the left rather than supporting him against Le Pen,” she added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VN3lUB"&gt;Macron himself &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2022/04/10/french-election-results-2022/"&gt;seems to be recognizing his missteps&lt;/a&gt;, and has tried to correct course on the campaign trail. Take his pension reform proposal, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/macron-proposes-increasing-frances-retirement-age-to-65-11647547654"&gt;which included raising the retirement age to 65 from 62&lt;/a&gt;. As experts pointed out, this probably isn’t a great policy to ever introduce before a national election, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/12/macron-hints-at-compromise-over-plan-to-raise-retirement-age-france-le-pen"&gt;but Macron has now said&lt;/a&gt; he’s open to a more incremental timeline, or raising the age to 64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A711wc"&gt;The question is whether Macron’s late-game pivot will be enough. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/macron-cements-french-presidential-frontrunner-status-with-combative-debate-2022-04-21/"&gt;Macron and Le Pen squared off in a debate Wednesday night&lt;/a&gt;, their only meeting before the vote. Macron dug into Le Pen’s ties to Vladimir Putin, a particularly salient issue amid the Ukraine war. Le Pen tried to frame Macron as out of touch. In 2017, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/may/04/french-election-marine-le-pen-and-emmanuel-macron-trade-insults-in-tv-debate"&gt;Macron’s debate performance was decisive&lt;/a&gt; in his victory. This time around, Macron was also seen as having the edge; in at least one &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/macron-cements-french-presidential-frontrunner-status-with-combative-debate-2022-04-21/"&gt;snap poll&lt;/a&gt;, 59 percent of people said Macron was the most convincing in the debate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J3O11S"&gt;In the end, Macron may have done enough to secure a second term. Macron remains ahead in the polls, and many voters do understand the threat of Le Pen. Alouane said, in broad terms, especially for France’s most vulnerable, it is a “vote that stinks versus vote that kills.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jNKM-1xfy_41lCKmlZ2zrGDBxHs=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23404122/AP22106576514184.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Christophe Ena/AP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Demonstrators hold banners reading “For Social Justice” and “United Against the Far Right” during a protest against far-right politics in Paris, on April 16, ahead of the runoff vote on April 24.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TfQpTC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2021/06/30/behind-bidens-2020-victory/"&gt;But maybe, as the United States can attest&lt;/a&gt;, voting against one person isn’t really the same as voting&lt;em&gt; for&lt;/em&gt; a person. Macron may eke out a win, but that is unlikely to vanquish Le Pen and the far-right, and it may mean Macron begins his second term as a far weaker president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xcb6j7"&gt;And that may not just be based on Sunday’s results. As experts pointed out, France’s future will also &lt;a href="http://fingfx.thomsonreuters.com/gfx/rngs/FRANCE-ELECTION/010041FQ34H/index.html"&gt;be decided in the elections&lt;/a&gt; for France’s National Assembly later this spring. Experts said that if Macron wins the election Sunday, his party is likely to win control of the Assembly, but likely not with the majorities he had in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzrahq"&gt;But, experts added, if Le Pen wins on Sunday, it may be the type of shock that fully rattles the electorate. “It is very likely that will be a strong backlash against her and her party,” Vassallo said. “And so people would vote for other parties and not for hers. This means she will be a president without having a political majority in the National Assembly. That is not fun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oLwQxc"&gt;If that happens, it would restrain Le Pen’s domestic agenda, and make her a fairly weak president. But president nonetheless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UkXcsY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/23032713/macron-le-pen-debate-french-elections-april-24" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/23032713/macron-le-pen-debate-french-elections-april-24</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jen Kirby</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-04-21T15:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-21T15:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How “Z” became Putin’s new propaganda meme</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A young man with his back to the camera wears a black jacket with a white letter “Z” made of tape on the back. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/341UnXhHmOCQcVg8ZjSj7S9KdsM=/240x0:1680x1080/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70777740/thumb_clean.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The letter now signifies loyalty to the Russian president.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="qCCB5g"&gt;Russian gymnast Ivan Kuliak caused controversy in March when he accepted a bronze medal at a World Cup event, while sporting a taped-on letter “Z” on his uniform. The Z symbol had already been appearing all over Russia, as a sign of support for the Russian invasion of Ukraine and loyalty to Russian President Vladimir Putin. The letter popped up on merchandise, in highly organized flash mobs that often involved children, at pro-war rallies, and in internet memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ygSQg"&gt;The symbol was originally spotted on Russian tanks and trucks building up at Ukraine’s border in late February, along with other letters like V and O. Questions about what the symbols meant began circulating online, and once the invasion began on February 24, most analysts agreed the markings were likely for tactical purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LfIkaa"&gt;But as intrigue around them grew, the Russian Defense Ministry &lt;a href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2022/03/16/z"&gt;seized on the opportunity&lt;/a&gt; to claim that the letters carry extra meaning. They began generating memes that incorporated the Z and V into propaganda slogans. Those letters don’t appear in the Russian language’s Cyrillic alphabet, so some of the memes Latinize them: most common are ones that begin with the word “for” — spelled “Зa” in Russian, but Latinized to “Za” for the memes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OiVToV"&gt;Another way Putin’s regime has turned the Z into a propaganda meme has been by connecting it with the Soviet victory over Nazi Germany in World War II. The “Great Patriotic War” maintains a significant presence in Russian culture — the anniversary of Germany’s defeat is celebrated each year on May 9, and World War II imagery is heavily associated with Russian patriotism and national pride. Z memes that incorporate old photos of Soviet soldiers — and the recognizable orange-and-black stripes of the Ribbon of St. George, a Russian military decoration — are an attempt to equate the current war in Ukraine with World War II. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nNZOHj"&gt;The Z has spread beyond Russia, too. It’s now seen in pro-Russian demonstrations worldwide and is banned in a growing list of countries. The Z’s evolution from tactical markings on invasion vehicles to &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/z-is-the-symbol-of-the-new-russian-politics-of-aggression"&gt;a global pro-war symbol&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates the effectiveness of the Putin regime’s propaganda strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VOBwvl"&gt;This video is part of our ongoing, broader coverage of the Russian invasion of Ukraine. For more videos that provide historical context to the headlines in the news today, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLJ8cMiYb3G5eZQK-3tCqQCWV49C1M6aKh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watch our playlist here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O4zB9x"&gt;You can find this video, our playlist, and the entire library of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vox’s videos on our YouTube channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/videos/2022/4/21/23036130/russia-propaganda-z-ukraine-putin" />
    <id>https://www.vox.com/videos/2022/4/21/23036130/russia-propaganda-z-ukraine-putin</id>
    <author>
      <name>Coleman Lowndes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>