<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>World – TIME</title>
    <link>https://time.com</link>
    <description>Current &amp; Breaking News | National &amp; World Updates</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:53:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">162509141</site>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/time/world" />
    <feedburner:info uri="time/world" />
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly>
    <item>
      <title>The History Behind Victory Day in Russia</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173515/russia-victory-day-history/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia B. Waxman]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[nationpod]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173515</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The holiday marks the Soviet victory over Nazi Germany in WW II. Now, as Russia's war on Ukraine continues, the day takes on new meaning]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173515"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173515/russia-victory-day-history/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>Victory Day is always a big holiday in Russia: It marks the Soviet Union&#8217;s victory over Nazi Germany in World War II, a conflict during which more than 8 million Soviet soldiers died.</p>
<p>But this year, as Russia&#8217;s war on Ukraine continues, the day will take on new meaning. Since Russia invaded Ukraine on Feb. 24, there&#8217;s been <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/03/europe/russia-victory-day-explainer-intl/index.html"  target="_blank">speculation</a> about whether Victory Day will mark <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/05/putin-speech-may-9-victory-day-russia/629742/"  target="_blank">a turning point</a> in the war that has already killed thousands and forced millions to flee from their homes.</p>
<p>In March, the <em>Kyiv Independent</em> reported that Russian troops were being told <a href="https://twitter.com/KyivIndependent/status/1507095376247074826?s=20&amp;t=g2UK3kTdZE9mYLyY1za1ow"  target="_blank">the war must end by May 9</a>, while more recently, U.S. and western officials have openly wondered if <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/03/europe/russia-ukraine-declaration-of-war-intl-hnk-ml/index.html"  target="_blank">Russia will officially declare war on May 9</a>, escalating what Russian President Vladimir Putin has insisted is merely a &#8220;special military operation.&#8221; But on May 1, Russia&#8217;s foreign minister Sergei Lavrov said, &#8220;Our military will not artificially adjust their actions to any date, including Victory Day,&#8221; the Moscow <em>Times </em><a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/05/02/russia-not-seeking-to-end-ukraine-war-by-may-9-foreign-minister-a77551"  target="_blank">reported</a>.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>&#8220;We will solemnly celebrate May 9, as we always do,&#8221; Lavrov continued. &#8220;Remember those who fell for the liberation of Russia and other republics of the former U.S.S.R., for the liberation of Europe from the Nazi plague.&#8221;</p>
<p>World War II has shaped Putin&#8217;s approach to the Russia-Ukraine war; In justifying the invasion of Ukraine, he claimed he had set out to &#8220;denazify&#8221; the country&mdash;a phrase that many pundits noted is <a href="https://time.com/6154493/denazification-putin-ukraine-history-context/" >inaccurate</a> in this context given Ukraine has <a href="https://time.com/6154139/volodymyr-zelensky-ukraine-profile-russia/" >a Jewish President</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong>Read more: </strong></em><a href="https://time.com/5832549/world-war-ii-memory/" ><em>World War II in Europe Ended 75 Years Ago&mdash;But the World Is Still Fighting Over Who Gets to Say What Happened</em></a></p>
<p>World War II has always been central to the Russian state&#8217;s approach to telling the country&#8217;s history. While the Allies marked May 7 as <a href="https://time.com/3845239/victory-day-may-11/" >&#8220;V-E Day&#8221;</a>&mdash;Victory in Europe Day&mdash;to commemorate the Nazis surrendering in Reims, France, Soviet leader Joseph Stalin wanted to wait to celebrate until the Nazis surrendered in Soviet-controlled Berlin the next day. By the time the text was signed late at night, it was already May 9 on Moscow time.</p>
<p>As TIME has previously reported, in the 1960s Soviet leader Leonid Brezhnev made May 9 a national holiday, <a href="https://time.com/5832549/world-war-ii-memory/" >complete with military parades</a>. Russia&#8217;s first post-Soviet President Boris Yeltsin turned those into an annual tradition; under Putin, hundreds of thousands of spectators have gathered to watch military personnel march alongside tanks<a href="http://content.time.com/time/photogallery/0,29307,1738768_1585965,00.html" > and missiles</a>. Billboards and buses have featured <a href="https://time.com/3852689/ussr-russia-victory-day-wwii-putin-ukraine/" >posters</a> of Stalin for Victory Day. Tens of millions of Russian citizens have <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/10/world/europe/russia-immortal-regiment-parade-victory-day.html"  target="_blank">marched</a> in Moscow carrying portraits of relatives who died in World War II. Ivan I. Kurilla, a professor at the European University of St. Petersburg, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/10/world/europe/russia-immortal-regiment-parade-victory-day.html"  target="_blank">told</a> the New York <em>Times </em>in 2018 that acknowledgement of family sacrifices during the war &ldquo;is probably the only social glue to form a single society&rdquo; in Russia.</p>
<p>But scholars say that often lost in the Victory Day celebrations are hard truths about what Russia&#8217;s victory in the war really meant. &#8220;The Stalin regime was almost as criminal as the Hitler regime,&#8221; scholar Nikolay Koposov <a href="https://www.wilsoncenter.org/event/webcast-victory-day-and-russias-politics-history"  target="_blank">stated</a> in a Wilson Center webcast in 2020, &#8220;and most Russians do not realize that the war was not for their freedoms but was largely a battle between the two dictators.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>Read more: </strong></em><a href="https://time.com/6170974/olaf-scholz-germany-interview/" ><em>Chancellor Olaf Scholz Wants to Transform Germany&#8217;s Place in the World. He&#8217;d Just Rather Not Talk About It</em></a></p>
<p>Pundits in Russia have pointed out that Victory Day has also become about more than just celebrating Russia&#8217;s military achievements in the past; it&#8217;s very much about galvanizing support for Russia in the present and showing off the strength of Russia&#8217;s military forces.</p>
<p>Journalist Andrei Kolesnikov <a href="https://carnegiemoscow.org/2017/10/05/past-that-divides-russia-s-new-official-history-pub-73304"  target="_blank">wrote</a> in a 2017 article about the modern-day significance of Victory Day that it&#8217;s &#8220;central&#8221; to Putin&#8217;s view of Russian history, and &#8220;the Great Patriotic War&#8221; has become his nickname for World War II. &#8220;The current regime, which calls itself the sole heir of this victory, uses this achievement to make itself immune to criticism on other issues while justifying its current militarization efforts and excessive state interference in all aspects of life,&#8221; Kolesnikov <a href="https://carnegiemoscow.org/2017/10/05/past-that-divides-russia-s-new-official-history-pub-73304"  target="_blank">wrote</a>. &#8220;In its official conception, Russia&rsquo;s commemoration of Victory Day in 1945 is only formally an occasion for collectively mourning for Russia&rsquo;s war dead. It has turned instead into an instrument for providing support to the most militarized, bellicose kind of Russian leader.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the walk-up to Victory Day this year, the United Nations <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/04/26/1094796253/ukraine-russia-refugees"  target="_blank">says</a> that the Russia-Ukraine war has displaced more than 5 million Ukrainians so far&mdash;and projects it will displace more than 8 million before it&#8217;s done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173515</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s War on Ukraine Is a Threat to Press Freedom, Report Says</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173543/world-press-freedom-index-2022/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eloise Barry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 18:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Misinformation & Disinformation]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Second click]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173543</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[“Journalists and independent media all over the world are at risk right now,” says Zahra Joya, an Afghan journalist who leads an independent platform in the country.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173543"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173543/world-press-freedom-index-2022/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Journalism is coming under increasingly intense pressure in Ukraine, exacerbated by the war, as press freedom remains restricted in well over two thirds of the world, according to Reporters Without Borders (RSF).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RSF&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://rsf.org/en/index"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2022 World Press Freedom Index</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> released on May 3, which measures access to information and curbs on journalistic freedoms, found that the situation for the press is &ldquo;very bad&rdquo; in 28 countries, &ldquo;difficult&rdquo; in 42 and &ldquo;problematic&rdquo; in 62. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those 132 countries represent just over 73% of the 180 nations surveyed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Russia&rsquo;s February invasion of Ukraine and the ongoing war is a threat to the future of Ukrainian media, which were already fairly restricted before the invasion due to an oligarch monopoly, according to RSF. Ukraine ranks 106 on the index of 180 countries, while Russia ranks 155. </span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;In this &#8216;information war&#8217;, Ukraine stands at the front line of resistance against the expansion of the Kremlin&rsquo;s propaganda system,&rdquo; RSF said in its report.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since February, journalists in Ukraine have been deliberately targeted by military fire, and the number of reporters killed has risen to at least 20, according to the </span><a href="https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2022/04/13/20-journalists-killed-in-ukraine-war-union-a77336"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moscow Times</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ukraine&rsquo;s government has blocked media carrying Kremlin-backed propaganda, while the Russian army has deliberately targeted journalists, media and infrastructure to prevent the Ukrainian population from having access to independent news and information. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><a href="https://time.com/6151572/russian-media-ukraine-coverage/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Russia</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, journalism was already tightly controlled by the Kremlin before the outbreak of war in Ukraine, but some independent media outlets fought to challenge the state narrative. That changed on March 4, when President Vladimir Putin </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/04/world/europe/russia-censorship-media-crackdown.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">enacted a law</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> making sharing &ldquo;false information&rdquo; about the war punishable by up to 15 years in prison. The Kremlin also blocked access to Facebook and foreign news outlets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The clampdown forced independent media outlets&mdash;including </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Novaya Gazeta,</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which is led by </span><a href="https://time.com/6126259/nobel-peace-prize-dmitry-muratov/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nobel Peace Prize winner Dmitry Muratov</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&mdash;to cease publication. The Russian version of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Euronews </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was suspended by the country&rsquo;s media regulator on March 22, and all privately-owned independent TV channels, except for cable entertainment channels, are banned from broadcasting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the Russian-occupied territories of Ukraine, Crimea and Donbass, the media are silenced and often replaced by Kremlin propaganda, according to RSF.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In April, footage circulated on </span><a href="https://twitter.com/JuliaDavisNews/status/1514339222118883334?s=20&amp;t=jOLWfK2xHUOYDvuT1m1_9A"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">social media</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of Margarita Simonyan, the Editor in Chief of Russian state broadcaster RT advocating for government censorship of the media. &ldquo;No great nation can exist without control over information,&rdquo; she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Global media polarization has increased two-fold over the past year, RSF found. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The disparity between open societies and authoritarian regimes that censor negative media coverage and spread propaganda is fuelling geopolitical tensions. Leading up to and following the invasion of Ukraine, Russia </span><a href="https://time.com/6151578/russia-disinformation-ukraine-social-media/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">disseminated false information</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to dupe Ukrainian forces, denounced foreign reports of war crimes as </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-denies-killing-civilians-ukraines-bucha-2022-04-03/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;fakes&rdquo;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/03/15/1086705796/russian-propaganda-war-in-ukraine"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">criminalized</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> anti-war reporting back home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;The creation of media weaponry in authoritarian countries eliminates their citizens&rsquo; right to information but is also linked to the rise in international tension, which can lead to the worst kind of wars,&rdquo; RSF Secretary-General Christophe Deloire said in a statement.</span></p>
<h2>Women journalists under most threat in Afghanistan</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The press freedom index highlighted that journalists in Afghanistan and Hong Kong have also come under increased constraints. The fall of Kabul to the Taliban in August last year radically altered Afghanistan&rsquo;s media landscape&mdash;within the space of three months, almost half of media outlets disappeared. At the end of last year, only four out of 10 journalists were still in their jobs, according to RSF. The country plunged to 156 on the index, in the worst category.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;Journalists and independent media all over the world are at risk right now,&rdquo; says </span><a href="https://time.com/collection/women-of-the-year/6150546/zahra-joya/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zahra Joya</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an Afghan journalist </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">who leads an independent platform </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">to spotlight women&rsquo;s stories in Afghanistan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joya, who founded </span><a href="https://rukhshana.com/en/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rukhshana Media</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2020 and works with women journalists on the ground in the country, says many fear for their safety. &ldquo;They are working in extremely difficult situations because they are in hiding,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;They are in serious danger, they could be tortured.&rdquo; The few that can work are forced by the Taliban to cover up and are completely separated from their male colleagues. In southern regions like Kandahar, Joya says there isn&rsquo;t a single woman journalist left working.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RSF found only 410 women journalists were still working in the country in December. The shift reflects a trend across the country as a whole, where four out of 5 women have lost their jobs compared to around half of men. J</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">oya, was forced to flee the country when she realized the danger posed to women journalists under Taliban rule.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If women are not represented in newsrooms, the Afghan media will fail half the country&rsquo;s population, Joya says. &ldquo;If women can&#8217;t be educated, and they can&rsquo;t have contact with the male journalists, they can&rsquo;t share their stories and experiences,&rdquo; Joya says.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Taliban, who </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were last in power from 1996 to 2001, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">also control and review all media reports before they are released, to remove negative coverage. &ldquo;They haven&#8217;t changed. They are still the Taliban who they were in 1996,&rdquo; Joya says.</span></p>
<h2><b>National Security Law crackdown on Hong Kong journalists</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Hong Kong, where independent journalism previously thrived, the local press has been restricted since the introduction of the </span><a href="https://time.com/5867000/hong-kong-china-national-security-law-effect/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">National Security Law</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in June 2020, which</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> prohibits acts deemed to be treason, secession, sedition, and subversion against the Chinese government. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following the silencing of prominent journalists and media outlets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the past year, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hong Kong has fallen over a third of the way down RSF&rsquo;s index.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2021, two major independent news outlets, </span><a href="https://time.com/6074478/apple-daily-close-hong-kong/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple Daily</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stand News</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, were forced to shut down after the government froze their assets, while numerous smaller-scale media outlets ceased operations due to the legal risks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Public broadcaster </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Radio Television Hong Kong</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&mdash;once </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-57253030"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">seen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as Hong Kong&rsquo;s version of the BBC&mdash;has been placed under a pro-government management, which has prevented programs featuring pro-democracy advocates from airing. Beijing-backed Hong Kong lawmakers have claimed the broadcaster is biased, and welcomed the sacking of editorial staff who criticized the regime. The platform has also been used to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">promote </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-57253030"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beijing-led changes to electoral laws</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to RSF, journalists are a prime target of the National Security Law. Following on from the arrest of hundreds of journalists during the pro-democracy protests in 2019, a dozen more were detained last year. Earlier this month, a prominent journalist and former columnist of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stand News</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Allan Au was</span> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/apr/11/prominent-hong-kong-journalist-allan-au-reportedly-held-on-sedition-charge"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">arrested</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">for allegedly conspiring to publish &ldquo;seditious materials&rdquo;.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173543</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Want to Know a Country’s Economic Future, Check How Far It Is From the Equator</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173536/economic-risk-climate-geography/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Barone]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 17:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Climate Is Everything]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[healthscienceclimate]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[interactive]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173536</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that global climate change hurts the economy. With more frequent and more severe storms, flooding, drought, and fires, countries around the world are already taking economic hits. And as long-term events like rising sea levels and temperature patterns continue to affect agriculture and human health, the economic damage will only grow. The&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173536"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173536/economic-risk-climate-geography/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>It&rsquo;s no secret that global climate change <a href="https://time.com/6093845/how-heat-hurts-the-economy/" >hurts the economy</a>. With more frequent and more severe storms, flooding, drought, and fires, countries around the world are already taking economic hits. And as long-term events like rising sea levels and temperature patterns continue to affect agriculture and human health, the economic damage will only grow.</p>
<p>The impact, however, will be <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/_assets/documents/ratings/research/101529900.pdf"  target="_blank">unequally distributed</a>. A recent report from <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2015/12/01/dominica-lost-almost-all-gdp-climate-change"  target="_blank">S&amp;P Global</a> assessed how 135 countries might be affected by climate-related events in 2050. The economic risk levels ranged from 0% of GDP (indicating that the economy will likely not be exposed to climate hazards) to 100% of GDP (the entire economy could be exposed to climate hazards). The measurement predicts only economic vulnerability&mdash;not economic loss. For example, a country with 80% GDP exposure doesn&rsquo;t mean that 80% of the economy will be wiped out in 30 years, but rather that 80% of the economy is <em>at risk</em> of experiencing a loss.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>Using these percentages, TIME &ldquo;mapped&rdquo; countries on a blue-to-red scale to see which economies are in least and most danger. But instead of a standard map&mdash;one with, say, borders and oceans&mdash;we looked at each country as a latitudinal point. The result was a chart that looks a bit like a volcano turned sideways.</p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="Share of country GDP exposed to climate impacts, by latitude" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/4W5jT/5/#?secret=zhEmMHBlIn" data-secret="zhEmMHBlIn" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="540"></iframe></p>
<p>What this shows is that economies that have huge physical climate risk&mdash;in some cases 100% exposed&mdash;are generally within 20 degrees of the equator. And none are in the far northern or southern parts of the globe. On the other hand, countries that have minimal risk are from a wide range of latitudes, but skew more to the poles.</p>
<p>To arrive at these numbers, S&amp;P Global researchers considered how much of each country&rsquo;s area is prone to experience wildfires, storms, floods, and rising sea levels, as well as how much of agricultural land is at risk of water stress, and workforce population impacted by extreme heat.</p>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6171610/palau-marine-protected-area-climate-justice/" ><em>One Island Nation&#8217;s Controversial Plan to Take Climate Justice Into Its Own Hands</em></a></p>
<p>There are a few reasons why this geographic pattern exists. For one, a number of nations at or near Earth&rsquo;s waistline are small island states that are highly vulnerable to massive storms that can devastate infrastructure and crimp their most dependent industries, such as tourism. Additionally, a large share of countries located around the equator have less diversified economies that rely on physical labor to produce goods. Extreme heat can have devastating effects on labor productivity in these nations. In sub-Saharan Africa, for instance, higher-income and service-driven countries like Botswana and South Africa, which are at the tip of the continent, have 19% and 0% GDP exposure; low-income countries like Ethiopia and Burkina Faso that rely more on agriculture and industry and sit just above the equator, have 93% and 99% GDP exposure, respectively.</p>
<p>A separate element of the study looked at how prepared each country might be to adapt to climate impacts on a scale from 1 (most ready) to 6 (least ready). This score is not a factor in the GDP risk assessment, but it does serve to show how prepared each country might be to address those risks.</p>
<p>When TIME plotted this readiness assessment based on country latitude, the trends&mdash;particularly at the extreme ends of the readiness scale&mdash;were even more stark than GDP exposure. Among countries with the best readiness score, only the highly developed city-state of Singapore lies on the equator. And conversely, nearly all the countries with the worst readiness score are within 20 degrees of the equator.</p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="Readiness to adapt to climate risks, by latitude" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/haM2n/4/#?secret=MBFr5XzCHw" data-secret="MBFr5XzCHw" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="546"></iframe></p>
<p>Taken together, the charts indicate that countries in northern and southern latitudes are more likely to have resources to prepare the best for climate effects&mdash;even though their economies are the least at risk. This is because these nations, particularly those on the European continent&mdash;have diversified and service-based economies that can take Mother Nature&rsquo;s punches. They are also wealthier and more technologically advanced, which allows them to funnel resources into climate adaptation efforts.</p>
<p>While S&amp;P Global didn&rsquo;t quantify GDP losses on a country level due to uncertainty surrounding the reliability of data at that level, it did calculate an estimate for global regions and the world. It found that 4% of the global economy could be lost to climate change impacts by 2050, assuming that countries stick to their current pledges to address climate change. As Marion Amiot, one of authors of the study, points out, a loss that small may not seem like a big deal, but it would be even worse than the 3.4% global GDP decline in 2020 due to COVID-19.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173536</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lula Conversa com TIME Sobre Ucrânia, Bolsonaro e a Frágil Democracia Brasileira</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173104/lula-da-silva-transcricao/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ciara Nugent/São Paulo, Brazil]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173104</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Read this story in English A volta de Luiz In&#225;cio Lula da Silva &#224; linha de frente da pol&#237;tica foi uma bomba para o Brasil. Em abril de 2021 o Supremo Tribunal Federal anulou uma s&#233;rie de condena&#231;&#245;es por corrup&#231;&#227;o que exclu&#237;ram o ex-presidente petista das elei&#231;&#245;es presidenciais de 2018. O tribunal afirmou que a&#8230;]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173104"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173104/lula-da-silva-transcricao/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><em>Read this story in <a href="https://time.com/6173232/lula-da-silva-transcript/" ><strong>English</strong></a></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A volta de <a href="https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/" >Luiz In&aacute;cio Lula da Silva &agrave; linha de frente da pol&iacute;tica</a> foi uma bomba para o Brasil. Em abril de 2021 o Supremo Tribunal Federal anulou uma s&eacute;rie de condena&ccedil;&otilde;es por corrup&ccedil;&atilde;o que exclu&iacute;ram o ex-presidente petista das elei&ccedil;&otilde;es presidenciais de 2018. O tribunal afirmou que a parcialidade do juiz respons&aacute;vel pelo caso comprometeu o direito de Lula &#8211; como o ex-presidente &eacute; mundialmente conhecido &#8211; a um julgamento justo. A decis&atilde;o </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">preparou o terreno para </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">um duelo entre Lula e o atual presidente de extrema-direita<a href="https://time.com/collection/100-most-influential-people-2020/5888329/jair-bolsonaro-brazil/" > Jair Bolsonaro</a> nas elei&ccedil;&otilde;es de outubro de 2022.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><em><strong>Read the Cover Story</strong>:</em> <a href="https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/" ><em>Brazil&rsquo;s Most Popular President Returns From Political Exile With a Promise to Save the Nation</em></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lula, que <a href="https://g1.globo.com/politica/eleicoes/2022/noticia/2022/04/11/pt-anuncia-que-lancara-oficialmente-pre-candidatura-de-lula-a-presidencia-em-maio.ghtml"  target="_blank">lan&ccedil;ar&aacute;</a> oficialmente sua pr&eacute;-candidatura no dia 7 de maio, promete levar o Brasil de volta aos bons tempos da sua Presid&ecirc;ncia (2003-2010), que ele encerrou com taxa de aprova&ccedil;&atilde;o de 83%. Isso implicaria reavivar uma economia debilitada, salvar <a href="https://time.com/6130308/bolsonaro-brazil-2022-election/" >uma democracia amea&ccedil;ada</a> e recuperar uma na&ccedil;&atilde;o marcada pela segunda maior taxa mundial de mortalidade ligada &agrave; Covid-19 e por dois anos de gest&atilde;o ca&oacute;tica da pandemia. At&eacute; o momento, as promessas est&atilde;o surtindo efeito: Lula aparece <a href="https://www.uol.com.br/eleicoes/2022/04/22/pesquisa-ipespe-abril-2022-presidencia-lula-bolsonaro.htm"  target="_blank">nas pesquisas</a> com 45% das inten&ccedil;&otilde;es de voto, contra 31% de Bolsonaro. Por&eacute;m, esta diferen&ccedil;a est&aacute; diminuindo.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TIME sentou para conversar com Lula no fim de mar&ccedil;o, na sede do Partido dos Trabalhadores (PT) em S&atilde;o Paulo, para falar sobre o tempo que ele passou na pris&atilde;o, sobre a guerra na Ucr&acirc;nia e para saber se seus planos para o Brasil est&atilde;o baseados em algo al&eacute;m da nostalgia. Essa transcri&ccedil;&atilde;o foi condensada e editada para maior clareza.</span></p>
<p><strong>Quando o Supremo Tribunal Federal restaurou seus direitos pol&iacute;ticos no ano passado, voc&ecirc; j&aacute; estava, segundo a m&iacute;dia brasileira, se preparando para uma vida mais tranquila, fora da pol&iacute;tica. Voc&ecirc; decidiu imediatamente voltar &agrave; pol&iacute;tica quando isso aconteceu?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu na verdade nunca desisti da pol&iacute;tica. A pol&iacute;tica est&aacute; em cada c&eacute;lula minha, a pol&iacute;tica est&aacute; no meu sangue, est&aacute; na minha cabe&ccedil;a. Porque o problema n&atilde;o &eacute; a pol&iacute;tica simplesmente, o problema &eacute; a causa que te leva &agrave; pol&iacute;tica. E eu tenho uma causa.</span><b></b></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=600,450 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=489,367 489w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=979,734 979w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=249,187 249w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=499,374 499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=360,270 360w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=745,559 745w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=720,540 720w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1440,1080 1440w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1920,1440 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=407,305 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=814,611 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=280,210 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=560,420 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1333,1000 1333w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=190,143 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=380,285 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=263,197 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=526,395 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=61,46 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1200,900 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=640,480 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=760,570 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1520,1140 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=700,525 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1000,750 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=41,31 41w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=550,413 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1100,825 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=840,630 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1680,1260 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1012,759 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=2024,1518 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=320,240 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=649,487 649w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=192,144 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=533,400 533w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=267,200 267w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=171,128 171w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=333,250 333w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=479,359 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=958,719 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=767,575 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1534,1151 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=800,600 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-1.jpg?resize=1600,1200 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Luiz In&aacute;cio Lula da Silva gives a speech to union workers at Pra&ccedil;a Charles Muller, S&atilde;o Paulo, on International Workers&#8217; day, May 1, 2022.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quando <a href="http://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1984685_1984864_1984866,00.html" >deixei a Presid&ecirc;ncia em 2010</a>, efetivamente eu n&atilde;o pensava mais em ser candidato &agrave; Presid&ecirc;ncia da Rep&uacute;blica. Entretanto, o que eu estou vendo, doze anos depois, &eacute; que tudo aquilo que foi pol&iacute;tica para beneficiar o povo pobre&mdash; todas as pol&iacute;ticas de inclus&atilde;o social, o que n&oacute;s fizemos para melhorar a qualidade das universidades, das escolas t&eacute;cnicas, melhorar a qualidade do sal&aacute;rio, melhorar a qualidade do emprego&mdash;, tudo isso foi destru&iacute;do, desmontado. Porque as pessoas que come&ccedil;aram a ocupar o governo depois que deram o golpe na presidenta Dilma [Rousseff] eram pessoas que tinham o objetivo de destruir todas as conquistas que o povo brasileiro tinha obtido desde 1943.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> H&aacute; uma expectativa de que eu volte a presidir o pa&iacute;s porque as pessoas t&ecirc;m boas lembran&ccedil;as do tempo em que eu fui presidente. As pessoas trabalhavam, as pessoas tinham aumento de sal&aacute;rio, os reajustes salariais eram acima da infla&ccedil;&atilde;o. Ent&atilde;o eu penso que as pessoas t&ecirc;m saudades disso e as pessoas querem isso melhorado. </span></p>
<p><strong>A situa&ccedil;&atilde;o do Brasil hoje&mdash;a polariza&ccedil;&atilde;o pol&iacute;tica, a economia, o panorama internacional&mdash;&eacute; muito diferente do que quando voc&ecirc; ganhou a Presid&ecirc;ncia pela primeira vez. N&atilde;o vai ser mais dif&iacute;cil governar desta vez?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> O futebol americano tem um jogador, que ali&aacute;s &eacute; casado com uma brasileira que &eacute; modelo, e que &eacute; o melhor jogador do mundo h&aacute; muito tempo. A cada jogo que ele faz, a torcida fica exigindo que ele jogue melhor do que no jogo anterior. No caso da Presid&ecirc;ncia &eacute; a mesma coisa. S&oacute; tem sentido eu estar candidato &agrave; Presid&ecirc;ncia da rep&uacute;blica porque eu acredito que eu sou capaz de fazer mais e fazer melhor do que eu j&aacute; fiz.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu tenho clareza de que eu posso resolver os problemas [do Brasil]. Eu tenho a certeza de que esses problemas s&oacute; ser&atilde;o resolvidos quando os pobres estiverem participando da economia, quando os pobres estiverem participando do or&ccedil;amento, quando os pobres estiverem trabalhando, quando os pobres estiverem comendo. Isso s&oacute; &eacute; poss&iacute;vel se voc&ecirc; tiver um governo que tenha compromisso com as pessoas mais pobres. </span></p>
<p><strong>Muitas pessoas no Brasil dizem que houve muitas encarna&ccedil;&otilde;es do Lula, especificamente em pol&iacute;tica econ&ocirc;mica. Qual Lula temos hoje?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu sou o &uacute;nico candidato com quem as pessoas n&atilde;o deveriam ter essa preocupa&ccedil;&atilde;o, porque eu j&aacute; fui presidente duas vezes. E a gente n&atilde;o discute pol&iacute;tica econ&ocirc;mica antes de ganhar as elei&ccedil;&otilde;es. Primeiro voc&ecirc; precisa ganhar para depois saber com quem voc&ecirc; vai compor e o que voc&ecirc; vai fazer. Quem tiver d&uacute;vida sobre mim olhe o que aconteceu nesse pa&iacute;s quando eu fui presidente da Rep&uacute;blica: o crescimento do mercado. O Brasil tinha dois IPOs. No meu governo fizemos 250 IPOs. O Brasil devia 30 bilh&otilde;es, o Brasil passou a ser credor do FMI, porque emprestamos 15 bilh&otilde;es. O Brasil n&atilde;o tinha um d&oacute;lar de reserva internacional, o Brasil tem hoje 370 bilh&otilde;es de d&oacute;lares de reserva internacional. [&#8230;] Ent&atilde;o as pessoas precisam ter em conta o seguinte: ao inv&eacute;s de perguntar o que &eacute; que eu vou fazer, olhe o que eu fiz.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="115156118" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=768,509 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=600,398 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1536,1018 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=2048,1357 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=280,186 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=550,364 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1100,729 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=560,371 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=408,270 408w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=838,555 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=815,540 815w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1630,1080 1630w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=814,539 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1509,1000 1509w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=190,126 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=380,252 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=263,174 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=526,348 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=61,40 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1200,795 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=640,424 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=760,504 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1520,1007 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=700,464 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1000,663 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=840,557 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1680,1113 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1012,670 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=2024,1341 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=320,212 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=730,484 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=377,250 377w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=479,317 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=958,635 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=767,508 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1534,1016 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=800,530 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-2.jpg?resize=1600,1060 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Antonio Ribeiro&mdash;Gamma-Rapho/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >Lula at an event in Sao Bernardo Do Campo during his 1989 presidential campaign.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Na primeira Presid&ecirc;ncia, o petr&oacute;leo, entre outros produtos, impulsionaram muito esse sucesso. Agora, com a crise clim&aacute;tica, estamos tentando usar menos combust&iacute;veis f&oacute;sseis. O candidato &agrave; Presid&ecirc;ncia na Col&ocirc;mbia, Gustavo Petro, <a href="https://time.com/6139508/gustavo-petro-anti-oil-bloc/" >prop&ocirc;s um bloco antipetr&oacute;leo</a> em que os pa&iacute;ses deixariam imediatamente de explorar o petr&oacute;leo. Voc&ecirc; quer se unir a este bloco?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veja, eu acho que o Petro tem o direito de fazer todas as propostas que ele quiser fazer. Mas no caso do Brasil &eacute; irreal. No caso do mundo &eacute; irreal. Voc&ecirc; ainda precisa do petr&oacute;leo por um tempo, voc&ecirc; n&atilde;o consegue&#8230;</span></p>
<p><strong>Por&eacute;m a ideia &eacute; continuar extraindo o petr&oacute;leo que j&aacute; descobriram, mas deixar de explorar. Voc&ecirc; quer deixar de explorar?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enquanto voc&ecirc; n&atilde;o tiver energia alternativa, voc&ecirc; vai utilizar a energia que voc&ecirc; tem. Isso vale para o Brasil e vale para o mundo inteiro. Veja a depend&ecirc;ncia da nossa querida Alemanha agora. Angela Merkel tomou a decis&atilde;o de fechar todas as usinas nucleares, n&atilde;o contava com a guerra da Ucr&acirc;nia. Hoje a Europa &eacute; muito <a href="https://time.com/6153184/ukraine-crisis-scrambled-germanys-energy-politics/" >dependente dos russos para poder ter energia.</a> O que voc&ecirc; pode estabelecer &eacute; um plano de longo prazo para voc&ecirc; diminuir [o consumo de petr&oacute;leo] na medida em que voc&ecirc; vai criando alternativas. N&atilde;o d&aacute; para imaginar que os Estados Unidos v&atilde;o parar de utilizar petr&oacute;leo do dia para a noite, ou qualquer pa&iacute;s.</span></p>
<p><strong>Quero falar da Ucr&acirc;nia. Voc&ecirc; sempre teve orgulho de poder falar com todos&mdash;Hugo Ch&aacute;vez e tamb&eacute;m George Bush. Mas o mundo de hoje &eacute; muito fragmentado diplomaticamente. Quero saber se sua abordagem na diplomacia ainda funciona. Voc&ecirc; poderia falar com Putin depois da<a href="https://time.com/6155129/russian-strategy-guiding-invasion-ukraine/" > invas&atilde;o da Ucr&acirc;nia</a>?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">N&oacute;s, pol&iacute;ticos, colhemos aquilo que n&oacute;s plantamos. Se eu planto fraternidade, solidariedade, conc&oacute;rdia, eu vou colher coisa boa. Mas se eu planto disc&oacute;rdia, eu vou colher desaven&ccedil;as. Putin n&atilde;o deveria ter invadido a Ucr&acirc;nia. Mas n&atilde;o &eacute; s&oacute; o Putin que &eacute; culpado, s&atilde;o culpados os Estados Unidos e &eacute; culpada a Uni&atilde;o Europeia. Qual &eacute; a raz&atilde;o da invas&atilde;o da Ucr&acirc;nia? &Eacute; a OTAN? Os Estados Unidos e a Europa poderiam ter dito: &#8216;A Ucr&acirc;nia n&atilde;o vai entrar na OTAN&#8217;. Estaria resolvido o problema.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="AMA2004003G1010111" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-7.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Alex Majoli&mdash;Magnum Photos</span><span class="caption" >Inside a shop in S&atilde;o Paulo in 2004, Lula is seen on television giving a speech responding to accusations of corruption against his government.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Voc&ecirc; acha que a OTAN foi a raz&atilde;o da R&uacute;ssia para invadir?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Esse &eacute; o argumento que est&aacute; colocado. Se tem um segredo n&oacute;s n&atilde;o sabemos. O outro &eacute; a [possibilidade de a] Ucr&acirc;nia entrar na Uni&atilde;o Europeia. Os europeus poderiam ter resolvido e dito: &#8216;N&atilde;o, n&atilde;o &eacute; o momento de a Ucr&acirc;nia entrar na Uni&atilde;o Europeia, vamos esperar&#8217;. Eles n&atilde;o precisariam fomentar o confronto! </span></p>
<p><strong>Mas acho que tentaram falar com a R&uacute;ssia. </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">N&atilde;o tentaram. As conversas foram muito poucas. Se voc&ecirc; quer paz, voc&ecirc; tem que ter paci&ecirc;ncia. Eles poderiam ter sentado numa mesa de negocia&ccedil;&atilde;o e passado 10 dias, 15 dias, 20 dias, um m&ecirc;s discutindo para tentar encontrar a solu&ccedil;&atilde;o. Ent&atilde;o eu acho que o di&aacute;logo s&oacute; d&aacute; certo quando ele &eacute; levado a s&eacute;rio.</span></p>
<p><strong>Ent&atilde;o se voc&ecirc; fosse presidente neste momento, o que voc&ecirc; faria? Voc&ecirc; seria capaz de evitar o conflito?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu n&atilde;o sei se seria capaz. Eu, se fosse presidente hoje, teria ligado para o [Joe] <a href="https://time.com/6171813/biden-congress-billions-aid-ukraine/" >Biden</a>, teria ligado para o Putin, para <a href="https://time.com/6170974/olaf-scholz-germany-interview/" >a Alemanha</a>, para o [Emmanuel] <a href="https://time.com/6170037/emmanuel-macron-wins-french-elections/" >Macron</a>, porque a guerra n&atilde;o &eacute; sa&iacute;da. Eu acho que o problema &eacute; que, se a gente n&atilde;o tentar, a gente n&atilde;o resolve. &Eacute; preciso tentar. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&Agrave;s vezes eu fico preocupado</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Eu fiquei muito preocupado quando os Estados Unidos e quando a Uni&atilde;o Europeia <a href="https://time.com/5518443/juan-guaido-interview-venezuela/" >adotaram o [Juan] Guaid&oacute;</a> [ent&atilde;o l&iacute;der da assembleia nacional da Venezuela] como presidente do pa&iacute;s [em 2019]. Voc&ecirc; n&atilde;o brinca com democracia. O Guaid&oacute; para ser presidente da Venezuela teria que ser eleito. A burocracia n&atilde;o substitui a pol&iacute;tica. Na pol&iacute;tica s&atilde;o os dois chefes que mandam, os dois que foram eleitos pelo povo, que t&ecirc;m que sentar numa mesa de negocia&ccedil;&atilde;o, olho no olho, e conversar. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">E agora, &agrave;s vezes fico vendo <a href="https://time.com/6171277/volodymyr-zelensky-interview-ukraine-war/" >o presidente da Ucr&acirc;nia</a> na televis&atilde;o como se estivesse festejando, sendo aplaudido em p&eacute; por todos os parlamentos, sabe? Esse cara &eacute; t&atilde;o respons&aacute;vel quanto o Putin. Ele &eacute; t&atilde;o respons&aacute;vel quanto o Putin. Porque numa guerra n&atilde;o tem apenas um culpado. O Saddam Hussein era t&atilde;o culpado quanto o Bush. Porque o Saddam Hussein poderia ter dito: &#8216;Pode vir aqui visitar e eu vou provar que eu n&atilde;o tenho armas&#8217;. Ele ficou mentindo para o seu povo. Agora, esse presidente da Ucr&acirc;nia poderia ter dito: &#8216;Olha, vamos deixar para discutir esse neg&oacute;cio da OTAN e esse neg&oacute;cio da Europa mais para frente. Vamos primeiro conversar um pouco mais.&rsquo;</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_vertical alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?w=700&w=700" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=480,600 480w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=294,367 294w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=587,734 587w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=150,187 150w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=299,374 299w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=216,270 216w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=447,559 447w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=432,540 432w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=864,1080 864w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1152,1440 1152w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=407,509 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=814,1018 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=280,350 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=560,700 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=800,1000 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=190,238 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=380,475 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=263,329 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=526,658 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=61,76 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1200,1500 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=640,800 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=760,950 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1520,1900 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=700,875 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1000,1250 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=25,31 25w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=550,688 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1100,1375 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=840,1050 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1680,2100 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1012,1265 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=320,400 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=600,750 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=390,487 390w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=300,375 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=192,240 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=160,200 160w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=102,128 102w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=200,250 200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=479,599 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=958,1198 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=767,959 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1534,1918 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-0.jpg?resize=1600,2000 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Lula, former Brazilian President and 2022 presidential candidate, photographed in S&atilde;o Paulo on March 23.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Ent&atilde;o Zelensky tinha que falar mais com Putin, mesmo com 100,000 soldados russos na sua fronteira?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu n&atilde;o conhe&ccedil;o o presidente da Ucr&acirc;nia. Agora, o comportamento dele &eacute; um comportamento um pouco esquisito, porque parece que ele faz parte de um espet&aacute;culo. Ou seja, ele aparece na televis&atilde;o de manh&atilde;, de tarde, de noite, aparece no parlamento ingl&ecirc;s, no parlamento alem&atilde;o, no parlamento franc&ecirc;s como se estivesse fazendo uma campanha. Era preciso que ele estivesse mais preocupado com a mesa de negocia&ccedil;&atilde;o. </span></p>
<p><strong>N&atilde;o seria um pouco dif&iacute;cil dizer isso a Zelensky? Ele n&atilde;o queria guerra, mas ela chegou.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ele quis a guerra. Se ele [n&atilde;o] quisesse a guerra, ele teria negociado um pouco mais. &Eacute; assim. Eu fiz uma cr&iacute;tica ao Putin quando estava na Cidade do M&eacute;xico, dizendo que foi errado invadir. Mas eu acho que ningu&eacute;m est&aacute; procurando contribuir para ter paz. As pessoas est&atilde;o estimulando o &oacute;dio contra o Putin. Isso n&atilde;o vai resolver! &Eacute; preciso estimular um acordo. Mas h&aacute; um est&iacute;mulo [ao confronto]! Voc&ecirc; fica estimulando o cara [Zelensky] e ele fica se achando o m&aacute;ximo. Ele fica se achando o rei da cocada, quando na verdade deveriam ter tido conversa mais s&eacute;ria com ele: &#8216;&Ocirc;, cara, voc&ecirc; &eacute; um bom artista, voc&ecirc; &eacute; <a href="https://time.com/5742108/ukraine-zelensky-interview-trump-putin-europe/" >um bom comediante</a>, mas n&atilde;o vamos fazer uma guerra para voc&ecirc; aparecer&#8217;. E dizer para o Putin: &#8216;&Ocirc;, Putin, voc&ecirc; tem muita arma, mas n&atilde;o precisa utilizar arma contra a Ucr&acirc;nia. Vamos conversar!&#8217;</span></p>
<p><strong> O que voc&ecirc; acha de Joe Biden?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu fiz at&eacute; um discurso elogioso ao Biden quando ele anunciou o primeiro programa econ&ocirc;mico dele. O problema &eacute; que n&atilde;o basta voc&ecirc; anunciar um programa, &eacute; preciso executar o programa. E eu acho que o Biden est&aacute; vivendo <a href="https://time.com/6140442/joe-biden-presidency-second-year/" >um momento dif&iacute;cil</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">E acho que ele n&atilde;o tomou a decis&atilde;o correta nessa guerra R&uacute;ssia e Ucr&acirc;nia. Os Estados Unidos t&ecirc;m um peso muito grande e ele poderia evitar isso, e n&atilde;o estimular. Poderia ter falado mais, poderia ter participado mais, o Biden poderia ter pegado um avi&atilde;o e descido em Moscou para conversar com o Putin. &Eacute; esta atitude que se espera de um l&iacute;der. Que ele tenha interfer&ecirc;ncia para que as coisas n&atilde;o aconte&ccedil;am de forma atabalhoada. E eu acho que ele n&atilde;o fez. </span></p>
<p><strong>Biden deveria ter feito mais concess&otilde;es a Putin?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">N&atilde;o. Da mesma forma que os americanos convenceram os russos a <a href="https://time.com/5899754/jfk-decisionmaking-cuban-missile-crisis/" >n&atilde;o colocar m&iacute;sseis em Cuba</a> em 1961, o Biden poderia falar: &#8216;Vamos conversar um pouco mais. N&oacute;s n&atilde;o queremos a Ucr&acirc;nia na OTAN, ponto&#8217;. N&atilde;o &eacute; concess&atilde;o. Deixa eu lhe contar uma coisa: se eu fosse presidente da Rep&uacute;blica e me oferecessem &#8216;o Brasil pode entrar na OTAN&#8217;, eu n&atilde;o ia querer.</span></p>
<p><strong>Por qu&ecirc;?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Porque eu sou um cara que s&oacute; pensa em paz. Eu n&atilde;o penso em guerra. [&#8230;] O Brasil n&atilde;o tem contencioso nem com os Estados Unidos, nem com a China, nem com a R&uacute;ssia, nem com a Bol&iacute;via, nem com a Argentina, nem com o M&eacute;xico. E &eacute; o fato de o Brasil ser um pa&iacute;s de paz que vai lhe fazer restabelecer a rela&ccedil;&atilde;o que n&oacute;s criamos de 2003 a 2010. O Brasil vai virar protagonista internacional, porque a gente vai provar que &eacute; poss&iacute;vel ter um mundo melhor.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><div class="time-diptyche-shortcode"></div></p>
<p><b>O que voc&ecirc; precisa fazer para conseguir isso?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&Eacute; urgente e &eacute; preciso a gente criar uma nova governan&ccedil;a mundial. A ONU de hoje n&atilde;o representa mais nada. A ONU de hoje n&atilde;o &eacute; levada a s&eacute;rio pelos governantes. Porque cada um toma decis&atilde;o sem respeitar a ONU. O Putin invadiu a Ucr&acirc;nia de forma unilateral, sem consultar a ONU. Os Estados Unidos costumam invadir os pa&iacute;ses sem conversar com ningu&eacute;m e sem respeitar o Conselho de Seguran&ccedil;a. Ent&atilde;o &eacute; preciso que a gente reconstrua a ONU, coloque mais pa&iacute;ses, envolva mais pessoas. Se a gente fizer isso, a gente come&ccedil;a a melhorar o mundo. </span></p>
<p><b>No Brasil, durante a pandemia, a popula&ccedil;&atilde;o negra sofreu um risco de mortalidade maior que os brancos, e uma taxa maior de desemprego tamb&eacute;m. E <a href="https://time.com/6047032/jair-bolsonaro-crime-policies-brazils-favelas/" >os problemas com a viol&ecirc;ncia policial</a> pioraram durante o governo do Bolsonaro. Voc&ecirc; tem coisas que vai fazer para melhorar o mundo para <a href="https://time.com/5915902/brazil-racism-quilombos/" >os brasileiros negros</a> especificamente?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Olha, eu li muito sobre a escravid&atilde;o quando eu estava preso e eu &agrave;s vezes tenho dificuldade de compreender o que foram 350 anos de escravid&atilde;o. E eu tenho mais dificuldade de compreender que a escravid&atilde;o ela est&aacute; dentro da cabe&ccedil;a das pessoas, o preconceito est&aacute; dentro da cabe&ccedil;a das pessoas. Aqui no Brasil, na periferia brasileira, milhares de jovens s&atilde;o mortos quase todo m&ecirc;s, todo ano. Ent&atilde;o n&atilde;o &eacute; poss&iacute;vel isso continuar. Quando eu estava na presid&ecirc;ncia n&oacute;s criamos uma lei para que a hist&oacute;ria africana fosse contada na escola brasileira. Para que a gente aprendesse sobre a hist&oacute;ria africana para n&atilde;o ver os africanos como cidad&atilde;os inferiores. Ent&atilde;o n&oacute;s precisamos come&ccedil;ar essa educa&ccedil;&atilde;o dentro de casa, na escola. E o Bolsonaro despertou o &oacute;dio, despertou o preconceito. A&iacute; tem outros presidentes tamb&eacute;m na Europa, na Hungria, [que fazem o mesmo]; est&aacute; aparecendo muito fascista, muito nazista no mundo. </span></p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="5gWwIETb" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
<p><strong>O Bolsonaro tem culpa pelo racismo hoje no Brasil ou &eacute; um pa&iacute;s racista?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu n&atilde;o diria que ele tem culpa pelo racismo porque o racismo &eacute; cr&ocirc;nico no Brasil. Mas ele estimula.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="1237319533" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1100,734 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=560,374 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=809,540 809w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1619,1080 1619w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1680,1121 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1499,1000 1499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1200,801 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1520,1014 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=46,31 46w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=2024,1350 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=479,320 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=767,512 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=800,534 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-portuguese-6.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Jonne Roriz&mdash;Bloomberg/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >A street vendor sells towels with images of Bolsonaro and Lula near Eldorado dos Caraj&aacute;s in September 2021.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Voc&ecirc; passou por muitas trag&eacute;dias pessoais nos &uacute;ltimos cinco anos. Isso mudou voc&ecirc; de alguma maneira?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">N&atilde;o. Eu confesso que se eu dissesse a voc&ecirc; que eu n&atilde;o fiquei magoado, que eu n&atilde;o fiquei muito nervoso com os mentirosos que montaram essa quadrilha para me condenar, eu estaria mentindo. Eu tinha consci&ecirc;ncia do que estava acontecendo no Brasil: o impeachment da Dilma n&atilde;o poderia terminar na Dilma, porque n&atilde;o tinha nenhum sentido fazer o impeachment da Dilma e dois anos depois o Lula voltar a ser presidente da Rep&uacute;blica. Ent&atilde;o era preciso afastar o Lula. E como eles n&atilde;o tinham como afastar, eles resolveram construir um ros&aacute;rio de mentiras contra mim para poder <a href="https://time.com/5840854/sergio-moro-brazil-interview/" >me colocar na cadeia</a>. Hoje eu estou aqui, livre, todos os meus processos foram anulados. </span></p>
<p><b>Sim, as condena&ccedil;&otilde;es foram anuladas. Mas como te impactaram? </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu fiquei 580 dias na cadeia. Eu li muito. Ent&atilde;o eu fiz muita reflex&atilde;o, eu me preparei para sair da cadeia sem &oacute;dio, sem m&aacute;goa, sem ressentimento, apenas lembrando que aquilo foi um processo hist&oacute;rico que eu n&atilde;o posso esquecer. Eu n&atilde;o posso esquecer, mas eu n&atilde;o posso colocar na mesa esse assunto todo dia porque &eacute; uma coisa do passado. Eu quero pensar no futuro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Para voc&ecirc; entender a minha vida, eu fui comer p&atilde;o pela primeira vez com sete anos de idade. A minha m&atilde;e, muitas vezes, n&atilde;o tinha nada para colocar no fog&atilde;o para fazer comida para a gente. E eu nunca vi minha m&atilde;e desesperada. Ela sempre falava o seguinte: &#8216;Amanh&atilde; vai ter. Amanh&atilde; vai melhorar&#8217;. E isso foi introjetado na minha consci&ecirc;ncia, no meu sangue, e eu sou assim. N&atilde;o tem problema que a gente n&atilde;o consiga vencer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu tenho orgulho de provar que um metal&uacute;rgico que n&atilde;o tem diploma universit&aacute;rio tem mais compet&ecirc;ncia para governar esse pa&iacute;s do que a elite brasileira toda. Porque a arte de governar &eacute; voc&ecirc; saber utilizar o cora&ccedil;&atilde;o junto com a raz&atilde;o. </span></p>
<p><b>Voc&ecirc; vai se casar em breve. Voc&ecirc; quer falar um pouco sobre sua noiva?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu n&atilde;o gosto de falar dela. Porque ela tem autonomia para falar dela. </span></p>
<p><b>Voc&ecirc; aprendeu alguma coisa com ela?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eu aprendi. Eu aprendi que quando voc&ecirc; perde a tua mulher e voc&ecirc; pensa que a vida n&atilde;o tem mais sentido, quando voc&ecirc; pensa que tudo acabou, aparece uma pessoa que come&ccedil;a a dar sentido &agrave; vida outra vez. Estou apaixonado como se eu tivesse 20 anos de idade, como se fosse minha primeira namorada. Vou casar da forma mais tranquila poss&iacute;vel e vou fazer a campanha feliz. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ent&atilde;o, um cara que est&aacute; feliz como eu n&atilde;o tem que ter outra preocupa&ccedil;&atilde;o. N&atilde;o tem que ter raiva, n&atilde;o tem que falar mal dos advers&aacute;rios. Deixa os advers&aacute;rios fazerem o que eles quiserem. Brigar, xingar. Eu, sinceramente, se puder fa&ccedil;o uma campanha falando de amor. Eu n&atilde;o acho que seja poss&iacute;vel voc&ecirc; ser um bom presidente se voc&ecirc; s&oacute; tem &oacute;dio dentro de voc&ecirc;, se voc&ecirc; s&oacute; tem vingan&ccedil;a dentro de voc&ecirc;. N&atilde;o. Voc&ecirc; tem que ter paz e pensar no futuro. O que passou, passou. Eu vou construir um novo Brasil.</span></p>
<p><em>Tradu&ccedil;&atilde;o e transcri&ccedil;&atilde;o por P&acirc;mela Reis</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173104</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lula Talks to TIME About Ukraine, Bolsonaro, and Brazil’s Fragile Democracy</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173232/lula-da-silva-transcript/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ciara Nugent/São Paulo, Brazil]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 11:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173232</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Read a transcript of our interview with the former Brazilian leader as he launches a new bid for the presidency]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173232"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173232/lula-da-silva-transcript/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><i>Read this story in </i><a href="https://time.com/6173104/lula-da-silva-transcricao/" ><strong><i>Portuguese</i></strong></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luiz In&aacute;cio Lula da Silva&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/5946236/brazil-lula-returns/" >return to frontline politics</a> was a bombshell for Brazil. In April 2021, the Brazilian Supreme Court annulled a series of corruption convictions that had excluded the leftist former President from national elections in 2018, saying a biased judge on his case had compromised his right to a fair trial. The decision set Brazil on course for a showdown between Lula&mdash;as he is universally known&mdash;and current far-right <a href="https://time.com/collection/100-most-influential-people-2020/5888329/jair-bolsonaro-brazil/" >President Jair Bolsonaro</a> in the October 2022 elections.</span></p>
<p><strong>Read the Cover Story: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/" ><em>Brazil&rsquo;s Most Popular President Returns From Political Exile With a Promise to Save the Nation</em></a><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lula, who officially launches his campaign on May 7, promises to bring Brazil back to the good old days of his 2003-2010 presidency, which he wrapped with an 83% approval rating. That would mean reviving an ailing economy, saving a threatened democracy, and healing a nation scarred by the world&rsquo;s second-highest COVID-19 death toll and two years of chaotic pandemic mismanagement. So far, his<a href="https://time.com/6130308/bolsonaro-brazil-2022-election/" > promises are resonating</a>: Lula is <a href="https://www.uol.com.br/eleicoes/2022/04/22/pesquisa-ipespe-abril-2022-presidencia-lula-bolsonaro.htm"  target="_blank">polling</a> at 45% compared to Bolsonaro&rsquo;s 31%. But the gap is narrowing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TIME staff writer Ciara Nugent <a href="https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/" >sat down with Lula in late March</a>, in the S&atilde;o Paulo headquarters of his Workers&rsquo; Party (PT), to speak about his time in prison, the war in Ukraine, and whether his plans for the country are based on more than nostalgia. This transcript has been condensed and edited for clarity.</span></p>
<p><strong>TIME: When the Supreme Court restored your political rights last year, you were already preparing for a quieter life away from politics, according to Brazilian media. Did you immediately decide to return?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In truth, I never gave up. Politics lives in every cell of my body, in my blood, in my head. Because the issue is not politics itself, but the cause that brings you to politics. And I have a cause.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=600,450 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=489,367 489w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=979,734 979w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=249,187 249w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=499,374 499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=360,270 360w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=745,559 745w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=720,540 720w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1440,1080 1440w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1920,1440 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=407,305 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=814,611 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=280,210 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=560,420 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1333,1000 1333w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=190,143 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=380,285 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=263,197 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=526,395 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=61,46 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1200,900 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=640,480 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=760,570 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1520,1140 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=700,525 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1000,750 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=41,31 41w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=550,413 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1100,825 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=840,630 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1680,1260 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1012,759 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=2024,1518 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=320,240 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=649,487 649w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=192,144 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=533,400 533w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=267,200 267w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=171,128 171w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=333,250 333w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=479,359 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=958,719 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=767,575 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1534,1151 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=800,600 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-1.jpg?resize=1600,1200 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Luiz In&aacute;cio Lula da Silva gives a speech to union workers at Pra&ccedil;a Charles Muller, S&atilde;o Paulo, on International Workers&#8217; day, May 1, 2022.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I <a href="http://content.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1984685_1984864_1984866,00.html" >left the presidency in 2010</a>, I was not planning to be a presidential candidate again. But in the 12 years since I left office, I see that all the policies I created to benefit the poor&mdash;all our social inclusion policies, everything we did to improve universities, technical schools, improving salaries, improving the quality of jobs&mdash;all that was destroyed, dismantled. Because the people who started to occupy the government after the coup that took Dilma [Rousseff] out, were people who wanted to destroy all of the things that the Brazilian people had won after 1943. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is an expectation that I would become President of Brazil, again, because people have good memories of the time when I was President. Because people had jobs. Because people had better wages, because they had wage increases above inflation. So I think people miss that, and they want those things improved.</span></p>
<p><b>Brazil is facing a very different situation today than when you won the presidency for the first time in 2002&mdash;in terms of the economy, political polarization, the international situation. Can you do as good a job as you did the first time?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In American football, there is a player. As it happens he&rsquo;s ended up with a Brazilian woman. A model. And he&rsquo;s been the best player in the world for a long time. In each game he&rsquo;s going to play, his fans demand that he plays better than he did in the last one. With the presidency it&rsquo;s the same thing</span><b>.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I am only running because I can do better than I did before.</span></p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure that I can resolve [Brazil&#8217;s] problems. I&#8217;m certain that our problems will only be solved when poor people are participating actively in the economy, when poor people participate in the budget, when poor people are working, when poor people can eat. That is only possible if you have a government that is dedicated to the poor.</p>
<p><b>Many people in Brazil say that there were many incarnations of Lula, particularly on economic policy. Which Lula do we have today? </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Look, I am the only candidate with whom people should not be concerned about that. You know why? Because I&#8217;ve been a President twice already. And we don&#8217;t discuss economic policies before winning the elections. First, you have to win the elections. And then you have to know who you will have in your team and what you will do. But if you have questions about me, look at what happened in Brazil when I was President of the Republic. Look at how the market grew. Brazil was only doing [a few] IPOs. Under my government, we had 250. Brazil had a debt of $30 billion, and after my government, we started loaning money to the IMF. Brazil didn&rsquo;t have a single dollar of hard currency reserves. Today, we have $370 billion in hard currency reserves. [&#8230;] So you have to understand that instead of asking what I will do, just look at what I&#8217;ve done.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="115156118" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=768,509 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=600,398 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1536,1018 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=2048,1357 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=280,186 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=550,364 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1100,729 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=560,371 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=408,270 408w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=838,555 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=815,540 815w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1630,1080 1630w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=814,539 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1509,1000 1509w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=190,126 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=380,252 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=263,174 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=526,348 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=61,40 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1200,795 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=640,424 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=760,504 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1520,1007 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=700,464 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1000,663 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=840,557 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1680,1113 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1012,670 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=2024,1341 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=320,212 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=730,484 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=377,250 377w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=479,317 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=958,635 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=767,508 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1534,1016 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=800,530 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-2.jpg?resize=1600,1060 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Antonio Ribeiro&mdash;Gamma-Rapho/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >Lula at an event in Sao Bernardo Do Campo during his 1989 presidential campaign.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>During your first presidency, oil, among other products, powered a lot of that economic success. Now, with the climate crisis, we&rsquo;re trying to use less oil. The front runner in Colombia&rsquo;s May election, Gustavo Petro, has <a href="https://time.com/6139508/gustavo-petro-anti-oil-bloc/" >proposed an anti-oil bloc</a>, in which countries would immediately stop exploration for oil. Would you join?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Look, Petro has the right to propose whatever he wants. But, in the case of Brazil, this is not for real. In the case of the world, it&rsquo;s not for real. We still need oil for a while, you can&rsquo;t just&hellip;</span></p>
<p><b>But the idea is to continue extracting and using the oil they&rsquo;ve already found, and stop exploring for new deposits. Would you consider that?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, as long as you don&rsquo;t have alternative energy, you will continue to use the energy that you have. Think of our dear Germany: Angela Merkel decided to close all the nuclear power plants. She did not count on the war in Ukraine. And today, Europe <a href="https://time.com/6153184/ukraine-crisis-scrambled-germanys-energy-politics/" >depends on Russia for energy</a>. What you can do is begin a long-term process to reduce [the need for oil] as you scale up other alternatives. You cannot imagine the United States stopping its use of oil from one day to the next. </span></p>
<p><b>I want to speak about the war in Ukraine. You have always prided yourself on being able to speak to everyone&mdash;Hugo Chavez as much as George Bush. But the world today is very fragmented diplomatically. I want to know if your approach still works. Could you speak to Vladimir Putin after what he&rsquo;s done in Ukraine?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We politicians reap what we sow. If I sow fraternity, solidarity, harmony, I&rsquo;ll reap good things. If I sow discord, I&rsquo;ll reap quarrels. Putin shouldn&#8217;t have invaded Ukraine. But it&rsquo;s not just Putin who is guilty. The U.S. and the E.U. are also guilty. What was the reason for the Ukraine invasion? NATO? Then the U.S. and Europe should have said: &ldquo;Ukraine won&rsquo;t join NATO.&rdquo; That would have solved the problem.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="AMA2004003G1010111" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-7.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Alex Majoli&mdash;Magnum Photos</span><span class="caption" >Inside a shop in S&atilde;o Paulo in 2004, Lula is seen on television giving a speech responding to accusations of corruption against his government.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Do you think the threat of Ukraine joining NATO was Russia&rsquo;s real reason for invading?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That&rsquo;s the argument they put forward. If they have a secret one, we don&rsquo;t know. The other issue was Ukraine joining the E.U. The Europeans could have said: &ldquo;No, now is not the moment for Ukraine to join the E.U., we&rsquo;ll wait.&rdquo; They didn&rsquo;t have to encourage the confrontation.</span></p>
<p><b>But I think they did try to speak to Russia.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, they didn&rsquo;t. The conversations were very few. If you want peace, you have to have patience. They could have sat at a negotiating table for 10, 15, 20 days, a whole month, trying to find a solution. I think dialogue only works when it is taken seriously.</span></p>
<p><b>If you were President right now, what would you do? Would you have been able to avoid the conflict?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don&rsquo;t know if I&rsquo;d be able to. If I was President, I would have phoned <a href="https://time.com/6171813/biden-congress-billions-aid-ukraine/" >[Joe] Biden,</a> and Putin, </span><a href="https://time.com/6170974/olaf-scholz-germany-interview/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">and Germany,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and [Emmanuel] </span><a href="https://time.com/6170037/emmanuel-macron-wins-french-elections/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Macron</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Because war is not the solution. I think the problem is that if you don&rsquo;t try, you don&rsquo;t fix things. And you have to try.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I sometimes get worried. I was very concerned when the U.S. and the E.U.<a href="https://time.com/5518443/juan-guaido-interview-venezuela/" > adopted [Juan] Guaid&oacute;</a> [then leader of Venezuela&rsquo;s parliament] as President of the country [in 2019]. You don&rsquo;t play with democracy. For Guaid&oacute; to be President, he would have to be elected. Bureaucracy can&rsquo;t substitute politics. In politics, it&rsquo;s two heads of state who are governing, both elected by their people, who have to sit down at the negotiating table and look each other in the eye and talk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And now, sometimes I sit and watch the</span><a href="https://time.com/6171277/volodymyr-zelensky-interview-ukraine-war/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;"> President of Ukraine</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> speaking on television, being applauded, getting a standing ovation by all the [European] parliamentarians. This guy is as responsible as Putin for the war. Because in the war, there&rsquo;s not just one person guilty. Saddam Hussein was as guilty as Bush [for the outbreak of the 2003 Iraq war]. Because Saddam Hussein could have said, &ldquo;You can come here and check and I will prove that I do not have mass destruction weapons.&rdquo; But he lied to his people. And now, this President of Ukraine could have said, &ldquo;Come on, let&#8217;s stop talking about this NATO business, about joining the E.U. for a while. Let&rsquo;s discuss a bit more first.&rdquo;</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_vertical alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?w=700&w=700" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=480,600 480w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=294,367 294w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=587,734 587w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=150,187 150w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=299,374 299w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=216,270 216w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=447,559 447w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=432,540 432w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=864,1080 864w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1152,1440 1152w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=407,509 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=814,1018 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=280,350 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=560,700 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=800,1000 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=190,238 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=380,475 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=263,329 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=526,658 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=61,76 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1200,1500 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=640,800 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=760,950 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1520,1900 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=700,875 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1000,1250 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=25,31 25w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=550,688 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1100,1375 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=840,1050 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1680,2100 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1012,1265 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=320,400 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=600,750 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=390,487 390w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=300,375 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=192,240 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=160,200 160w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=102,128 102w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=200,250 200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=479,599 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=958,1198 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=767,959 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1534,1918 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-0.jpg?resize=1600,2000 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Lula, former Brazilian President and 2022 presidential candidate, photographed in S&atilde;o Paulo on March 23.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>So Volodomyr Zelensky should have talked to Putin more, even with 100,000 Russian troops at his border?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don&#8217;t know the President of Ukraine. But his behavior is a bit weird. It seems like he&#8217;s part of the spectacle. He is on television morning, noon, and night. He is in the U.K. parliament, the German parliament, the French parliament, the Italian parliament, as if he were waging a political campaign. He should be at the negotiating table.</span></p>
<p><b>Can you really say that to Zelensky? He didn&rsquo;t want a war, it came to him.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He did want war. If he didn&rsquo;t want war, he would have negotiated a little more. That&rsquo;s it. I criticized Putin when I was in Mexico City [in March], saying that it was a mistake to invade. But I don&rsquo;t think anyone is trying to help create peace. People are stimulating hate against Putin. That won&rsquo;t solve things! We need to reach an agreement. But people are encouraging [the war]. You are encouraging this guy [Zelensky], and then he thinks he is the cherry on your cake. We should be having a serious conversation: &ldquo;OK, you were <a href="https://time.com/5742108/ukraine-zelensky-interview-trump-putin-europe/" >a nice comedian</a>. But let us not make war for you to show up on TV.&rdquo; And we should say to Putin: &ldquo;You have a lot of weapons, but you don&#8217;t need to use them on Ukraine. Let&rsquo;s talk!&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><b>What do you think of Joe Biden?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I actually made a speech praising Biden when he announced his economic program. The problem is it&rsquo;s not enough to announce the program, you&rsquo;ve got to execute it. And I think Biden is going through <a href="https://time.com/6140442/joe-biden-presidency-second-year/" >a difficult moment</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I don&rsquo;t think he has taken the right decision on the war between Russia and Ukraine. The U.S. has a lot of political clout. And Biden could have avoided [the war], not incited it. He could have talked more, participated more. Biden could have taken a plane to Moscow to talk to Putin. This is the kind of attitude you expect from a leader. To intervene so that things don&rsquo;t go off the rails. I don&rsquo;t think he did that.</span></p>
<p><b>Should Biden have made concessions to Putin?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No. In the same way that the Americans persuaded the Russians <a href="https://time.com/5899754/jfk-decisionmaking-cuban-missile-crisis/" >not to put missiles in Cuba</a> in 1961, Biden could have said: &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to speak a bit more. We don&rsquo;t want Ukraine in NATO, full stop.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s not a concession. Let me tell you something: if I were President of Brazil and they said to me, &ldquo;Brazil can join NATO,&rdquo; I&rsquo;d say no.</span></p>
<p><b>Why?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because I&rsquo;m a guy who only thinks about peace, not war. [&#8230;] Brazil doesn&rsquo;t have disputes with any country: not with the U.S., not China, nor Russia, nor Bolivia, nor Argentina, nor Mexico. And the fact that Brazil is a peaceful country will allow us to reestablish the relationships we created between 2003 and 2010. Brazil will once again become a protagonist on the world stage, because we will prove it&rsquo;s possible to have a better world.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><div class="time-diptyche-shortcode"></div></p>
<p><b>How will you do that?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We need to create a new global governance. Today&rsquo;s United Nations doesn&rsquo;t represent anything anymore. The U.N. isn&rsquo;t taken seriously by governments today, because each one makes decisions without respecting it. Putin invaded Ukraine unilaterally, without consulting the U.N. The U.S. is used to invading countries without asking anyone and without respecting the Security Council. So we need to rebuild the U.N., to include more countries and more people. If we do that, we can start to improve the world.</span></p>
<p><b>In Brazil, during the pandemic, the Black population had a higher risk of death than white people, and a higher unemployment rate because of the pandemic as well. And Brazil&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/6047032/jair-bolsonaro-crime-policies-brazils-favelas/" >police-violence problem</a> has only worsened during the Bolsonaro government. What will you do to improve the world for <a href="https://time.com/5915902/brazil-racism-quilombos/" >Black Brazilians</a> specifically? </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I read a lot about slavery when I was in prison. And sometimes it&#8217;s difficult for me to understand what it means to have had 350 years of slavery. It&#8217;s difficult for me to understand that slavery is in people&#8217;s minds. And on the outskirts of Brazilian cities, we have thousands of young people dying almost every month, every year. It cannot continue. When I was President, we enacted a law to tell African history in Brazilian schools. So we would not see Africans as inferior people. So you know, we have to have this type of education at home and in schools. But Bolsonaro woke up hatred, prejudice. And there are other Presidents in Europe, in Hungary. A lot of fascists, Nazis, are popping up across the world.</span></p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="5gWwIETb" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
<p><b>Is Bolsonaro to blame for racism in Brazil?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, I wouldn&#8217;t say he is to blame for Brazil&#8217;s racism. It is chronic in Brazil. But he stimulates it.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="1237319533" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1100,734 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=560,374 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=809,540 809w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1619,1080 1619w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1680,1121 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1499,1000 1499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1200,801 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1520,1014 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=46,31 46w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=2024,1350 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=479,320 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=767,512 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=800,534 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-interview-transcript-eng-6.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Jonne Roriz&mdash;Bloomberg/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >A street vendor sells towels with images of Bolsonaro and Lula near Eldorado dos Caraj&aacute;s in September 2021.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>You have gone through a lot of personal tragedies in the last five years. Has that changed you in any way?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No. I would be lying if I told you I wasn&#8217;t wounded, that it didn&rsquo;t make me very nervous when the liars mounted this scheme to convict me. I was aware of what was happening in Brazil, I knew that the reason for Dilma&#8217;s impeachment had to continue. I mean, it made no sense to impeach Dilma, and two years later, I would be President again. So of course, they had to take me out of the game. But they had no reason. They cannot stop me from running for President. So what did they do? They set me up, they framed me using lies. To <a href="https://time.com/5840854/sergio-moro-brazil-interview/" >put me in jail</a>. Now I am free and all of my trials have been annulled. </span></p>
<p><b>Yes, the convictions have been annulled. But how did that period impact you?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I spent 580 days in jail. I read a lot. I reflected a lot. I was prepared to leave prison without feeling any resentment, only remembering that it was a part of history. I cannot forget it. But I can&rsquo;t put it on the table every day. I want to think about the future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For you to understand my life, I only ate bread for the first time when I was 7 years old. My mother, many times, didn&rsquo;t have anything to put on the stove for us. And I never saw her desperate. She always said: &ldquo;Tomorrow we&rsquo;ll have enough. Tomorrow will be better.&rdquo; And that was ingrained in my consciousness, in my blood. That&rsquo;s how I am. There are no problems you can&rsquo;t overcome.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I feel proud to have proven that a metalworker without a university diploma is more competent to govern this country than the elite of Brazil. Because the art of government is to use your heart, not only your head.</span></p>
<p><b>You&rsquo;re getting married soon. Can you talk a bit about your fianc&eacute;e?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don&rsquo;t like to talk about her. She can speak for herself. </span></p>
<p><b>Have you learned anything from her?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have. When you lose your wife, and you think, well, my life has no more meaning. Then suddenly, this person appears who makes you feel like you want to live again. I&rsquo;m in love as if I were 20 years old, as if it were my first girlfriend. I am going to get married in the most peaceful way possible, and I&rsquo;m going to run a happy campaign.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A guy as happy as I am doesn&rsquo;t have to rage, doesn&#8217;t have to speak badly about his opponents&mdash;let them do what they want. If I can, on the campaign, I will speak only about love. I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s possible to be a good President if you only feel hate inside you, if all you want is revenge. No, you have to think about the future. The past is over. I will build a new Brazil.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173232</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s Most Popular President Returns From Political Exile With a Promise to Save the Nation</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ciara Nugent/São Paulo, Brazil]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Exclusive]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Magazine]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6172611</guid>
      <description><![CDATA['I never gave up,' Brazil's former leader tells TIME as he launches a new bid for the presidency]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6172611"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6172611/brazil-president-lula-interview/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p class="p1">The genre we assign to a life story depends a lot on how it ends. Luiz In&aacute;cio Lula da Silva&rsquo;s life has already completed several dramatic arcs. First, the hero&rsquo;s journey: a child born into poverty moves to the big city, rises to lead a labor union, and then becomes the most popular President in the history of modern Brazil. Then the tragedy: a celebrated statesman is fingered in a staggering corruption scheme, sent to prison, and forced to watch from the sidelines while rivals dismantle his legacy.</p>
<p class="p2">The endings don&rsquo;t seem to stick, though. In April 2021, Brazil&rsquo;s Supreme Court annulled the corruption convictions that had excluded Lula&mdash;as he&rsquo;s universally known&mdash;from politics in 2018, <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/americas/20210324-brazil-s-supreme-court-rules-judge-moro-was-biased-in-lula-corruption-trial"  target="_blank">saying</a> a biased judge on his case had compromised his right to a fair trial. The bombshell decision <a href="https://time.com/5946236/brazil-lula-returns/" >set Brazil on course for a showdown</a> between the leftist Lula and current far-right President Jair Bolsonaro in the October 2022 elections. Polls <a href="https://www.uol.com.br/eleicoes/2022/04/22/pesquisa-ipespe-abril-2022-presidencia-lula-bolsonaro.htm"  target="_blank">now put</a> the challenger at 45% and the incumbent at 31%, with more centrist candidates all but out of the running.</p>
<p>[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6173104/lula-da-silva-transcricao/" ><em>Lula Conversa com TIME Sobre Ucr&acirc;nia, Bolsonaro e a Fr&aacute;gil Democracia Brasileira</em></a></p>
<p class="p2">For Lula, who is 76 and had been preparing for a quieter life away from the halls of power, this new twist in his story was a surprise. But he didn&rsquo;t hesitate to return to frontline politics. &ldquo;In truth, I never gave up,&rdquo; he rumbles in his famously gravelly voice, made hoarser by age. &ldquo;Politics lives in every cell of my body, because I have a cause. And in the 12 years since I left office, I see that all the policies I created to benefit the poor have been destroyed.&rdquo;</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_vertical alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?w=700&w=700" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg 2250w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=450,600 450w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=275,367 275w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=551,734 551w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=140,187 140w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=281,374 281w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=203,270 203w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=419,559 419w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=405,540 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=810,1080 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1080,1440 1080w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=407,543 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=814,1085 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=280,373 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=560,747 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=750,1000 750w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=190,253 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=380,507 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=263,351 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=526,701 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=61,81 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=243,323 243w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=364,484 364w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1200,1600 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=640,853 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=760,1013 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1520,2027 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=700,933 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1000,1333 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=23,31 23w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=550,733 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1100,1467 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=840,1120 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1680,2240 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1012,1349 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=2024,2699 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=320,427 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=600,800 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=365,487 365w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=300,400 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=192,256 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=150,200 150w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=96,128 96w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=188,250 188w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=479,639 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=958,1277 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=767,1023 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1534,2045 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=800,1067 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lula_Cover_final3.jpg?resize=1600,2133 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Photograph by Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="p2">It&rsquo;s late March, six weeks before Lula launches his campaign, and he&rsquo;s sitting in a studio in the S&atilde;o Paulo headquarters of his Workers&rsquo; Party (PT). Chuckling and griping that no one knows how to design a comfortable chair these days, he comes off as a jovial grandfather. But at his allusion to the current government, his back stiffens and the deeper, gruffer notes of his voice take over. Lula becomes the fiery young union leader he was in the 1970s, and launches into a soapbox-ready tirade.</p>
<p class="p2">The dream of Brazil that Lula pursued during his presidency from 2003 to 2010 lies in tatters, he says. Through progressive social programs, paid for by a boom in Brazilian products like steel, soy, and oil, Lula&rsquo;s government lifted millions out of poverty and transformed life for the country&rsquo;s <a href="https://time.com/5915902/brazil-racism-quilombos/" >Black majority</a> and <a href="https://time.com/5676877/indigenous-leader-amazon-brazil/" >Indigenous minority</a>. Bolsonaro has taken a hammer to all that, scrapping policies that expanded poor people&rsquo;s access to education, limited <a href="https://time.com/6046299/fighting-injustice-world/" >police violence against Black communities</a>, and <a href="https://time.com/longform/amazon-rainforest-fires-photos/" >protected Indigenous lands and the Amazon rain forest</a>. <a href="https://time.com/5840208/brazil-coronavirus/" >COVID-19 has killed</a> at least 660,000 Brazilians. The toll, the second highest in the world, was <a href="https://time.com/5946401/brazil-covid-19-vaccines-bolsonaro/" >likely worsened by Bolsonaro</a>, who called the virus &ldquo;a little flu,&rdquo; dubbed people who followed isolation guidance &ldquo;idiots,&rdquo; and refused to get a vaccine himself and to buy doses for Brazilians when they first became available. A <a href="http://olheparaafome.com.br/"  target="_blank">December 2020 national survey</a> showed more than 55% of Brazilians were living in food insecurity, up from 23% in 2013.</p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="5gWwIETb" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6130308/bolsonaro-brazil-2022-election/" ><em>Why 2022 Might Be the Year Brazil Says Goodbye to President Bolsonaro</em></a></p>
<p class="p2">Even Brazil&rsquo;s young democracy <a href="https://time.com/5951841/the-week-brazil-went-off-the-rails/" >feels less than secure</a>. Bolsonaro, a defender of the nation&rsquo;s 20th century military dictatorship, has called mass rallies against judges who displease him and attacked critical journalists. He has also spent months warning of electoral fraud in Brazil, in an echo of President Donald Trump&rsquo;s behavior before the 2020 U.S. election. In April, he <a href="https://www.correiobraziliense.com.br/politica/2022/04/5003734-bolsonaro-defende-suspensao-de-eleicoes-caso-ocorra-algo-anormal.html"  target="_blank">suggested</a> elections could be &ldquo;suspended&rdquo; if &ldquo;something abnormal happens.&rdquo; If he loses, analysts warn, a Brazilian version of a Jan. 6 riot is likely. If he wins, Brazil&rsquo;s institutions may not withstand another four years of his rule.</p>
<p class="p3">Riding out of his political exile like a white knight, Lula claims that he can save Brazil from that nightmare. But it may no longer be the same country he once ruled. Its economy is reeling from the pandemic, with double-digit inflation and no commodities boom on the horizon. A six-year political crisis has bitterly divided society. Geopolitical rifts that Brazil once straddled have widened, and the West is in a new hot-and-cold war with Russia.</p>
<p class="p2">Lula, though, believes lightning will strike twice. &ldquo;In American football, there is a player&mdash;as it happens he&rsquo;s ended up with a Brazilian model,&rdquo; he says, referring to Tom Brady and his wife Gisele B&uuml;ndchen. &ldquo;He&rsquo;s been the best player in the world for a long time, but in each game, his fans demand that he plays better than he did in the last one. For me, with the presidency, it&rsquo;s the same thing. I am only running because I can do better than I did before.&rdquo;</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=600,480 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=459,367 459w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=918,734 918w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=234,187 234w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=468,374 468w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=338,270 338w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=699,559 699w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=675,540 675w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1350,1080 1350w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1800,1440 1800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=407,326 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=814,651 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=280,224 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=560,448 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1250,1000 1250w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=190,152 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=380,304 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=263,210 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=526,421 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=61,49 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1200,960 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=640,512 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=760,608 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1520,1216 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=700,560 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1000,800 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=39,31 39w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=550,440 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1100,880 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=840,672 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1680,1344 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1012,810 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=2024,1619 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=320,256 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=609,487 609w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=192,154 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=500,400 500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=250,200 250w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=160,128 160w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=313,250 313w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=479,383 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=958,766 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=767,614 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1534,1227 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=800,640 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-5.jpg?resize=1600,1280 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Lula, who will run in October&#8217;s presidential elections, takes part in a labor union event during International Workers&#8217; Day in S&atilde;o Paulo.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="p4"><strong>The crowd has</strong> been waiting for hours. Children sit restlessly on white plastic chairs, crammed together with their parents under a marquee to keep out the searing midday sun. Many wear red T-shirts with the logo of the Homeless Workers&rsquo; Movement (MTST), which fights for public housing and has organized this rally in a parking lot in the working-class outskirts of S&atilde;o Paulo. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a long time,&rdquo; Lula finally begins over chants of his name, &ldquo;that I&rsquo;ve been missing the microphone.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Neighborhoods like this are Lula&rsquo;s home turf. When he was 7 years old, in 1952, his mother brought him and his seven siblings from Brazil&rsquo;s desert-like northeast, traveling two weeks in an open truck bed, to S&atilde;o Paulo. They lived in the back room of a bar, and Lula left school at 12 to help support them. By 17, he was making door handles at a factory, and on one night shift, he lost his left pinkie in a machine. At 23, Lula married a neighbor, Maria de Lourdes. But she died two years later from a hepatitis infection while eight months pregnant with their first son, who also died&mdash;victims, Lula would later say, of the low-quality health care offered to Brazil&rsquo;s poor. A few years later, in 1975, he was elected leader of the Steel Workers&rsquo; Union of S&atilde;o Bernardo do Campo, a S&atilde;o Paulo district a few miles from the site of this rally.</p>
<p class="p3">Many in Brazil know that story, which was immortalized in a <a href="http://content.time.com/time/world/article/0,8599,1950540,00.html" >syrupy 2009 film</a>, <i>Lula, Son of Brazil.</i> &ldquo;Lula&rsquo;s trajectory has a very strong mythic quality for everyone who fights for social justice in Brazil,&rdquo; says Guilherme Boulos, 39, coordinator of the MTST, who is often considered Lula&rsquo;s political heir. &ldquo;But he himself isn&rsquo;t a distant, ceremonial person. He still speaks the language of the people.&rdquo; Lula says the secret to his success lies in his ability to relate to working-class Brazilians&mdash;an unusual feat in a country where politicians are prone to price-of-milk gaffes. &ldquo;I feel proud to have proven that a metal-worker without a university diploma is more competent to govern this country than the elite of Brazil,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;Because the art of government is to use your heart, not only your head.&rdquo;</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=768,509 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=600,398 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1536,1018 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=2048,1357 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=280,186 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=550,364 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1100,729 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=560,371 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=408,270 408w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=838,555 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=815,540 815w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1630,1080 1630w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=814,539 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1509,1000 1509w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=190,126 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=380,252 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=263,174 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=526,348 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=61,40 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1200,795 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=640,424 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=760,504 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1520,1007 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=700,464 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1000,663 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=840,557 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1680,1113 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1012,670 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=2024,1341 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=320,212 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=730,484 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=377,250 377w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=479,317 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=958,635 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=767,508 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1534,1016 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=800,530 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-2.jpg?resize=1600,1060 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Antonio Ribeiro&mdash;Gamma-Rapho/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >Lula at an event in Sao Bernardo Do Campo during his 1989 presidential campaign.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="p2">Bolsonaro, a former army captain devoted to the &ldquo;says what he really thinks&rdquo; political style, would probably agree on the importance of connecting emotionally with voters. But Lula&rsquo;s populism conceals a shrewd pragmatism that has allowed him to navigate Brazil&rsquo;s choppy political waters. As President, Lula maintained the fiscal conservatism of his center-right predecessor, Fernando Henrique Cardoso, sticking to Brazil&rsquo;s agreements with the International Monetary Fund and satisfying investors. At the same time, his flagship Bolsa Fam&iacute;lia program boosted the income of poorer families, while other policies expanded access to education and health care. &ldquo;If I can tell you that I have a daughter with a law degree, it&rsquo;s because of programs created by the Lula government,&rdquo; says Mel Nogueira, 39, at the S&atilde;o Paulo rally. &ldquo;He represents hope itself.&rdquo; In 2009, two years before Lula left office with an 83% approval rating, President Barack Obama called him &ldquo;the most popular politician on earth.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Then it all came crashing down. In 2014, Brazilian investigators uncovered a vast kickbacks-for-contracts scheme, centered on the state oil giant Petrobras, with billions in public funds pilfered. The <a href="https://time.com/4135814/brazil-dilma-rousseff-impeachment/" >probe was dubbed Car Wash</a>. Lula was no longer in office, but opposition parties in Congress took advantage of anger at the scandal, and an economic crisis in Brazil, to impeach his PT prot&eacute;g&eacute; <a href="https://time.com/4476011/brazil-dilma-rousseff-crisis-impeachment/" >President Dilma Rousseff</a>. She was not directly implicated in Car Wash, but lawmakers voted her out on the pretext that she had fudged numbers to make public accounts look better ahead of an election, and replaced her with a right-wing interim President. Two weeks later, prosecutors <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-09-14/brazil-prosecutors-charge-lula-with-corruption-papers-report"  target="_blank">alleged that</a> Lula was the graft scheme&rsquo;s &ldquo;mastermind.&rdquo; The <a href="https://time.com/4253508/brazil-lula-da-silva-money-laundering/" >formal charge</a> was that he had received a beachfront apartment as a bribe from a construction company. Lula denied that he had ever owned the property, but in 2017 <a href="https://time.com/4302096/sergio-moro-2016-time-100/" >federal judge Sergio Moro</a> sentenced him to nearly 10 years in prison.</p>
<p class="p3">From behind bars the following year, Lula mounted a new campaign for October&rsquo;s presidential race. He was ahead in the polls when Brazil&rsquo;s top electoral court ruled that he could not be a candidate. Lula detected the logic of that: &ldquo;It made no sense to impeach Dilma, if two years later, I would be President again. So they had to take me out of the game.&rdquo; Bolsonaro <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-46013408"  target="_blank">defeated Lula&rsquo;s PT replacement</a> by 55.2% to 44.8%. Moro would serve as Justice Minister in Bolsonaro&rsquo;s government.</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=810,540 810w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1620,1080 1620w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1680,1120 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1500,1000 1500w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1520,1013 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=2024,1349 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-7.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Alex Majoli&mdash;Magnum Photos</span><span class="caption" >Lula is seen on television giving a speech responding to accusations of corruption against his government, inside a shop in S&atilde;o Paulo in 2004.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><a href="https://time.com/5840854/sergio-moro-brazil-interview/" ><em>Brazil&#8217;s Star Justice Minister Sergio Moro on His Resignation and Clash With President Bolsonaro</em></a></p>
<p class="p2">For the Brazilian left, Rousseff&rsquo;s impeachment amounted to a coup, an attack not on corruption&mdash;Car Wash implicated politicians across the political spectrum&mdash;but on the social progress that Lula and Rousseff had tried to achieve. Yet some supporters remained unsure about what had taken place under Lula&rsquo;s watch. &ldquo;I wish the investigation had convinced me whether he was guilty or innocent,&rdquo; left-wing filmmaker Petra Costa said in her 2019 documentary <i>The Edge of Democracy.</i> &ldquo;But instead, I was seeing prosecutors making a spectacle to present their case.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Lula had spent 18 months in prison when the Supreme Court ruled, in November 2019, that defendants can&rsquo;t be jailed before exhausting their appeal options. (In April 2022, the U.N.&rsquo;s human-rights committee said Lula&rsquo;s trial had been biased and violated due process.)It was a dark period in his life. Publications that had once celebrated his accomplishments were describing him as a criminal. His second wife, of 43 years, Marisa Let&iacute;cia, had died from a stroke during his prosecution, and while he was in jail his 7-year-old grandson Arthur died of meningitis.</p>
<p class="p3">Lula deflects questions about his state of mind during that time. He says he drew strength from calls of &ldquo;Good morning, President&rdquo; from supporters who maintained a vigil outside the jail. &ldquo;I was prepared to leave prison without feeling any resentment, only remembering that it was a part of history. I cannot forget it,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;But I can&rsquo;t put it on the table every day. I want to think about the future.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p1"><div class="time-diptyche-shortcode"></div></p>
<p class="p5"><strong>For all his</strong> talk of the future, Lula&rsquo;s campaign has so far run on nostalgia. When he was President, his Facebook ads point out, <a href="https://m.facebook.com/Lula/photos/a.328598417209165/4746598012075828/?type=3&amp;source=57"  target="_blank">unemployment was lower</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=541518240668530&amp;set=a.532393174914370"  target="_blank">wages were higher</a>, and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pt.brasil/posts/2026318690787829/"  target="_blank">fuel was cheap</a>. &ldquo;Lula hasn&rsquo;t really presented a plan for the future. For the time being, he is only presenting the idea that he was a better President than Bolsonaro,&rdquo; says Thomas Traumann, a political consultant and former Brazilian communications secretary.</p>
<p class="p2">Bolsonaro&rsquo;s pandemic mismanagement and attacks on democratic institutions have allowed Lula to command a broad unity coalition. Geraldo Alckmin, a center-right former S&atilde;o Paulo governor who was Lula&rsquo;s rival in the 2006 election, will be his running mate. Other former critics are backing his campaign, including Felipe Neto, a popular YouTuber who was a fierce voice against the PT during the Car Wash probe. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not a member of the PT, and I have hard criticism about a lot of matters related to Lula. But those criticisms are in the political field, not about human rights,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;I would like to oppose a legitimate leader; I can&rsquo;t stand doing it against a murderer any longer.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">In a country where per capita GDP has been cut almost in half since 2014, even elites, many of whom supported Bolsonaro in 2018, have warmed to the idea that Lula may be better for business. &ldquo;I am the only candidate with whom people should not be concerned about [economic policy],&rdquo; Lula says. &ldquo;Because I&rsquo;ve been a President twice already. We don&rsquo;t discuss economic policies before winning the elections. First, you have to win the elections.&rdquo; That will come as a surprise to many, since the economy has usually been at the center of Brazil&rsquo;s presidential campaigns. But Lula doubles down, citing stats from Brazil&rsquo;s 2000s boom. &ldquo;You have to understand that instead of asking what I will do, just look at what I&rsquo;ve done.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">If he wins, though, Lula would inherit a darker economic outlook than he did in 2003. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s hard to quantify how much of the economic success of Lula&rsquo;s first administration was due to the incredible conditions that he was fortunate to have,&rdquo; says Gustavo Ribeiro, a political analyst. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s going to be a much more daunting task ahead of him.&rdquo;</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_vertical alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?w=700&w=700" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg 1920w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=480,600 480w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=294,367 294w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=587,734 587w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=150,187 150w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=299,374 299w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=216,270 216w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=447,559 447w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=432,540 432w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=864,1080 864w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1152,1440 1152w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=407,509 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=814,1018 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=280,350 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=560,700 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=800,1000 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=190,238 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=380,475 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=263,329 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=526,658 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=61,76 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1200,1500 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=640,800 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=760,950 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1520,1900 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=700,875 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1000,1250 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=25,31 25w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=550,688 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1100,1375 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=840,1050 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1680,2100 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1012,1265 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=320,400 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=600,750 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=390,487 390w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=300,375 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=192,240 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=160,200 160w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=102,128 102w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=200,250 200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=479,599 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=958,1198 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=767,959 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1534,1918 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-0.jpg?resize=1600,2000 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Luisa D&ouml;rr for TIME</span><span class="caption" >Lula, former Brazilian President and 2022 presidential candidate, photographed in S&atilde;o Paulo on March 23.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="p2">That is perhaps most evident in the issue of oil. During the PT&rsquo;s rule, offshore discoveries by Petrobras bolstered state budgets and kept fuel prices low in Brazil. Today the global oil price is surging, driving inflation in Brazil, while efforts to <a href="https://time.com/5956519/brazil-biden-climate-change/" >fight the climate crisis</a> have cast a shadow over the future of the oil sector, which <a href="https://oec.world/en/profile/country/bra"  target="_blank">makes up 11.5%</a> of Brazil&rsquo;s exports. In Colombia, Gustavo Petro, the left-wing front runner in its upcoming election, has pledged an immediate halt to oil exploration in his country&mdash;in line with recommendations of the International Energy Agency. He <a href="https://time.com/6139508/gustavo-petro-anti-oil-bloc/" >expressed hope</a> that Lula and other progressive allies would join him in an anti-oil bloc.</p>
<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/amazon-rainforest-disappearing/" ><em>The Amazon Rain Forest Is Nearly Gone. We Went to the Front Lines to See If It Could Be Saved</em></a></p>
<p class="p3">Lula&rsquo;s response will disappoint environmentalists. &ldquo;Look, Petro has the right to propose whatever he wants. But in the case of Brazil, this is not for real,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;In the case of the world, it&rsquo;s not for real.&rdquo; Might he stop exploration for new oil deposits while extracting the oil Brazil has already located? &ldquo;No, as long as you don&rsquo;t have alternative energy, you will continue to use the energy that you have.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Though Lula says his administration would scale up Brazil&rsquo;s production of clean energy, he has also pledged to invest in new oil-refinery infrastructure in an effort to decouple Brazil&rsquo;s oil from the global market. He frames it as a sovereignty issue. &ldquo;Think of <a href="https://time.com/6153184/ukraine-crisis-scrambled-germanys-energy-politics/" >our dear Germany</a>: Angela Merkel decided to close all the <a href="https://time.com/6169164/ukraine-nuclear-energy-europe/" >nuclear power plants</a>. She did not count on the war in Ukraine. And today, Europe depends on Russia for energy.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Lula&rsquo;s views on foreign policy put him against the prevailing wind today. As President, he refused to take a side in the West&rsquo;s arguments with its rivals, and prided himself on speaking with Venezuela&rsquo;s Hugo Ch&aacute;vez or Iran&rsquo;s Mahmoud Ahmadinejad the same week as George W. Bush or Barack Obama. He says he was &ldquo;very concerned&rdquo; when the U.S. and many Latin American countries recognized <a href="https://time.com/5518443/juan-guaido-interview-venezuela/" >Juan Guaid&oacute;,</a> Venezuela&rsquo;s center-left opposition leader, as President in 2019, in a bid to force Nicol&aacute;s Maduro, <a href="https://time.com/5918527/venezuela-parliamentary-elections-maduro/" >Ch&aacute;vez&rsquo;s authoritarian successor</a>, from power. Even today, after Venezuela&rsquo;s collapse into kleptocracy, Lula refuses to call Maduro a dictator.</p>
<p class="p2">Lula remains a die-hard believer that &ldquo;two elected heads of state, sitting at a table, looking each other in the eye,&rdquo; can resolve any differences. He claims that President Joe Biden and <a href="https://time.com/6170974/olaf-scholz-germany-interview/" >E.U. leaders</a> failed to do that enough in the run-up to Russia&rsquo;s invasion of its neighbor in February. &ldquo;The United States has a lot of political clout. And Biden could have avoided [the war], not incited it,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;He could have participated more. Biden could have taken a plane to Moscow to talk to Putin. This is the kind of attitude you expect from a leader.&rdquo;</p>
<figure class="inline-longform_large alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?w=1000&w=1000" alt="" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg 2400w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=550,367 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1100,734 1100w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=280,187 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=560,374 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=809,540 809w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1619,1080 1619w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=840,560 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1680,1121 1680w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1499,1000 1499w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=526,351 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1232,821 1232w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1850,1234 1850w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1200,801 1200w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=640,427 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=760,507 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1520,1014 1520w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=700,467 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1000,667 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=46,31 46w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1012,675 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=2024,1350 2024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=479,320 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=958,639 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=767,512 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1534,1023 1534w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=800,534 800w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/lula-return-to-presidency-6.jpg?resize=1600,1067 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Jonne Roriz&mdash;Bloomberg/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >A street vendor sells towels with images of Bolsonaro and Lula near Eldorado dos Caraj&aacute;s in September 2021.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="p3">Most Western analysts argue that Vladimir Putin&rsquo;s invasion was <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2022/03/02/long-history-russian-imperialism-shaping-putins-war/"  target="_blank">fueled by an imperialistic desire</a> to seize territory, rather than any provocations from Ukraine. But in Lula&rsquo;s view, even <a href="https://time.com/6171277/volodymyr-zelensky-interview-ukraine-war/" >Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky</a>, who faced a months-long buildup of troops at his borders before the outbreak of war in February, shares blame. &ldquo;I see the President of Ukraine, speaking on television, being applauded, getting a standing ovation by all the [European] parliamentarians,&rdquo; he says, shaking his head angrily. &ldquo;This guy is as responsible as Putin for the war. Because in the war, there&rsquo;s not just one person guilty.&rdquo; He argues that it is irresponsible for Western leaders to celebrate Zelensky rather than focusing on closed-door negotiations. &ldquo;You are encouraging this guy, and then he thinks he is the cherry on your cake. We should be having a serious conversation. OK, you were a nice comedian. But let us not make war for you to show up on TV.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Read More: </strong><em><a href="https://time.com/6171277/volodymyr-zelensky-interview-ukraine-war/" >Inside Zelensky&#8217;s World</a></em></p>
<p class="p3">The U.S. and the E.U. should have assured Putin that <a href="https://time.com/6151115/nato-russia-ukraine-article-4/" >Ukraine would not join NATO</a>, Lula says, drawing a comparison with the 1962 Cuban missile crisis, when the U.S. and Russia agreed to remove missile deployments from each other&rsquo;s backyards. Western sanctions on Russia have unfairly impacted other regions&rsquo; economies, he adds. &ldquo;War is no solution,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;And now we are going to have to foot the bill because of the war on Ukraine. Argentina, Bolivia will also have to pay. You&rsquo;re not punishing Putin. You&rsquo;re punishing many different countries, you&rsquo;re punishing mankind.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">The conflict underscores the need to renew global institutions, he says. &ldquo;Today&rsquo;s United Nations doesn&rsquo;t represent anything anymore. Governments don&rsquo;t take the U.N. seriously today, because they make decisions without respecting it,&rdquo; Lula says. &ldquo;We need to create a new global governance.&rdquo; However difficult that may be in today&rsquo;s fractured world, many leaders and diplomats would welcome Lula&rsquo;s return: over the past four years, Bolsonaro has burned countless bridges, angering China with racist jokes about COVID-19 and <a href="https://time.com/5658418/europe-brazil-amazon-deforestation-tension/" >mocking E.U. leaders.</a> &ldquo;Brazil will again become a protagonist on the international stage,&rdquo; Lula pledges, &ldquo;and we will prove that it&rsquo;s possible to have a better world.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p4">If Lula&rsquo;s stance on Ukraine, or his refusal to acknowledge any corruption-related mistakes by his party, suggest stubbornness, his supporters say he is willing to evolve where it matters.</p>
<p class="p2">For example, Brazil&rsquo;s conversation on systemic racism has advanced since 2010. According to Douglas Belchior, an organizer for the nation&rsquo;s Black Coalition for Rights, Lula&rsquo;s antipoverty and education-access programs gave him a strong record on improving <a href="https://time.com/6046299/fighting-injustice-world/" >life for Black and mixed-race Brazilians</a>, who make up 56% of the population and 75% of the country&rsquo;s poorest. But today, Black and Indigenous Brazilians are <a href="https://time.com/5867784/black-domestic-workers-treatment-brazil/" >calling for more targeted action</a> to undo the pervasive legacy of slavery and colonialism. Lula&rsquo;s next administration will need to put more emphasis on antiracism, and correct &ldquo;some serious failings&rdquo; by past PT governments on policing, Belchior says. &ldquo;Going back to the point immediately before Bolsonaro isn&rsquo;t enough for us. We have to move forward from where the PT governments stopped,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;And Lula has listened to many Black activists, intellectuals, and politicians. He knows that the reconstruction of Brazil requires tackling racism.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Read More:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/5915902/brazil-racism-quilombos/" ><em>How Black Brazilians Are Looking to a Slavery-Era Form of Resistance to Fight Racial Injustice Today</em></a></p>
<p class="p2">There also are signs of movement on environmental issues. Though Lula is less ambitious about phasing out fossil fuels, his administrations were successful in curbing deforestation. Now he is centering the shifts Brazil needs to make on food to fight climate change&mdash;arguably more important in a country where <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/ghg-emissions-by-sector?time=latest&amp;country=~BRA"  target="_blank">agriculture and land use make up 61.5%</a> of annual greenhouse-gas emissions. &ldquo;I have improved how I speak. Now I&rsquo;m not only talking about [ensuring that people can afford] a barbecue, but also about vegetarians,&rdquo; he tweeted in February. &ldquo;So we can stimulate a healthier agriculture in our country.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Brazilian media <a href="https://veja.abril.com.br/coluna/maquiavel/tres-pautas-que-janja-noiva-de-lula-incluiu-na-agenda-do-petista/"  target="_blank">attributes some of Lula&rsquo;s new talking points</a>&mdash;which also include an emphasis on gender equality and animal rights&mdash;to the influence of his fianc&eacute;e Ros&acirc;ngela da Silva (no relation). In 2019, Lula announced his engagement to da Silva, a 55-year-old sociologist and PT activist, and they plan to wed in May. He&rsquo;s hesitant to talk about her&mdash;&ldquo;She can speak for herself!&rdquo;&mdash;but he has &ldquo;learned from her,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;When you lose your wife, you think, well, my life has no more meaning. Then suddenly this person appears who makes you feel like you want to live again. I&rsquo;m in love as if I were 20 years old, as if it were my first girlfriend.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2">Lula believes the marriage will shape the tone of his next political chapter. &ldquo;A guy as happy as I am doesn&rsquo;t have to rage&mdash;let your opponents do what they want,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;If I can, on the campaign, I will speak only about love. I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s possible to be a good President if you only feel hate inside you, if all you want is revenge. No, the past is over. I will build a new Brazil.&rdquo;</p>
<p class="p2"><i>With reporting by</i> <em>Eloise Barry/London</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6172611</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Hunger to Worsen After Spiking 25% Before Ukraine War</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173422/world-hunger-ukraine/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Durisin / Bloomberg]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[bloomberg wire]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[food insecurity]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173422</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Almost 193 million people across 53 countries or territories suffered acute food insecurity in 2021]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173422"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/6173422/world-hunger-ukraine/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>The number of people going hungry surged by 25% last year and the toll is rising as the war in Ukraine sends food prices ever higher.</p>
<p>Conflicts in countries like Ethiopia and Afghanistan have worsened crises there, and economic shocks from the Covid-19 pandemic curbed food access in almost two dozen nations, the Global Network Against Food Crises said. Extreme weather, like severe drought in Madagascar, is also exacerbating the problem.</p>
<p>Almost 193 million people across 53 countries or territories suffered acute food insecurity in 2021, meaning their lack of meals posed an immediate threat to their lives or livelihoods, the international alliance said in a <a href="http://www.fightfoodcrises.net/"  target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">report</a>. That&rsquo;s up from 155 million in 55 countries for the prior year, and a record in the six years since the report began. The outlook is expected to &ldquo;deteriorate further&rdquo; this year.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/6159061/ukraine-wheat-changing-course-of-history/" ><em>Ukrainian Wheat Is Once Again Changing the Course of History</em></a></p>
<p>&ldquo;The war in Ukraine is supercharging a three-dimensional crisis&mdash;food, energy and finance&mdash;with devastating impacts on the world&rsquo;s most vulnerable people, countries and economies,&rdquo; United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said in the report.</p>
<p><a href="https://time.com/6157236/ukraines-fuel-crisis-cause-global-hunger-worsen-inflation/" >Ukraine</a> is one of the world&rsquo;s top grain and vegetable-oil suppliers and the war is disrupting its harvests and exports. A gauge of world food prices has soared to a record&mdash;eclipsing levels seen in 2008 and 2011 that contributed to global food crises&mdash;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2022-04-20/rising-food-energy-prices-are-just-the-start-of-an-emerging-economic-crisis"  target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">piling pressure</a> on governments from Sri Lanka to Peru. That&rsquo;s helping to spark a wave of protectionism as some exporters curb overseas crop sales to ensure local supplies.</p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong> <em><a href="https://time.com/6164661/ukraine-war-hunger-wwi-lessons/" >How a Post-War Famine in Russia and Ukraine Shaped the 20th Century</a></em></p>
<p>The war will have &ldquo;severe consequences&rdquo; on global food security, as millions of Ukrainians are displaced and many import-dependent countries can&rsquo;t get staple crops or fertilizers from Ukraine and Russia, according to the report. The war is also hampering the global economic recovery from the pandemic.</p>
<div class="video-container"><div id="ckWgQS3B" class="jw-video" data-media-id="test"></div></div>
<p>Early data already indicate the food crisis is worsening. The number facing hunger this year will reach about 180 million in 41 of the countries surveyed last year, plus Cabo Verde. While there&rsquo;s no forecast yet for the remaining 12 nations, it represents an additional 5 million hungry people across the countries where there are already projections.</p>
<p>The food crises network was founded by the European Union, World Food Programme and UN&rsquo;s Food and Agriculture Organization in 2016.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173422</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E.U. Leader Calls for a Russian Oil Ban in a New Set of Sanctions</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173405/eu-russia-oil-ban-sanctions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Lorne Cook and Samuel Petrequin / AP]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 08:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[overnight]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[wire]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173405</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Ursula von der Leyen called on member nations to phase out imports of Russian crude oil within six months]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173405"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module video-2" data-src="https://time.com/6173405/eu-russia-oil-ban-sanctions/" data-widget-id="SB_4" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p>BRUSSELS &mdash; The European Union&#8217;s top official on Wednesday called on the 27-nation bloc to ban oil imports from Russia in a sixth package of sanctions targeting Moscow for its war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen also proposed that Sberbank, Russia&rsquo;s largest bank, and two other major banks be disconnected from the SWIFT international banking payment system.</p>
<p>Von der Leyen, addressing the European Parliament in Strasbourg, France, called on the EU&#8217;s member nations to phase out imports of crude oil within six months and refined products by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We will make sure that we phase out Russian oil in an orderly fashion, in a way that allows us and our partners to secure alternative supply routes and minimizes the impact on global markets,&rdquo; von der Leyen said.<br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p>The proposals need to be unanimously approved to take effect and are likely to be the subject of fierce debate. Von der Leyen conceded that getting all 27 member countries &mdash; some of them landlocked and highly dependent on Russia for energy supplies &mdash; to agree on oil sanctions &ldquo;will not be easy.&rdquo;</p>
<p><em><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/6172292/russia-ukraine-invasion-energy/" >Column: Russia Is Still Winning the Energy War</a></em></p>
<p>If approved, the ban on oil imports will be the second package of EU sanctions targeting Russia&rsquo;s lucrative energy industry over its war in Ukraine that President Vladimir Putin started on Feb. 24. In addition to sanctions on various entities and individuals &mdash; including Putin himself and members of his family &mdash; the bloc previously approved an embargo on coal imports.</p>
<p>The EU has started discussions on a possible natural gas embargo, but consensus among member countries on targeting the fuel used to generate electricity and heat homes is more difficult to secure.</p>
<p>Hungary and Slovakia have already said they wouldn&#8217;t take part in any oil sanctions, but von der Leyen didn&#8217;t elaborate on whether they would receive an exemption from the sanctions, although this appears likely.</p>
<p>Von der Leyen also said that the EU should target high-ranking military officers and others &ldquo;who committed war crimes in Bucha,&rdquo; a suburb of the capital Kyiv. Ukrainian officials have alleged that retreating Russian troops carried out mass killings of civilians in Bucha.</p>
<p>&ldquo;This sends another important signal to all perpetrators of the Kremlin&rsquo;s war: We know who you are. We will hold you accountable. You&rsquo;re not getting away with this,&rdquo; von der Leyen told the lawmakers.</p>
<p>Banks are also in the EU executive arm&rsquo;s sights, and notably Sberbank. Von der Leyen said the aim is that &ldquo;we de-SWIFT Sberbank.&#8221; SWIFT is the major global system for financial transfers.</p>
<p>Von der Leyen said Sberbank holds around 37% of the Russian banking sector.</p>
<p>&ldquo;And we will also de-SWIFT two other major banks in Russia. By that, we hit banks that are systemically critical to the Russian financial system and Putin&rsquo;s ability to wage destruction,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><em><strong>Read more:</strong> <a href="https://time.com/6154189/russia-swift-china-usd-rmb-finance-trade/" >Sanctions on Russia Could Drive Moscow Closer to Beijing and Change the Global Financial System</a></em></p>
<p>Von der Leyen added that those alleged to be spreading disinformation about the war in Ukraine would be targeted.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We are banning three big Russian state-owned broadcasters from our airwaves. They will not be allowed to distribute their content anymore in the EU, in whatever shape or form be it on cable, via satellite, on the internet or via smartphone apps.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She didn&#8217;t name the broadcasters directly, but branded the television channels &ldquo;as mouthpieces that amplify Putin&acute;s lies and propaganda aggressively. We should not give them a stage anymore to spread these lies.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173405</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Abortion Rights Around the World</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6173229/countries-abortion-illegal-restrictions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eloise Barry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Explainer]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6173229</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[The rollback of abortion rights in the U.S. has been mirrored in many other nations, but in others, women's rights activists have succeeded in broadening abortion access]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6173229"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6173229/countries-abortion-illegal-restrictions/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Supreme Court is </span><a href="https://time.com/6172868/roe-wade-supreme-court/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">reportedly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> considering overturning the landmark </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ruling on abortion rights, according to a leaked </span><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/05/02/supreme-court-abortion-draft-opinion-00029473"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">draft opinion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If carried out, abortion will no longer be considered a constitutional right in the U.S., and each state will be free to determine the legality of the procedure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 1973, </span><a href="https://time.com/3669867/roe-v-wade-history/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe v. Wade</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> gave women in the U.S. an absolute right to an abortion in the first three months of pregnancy, and limited rights beyond then. While abortion is legal in some form in every state under </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roe, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">abortion access has been eroded over the years in more than a dozen states. </span><a href="https://time.com/6099921/texas-self-managed-abortions/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Texas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for example, passed a law in 2021 allowing residents to sue clinics and doctors for carrying out an abortion after six weeks. In Mississippi&mdash;the state at the center of the Supreme Court case&mdash;most abortions are banned after 15 weeks.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6173019/supreme-court-leak-roe-v-wade-abortion/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What to Know About the Leaked Roe v. Wade Supreme Court Draft Opinion</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rollback of abortion rights in the U.S. has been mirrored in many other nations globally, where the rise of pro-life movements have coincided with radical political or cultural shifts. In other countries, abortion rights activists have succeeded in pushing for less restrictive laws as part of a broader fight for women&rsquo;s rights.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here is a look at countries where abortion is banned, restricted, or has recently been legalized.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries where abortion is illegal</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?category[1348]=1348"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Center for Reproductive Rights</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a global legal advocacy organization, there are 24 countries in the world where abortion is completely prohibited. These include Andorra and Malta in Europe, El Salvador and Honduras in Central America, Senegal and Egypt in Africa, and the Philippines and Laos in Asia. Some </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?category[1348]=1348"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">90 million (5%) women</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">of reproductive age live in countries that prohibit abortion altogether.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Activists and campaigners in many of these countries continue to fight to ease abortion restrictions. The hardline laws in El Salvador, which were introduced in 1998 after campaigning from conservative sectors of the Catholic Church, have led to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">dozens of women being found guilty of &#8220;aggravated homicide,&#8221; even in cases of miscarriage. In March, thousands of Salvadoran women </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-60646938"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">marched</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to demand that the ban be eased to allow abortions in cases of rape, when the fetus is not viable, or if the woman&#8217;s life is at risk.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries with significant restrictions to abortion access</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than 50 countries and regions permit abortions only when the woman&rsquo;s health is at risk. (Some refer only to physical health, while others include mental health.) These include Libya, Iran, Indonesia, Venezuela and Nigeria. Others have exceptions for cases of rape, incest, or fetal abnormality.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Brazil, for example, abortion is illegal except in cases of rape, risks to the life of the mother, or when the fetus has anencephaly&mdash;missing part of the brain or skull. In these cases, the woman needs approval from a doctor and at least three other</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> clinical experts.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In August 2020, under President Bolsonaro&rsquo;s far-right government, a </span><a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2020/09/21/brazil-revoke-regulation-curtailing-abortion-access"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Health Ministry regulation</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">was introduced that requires medical professionals to collect evidence and report to the police anyone who seeks legal termination of a pregnancy after rape&mdash;which Human Rights Watch </span><a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2020/09/21/brazil-revoke-regulation-curtailing-abortion-access"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">suggests</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is to dissuade rape survivors.</span></p>
<figure class="inline-portrait_small_2x alignnone "><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?w=560&w=560" alt="Protests Continue Against Abortion Ruling In Poland" srcset="https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg 1024w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=600,400 600w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=550,366 550w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=280,186 280w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=560,373 560w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=405,270 405w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=838,559 838w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=811,540 811w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=840,559 840w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=407,271 407w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=814,542 814w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=190,127 190w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=380,253 380w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=263,175 263w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=526,350 526w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=61,41 61w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=616,411 616w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=321,214 321w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=642,428 642w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=925,617 925w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=640,426 640w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=760,506 760w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=700,466 700w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=1000,666 1000w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=47,31 47w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=1012,674 1012w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=320,213 320w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=730,487 730w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=345,230 345w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=270,180 270w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=192,128 192w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=375,250 375w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=479,319 479w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=958,638 958w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=767,511 767w, https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/abortion-protest-poland.jpg?resize=800,533 800w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
<figcaption class="image-caption" ><span class="credit" >Omar Marques/Getty Images</span><span class="caption" >A woman holds a European Union flag at a protest against the Constitutional Court ruling on tightening abortion laws on Oct. 30, 2020 in Warsaw, Poland. </span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In January 2021, a </span><a href="https://time.com/5905885/poland-abortion-ban-protest/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">near-total ban on abortion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was introduced in Poland, only allowing the procedure in cases of rape, incest, or when the mother&rsquo;s life is at risk. The ban removed the exception for an abortion </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in cases of severe and irreversible fetal abnormalities&mdash;the grounds for which 98% of abortions in Poland were carried out in 2019.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Mass demonstrations broke out in Poland in November 2021 following the </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-59206683"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">death of a woman</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at 22 weeks pregnant from sepsis, after her family said that life-saving treatment was delayed because of the ban. This month, the first pro-choice activist to be charged under the new law </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2022/mar/28/polish-woman-is-first-to-face-trial-for-violating-strict-abortion-law"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">went on trial</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for providing a pregnant woman with tablets to induce a miscarriage.</span></p>
<h2><b>Countries with broader access to abortion </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Center for Reproductive Rights</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in countries from Japan to India to Canada, as well as most of Europe and the U.S., more than </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">half of women of reproductive age </span><a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/worlds-abortion-laws/?country=JPN&amp;category[1351]=1351"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">can safely access</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> abortion either on request or based on broad social or economic grounds.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seventy-two countries, including France and Germany, allow for abortion subject to gestational time limits&mdash;the most common being 12 weeks. Even in these countries, there are often a variety of exceptions that allow abortions to take place later. In the U.K. for example, there is a 24-week limit on abortion, but if the fetus has a disability such as </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/sep/23/woman-with-downs-syndrome-loses-uk-abortion-law-case"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Down&rsquo;s Syndrome</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the pregnancy can be terminated right up until birth.</span></p>
<p><b>Read More: </b><a href="https://time.com/6172956/consequences-overruling-roe-wade/" ><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Enormous Consequences of Overturning Roe v. Wade</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While pro-life movements in countries like Poland and the U.S. have successfully lobbied for rollbacks in reproductive rights, other nations are making strides towards greater freedoms. In the past 18 months, Colombia, Argentina, and Mexico&mdash;traditionally conservative Catholic countries in Latin America&mdash;decriminalized abortions following waves of protests and campaigning by women&rsquo;s rights and pro-choice groups. The most recent, Colombia, </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2022/feb/22/colombia-legalises-abortion-in-move-celebrated-as-historic-victory-by-campaigners"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">set the legal gestational limit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at 24 weeks of pregnancy in February.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The changes have inspired other pro-choice movements in the region&mdash;dubbed the </span><a href="https://time.com/5358823/argentina-abortion-vote-latin-america/" ><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;green wave&rdquo;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the colors worn by campaigners. Chile could become the </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/chile-abortion-debate-gets-key-place-constitution-redraft-2022-03-16/"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">first Latin American country</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to have the right to abortion enshrined in the country&rsquo;s constitution, pending the results of a vote later this year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And in Europe, Ireland drew worldwide attention after a May 2018 popular referendum that led to abortion being legalized up to 12 weeks, and limited circumstances beyond then. Before the change, thousands of Irish women would typically travel to nearby England fo</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">r the procedure every year, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the Belfast-based journalism project </span><a href="https://www.thedetail.tv/articles/abortion-exported-women-travelling-for-terminations"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Detail Data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>More than a year later in October 2019 neighboring Northern Ireland became the last nation in the U.K. to decriminalize abortion. Despite the procedure now being legal on request up until 12 weeks in most cases, and up to 24 weeks if the pregnancy is a threat to the mother&rsquo;s health, the country has <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/63461e65-c55a-4f1f-8e86-7cff69c90dff"  target="_blank">yet to establish</a> sufficient state-run abortion services. The majority of those that currently exist are provided by charities. This means that women who are more than 10 weeks pregnant still need to travel elsewhere in the U.K. for the procedure and, although the cost of the trip is covered by the state, the pandemic has made it more difficult for those women to travel. In March, U.K. lawmakers in Westminster began a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/mar/24/uk-government-to-override-northern-ireland-on-abortion-services"  target="_blank">legal process</a> to compel their counterparts in the devolved nation to provide adequate state-run access.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2020, New Zealand </span><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-51955148"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">decriminalized</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> abortion and extended the legal period to 20 weeks of pregnancy. Prior to that, two doctors were required to approve an abortion&mdash;and they would only do so if there was a &ldquo;serious danger&rdquo; to the woman&rsquo;s health. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6173229</post-id>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s Conspiracy-Laden Claims that Israel Is Supporting Neo-Nazis Could Change Tel Aviv’s Stance on the War in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://time.com/6172946/sergei-lavrov-hitler-israel-ukraine/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Charlie Campbell]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 16:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Londontime]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Second click]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://time.com/?p=6172946</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Sergei Lavrov has doubled down on comments about Hitler's 'Jewish blood' and said Israel supports the 'neo-Nazi' regime in Kyiv]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right-rail__container right-rail__container--ad"><div class="right-rail__ad__wrapper right-rail__module"><div class="right-rail__ad" id="right-rail__ad-6172946"></div></div><br />
<div class="OUTBRAIN right-rail__outbrain right-rail__module" data-src="https://time.com/6172946/sergei-lavrov-hitler-israel-ukraine/" data-widget-id="SB_2" data-ob-template="timemag"></div></aside>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a lesson in defending the indefensible, Sergei Lavrov is your man. Russia&rsquo;s Foreign Minister&rsquo;s comments broadcast Sunday that Hitler had &ldquo;Jewish blood&rdquo; and the &ldquo;most rabid antisemites tend to be Jews&rdquo; has shocked much of the world, especially Israel, which denounced an &#8220;unforgivable&#8221; lie that besmirched the horrors of the Nazi Holocaust.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Lavrov doubled down on these sentiments Tuesday. In a</span><a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/russia-doubles-down-says-israel-supports-neo-nazi-regime-ukraine-1.10777197"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">statement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, his ministry said that the subsequent uproar explained &ldquo;to a large extent why the current Israeli government supports the neo-Nazi regime in Kyiv.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lavrov&rsquo;s original comments came after he was asked by an Italian TV station to explain his government&rsquo;s</span><a href="https://time.com/6154493/denazification-putin-ukraine-history-context/" > <span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;denazification&rdquo; justification</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for invading Ukraine when the nation&rsquo;s President,</span><a href="https://time.com/6171277/volodymyr-zelensky-interview-ukraine-war/" > <span style="font-weight: 400;">Volodymyr Zelensky</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is himself Jewish and comes from a family </span><a href="https://www.kyivpost.com/ukraine-politics/in-israel-zelensky-tells-own-familys-holocaust-story.html"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">partially wiped out</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the Holocaust.</span><br />
[time-brightcove not-tgx=&#8221;true&#8221;]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">His response&mdash;which included the assertion that &ldquo;there is no family without a monster&rdquo;&mdash;sparked a diplomatic spat with Russia&rsquo;s close partner Israel, which summoned Moscow&rsquo;s Ambassador, Anatoly Viktorov, for a</span><a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/lapid-says-russian-envoy-subjected-to-tough-conversation-over-lavrov-comments/"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;tough conversation.&rdquo;</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;His words are untrue and their intentions are wrong,&rdquo; <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraeliPM/status/1521084831085600774"  target="_blank">said</a> Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett. &ldquo;Using the Holocaust of the Jewish people as a political tool must cease immediately.&rdquo;</span></p>
<div class="gmail_default">Israel has not joined sanctions against Russia over its invasion nor has it provided military aid to Ukraine, though it&rsquo;s yet to be seen whether Sergei Lavrov&rsquo;s words will change that dynamic. At the very least, the spat prompted Israel for the first time to publicly condemn Russia&#8217;s claim that Zelensky is a Nazi.</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, experts say it&rsquo;s wrong to simply attribute Lavrov&rsquo;s comments to simple blundering. Despite Russia&rsquo;s insistence that Ukraine must be &ldquo;denazified,&rdquo; the government of Vladimir Putin is all too willing to wield antisemitic conspiracies when they suit. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oliver Bullough, author of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looting Ukraine: How East and West Teamed Up to Steal a Country</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, tells TIME that Lavrov&rsquo;s comments &ldquo;reflect the weirdly irrational conspiratorial mindset of most senior Russian officials.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even so, it&#8217;s rare for a senior Kremlin official to openly voice such views. &ldquo;At the moment, the Russian political class has crossed the red line,&rdquo; says Ilya Yablokov, a lecturer at the University of Sheffield and author of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anti-Jewish conspiracy theories in Putin&#8217;s Russia.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &ldquo;Basically, they have no limitations and can talk about whatever they want.&rdquo;</span></p>
<h2><b>Russia&rsquo;s relations reset with Israel</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following the fall of the Soviet Union, Russia experienced an uptick in mainstream anti-Jewish rhetoric as curbs on speech were <a href="https://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/181494/1/Anti-Jewish%20CTs%20in%20Putin%27s%20Russia%20IY%20FINAL%2010%20Jan.pdf"  target="_blank">rolled back</a>. However, since Putin came to power antisemitic hate speech and violence</span><a href="https://www.wilsoncenter.org/event/russian-anti-semitism-and-the-scape-goating-jews-the-dog-didnt-bark"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">has dwindled</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, from the mid-2000s, the Putin regime has leaned into the idea that the West is a singular enemy hellbent on destroying Russia. In support of this proposition, all manner of subplots percolate despite some blatant inherent contradictions, including of gay people, Nazis and Jews conspiring toward the same goal: Russia&rsquo;s downfall. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Putin has avoided antisemitic language himself, and poses with Russia&rsquo;s chief Rabbi on Jewish holidays, he frequently cites antisemitic Russian thinkers in his speeches, such as</span><a href="https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2018/03/16/ivan-ilyin-putins-philosopher-of-russian-fascism/"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">philosopher Ivan Ilyin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://discovery.ucl.ac.uk/id/eprint/1446515/1/U602440.pdf"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">historian Lev Gumilev</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Russia&rsquo;s President has even</span> <a href="https://www.euronews.com/2019/08/10/what-protests-putin-rides-with-night-wolves-bikers-in-crimea"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">saddled up</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with notorious antisemitic motorcycle gang the Night Wolves, to whom he</span><a href="https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-russian-bikers-get-crimea-land-gift/27014307.html"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">gave a slice of seized Crimea</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Putin has also</span><a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/putin-praises-achievements-of-ultra-nationalist-anti-semitic-writer/"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">showered praise</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on ultra-nationalist Russian writer Alexander Prokhanov, who, among many other rants, in 2012</span><a href="https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=ZrMyDwAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PT59&amp;lpg=PT59&amp;dq=Alexander+Prokhanov+%E2%80%9CJews+took+over+the+world+and+are+using+their+power+for+evil.%E2%80%9D&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=tjfy-P_vYU&amp;sig=ACfU3U0nwq_NfJKTTcG3tLmUnACMIE7UCQ&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjJlqmamcP3AhXOSsAKHZ8lAGkQ6AF6BAgCEAM#v=onepage&amp;q=Alexander%20Prokhanov%20%E2%80%9CJews%20took%20over%20the%20world%20and%20are%20using%20their%20power%20for%20evil.%E2%80%9D&amp;f=false"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">said</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that &ldquo;Jews took over the world and are using their power for evil.&rdquo; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And it ultimately seems that in today&rsquo;s Russia, any conspiracy theory is a good one. When anti-Putin protest rock group</span><a href="https://entertainment.time.com/2012/07/31/pussy-riot-trial-punk-putin-and-protest/" > <span style="font-weight: 400;">Pussy Riot stormed Moscow&rsquo;s Church of Christ the Saviour</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, media allies of the president</span><a href="https://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/181494/1/Anti-Jewish%20CTs%20in%20Putin%27s%20Russia%20IY%20FINAL%2010%20Jan.pdf"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">suggested that Jews</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were possible instigators in a nefarious bid to destroy the Russian Orthodox Church, while Putin himself claimed </span><a href="https://www.haaretz.com/jewish/putin-provokes-criticism-with-pussy-riot-anti-semitism-charge-1.5198750"  target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the group might be antisemitic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lavrov&rsquo;s comments also echo a popular strand of antisemitism in eastern Europe that Jews have co-opted the Holocaust to seize the victimhood narrative from its &ldquo;genuine&rdquo; victims, who were Eastern European Christians. The Foreign Ministry&rsquo;s statement Tuesday that Israel&rsquo;s condemnation was &ldquo;anti-historical&rdquo; also suggests such a tactic. Whether that was unintentional, or a deliberate attempt to win approval in the Middle East, is unclear.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, such sentiments work better for domestic consumption and Lavrov&rsquo;s very public broadcasting of revisionist Christian nationalism may score an own goal in Russia&rsquo;s military aims. Already, Moscow&rsquo;s relations with Jerusalem had been cooling as it</span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-putin-iran-moscow-tehran-5438506fba2505fbcd227f93c533e86d"  target="_blank"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">tilts toward Tehran</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S, E.U. and other Western nations have also been pressing Israel to take a firmer position against Russia. In February, Israel condemned Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine as a &#8220;violation of the world order&#8221; but has stopped short of condemning Russia itself, which holds enormous influence in neighboring Syria, while still allowing Israel freely conduct its own operations against Tehran-backed forces there. Lavrov&rsquo;s comments may alter that relationship. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&ldquo;Israel used to be a reliable partner for Russia,&rdquo; says Yablokov. &ldquo;But they have no reason to be loyal after these remarks. So strategically, it&#8217;s a big failure.&rdquo;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6172946</post-id>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>