<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.nist.gov/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybersecurity Insights</title>
    <link>https://www.nist.gov/</link>
    <description>Cybersecurity Insights blog posts</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Application of Cybersecurity for IoT Capabilities to Real-World Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/application-cybersecurity-iot-capabilities-real-world-scenarios</link>
      <description>NIST has a history of collaboration between its programs, which helps maximize project impacts and practicality to industry. One great example is between NIST’s National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence (NCCoE) and the Cybersecurity for the Internet of Things (IoT) Program. Recent project reports from the NCCoE include mappings of relevant IoT device cybersecurity capabilities and nontechnical supporting capabilities; these three mappings align NIST’s IoT cybersecurity guidance with real-world implementation approaches: Securing Telehealth Remote Patient Monitoring Ecosystem Securing</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Jeff Marron</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1700611</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Peek at Privacy: Where We Started, Where We are Now, and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/peek-privacy-where-we-started-where-we-are-now-and-whats-next</link>
      <description>As part of NIST’s 50th anniversary of cybersecurity, this month’s blog post is centered on privacy at NIST. Since many of you have become familiar with the Privacy Engineering Program’s popular Venn diagram showing the relationship between cybersecurity and privacy risks, let’s use it to show how NIST has expanded and matured its understanding of privacy over the last 50 years. If we go back in time to the 1960s, data privacy really came into focus when the growing use of computers created concerns about secret databases of people’s information. The report, Records, Computers, and the Rights</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Meghan Anderson</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1699526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST Seeks Input on International Aspects of the Cybersecurity Framework, Other Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/nist-seeks-input-international-aspects-cybersecurity-framework-other</link>
      <description>Addressing global needs is a critical part of NIST’s work in the evolution of the Cybersecurity Framework, especially as we continue to see international adaptions and use cases to address emerging risks. Recently translated into French and Ukrainian, the Framework is now available in 10 languages, and additional translations are in the works. With a growing user base around the world, the Framework is primed for an update that draws more deeply on international viewpoints. The recently released Request for Information (RFI) on “Evaluating and Improving NIST Cybersecurity Resources: The</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Amy Mahn</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1699516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Education and Workforce Development: Employer-Driven and Learner-Centered</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-education-and-workforce-development-employer-driven-and</link>
      <description>In this installment of our 50th Anniversary of Cybersecurity series, we hear from NIST’s Rodney Petersen, Director of the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE). In this look back, Rodney offers a brief history of NICE, discusses recent advances in cybersecurity education and workforce development, and shares a few memories from around the community. In this year-long celebration of cybersecurity at NIST, we at the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) are proud to be the first to take a detailed look at some of the advances that have taken place to address</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rodney Petersen</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1697931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 50 Years of Cybersecurity at NIST!</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/celebrating-50-years-cybersecurity-nist</link>
      <description>With each day bringing new cybersecurity challenges and advances, it is easy to understand why people feel like it’s hard to keep up. It is important to be agile and move quickly to avoid the consequences of cybersecurity attacks—and that need extends to government agencies, like NIST, as we work collaboratively with industry, academia, and government to help meet these challenges. Those of us at NIST realize that we have a responsibility to keep an eye on current needs AND on potential future needs including changes in technologies and threats that could affect the ability of organizations to</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kevin Stine</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1696471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Quest: Advancing Product Labels to Help Consumers Consider Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/our-quest-advancing-product-labels-help-consumers-consider</link>
      <description>For many decades, consumers have relied on labels to help them make decisions about which products to buy. Sometimes the labels make assertions about what ingredients or components the product uses. (What’s in that peanut butter?) Other times labels claim a level of performance. (How much storage does that laptop have?) These statements may come from the manufacturer or from a third party who has reviewed and perhaps tested the product. (This appliance has been tested to meet specific electrical safety standards) Labels have assisted manufacturers and retailers to help consumers make more</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Katerina Megas, Michael Ogata</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1695631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Celebrate Data Privacy Week &amp;amp; NIST Privacy Framework’s 2nd Birthday!</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/help-celebrate-data-privacy-week-nist-privacy-frameworks-2nd-birthday</link>
      <description>Today’s blog celebrates Data Privacy Week, an international awareness initiative led by the National Cyber Security Alliance to help spread awareness about online privacy. NIST is very proud to participate again this year in this initiative that was successfully expanded from a single day event to a weeklong effort. At NIST, our NIST Privacy Engineering Program plays an integral role in establishing trustworthiness in information system technologies. This blog aims to highlight NIST’s accomplishments in the privacy field, as well as celebrate the two-year anniversary of the NIST Privacy</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Naomi Lefkovitz</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1693576</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differential Privacy: Future Work &amp;amp; Open Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/differential-privacy-future-work-open-challenges</link>
      <description>In this series of blog posts, we have tried to give an accessible overview of the state-of-the-art in differential privacy. In this final post, we review some of the open challenges in the practical use of differential privacy, and conclude with a summary of contexts where differential privacy is already ready for deployment and what comes next. Setting the Privacy Parameter The impact of the privacy parameter (or privacy budget) ε has been a consistent theme throughout this series. Conceptually, the privacy parameter is simple: smaller values of ε yield better privacy, and larger values yield</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Near, David Darais</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1692406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Topics in Consumer Cybersecurity Labeling – Our December 2021 Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/hot-topics-consumer-cybersecurity-labeling-our-december-2021-workshop</link>
      <description>On May 12, 2021 the White House released an Executive Order (EO) on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity which, among other things, tasked NIST to develop cybersecurity criteria and labeling approaches for consumer software and Internet of Things (IoT) products. Activity since then includes a call for papers, multiple workshops, draft criteria, and processing all of the feedback received. The goal of the latest workshop on December 9th was to provide the community an update, answer questions, and gather a final round of feedback which will be factored into final criteria to be released at the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Katerina Megas</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1692411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy machine learning with differential privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/how-deploy-machine-learning-differential-privacy</link>
      <description>We are delighted to introduce the final guest authors in our blog series, Nicolas Papernot and Abhradeep Thakurta, research scientists at Google Brain, whose research explores applications of differential privacy to machine learning. - Joseph Near and David Darais Previous posts in this series have explored differential privacy for traditional data analytics tasks, such as aggregate queries over database tables. What if we want to use state-of-the-art techniques like machine learning? Can we achieve differential privacy for these tasks, too? Machine learning is increasingly being used for</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Nicolas Papernot, Abhradeep Guha Thakurta</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1691106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST Launches New International Cybersecurity and Privacy Resources Website</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/nist-launches-new-international-cybersecurity-and-privacy-resources</link>
      <description>Every day, NIST cybersecurity and privacy resources are being used throughout the world to help organizations manage cybersecurity and privacy risks. To assist our international colleagues, NIST has launched a new International Cybersecurity and Privacy Resources Site. The site includes translations of the Cybersecurity Framework, including a newly published Indonesian translation. You can get more information and add to this list by reaching out to &lt;span class="spamspan"&gt;&lt;span class="u"&gt;intl-cyber-privacy&lt;/span&gt; [at] &lt;span class="d"&gt;nist.gov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Check out this site for information on upcoming international events with NIST participation, links to these</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Amy Mahn</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1690896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convergent Evolution: SP 800-213, the Federal Profile, and the IoT Cybersecurity Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/convergent-evolution-sp-800-213-federal-profile-and-iot-cybersecurity</link>
      <description>NIST has been engaged for several years in developing guidance for Internet of Things (IoT) cybersecurity. We’ve held workshops, talked with stakeholders, published drafts, listened to your feedback, refined the content and presentation of our draft guidance, and now are proud to present the updated SP 800-213 and the updated catalog of capabilities in SP 800-213A. But always remember: The goal is to manage your risk … The IoT Cybersecurity Act of 2020 stated requirements for NIST to provide guidance for federal agencies on “the appropriate use and management by agencies of [IoT] devices”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Katerina Megas</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1688211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utility Metrics for Differential Privacy: No One-Size-Fits-All</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/utility-metrics-differential-privacy-no-one-size-fits-all</link>
      <description>In previous posts we discussed different ways to implement differential privacy, each of which offers some trade-off between privacy and utility. But what does “utility” mean, and how do we know we are preserving it? To discuss this topic, we are delighted to introduce another guest author in our blog series, Claire McKay Bowen, Lead Data Scientist for Privacy and Data Security at the Urban Institute. Claire’s research focuses on assessing the quality of differentially private data synthesis methods and science communication. In 2021, the Committee of Presidents of Statistical Societies</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Claire McKay Bowen</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1688206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy-Enhancing Cryptography to Complement Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/privacy-enhancing-cryptography-complement-differential-privacy</link>
      <description>In previous posts we discussed many aspects of differential privacy: what it is, what it is useful for, and how it is applied to data analysis problems. All of those ideas can be applied once you get your hands on a whole dataset. What if the data you are interested in extracting insights from belongs to mutually distrusting organizations? For example, say you run a pumpkin spice latte stand and are wondering if your pumpkin spice supplier is overcharging you compared to the industry-wide average. You are willing to participate in a study that computes this average, but not comfortable giving</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Luís T.A.N. Brandão, René Peralta</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1686606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Awareness Month: Cybersecurity First</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-awareness-month-cybersecurity-first</link>
      <description>This week’s blog post highlighting Cybersecurity Awareness Month is from NIST’s Marian Merritt, Deputy Director and Lead for Industry Engagement for the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE). In this post, Marian discusses ways to minimize cybersecurity risks for small businesses. How did you end up at NIST working on small business cybersecurity projects? Like many in the cybersecurity industry, my career path to my current role was anything but a straight line. I began in the marketing field, working in consumer-packaged goods. It was that experience translating consumer</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Marian Merritt</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1680871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Awareness Month: Explore. Experience. Share</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-awareness-month-explore-experience-share</link>
      <description>This week’s blog post highlighting Cybersecurity Awareness Month is from NIST’s Rodney Petersen, Director of the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE). In this post, Rodney discusses Cybersecurity Career Awareness Week, a week-long campaign that inspires and promotes the exploration of cybersecurity careers. What is your job at NIST? I am the Director of the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) in the Applied Cybersecurity Division that is part of the Information Technology Lab. I am also the informal lead for the “National Cybersecurity Awareness and</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rodney Petersen</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1680671</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Awareness Month: Fight the Phish</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-awareness-month-fight-phish</link>
      <description>This week’s blog post highlighting Cybersecurity Awareness Month is from NIST’s Dr. Shaneé Dawkins, Computer Scientist in ITL’s Visualization and Usability Group. In this post, Shaneé discusses Phishing attacks and scams, as well as ways to keep your information protected. How did you end up at NIST working on cybersecurity projects? I have been a computer scientist in ITL’s Visualization and Usability Group for about 10 years conducting research on the human aspects of information technology. At the end of 2019, an opportunity was presented to join the group’s Usable Cybersecurity program and</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Shaneé Dawkins</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1680666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Awareness Month: Be Cyber Smart</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-awareness-month-be-cyber-smart</link>
      <description>This week’s blog post highlighting Cybersecurity Awareness Month kicks off our series and is from NIST’s Dave Temoshok, Senior Advisor in the Information Technology Laboratory Applied Cybersecurity Division. In this post, Dave discusses how to “Be Cyber Smart” with passwords by using Multifactor Authentication best practices. How did you end up at NIST working on cybersecurity projects? I currently serve as the Senior Advisor in the NIST Information Technology Laboratory Applied Cybersecurity Division. In general, I am responsible for digital identity management standards, guidance, and</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>David Temoshok</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1680661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Events Amplify NIST’s Cybersecurity and Privacy International Engagements</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/virtual-events-amplify-nists-cybersecurity-and-privacy-international</link>
      <description>For the past many months, NIST has taken advantage of the shift to online events to deepen our international engagement. NIST looked overseas as we kicked off our virtual Cybersecurity Risk Management webinar series in May, along with our co-hosts from the Center for Cybersecurity Policy and Law. The event on May 25 drew registrants from over 70 countries and we shared and heard perspectives on international cybersecurity risk management. The event featured a panel discussion with speakers from Microsoft, NTT, the National Cyber Security Centre Ireland, and NIST focusing on the release of</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Amy Mahn</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1680541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staff Spotlight: NIST’s Human Factors Scientist</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/staff-spotlight-nists-human-factors-scientist</link>
      <description>For years, NIST has been conducting research in the areas of human-centered design and evaluation, usable cybersecurity, public safety communication technology, augmented-reality usability, biometrics usability, human factors, and cognitive engineering. We asked Yee-Yin Choong, a Human Factors Scientist in the Visualization and Usability Group, Information Technology Laboratory at NIST about her research and experience working in this unique field. Yee-Yin’s research goal is to understand people’s perceptions, expectations, experiences, and behaviors of human-system interactions – including</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Yee-Yin Choong</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1674716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Proofs of Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/automatic-proofs-differential-privacy</link>
      <description>We are excited to introduce our fourth guest author in this blog series, Chike Abuah, PhD student in computer science at the University of Vermont, whose research expands the state of the art in the subject of this blog post: static and dynamic analysis approaches to automatic proofs of differential privacy. - Joseph Near and David Darais Previously, we have discussed some differentially private algorithms and implementation bugs which can cause these algorithms to fail to protect privacy in practice. Previous posts have described two ways of addressing this problem: automated testing and</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Chike Abuah</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1673236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IoT Non-Technical Supporting Capabilities: You Talked, We Listened</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/iot-non-technical-supporting-capabilities-you-talked-we-listened</link>
      <description>As part of our ongoing community engagement following the publication of four IoT cybersecurity draft documents in December 2020, NIST conducted a quartet of roundtable discussions in June 2021 focused on draft NISTIR 8259B, IoT Non-Technical Supporting Capability Core Baseline. The roundtables spanned four weeks, and addressed the four core capabilities defined in NISTIR 8259B as well as general discussions on applying the baseline: June 8: Documentation June 15: Information Reception and Dissemination June 22: Education and Awareness June 29: Applying the non-technical capabilities baseline</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Barbara Cuthill</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1674831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Devices Can Cause Big Problems: Improving Enterprise Mobile Device Security</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/small-devices-can-cause-big-problems-improving-enterprise-mobile-device</link>
      <description>Mobile phones—those mini-computers in our pockets—are a permanent fixture in today’s workplace. Managing and securing them is no simple task. Gema Howell, computer scientist and mobile device project lead at the National Institute of Standards and Technology’s (NIST’s) National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence (NCCoE), joined us for a recent Learning Series* webinar to discuss the challenges of enterprise mobile device security and privacy. She also shared tips for securing mobile devices. Below is a sneak peek into the discussion. You can watch the entire webinar here. Assess the Risks</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Barbara Ware</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1671466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing for Differential Privacy Bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/testing-differential-privacy-bugs</link>
      <description>We are excited to introduce our third guest author in this blog series, Dan Kifer, Professor of Computer Science at Penn State. Dr. Kifer’s research spans many topics related to differential privacy and social data, and a selection of his work represents the state of the art in the subject of this blog post: testing methods for detecting differential privacy bugs. - Joseph Near and David Darais In the last post, we learned that it is fairly easy to introduce bugs in the design and implementation of differentially private algorithms. We also learned that it can be difficult to find them. In</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Kifer</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1664246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Cyber Games Launch First-Ever US Cybersecurity Team</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/us-cyber-games-launch-first-ever-us-cybersecurity-team</link>
      <description>Many of you might know me as the director of the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE). NICE, it is a public-private partnership between academia, industry, and government that is promoting and energizing a community working together to advance an integrated ecosystem of cybersecurity education, training, and workforce development. Therefore, it should not be surprising that NICE is partnering with Katzcy, a SWaM (Small, Women-owned, and Minority-owned Business) certified Virginia firm, and others to standup the first-ever US Cyber Games competition and national team. However</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Rodney Petersen</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1664531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST Releases Tips &amp;amp; Tactics for Control System Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/nist-releases-tips-tactics-control-system-cybersecurity</link>
      <description>The impact of cybersecurity breaches on infrastructure control system owners/operators is more visible than ever before. Whether you work for an infrastructure owner/operator or are a consumer of an infrastructure service, the events of the past few months have made it clear that cybersecurity is an important factor in ensuring the safe and reliable delivery of goods and services. For infrastructure control system owners/operators, it can be challenging to address the range of cybersecurity threats, vulnerabilities and risks that can negatively impact their operations, especially with limited</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Keith Stouffer, Victoria Yan Pillitteri</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1664241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differential Privacy Bugs and Why They’re Hard to Find</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/differential-privacy-bugs-and-why-theyre-hard-find</link>
      <description>In previous posts we have explored what differential privacy is, how it works, and how to answer questions about data in ways that protect privacy. All of the algorithms we’ve discussed have been demonstrated via mathematical proof to be effective for protecting privacy. However, when translating these algorithms from paper to code, it's possible to introduce bugs in the resulting software which can result in failure to protect privacy. In this post we'll explore what these bugs typically look like, why it is so hard to detect them, and approaches to software assurance that can ensure your</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Near, David Darais</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1661326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Foundation for Interoperable and Portable Security Automation is Revealed in NIST’s OSCAL Project</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/foundation-interoperable-and-portable-security-automation-revealed</link>
      <description>Today’s blog is from Michaela Iorga, Senior Technical Lead of the Computer Security Division (CSD) in the Information Technology Laboratory at NIST. Michaela’s team at NIST is working with the industry to develop the Open Security Controls Assessment Language (OSCAL). OSCAL is a set of formats expressed in XML, JSON, and YAML. These formats provide machine-readable representations of control catalogs, control baselines, system security plans, and assessment plans and results. We asked Michaela a series of questions about the OSCAL project, which have been answered by her, below. Why was the</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Michaela Iorga</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1661431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST Cybersecurity and Privacy International Engagement Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/nist-cybersecurity-and-privacy-international-engagement-updates</link>
      <description>A lot has changed for all of us over the last year as the result of the pandemic. In the NIST Information Technology Laboratory (ITL), we have continued our international engagement in new and creative ways, leading to more robust and meaningful discussions with our stakeholders. It’s more critical than ever for NIST to work with and learn from our partners around the world, particularly in the areas of cybersecurity and privacy. We’re excited to share some updates in these areas and look forward to more collaboration in coming months! Translations of key documents often are an essential step</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Amy Mahn</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1661041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSA Conference 2021 to Showcase Resilience, Featuring NIST Experts</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/rsa-conference-2021-showcase-resilience-featuring-nist-experts</link>
      <description>RSA Conference 2021 kicks off virtually May 17, and NIST’s cybersecurity experts will be on hand out of the gate to discuss the latest in cybersecurity guidance, practical solutions, and metrics. The conference theme this year is Resilience – an especially timely theme for a world wearied by a year of pandemic. The sudden, massive uptick in working from home, distance learning, and telehealth in late March 2020 illustrated more starkly than ever before the imperative of effective cybersecurity. Widespread cyber attacks made clear the necessity of resilient networks, systems, and tools. As we</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kristina Rigopoulos</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1661106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentially Private Synthetic Data</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/differentially-private-synthetic-data</link>
      <description>In this series, we've examined several different ways to answer queries over data using differential privacy. So far each approach requires changing the way we answer queries - usually by adding noise to the answer - and modifying the tools we would normally use for analyzing data. What if we want to use existing data analysis tools, but still protect privacy? For example, the marketing department of our pumpkin spice latte company might be accustomed to exporting sales data to a spreadsheet at the end of each month to analyze sales trends using a popular spreadsheet application. They would</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Joseph Near, David Darais</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1660566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Team! Announcing the Launch of the NIST Privacy Workforce Public Working Group</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/join-team-announcing-launch-nist-privacy-workforce-public-working-group</link>
      <description>When it comes to managing privacy risks, workforce is a key consideration. According to a recent IAPP/FairWarning report, on average, even mature privacy programs have only three employees dedicated to privacy. This is why we included workforce as a priority area in the NIST Privacy Framework Roadmap. The benefits of using the Privacy Framework are enhanced when organizations have a sufficient pool of knowledgeable and skilled privacy professionals to draw from. In response to stakeholder challenges with privacy workforce recruitment and development, we are planning to create a privacy</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Dylan Gilbert</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1656946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differential Privacy for Complex Data: Answering Queries Across Multiple Data Tables</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/differential-privacy-complex-data-answering-queries-across-multiple</link>
      <description>We are excited to introduce our second guest author in this blog series, Xi He, assistant professor of Computer Science at the University of Waterloo, whose research represents the state of the art in the subject of this blog post: answering queries with joins while preserving differential privacy. - Joseph Near and David Darais So far in this blog series, we have discussed the challenges of ensuring differential privacy for queries over a single database table. In practice, however, databases are often organized into multiple tables, and queries over the data involve joins between these</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Xi He</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1655241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stakeholders: The “Be-All and End-All” of NIST’s Cybersecurity and Privacy Work</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/stakeholders-be-all-and-end-all-nists-cybersecurity-and-privacy-work</link>
      <description>When it comes down to it, NIST’s cybersecurity and privacy work is all about its stakeholders. Our researchers and other staff can do the most extraordinary work to advance the state of the art or solve problems in these areas – but our success truly should only be measured by the difference we make in providing the best possible and most useful tools and information. That’s why we put such a high premium on engaging with the public and private sectors, academia, and other stakeholders. NIST counts on developers, providers, and everyday users of cybersecurity and privacy technologies and</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kevin Stine</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1654936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIST Risk Management Framework Team Did Some Spring Cleaning!</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/nist-risk-management-framework-team-did-some-spring-cleaning</link>
      <description>Check out our new and improved Risk Management Framework (RMF) website that better highlights the resources NIST developed to support implementers. In addition to the look, we have: updated the layout of the site to focus on the RMF steps, identified specific resources and tools available for each RMF step, included supporting NIST publications for each RMF step, updated the RMF logo, and Featured resources specific to the NIST Security and Privacy Controls in Special Publication (SP) 800-53, such as: a new, web-based version of the SP 800-53, Revision 5 controls and SP 800-53B control</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Victoria Yan Pillitteri</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1654361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s Still Time to Comment on IoT Cybersecurity Guidance – Send Us Your Feedback Today!</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/theres-still-time-comment-iot-cybersecurity-guidance-send-us-your</link>
      <description>Throughout this snowy winter, NIST has been listening to the valuable feedback received on our recent flurry of IoT cybersecurity guidance drafts, including draft NISTIRs 8259B, 8259C, 8259D, and draft Special Publication 800-213. We have extended the comment deadline for all four draft publications to February 26th, and we hope reviewers will use the extra time to let us know what they think about this exciting new work. To those who have already submitted comments and reviews on the draft publications, thank you! We also want to thank everyone who participated virtually in our January 26th</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Michael Fagan</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1652781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workloads of Counting Queries: Enabling Rich Statistical Analyses with Differential Privacy</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/workloads-counting-queries-enabling-rich-statistical-analyses</link>
      <description>We are excited to introduce our first guest author in this blog series, Ryan McKenna, at University of Massachusetts at Amherst, whose research represents the state of the art in the subject of this blog post: answering workloads of statistical queries with differential privacy. - Joseph Near and David Darais To date, this series focused on relatively simple data analyses, such as learning one summary statistic about our data at a time. In reality, we’re often interested in a slightly more sophisticated analysis, so we can learn multiple trends and takeaways at once and paint a richer picture</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Ryan McKenna</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1651751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021: What’s Ahead from NIST in Cybersecurity and Privacy?</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/2021-whats-ahead-nist-cybersecurity-and-privacy</link>
      <description>In 2020, NIST prioritized helping individuals and organizations shift to a more online environment to keep people safe and our economy productive. Despite the many challenges brought by the pandemic, we were fortunate to be able to continue our work on an array of new resources to help manage cybersecurity and privacy risks. As NIST looks ahead to the “new normal,” we plan to build on lessons learned during the pandemic and to be even more strategic in anticipating and tackling the many challenges ahead. We’ve made New Year’s resolutions: to increase our attention on managing cybersecurity</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kevin Stine</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1650761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy First Birthday, NIST Privacy Framework!</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/happy-first-birthday-nist-privacy-framework</link>
      <description>Grab a cupcake or several—no judgment—and join us in celebrating the first birthday of the NIST Privacy Framework! Here at NIST, we feel like proud parents supporting the framework’s implementation over the past year, listening to all the amazing things stakeholders have to say, and learning from the organizations who are already using it. We have lots of “gifts” for you, our stakeholders, so read on to learn all about them! One Year with the Privacy Framework Like everyone, we can’t say good-bye fast enough to 2020, but there’s no doubt that the attention that the framework has been getting</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Naomi Lefkovitz</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1649501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Insights Blog: Year-In-Review 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/cybersecurity-insights-blog-year-review-2020</link>
      <description>We can all agree that 2020 has been a year we won’t forget anytime soon. Faced with unanticipated challenges, new concerns, and constant adjustments forced by the global pandemic, we were compelled to rethink the ways in which we work, study, and socialize. In many cases, this meant transferring day-to-day activities to an online environment, which pushed organizations of every kind to re-examine their approaches to cybersecurity. A positive note is that these changes presented a prime opportunity to highlight the criticality of cybersecurity and promote increased awareness and best practices</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Kristina Rigopoulos</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nist.gov/node/1647051</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>