<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.zimperium.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://blog.zimperium.com</link>
    <description>
    </description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:15:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>The Increase in Mobile Wallet Adoption Impacts the Need for Security</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/the-increase-in-mobile-wallet-adoption-impacts-the-need-for-security%ef%bf%bc/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tim Hartog]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 22:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[App Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[financial mobile app security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MAPS]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile app protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10132</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The use of mobile payments is on the rise! According to industry data, mobile wallets are used by more than two billion people globally, with many millions more adopting mobile payments every year. In 2021 a total of 25.7% of Point of Sale (POS) payments were performed using mobile wallets [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/the-increase-in-mobile-wallet-adoption-impacts-the-need-for-security%ef%bf%bc/">The Increase in Mobile Wallet Adoption Impacts the Need for Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>The use of mobile payments is on the rise! According to <a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/data/mobile-payments-app-market/">industry data</a>, mobile wallets are used by more than two billion people globally, with many millions more adopting mobile payments every year. In <a href="https://www.emizentech.com/blog/mobile-payment-statistics-facts.html">2021</a> a total of 25.7% of Point of Sale (POS) payments were performed using mobile wallets and 44.5% of eCommerce transactions were performed using mobile wallets, increasingly replacing cash and contact-based payments.</p>
<p>The pandemic only accelerated the adoption of <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/mobile-payments/">mobile wallets.</a> But this increased adoption has also gotten the attention of attackers and criminal organizations and heightens the need for robust, state of the art, application security.</p>
<h3>What are mobile wallets?</h3>
<p>Mobile wallets enable consumers to use their smartphone, smartwatch, and other smart wearables (e.g. ring, bracelets) to make contactless payments over NFC<sup>1</sup>, MST<sup>2</sup>, and QR codes. Often mobile wallets also offer related functionality such as membership and loyalty cards, gift cards, peer-to-peer payments, and in-app payments.</p>
<p>Since the introduction of Apple Pay and Google Pay in 2014, many banks and fintech companies worldwide have introduced mobile wallets. While Apple has not enabled third-party developers to use <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2022/02/apple-unveils-contactless-payments-via-tap-to-pay-on-iphone/">NFC on its iPhones</a>, Google has. This led to a wide development of mobile wallet solutions for Android by dozens of technology providers and banks.</p>
<p>In practice, there are two types of mobile wallets:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>OEM (Original Equipment Manufacturer) wallets:</strong> These mobile wallets are produced by the smartphone vendor and secured by the proprietary hardware security technology (e.g. <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/searchitoperations/definition/trusted-execution-environment-TEE">Trusted Execution Environment</a> or <a href="https://encyclopedia.kaspersky.com/glossary/secure-element/">Secure Element</a>) on the device itself.</li>
<li><strong>Third-party wallets:</strong> Third-party apps, like PayPal, do not have access to the proprietary hardware security technology on the device. Third-party mobile wallet developers include both technology providers which typically provide payment software development kits (e.g. a HCE<sup>3</sup>, SDK) and parties that have integrated payment SDKs (Software Development Kits) in the final mobile payment application.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Are mobile wallets secure?</h3>
<p>In order to reduce the risk of fraud, HCE mobile wallets use <i>tokenization</i>. Tokenization is a process where sensitive information, e.g. the credit card details such as the PAN<sup>4</sup>, is replaced with a token. A token is a randomized sequence of numbers that can be limited in the way it’s used — for example, the number of times it&#8217;s used and the payment amount for which it&#8217;s used.</p>
<p>While HCE and tokenization are designed to reduce the risk of fraud, mobile wallets still process payment data which can be abused by malware and criminal organizations to perform payment fraud. Though payment tokens can’t be reverse-engineered back to your credit card number, theft of these payment tokens enables criminals to perform fraudulent payments at the expense of legitimate mobile wallet holders.</p>
<h3>The future of mobile payment security</h3>
<p>As with cash, checks, and cards, mobile wallets are subject to fraud and abuse. With the increased adoption of mobile wallets and the non-stop growth of using smartphones for everything and payment purposes in general, mobile wallets are becoming an increasingly attractive target for attackers. This trend is also clearly visible in the increase of exploited <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/">zero-day mobile vulnerabilities</a>, up 466% in 2021, and the vast and growing amount of mobile malware with over 2 million new strains in 2021.</p>
<p>In order to secure mobile wallets, Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs) have the option of using hardware security capabilities as mentioned above. But for third-party mobile wallet developers, this isn’t a viable option as a result of fragmentation in OEM technology and limitations OEMs place on using the platform security capabilities. Secondly, reality has shown that the OEM platform technologies, like Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs) embedded in smartphones, are subject to attacks with a continuous flow of reported zero-day vulnerabilities and exploits.</p>
<p>As smartphones continue to be untrusted devices, mobile wallet solution developers need to protect the mobile wallet application and keep their security posture up-to-date and ahead of the continuously evolving attacker capabilities and attacker tooling.</p>
<h3>How Zimperium enables mobile wallet security</h3>
<p>Before launching for public use, mobile payment solutions must be certified by the card brands (Visa/MasterCard) or <a href="https://www.emvco.com/processes-forms/product-approval/mobile/sbmp/">EMVCo</a>. Zimperium’s Mobile Application Protection Suite  <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/mobile-app-protection/">(MAPS)</a> helps mobile payment solution developers to build secure and compliant mobile applications, and get your app security certified and ready to be published quickly.</p>
<p>MAPS takes a holistic view of mobile application security, by helping your developers find and <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/mobile-payments/">fix compliance</a>, privacy, and security issues before the app is released, <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/zkeybox/">protecting your cryptographic keys</a> and tokens so they can’t be extracted or stolen, keeping your source code and data safe from hackers, and protecting your apps from advanced attacks once they’re on the market. Delays in deployment are a critical stumbling block, and with Zimperium on your side, you can be confident that you’ll get it right the first time.</p>
<p>While security is a continuous cat and mouse game, Zimperium MAPS provides proven and ongoing protection for your mobile applications, even against the newest attacks and attacker tools.</p>
<h3>About Zimperium</h3>
<p>Zimperium, Inc. is a global leader in mobile device and app security. The Zimperium Mobile Application Protection Suite (MAPS) helps enterprises build safe and secure mobile apps resistant to attacks. It is the only unified platform that combines comprehensive in-app protection with centralized threat visibility. The platform provides app shielding, key protection, app scanning, and runtime protection capabilities. <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/">Contact us today</a> to learn how to secure mobile wallets.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>1 Near Field Communication or NFC is a technology which allows two devices to communicate over the air in close proximity.</em></p>
<p><em>2 Magnetic Secure Transmission or MST is a technology where a magnetic field is generated in order to mimic the magnetic stripe on a credit card.</em></p>
<p><em>3 Host Card Emulation or HCE is a technology used in the payment industry to virtualize credit card information in software. Prior to HCE, payment transactions were mainly performed using Secure Elements (e.g. the physical chip on a debit or credit card).</em></p>
<p><em>4 Primary Account Number or PAN is the unique sequence of digits (typically 14 to 19 digits) printed on a credit card.</em></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/the-increase-in-mobile-wallet-adoption-impacts-the-need-for-security%ef%bf%bc/">The Increase in Mobile Wallet Adoption Impacts the Need for Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quadrant Knowledge Solutions Names Zimperium The Leader in In-App Protection</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/quadrant-knowledge-solutions-names-zimperium-the-leader-in-in-app-protection/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[JT Keating]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 12:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[App Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MAPS]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile app protection]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10123</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Quadrant Knowledge Solutions, a global advisory and consulting firm, recently published its “SPARK Matrix: In-App Protection, 2022” report and ​​named Zimperium as the 2022 technology leader. The report offers a look at the way the in-app protection segment has evolved, outlining some of the key market drivers and technology trends. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/quadrant-knowledge-solutions-names-zimperium-the-leader-in-in-app-protection/">Quadrant Knowledge Solutions Names Zimperium The Leader in In-App Protection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p><a href="https://quadrant-solutions.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quadrant Knowledge Solutions</a>, a global advisory and consulting firm, recently published its “<a href="https://get.zimperium.com/quadrant-spark-matrix/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SPARK Matrix: In-App Protection, 2022</a>” report and ​​named Zimperium as the 2022 technology leader. The report offers a look at the way the in-app protection segment has evolved, outlining some of the key market drivers and technology trends. In addition, it provides an extensive examination of the competitive landscape, detailing the vendors and offerings in the space, and ultimately ranking them in the form of SPARK Matrix<sup>TM</sup>.</p>
<p>The report’s authors used a range of evaluation criteria, which are categorized into two key areas: technology excellence and customer impact. The technology excellence category includes such factors as sophistication, competitive differentiation, application diversity, and scalability. On the customer impact side, key categories include market presence, proven record, and customer service excellence.</p>
<p>We’re very pleased to report that Zimperium came out on top in this report. It is particularly gratifying to see our solutions get this validation and rate so highly in both technology excellence and customer impact.</p>
<blockquote><p>With its comprehensive functional capabilities, compelling technology differentiation, and robust customer value proposition, Zimperium is well-positioned to maintain and grow its market share amongst mid-market to large enterprise segments. – Quadrant Knowledge Solutions</p></blockquote>
<p>Ayush Patidar, an analyst at Quadrant Knowledge Solutions, said, “Zimperium Mobile Application Protection Suite (MAPS) offers a holistic approach to protect mobile applications on various mobile devices, enabling real-time threat visibility as well as the capacity to respond to emerging threats and attacks.”</p>
<p>Patidar continued, “Zimperium’s end-to-end application protection offers app scanning, app shielding, runtime protection, and the protection of sensitive cryptographic keys through one platform. The company, with its continued focus to develop broader and deeper attack coverage, comprehensive functional capabilities, compelling customer references, and user-specific customized solutions, has received strong ratings across the parameters of technology excellence and customer impact.”</p>
<blockquote><p>The COVID-19 pandemic-induced disrupted business scenarios, growth in remote working, and increased risk arising out of factors such as an unprecedented rise in unsecured BYOD, WYOD, and IoT devices across enterprises, and the pressure to comply with ever-stringent and the growing complexities of the global regulatory environment, including data privacy norms is driving significant investment in In-App Protection solutions. – Quadrant Knowledge Solutions</p></blockquote>
<p>To contend with the increased vulnerabilities of mobile apps, and the escalating threats of cyber attacks, teams need to employ advanced mobile app protection. This recent report from Quadrant Knowledge Solutions offers a compelling illustration of why so many security teams are turning to Zimperium and its MAPS solutions. <a href="https://get.zimperium.com/quadrant-spark-matrix/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Click here</a> to download the “SPARK Matrix: In-App Protection, 2022” report and learn more.</p>
<h3>About Zimperium</h3>
<p>Zimperium, Inc. is a global leader in mobile device and app security. The Zimperium Mobile Application Protection Suite (MAPS) helps enterprises build safe and secure mobile apps resistant to attacks. It is the only unified platform that combines comprehensive in-app protection with centralized threat visibility. The platform provides app shielding, key protection, app scanning, and runtime protection capabilities. For more information or to schedule a demo, <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contact us</a> today.</p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/quadrant-knowledge-solutions-names-zimperium-the-leader-in-in-app-protection/">Quadrant Knowledge Solutions Names Zimperium The Leader in In-App Protection</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Browser Extension Malware</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/the-state-of-browser-extension-malware/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nipun Gupta]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 18:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Chromebooks]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Threat Research]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile malware]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[threat research]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10091</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>It is time for us to change how we think about malware. No longer is it limited to one specific operating system or device type. Like with phishing attacks, malware developers have been working on malware that can impact a broader range of systems to increase the number of potential [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/the-state-of-browser-extension-malware/">The State of Browser Extension Malware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>It is time for us to change how we think about malware. No longer is it limited to one specific operating system or device type. Like with phishing attacks, malware developers have been working on malware that can impact a broader range of systems to increase the number of potential victims of their malicious campaigns. Web browsers have become very lucrative and effective attack surfaces enabling these threat actors&#8217; ability to execute code within the application itself as extensions, keeping malicious activity out of the eyes of a majority of endpoint security tools.</p>
<p>Web browsers are treasure troves of personal and private information, especially since most sensitive data processed on a device, like credit card info and passwords, pass through the web experience. This fact alone has driven a significant increase in the number of malicious browser extensions detected in the wild, targeting unsuspecting victims in consumer and enterprise settings.</p>
<p>Once installed, these malicious extensions can steal cookies or credentials, capture keystrokes, mine cryptocurrencies on the victim&#8217;s device, inject malicious javascript code to web pages, or even use browser exploits to drop malware on the victim&#8217;s device.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/6-real-world-threats-to-chromebooks-and-chromeos/">SentinelOne research</a>, browser extensions were one of the six real-world threats to Chromebook and ChromeOS. The Zimperium zLabs team has classified thousands of malicious browser extension samples hosted in multiple repositories and stores using various dynamic and static reverse engineering methods. The pieces covered in this blog were present in third-party extension stores and not present in any official Chrome repository.</p>
<p>During our research we found that the most common categories for undesirable extensions are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spyware</li>
<li>JavaScript Injector</li>
<li>Potentially unwanted applications (PUA)</li>
<li>Adware</li>
<li>Miner</li>
<li>Browser Modifier</li>
<li>Fake Ad Blocker</li>
</ul>
<p>The distribution of these families is shown in the figure below:</p>
<figure id="attachment_10095" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10095" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware.png"><img class="wp-image-10095 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware-1024x633.png" alt="Figure 1: Classification of malware" width="1024" height="633" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware-1024x633.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware-300x186.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware-768x475.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/figure_1_Classification_of_malware.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10095" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 1: Classification of malware</figcaption></figure>
<p>Adware and spyware account for the most common malware families, with 11 out of the top 15 discovered falling into one of those two. Other families were JavaScript Injectors, potentially unwanted applications (PUA), and Browser modifiers.</p>
<p>If we include some subfamilies for each category, the family distribution is shown in Figure 2.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">TOP MALWARE FAMILIES OF CHROME EXTENSIONS</h3>
<figure id="attachment_10096" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10096" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10096 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families-1024x513.png" alt="Figure 2: Top malware families" width="1024" height="513" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families-1024x513.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families-300x150.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families-768x385.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_2_Top_malware_families.png 1480w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10096" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 2: Top malware families</figcaption></figure>
<h4>Fake Ad Blockers</h4>
<p>Ad blockers are one common extension in the Chrome web store, promising to disable ads on websites and improve the web browsing experience. Many fake ad blockers are clones of legitimate, open-source ad blockers but with additional code inserted to serve a malicious purpose, commonly delivered through third-party extension stores. Some ad blockers are loaded with crypto mining or cookie stuffing for monetary purposes.</p>
<p>In affiliate marketing, a third-party website places ads for the product on their website. When users click on the ad and make a purchase, the third-party website earns a commission for that purchase. They can also earn a commission if the user closes that website after that redirect and makes a purchase later using the same browser. Whenever a user is redirected from an ad to the product website, it drops a cookie on the user&#8217;s browser, giving the affiliate marketer credit for the traffic (Figure 3). While affiliate marketing is a legitimate concept, cookie-stuffing is a process where these fake ad blockers redirect users to the website to drop cookies without the user&#8217;s knowledge to generate revenue for the extension developer.</p>
<p>Figure 4 shows an example of a redirection chain and cooking stuffing for an extension targeting <strong>aliexpress.com.</strong> From a technical point of view, the affiliate cookies are dropped to the victim’s browser using the Set-Cookie response header in the HTTP request <i>(Figure 5)</i>. If the user later visits the target website and completes a qualifying transaction (such as making a purchase), the malicious party is paid a commission.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10097" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10097" style="width: 782px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_3_CookieStuffing.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10097 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_3_CookieStuffing.png" alt="Figure 3: CookieStuffing" width="782" height="124" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_3_CookieStuffing.png 782w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_3_CookieStuffing-300x48.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_3_CookieStuffing-768x122.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10097" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 3: CookieStuffing</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_10098" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10098" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10098 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain-1024x134.png" alt="Figure 4: Redirection Chain" width="1024" height="134" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain-1024x134.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain-300x39.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain-768x101.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain-1536x201.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_4_Redirection_Chain.png 1786w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10098" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 4: Redirection Chain</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_10099" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10099" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10099 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response-1024x375.png" alt="Figure 5: Set-Cookie Header in HTTP Response" width="1024" height="375" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response-1024x375.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response-300x110.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response-768x282.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response-1536x563.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_5_Set_Cookie_Header_in_HTTP_Response.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10099" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 5: Set-Cookie Header in HTTP Response</figcaption></figure>
<h4>Spyware</h4>
<p>Spyware is a problem on all devices, from mobile to traditional endpoints, often relying on complicated malware and exploits. On traditional endpoints, spyware is usually surveilling users by accessing the camera and microphone, as well as monitoring web and communication activity. But spyware built into browser extensions can bypass traditional security layers, are less difficult to build and provide direct access to browser content &#8211; including unencrypted browser traffic. The spyware extensions are generally designed to steal cookies and credentials for various websites such as <a href="https://chromeunboxed.com/four-chrome-extensions-malicious-facebook-sues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/17/h/malicous-chrome-extensions-stealing-roblox-game-currency-sending-cookies-via-discord.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Roblox</a>, and <a href="https://thehackernews.com/2020/04/chrome-cryptocurrency-extensions.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crypto Wallets</a>. These types of spyware are often called Infostealers.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10100" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10100" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10100 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware-1024x632.png" alt="Figure 6: Classification of Spyware" width="1024" height="632" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware-1024x632.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware-300x185.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware-768x474.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_6_Classification_of_Spyware.png 1442w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10100" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 6: Classification of Spyware</figcaption></figure>
<p>One example of spyware is a Fake Google Translate extension ( identifier:hemlmgggokggmncimchkllhcjcaimcle) designed to steal a victim’s Facebook data. The name and icon of this extension are replaced with that of Google Translate to fool victims into believing that this is a legitimate extension (Figure 7). But analysis of the source code reveals its true intention as spyware.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10101" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10101" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10101 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware-1024x437.png" alt="Figure 7: Extension: hemlmgggokggmncimchkllhcjcaimcle(Fake Google Translate) spyware" width="1024" height="437" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware-1024x437.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware-300x128.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware-768x328.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_7_Extension_Fake_Google_Translate_spyware.png 1358w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10101" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 7: Extension: hemlmgggokggmncimchkllhcjcaimcle(Fake Google Translate) spyware</figcaption></figure>
<p>Figure 8 shows how this extension overrides the favicon, the broad set of permissions requested, and how the description is crafted to mimic Google Translate one.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10102" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10102" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10102 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description-1024x555.png" alt="Figure 8: manifest.json highlighting the name and fake description." width="1024" height="555" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description-1024x555.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description-300x163.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description-768x416.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description-1536x832.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_8_manifest_json_highlighting_the_name_and_fake_description.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10102" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 8: manifest.json highlighting the name and fake description.</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>manifest.json</strong> has the background variable with the page <strong>background.html</strong>, which includes background.js (Figure 9). The extension collects all the cookies in variable <strong>_0xd560x21</strong>, then converts it to JSON and encrypts it before sending it over to the C&amp;C.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10103" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10103 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js-1024x651.png" alt="Figure 9: background.js" width="1024" height="651" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js-1024x651.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js-300x191.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js-768x488.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js-1536x977.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_9_background_js.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10103" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 9: background.js</figcaption></figure>
<h4>Potentially Unwanted Applications (PUA)</h4>
<p>PUAs are programs that degrade user experience by displaying ads, redirecting web pages, using computer resources, tracking users, and more. Typically less malicious than other threats, these extensions are installed along with some OS applications. Many of the PUA extensions range from <strong>Toolbars</strong> to <strong>New-tab pages</strong>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10104" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10104" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10104 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar-1024x153.png" alt="Figure 10: ask.com toolbar" width="1024" height="153" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar-1024x153.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar-300x45.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar-768x115.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar-1536x229.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_10_ask_com_toolbar.png 1876w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10104" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 10: ask.com toolbar</figcaption></figure>
<p>Figure 10, shows the Ask Toolbar installed and some versions of Java setup (Figure 11). This toolbar statically binds itself on all the web pages a user visits.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10105" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10105" style="width: 498px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_11_Java_setup.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10105 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_11_Java_setup.jpg" alt="Figure 11: Java setup" width="498" height="386" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_11_Java_setup.jpg 498w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_11_Java_setup-300x233.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 498px) 100vw, 498px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10105" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 11: Java setup</figcaption></figure>
<h4>JavaScript Injectors</h4>
<p>JavaScript Injector malware injects its malicious javascript code into the web pages a victim visits. This injected Javascript can steal tokens, cookies, payment information, and passwords that are entered on any website. They can also inject malicious or deceiving ads on a webpage.</p>
<p>Javascript Injectors use more sophisticated techniques like <strong>steganography</strong> to smuggle malicious code inside images to evade perimeter tools such as web gateways and content filters. Figure 12 shows the manifest file of one example of such extensions.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10106" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file-.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10106 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file--1024x400.png" alt="Figure 12: manifest.json file" width="1024" height="400" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file--1024x400.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file--300x117.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file--768x300.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file--1536x600.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_12_manifest_json_file-.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10106" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 12: manifest.json file</figcaption></figure>
<p>Here the permissions include <strong>cookies</strong>, the web_accessible_resources are <strong>a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</strong> , <strong>tyutsfffr.js</strong>, and <strong>background.js</strong>, and the content_script is <strong>tyutsfffr.js</strong>. The code which injects malicious code to a webpage is located in the file t<strong>yutsfffr.js</strong>.</p>
<p>The image <strong>a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</strong> (Figure 13) has embedded the data shown in Figure 14. The injected code is used to collect Amazon searches and redirect Yahoo searches and other booking websites.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10107" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10107" style="width: 460px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_13_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10107 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_13_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png" alt="Figure 13:: a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png" width="460" height="446" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_13_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png 460w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_13_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-300x291.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 460px) 100vw, 460px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10107" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 13:: a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_10108" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10108" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10108 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-1024x585.png" alt="Figure 14: hex dump of a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png" width="1024" height="585" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-1024x585.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-300x171.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-768x439.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_14_hex_dump_of_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10108" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 14: hex dump of a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_10109" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10109" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10109 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js-1024x985.png" alt="Figure 15: tyutsfffr.js" width="1024" height="985" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js-1024x985.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js-300x289.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js-768x739.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js-1536x1478.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_15_tyutsfffr_js.png 1846w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10109" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 15: tyutsfffr.js</figcaption></figure>
<p>The malicious javascript code is hidden in image pixels and then passed to <strong>eval</strong> (in the run function). After decrypting the <strong>a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</strong> using the LoadPNGData process (Figure 15), the actual code results in the following unpacked JavaScript (Figure 16)</p>
<figure id="attachment_10110" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10110" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10110 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-1024x126.png" alt="Figure 16: decrypted code from a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png" width="1024" height="126" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-1024x126.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-300x37.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72-768x94.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_16_decrypted_code_from_a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png 1514w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10110" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 16: decrypted code from a548b2c2c8464aeaefad60db73ed6b72.png</figcaption></figure>
<p>After several redirections, the end URL is <strong>https[://]worksrc.cool/dd906ff71a73923712.js</strong>, which contains the malicious code (Figure 16). The analysis of the malicious code is beyond the scope of this blog post.</p>
<h4>Miners / CryptoJackers</h4>
<p><strong>Cryptojacking</strong> uses CPU and other resources on the victim&#8217;s personal computers, laptops, and mobile devices to mine cryptocurrencies. These are more commonly found in binaries such as cracked or downloaded applications, which are moving into leveraging extensions to gain access to CPU and memory resources.</p>
<p>Below is one example; this extension appears to be a simple clock, but it mines cryptocurrency on the user&#8217;s personal computer, using resources until the last browser tab is closed.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10111" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10111" style="width: 858px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_17_Miner_Extension.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10111 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_17_Miner_Extension.png" alt="Figure 17: Miner Extension" width="858" height="560" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_17_Miner_Extension.png 858w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_17_Miner_Extension-300x196.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_17_Miner_Extension-768x501.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 858px) 100vw, 858px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10111" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 17: Miner Extension</figcaption></figure>
<p>The below code is injected into the <strong>background.js</strong> file and renders a clock that the user may find valuable. In the background, It uses <strong>Coinhive</strong> service to mine <strong>monero</strong> on browser tabs and in the background.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10112" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10112" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10112 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js-1024x293.png" alt="Figure 18: background.js" width="1024" height="293" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js-1024x293.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js-300x86.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js-768x220.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js-1536x440.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_18_background_js.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10112" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 18: background.js</figcaption></figure>
<h4>Adware</h4>
<p>Adware is malware that automatically shows advertisements that malicious actors can profit from. In browser extensions, adware comes in many forms, and the most common versions of adware have the capability to:</p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Replace the default search engine with their own and display searches on the affiliated web pages that display ads and search results.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Inject ads/popups on all the web pages a user visits.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Inject clickunder ads in the current browser sessions. They usually redirect to the affiliated web pages as soon as a user clicks on the website that has been injected with clickunder ads.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Directly redirect a Google, Yandex, Bing, Yahoo search to the affiliated web pages.</li>
</ul>
<p>Figure 19 shows one such example of adware taking over the search page to show its own ads. When users use Google to search for anything, this extension adds advertisements with affiliated links.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10113" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10113" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10113 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed-1024x647.png" alt="Figure 19: Search results for “laptop” when the extension is installed" width="1024" height="647" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed-1024x647.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed-300x190.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed-768x486.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed-1536x971.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_19_Search_results_for_laptop_when_the_extension_is_installed.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10113" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 19: Search results for “laptop” when the extension is installed</figcaption></figure>
<h4>Browser Modifiers</h4>
<p>Browser Modifiers are types of extensions that change the general settings of browsers. As shown below (Figure 20), these settings are usually omnibox search engines or new tab pages, and even home pages of browsers. Some of these extensions change the font and appearance of the browser and display ads on additional tabs, as well as change the default new tab page to a compromised search engine home page. These can also act as redirectors to suspicious websites or even track the search results for their victims.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10114" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10114" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10114 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page-1024x363.png" alt="Figure 20: Inserted ads appearing on a search page." width="1024" height="363" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page-1024x363.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page-300x106.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page-768x272.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page-1536x544.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_Inserted_ads_appearing_on_a_search_page.png 1620w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10114" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 20: Inserted ads appearing on a search page.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Figure 21 shows the manifest of one of these extensions. In this case, it uses “chrome_url_override” to replace the newtab.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10115" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10115" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10115 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json-1024x543.png" alt="Figure 21: manifest.json" width="1024" height="543" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json-1024x543.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json-300x159.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json-768x407.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json-1536x814.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_20_manifest_json.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10115" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 21: manifest.json</figcaption></figure>
<p>After this modification, a new tab shows ads on the search page as shown previously on Figure 20. Furthermore, the icons shown in the new tab are mimicking those of legit apps such as Google Maps to trick users into clicking on them (Figure 22).</p>
<figure id="attachment_10116" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10116" style="width: 922px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_22_Logo_of_Google_Maps.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10116 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_22_Logo_of_Google_Maps.png" alt="Figure 22: Logo of Google Maps" width="922" height="84" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_22_Logo_of_Google_Maps.png 922w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_22_Logo_of_Google_Maps-300x27.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_22_Logo_of_Google_Maps-768x70.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 922px) 100vw, 922px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10116" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 22: Logo of Google Maps</figcaption></figure>
<p>However, the icons are not using any legitimate service. They are redirecting to a website crafted by the malicious actor to increase profit by exposing the user to more ads. An example of this is shown in Figure 23, in which a basic map is shown (redirected from a fake Google Maps icon) but with ads next to it.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10117" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10117" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10117 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left-1024x683.png" alt="Figure 23: Maps page with injected ads on the left." width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left-1024x683.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left-300x200.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left-768x512.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left-1536x1024.png 1536w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Figure_23_Maps_page_with_injected_ads_on_the_left.png 1999w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10117" class="wp-caption-text">Figure 23: Maps page with injected ads on the left.</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Summary</h3>
<p>Malicious actors will continue to use novel ways to evade traditional desktop and gateway security solutions to achieve financially motivated goals. Browser extensions can be installed in the same way as applications by unsuspecting users looking to solve problems or add value to their computing experience. This constantly evolving threat landscape indicates the need for a robust and more innovative way of detection instead of blocklisting IOCs.</p>
<p>Users should be trained on the risks associated with browser extensions, especially when sideloaded outside of official repositories, and enterprises should be considering what security controls they have in place for such risks.</p>
<p>As we consider risk assessment for applications on traditional and modern operating systems, enterprises must consider how they evaluate and assess risk associated with new and emerging threats.&nbsp; Zimperium is committed to assisting enterprises in assessing and solving modern endpoint security problems.</p>
<h3>About Zimperium</h3>
<p>Zimperium, the global leader in mobile security, offers the only real-time, on-device, machine learning-based protection against Android, iOS, and Chromebook threats. Powered by z9, Zimperium provides protection against device, network, phishing, and malicious app attacks. For more information or to schedule a demo, contact us today.</p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/the-state-of-browser-extension-malware/">The State of Browser Extension Malware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Mobile App Security: Key Takeaways from 2022 Threat Report</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/state-of-mobile-app-security-key-takeaways-from-2022-threat-report/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Krishna Vishnubhotla]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[App Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Threat Research]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[app security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile app security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile application security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[threat report]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10075</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few years, a major shift has occurred in how we use mobile devices and apps. Fundamentally, we continue to use our smartphones more and more. In the process, mobile apps continue to collect more sensitive personal and corporate data, while at the same time, mobile apps continue [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/state-of-mobile-app-security-key-takeaways-from-2022-threat-report/">The State of Mobile App Security: Key Takeaways from 2022 Threat Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>Over the last few years, a major shift has occurred in how we use mobile devices and apps. Fundamentally, we continue to use our smartphones more and more. In the process, mobile apps continue to collect more sensitive personal and corporate data, while at the same time, mobile apps continue to get more vulnerable. <a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-10050 alignright" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px.jpeg" alt="" width="306" height="396" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px.jpeg 396w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px-232x300.jpeg 232w" sizes="(max-width: 306px) 100vw, 306px" /></a></p>
<p>We’ve recently published our 2022 Global Mobile Threat Report, which offers extensive insights into the challenges today’s application security teams are confronting.</p>
<p>In this blog post, we’ll highlight some of the key takeaways from the report, specifically focusing on mobile application security. We will take a look at how usage and vulnerabilities are evolving and outline some of the key implications for enterprise security teams.</p>
<h3>Mobile Apps: Massive Growth in Usage and Exposure</h3>
<p>Today, the scope of the mobile app market is massive. In 2020, there were more than 218 billion app downloads.<sup>1</sup> By 2023, mobile apps are expected to generate annual revenue in excess of $935 billion, and apps in such areas as video streaming, gaming, and online fitness are all netting billions of dollars in revenue.<sup>2</sup></p>
<p>Further, our usage of mobile phones for payments accounts for even larger revenues. In 2020, the mobile payments segment accounted for $1.3 trillion globally, and revenues were expected to climb to $1.7 trillion in 2021.<sup>3</sup> Over the past several years, Android and iOS phones have begun to be used as point-of-sale (PoS) terminals, creating a major spike in contactless payment adoption and usage.</p>
<p>Mobile applications have come to impact just about every aspect of our lives, from how we think about managing our health and wellness to how we consume digital and physical goods.</p>
<p>Plus, it isn’t just the frequency but the way we’re using mobile apps that is changing. It wasn’t too long ago that our smartphones were for personal use, and our corporate laptops were for work. Today, it is safe to say those boundaries have blurred into oblivion. Within enterprises, continued innovations in mobile applications play an integral role in digital transformation and most any other strategic initiative or service.</p>
<p>For enterprise security teams, these shifts have fundamental, massive implications—implications for which many teams aren’t prepared to contend.</p>
<h3>Evolving Development Approaches: The Benefits and Risks</h3>
<p>In their quest to accelerate innovation in the mobile application arena, teams continue to evolve their development approaches. Following are a few examples:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Low-code and no-code approaches.</strong> To speed development and reduce the reliance on limited development expertise, teams continue to shift to no-code and low-code approaches. In the process, development is increasingly moving from writing code to assembling and integrating open-source and third-party components.</li>
<li><strong>Hybrid apps.</strong> Teams are employing hybrid app approaches, which enables them to manage a single code base that can run on both Android and iOS.</li>
<li><strong>Progressive web applications.</strong> Through these approaches, teams can evolve their web apps so they look and function like native mobile apps, while also affording teams the ability to work with a single code base.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, while these approaches offer powerful benefits in efficiency and agility, they also present significant hurdles for the teams looking to secure data and code. For example, many hybrid apps lack critical software development kits (SDKs) and other tools required for securing code effectively. Also, without the proper mechanisms in place, the ease of leveraging external, open-source components can just as easily introduce a number of exploitable vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>The upshot is that the focus on speeding time to market has resulted in an exponentially larger attack surface and significant supply chain risk. Apps contain more third-party code, process more sensitive data, and access more critical enterprise infrastructure than ever before. For all these reasons, resource-constrained app security teams struggle to keep pace and scale.</p>
<h3>The Risks Posed by Emerging Technologies</h3>
<p>While security teams have their hands full, several factors are serving to increase the pressure:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>5G.</strong> In recent years, mobile device usage has grown dramatically, and therefore the volume of sensitive data being collected and shared continues to see explosive growth as well. The increasing rollout of 5G communications networks will only accelerate and magnify this proliferation. These networks are capable of delivering higher data transfer speeds with lower latency. By the end of 2024, it is predicted that 5G will handle 25% of all mobile data traffic.<sup>4</sup> The result? Even more sensitive data being collected, transmitted, and stored gives cybercriminals even more data to target.</li>
<li><strong>Misconfigured cloud services.</strong> In an investigation into 23 mobile apps, researchers found that data of more than 100 million users was exposed.<sup>5</sup> How? Developers failed to configure their third-party cloud services properly. Based on our analysis of more than 1.3 million Android and iOS apps, we found that 131,000 used public cloud services in their backend, and 14% of those apps had misconfigurations that exposed users’ personal information.<sup>6</sup></li>
<li><strong>QR codes.</strong> Initially unveiled in the 1990s, QR Codes aren’t new—however, their usage grew dramatically in recent years, particularly as consumers and businesses adapted to the pandemic. Given this growth in usage, cybercriminals have taken note. In order to steal a victim’s financial information or other sensitive data, these threat actors are tampering with or deploying their own QR codes and compromising devices through the use of malicious applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>The insights above give you a glimpse of the extensive findings offered in the&nbsp;2022 Global Mobile Threat Report. Read our threat report to understand the evolving mobile app security landscape and gain key insights into how you can begin to ensure your security capabilities and policies are aligned with these new realities.</p>
<p>This year’s report features an expert analysis of mobile threat data from the field, including prominent attack vectors, regional trends, evolving vulnerabilities, phishing developments, and malware advancements. To learn more about mobile security threats and how to guard against them, download the <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<hr>
<ol>
<li>TechJury, “55+ Jaw Dropping App Usage Statistics in 2022,” 2022, https://techjury.net/blog/app-usage-statistics/#gref</li>
<li>&nbsp;Statista, “Mobile app revenue worldwide 2017–2025, by segment,” 2021, https://www.statista.com/forecasts/1262892/mobile-app-revenue-worldwide-by-segment</li>
<li>&nbsp;Curry, D., Business of Apps, “Mobile Payments App Revenue and Usage Statistics (2022),” January 11, 2022, https://www.businessofapps.com/data/mobile-payments-app-market/</li>
<li>&nbsp;Ericsson, “5G estimated to reach 1.5 billion subscriptions in 2024 – Ericsson Mobility Report, 2018,. Telefonaktiebolaget LM Ericsson. https://www.ericsson.com/en/press-releases/2018/11/5g-estimated-to-reach-1.5-billion-subscriptionsin-2024&#8211;ericsson-mobility-report</li>
<li>&nbsp;Sharma, M., TechRadar, “Android apps put data of 100 million Google Play Store users at risk,” May 20, 2021, https://www.techradar.com/uk/news/android-apps-put-data-of-100-million-google-play-store-users-at-risk</li>
<li>&nbsp;Newman, L. H., Wired, “Thousands of Android and iOS Apps Leak Data From the Cloud,” March 4, 2021, https://www.wired.com/story/ios-android-leaky-apps-cloud/</li>
</ol>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/state-of-mobile-app-security-key-takeaways-from-2022-threat-report/">The State of Mobile App Security: Key Takeaways from 2022 Threat Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Mobile Threat Report: Emerging Endpoint Security Risks in 2022</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-report-endpoint-security-risks-in-2022/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Monique Becenti]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 16:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Endpoint Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile endpoint security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile security]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10064</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The ownership and use of smartphones has grown increasingly ubiquitous. By 2021, the percentage of adults in the U.S. who owned a smartphone grew to 85%1. Between 2010 and 2021, the smartphone market grew from $18 billion to $73 billion.2   Whether we’re looking to stay informed, connected, or entertained, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-report-endpoint-security-risks-in-2022/">Global Mobile Threat Report: Emerging Endpoint Security Risks in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>The ownership and use of smartphones has grown increasingly ubiquitous. By 2021, the percentage of adults in the U.S. who owned a smartphone grew to 85%<sup>1</sup>. Between 2010 and 2021, the smartphone market grew from $18 billion to $73 billion.<sup>2  </sup></p>
<p>Whether we’re looking to stay informed, connected, or entertained, our smartphones are increasingly the tool of choice. Now, the same is true for when we’re looking to get work done—and this is a trend many security teams are still grappling to contend with.<a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-10069 aligncenter" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security.png" alt="" width="739" height="329" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security.png 1094w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security-300x134.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security-1024x456.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mobile-endpoint-security-768x342.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px" /></a></p>
<p>We’ve recently published our <a href="https://get.zimperium.com/2022-global-mobile-threat-report/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report</a>, which offers some key insights into the challenges today’s security teams are confronting. This report offers a comprehensive look at the mobile endpoint security landscape, and it specifically examines how the explosive growth in remote and hybrid work in recent years has led to increased reliance on mobile devices—and dramatic expansion in risk.</p>
<h3>How Remote Work Has Changed the Game for Security Teams</h3>
<p>Now, remote workers routinely use their own networks and their own devices in the course of their jobs. Incorporating BYOD policies have fundamentally changed the game in terms of which security tools and strategies work—and which do not.</p>
<p>In a recent survey, 44% of survey respondents say they have added security policies or requirements as a direct result of cyber security incidents associated with their distributed employee base. Of that group, 34% have switched security vendors or service providers.<sup>3</sup></p>
<p>In response to the threats posed by remote and hybrid work, many teams have started to implement cybersecurity best practices. However, a large percentage of organizations have yet to make this move.</p>
<h3>The Exposure Posed by BYOD</h3>
<p>To respond to the pandemic and the need to foster the productivity of remote workers, IT organizations have scrambled to build and expand support for bring-your-own-device (BYOD) policies. 30% of respondents in a survey cited BYOD as a top concern for endpoint security. Further, this concern is proving to be justified: In 2021, nearly 50% of respondents indicated that their work-from-home strategy played a significant role in cybersecurity incidents.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/endpoint-security-worries.png"><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-10070 aligncenter" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/endpoint-security-worries.png" alt="" width="628" height="229" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/endpoint-security-worries.png 628w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/endpoint-security-worries-300x109.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px" /></a></p>
<p>When it comes to vectors of attack, Microsoft Office represents the primary target of cybercriminals. One report indicated this software suite accounted for more than 72% of exploits, while browsers were responsible for 13%.<sup>4</sup> For enterprise security teams, the takeaway is clear: More than any other apps or tools, Office is the target of choice for cybercriminals looking to gain access to corporate data by monitoring email accounts and communications occurring via the Microsoft Teams app. Mitigating the exposure these apps present is a key imperative.</p>
<h3>Emerging iOS Threats</h3>
<p>As BYO device usage increases in the workforce, keeping up with the ever-evolving threat landscape is essential.  For some, the fact that Apple iOS devices are commonly being targeted for attacks may come as a surprise. In recent years, many had the perception that it was largely Android devices that were being successfully targeted. In 2021, iOS vulnerabilities accounted for 64% of the mobile-specific zero-day attacks discovered. That year, 11 separate zero-day exploits targeting iOS and Apple WebKit were found.<sup>5</sup></p>
<p>In addition, iOS devices were at the center of one of the spyware attacks that gained the most notoriety in 2021. First discovered in 2016, Pegasus spyware reappeared in the news. Attackers used Pegasus in a campaign that targeted 50,000 journalists, activists, political leaders, and others. Initially uncovered by Amnesty International, the spyware campaign featured zero-day exploits targeting iOS devices.</p>
<p>In years past, the closed nature of Apple’s App Store helped stem the proliferation of malicious apps on iOS devices. However, attackers are leveraging workarounds. For example, Apple offers configuration profiles that give legitimate businesses the ability to install and run applications, such as mobile device management solutions, without the scrutiny of Apple’s App Store submission process.</p>
<p>However, this feature also allows end-users to load unapproved and often unsecured apps. Third-party app stores and app signing services have started to emerge that are capitalizing on this workaround, which poses the threat of increased malware ultimately making its way onto unsuspecting users’ devices.</p>
<h3>Endpoints Creating Blind Spots</h3>
<p>Mobile endpoints represent an increasingly prominent target for cybercriminals. The reality today is that every time an employee uses a mobile device to open an email, send a text, or access a corporate application, it can pose a threat to the enterprise, potentially exposing personally identifiable information, intellectual property, and more.</p>
<p>However, if teams in the security operations center are relying on traditional endpoint security tools, this constant activity isn’t being tracked consistently and effectively, if it’s tracked at all. A significant percentage are clear this lack of visibility poses a problem: 39% say that, with their existing tools and procedures, reaction time is too slow.<sup>6</sup></p>
<p>These realities make clear that comprehensive mobile threat defense (MTD) solutions represent an urgent requirement. With advanced MTD offerings, teams can establish effective defenses against modern-day mobile threats, protecting against attacks at the device, network, and application level. Further, MTD solutions can protect end-users against phishing attacks that target such vectors as SMS text messages, messaging apps, personal email, and corporate email.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>The insights above give you a glimpse of the extensive findings reported in the <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report</a>. The report makes one thing abundantly clear: The mobile device has become a common target for malicious actors globally. Whether through device exploits, application misconfigurations, malware, or leaky databases, cybercriminals are succeeding in exploiting mobile devices and gaining access to sensitive personal and corporate assets.</p>
<p>Establishing robust, adaptive, and persistent mobile endpoint security is therefore a primary objective. Be sure to review this year’s report, which features expert analysis of mobile threat data from the field, including prominent attack vectors, regional trends, evolving vulnerabilities, phishing developments, and malware advancements. To learn more about mobile security threats and how to guard against them, download the <a href="https://get.zimperium.com/2022-global-mobile-threat-report/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report</a>.</p>
<hr />
<ol>
<li>Statista, “Percentage of U.S. adults who own a smartphone from 2011 to 2021,” April 2021, https://www.statista.com/statistics/219865/percentage-of-us-adults-who-own-a-smartphone/</li>
<li> O’Dea, S., Statista, “Smartphones in the U.S. &#8211; Statistics &amp; Facts,”  August 4, 2021, https://www.statista.com/topics/2711/us-smartphone-market/#dossierKeyfigures</li>
<li>Zimperium, Pulse QA, “How have you shifted your remote work strategy as an organization as a result of cybersecurity incidents in the past year?” 2021</li>
<li>Chebyshev, V., Securelist, “IT threat evolution Q3 2019. Statistics,” April 28, 2021, https://securelist.com/it-threat-evolution-q3-2019-statistics/95269/</li>
<li><i>Google Project Zero, 0day “In the Wild,” Google Docs, 2021, https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/u/1/d/1lkNJ0uQwbeC1ZTRrxdtuPLCIl7mlUreoKfSIgajnSyY/edit#gid=2129022708</i></li>
<li>Zimperium, Pulse QA, “Secure Access Practices In North America,” 2021</li>
</ol>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-report-endpoint-security-risks-in-2022/">Global Mobile Threat Report: Emerging Endpoint Security Risks in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Global Mobile Threat Report: Key Insights on the State of Mobile Security</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report-key-insights/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Melick]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 10:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Threat Research]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile threat defense]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10044</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; What’s the mobile security landscape like today, how has it changed, and what can security teams expect over the course of 2022? To provide answers, we’ve recently published our 2022 Global Mobile Threat Report. This report provides a comprehensive look at the landscape and its evolution and explores how [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report-key-insights/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report: Key Insights on the State of Mobile Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-10050 alignright" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px.jpeg" alt="" width="258" height="334" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px.jpeg 396w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Global_Mobile_cover_512px-232x300.jpeg 232w" sizes="(max-width: 258px) 100vw, 258px" /></a>What’s the mobile security landscape like today, how has it changed, and what can security teams expect over the course of 2022? To provide answers, we’ve recently published our 2022 Global Mobile Threat Report. This report provides a comprehensive look at the landscape and its evolution and explores how mobile threats and a modern security strategy drive impact throughout an enterprise&#8217;s entire ecosystem.</p>
<h3>The Increased Use of Mobile Phones for Work—and the Resulting Risks</h3>
<p>It wasn’t that long ago that those who had a mobile phone used it for pretty much one thing: making calls. Those younger than a certain age may find that impossible to fathom, but it’s true.</p>
<p>Clearly, those days are over. Now, smartphones play an increasingly integral role in our personal and professional lives. For work, it’s grown routine for us to use our phones to store passwords, do multi-factor authentication, access corporate files and applications, and more.</p>
<p>Sadly, in the process, these devices have come to capture the increased attention of cybercriminals. Malicious actors are waging increasingly sophisticated attacks that target mobile devices and applications, and they continue to invest more to advance their techniques and tactics.</p>
<h3>Mobile Security: A Moving Target</h3>
<p>The reality is that teams in many organizations are not clear on the risks, and they’re not well-positioned to contend with today’s mobile security demands.</p>
<p>The mobile landscape continues to grow in scope and complexity, with new apps, features, and capabilities introduced continuously. Therefore, it is essential to realize that security, like mobile devices, is a constantly moving target. It is vital to establish the right tools and resources, so teams understand the risks involved and their potential impact and make intelligent decisions about security efforts and investments.</p>
<h3>2022 Global Mobile Threat Report: Key Takeaways</h3>
<p>For teams looking to respond to these evolving security imperatives, Zimperium’s 2022 Global Mobile Threat Report offers data-driven insights and updates. Following are some of the key findings from our analysis:</p>
<h4>Mobile devices are an increasing focus of cybercriminals.</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>30% of the known, zero-day vulnerabilities</strong> discovered in 2021 targeted mobile devices.</li>
<li>The same year, there was a <strong>466% increase in exploited, zero-day vulnerabilities</strong> used in active attacks against mobile endpoints.</li>
<li>Further, <strong>75% of the phishing sites</strong> analyzed specifically targeted mobile devices.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Malware is everywhere.</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>2,034,217 new malware samples</strong> were detected in the wild in 2021.</li>
<li>The Zimperium zLabs team discovered threats affecting <strong>more than 10 million devices in 214 countries</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Advanced malware keeps resurfacing.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Prominent malware discovered in previous years made a mobile-focused comeback in 2021. For example, <strong>Pegasus, the spyware program</strong> first detected in 2016, surfaced again in 2021. Attackers targeted more than 50,000 individuals, including journalists, activists, and political leaders. This most recent variant leveraged zero-day exploits to target iOS devices.</li>
<li>In addition, the Joker trojan discovered in 2017 also reappeared in 2021 and specifically targeted Android devices.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Vulnerable mobile devices are resulting in incidents.</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>42% of organizations</strong> report that vulnerabilities in mobile devices and web applications have led to a security incident</li>
</ul>
<h4>Public cloud misconfigurations are exposing data.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Based on our analysis of more than 1.3 million Android and iOS apps, 14% of the apps using public cloud backends had misconfigurations that exposed users’ personal information<strong>.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>These findings illustrate why 2022 must be the year that security teams start to take mobile security seriously, and employ the same rigor in this arena that they’ve been applying to traditional endpoints.</p>
<p>The statistics above represent just a portion of the details found in the <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Global Mobile Threat Report</a>. The number of risks to mobile apps and devices, and the corporate assets they connect to, is growing year over year. Whether through device exploits, application misconfigurations, malware, or leaky databases, the mobile device has become a common target for malicious actors globally.</p>
<p>This year’s report provides a topical analysis of mobile threat data from the field, including prominent mobile attack vectors, regional analyses, exploited mobile vulnerabilities, mobile phishing trends, and mobile malware trends. To learn more about mobile security threats and how to guard against them, be sure to download the 2022 Global Mobile Threat Report<span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report/?utm_medium=Blog-CTA-Banner&amp;utm_campaign=2022-Global-Mobile-Threat-Report&amp;utm_content=Threat-Report-22-Banner"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10048" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ad_Global_1a_720x160px_orange.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="160" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ad_Global_1a_720x160px_orange.jpg 720w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ad_Global_1a_720x160px_orange-300x67.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/global-mobile-threat-report-key-insights/">2022 Global Mobile Threat Report: Key Insights on the State of Mobile Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming PSD2 Deadlines and What They Mean for Mobile App Security</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/psd2-compliance-mobile-devices-banks-need-know/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Krishna Vishnubhotla]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 18:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[App Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Compliance]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Financial Services]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=4276</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to compliance, you’re never truly done. The environments you’re tasked with securing and auditing continue to evolve, and so do the standards and deadlines you have to meet. The EU’s Payment Service Directive 2 (PSD2) is a current case in point. The directive had several goals, including [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/psd2-compliance-mobile-devices-banks-need-know/">Upcoming PSD2 Deadlines and What They Mean for Mobile App Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>When it comes to compliance, you’re never truly done. The environments you’re tasked with securing and auditing continue to evolve, and so do the standards and deadlines you have to meet. The EU’s Payment Service Directive 2 (PSD2) is a current case in point. The directive had several goals, including standardizing rules around payment services, opening up payment markets to competition, and increasing the protection of consumers and their data.</p>
<p>The regulation applies to payment service providers (PSPs) such as banks, processors, and FinTechs, as well as merchants that process e-commerce transactions. It is also important to recognize that it applies to any of these organizations that serve EU citizens.</p>
<p>While the directive took effect in 2018, the EU commission has given organizations extra time to implement some of these rules. The deadline for addressing the requirement for establishing strong customer authentication for e-commerce transactions will be taking effect on March 14, 2022.</p>
<p>In the sections below, we’ll offer some key takeaways for teams that have to comply with PSD2.</p>
<h3>PSD2 Can Introduce More Data Sharing, Potential for More Risk</h3>
<p>In order to foster increased competition, the directive offered rules around the need to “facilitate customer mobility.” One of the direct implications of this is that banks are required to share customers’ current and historical data with third parties, provided the customer offers their consent. In this way, customers will be able to more easily change banks or work with a third party, for example, a FinTech’s mobile app so they can manage multiple banking accounts.</p>
<p>This standard has significant implications for mobile security: Increasingly, mobile apps will represent a common way for banks to share data and for customers to access and manage this information.</p>
<p>Ultimately, this portability and data sharing will lead to a fundamental reality: Sensitive customer data will be stored, processed, and transmitted by more mobile apps and systems—inherently expanding the potential attack surface. If mobile apps and associated backend systems aren’t secured, the risk of data exposure will grow.</p>
<h3>Establishing Mobile Security</h3>
<p>Security for mobile devices differs fundamentally from that of desktop PCs. The critical difference is mobile devices require protection on at least three different attack surfaces: the device itself, the networks it uses, and the apps installed. PSD2 recognizes the need for multi-vector protection by specifying requirements for device and software integrity, secure communication, and data protection.</p>
<p>In addition, PSD2 requires PSPs have mechanisms in place that will minimize the potential harm if a security measure fails<sup>1</sup>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Payment service providers shall adopt security measures …to mitigate the risk which would result from that multi-purpose device being compromised.</p></blockquote>
<p>Banks and FinTechs are exploring a range of technologies to meet these requirements, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Containerization (together with rootkit/jailbreak detection mechanisms)</li>
<li>Hardware security elements</li>
<li>Anti-malware tools</li>
<li>Runtime application self-protection (RASP)</li>
<li>Mobile device analytics and behavior solutions</li>
</ul>
<h3>PSD2 Requires Device and Software Integrity</h3>
<p>For many mobile app developers, ensuring device and software integrity will be a constant challenge. Even if developers adhere to security best practices, such as writing secure code, using only authorized APIs, carefully vetting libraries, using only the least privilege, and so on—all of that won’t suffice if the device or operating system on which the app resides is compromised.</p>
<p>The challenges of ensuring device and software integrity are underscored by the fact that many mobile devices will be solely administered by the end-user. That means devices are likely to be running an outdated OS, be missing numerous security patches, and have dated versions of apps.</p>
<h3>PSD2 Requires Secure Communications</h3>
<p>PSD2 also requires secure communications<sup>2</sup>:</p>
<blockquote><p>In order to safeguard the confidentiality and the integrity of data, it is necessary to ensure the security of communication sessions between account servicing payment service providers, account information service providers, payment initiation service providers, and payment service providers issuing card-based payment instruments.</p></blockquote>
<p>Teams must ensure all communications with the device are encrypted. They must also employ measures to make sure communication only occurs with authenticated and legitimate sources and is not intercepted by a third party.</p>
<p>One complicating factor is that mobile users can and do connect to unsecured WiFi networks. In some cases, these networks are explicitly designed with malicious intent. For example, threat actors may give a network a display name that tricks the user into believing it is trustworthy. Further, even if a person uses a legitimate network, but that network isn’t effectively secured, it still leaves the door open to man-in-the-middle (MITM) and other attacks.</p>
<h3>PSD2 Requires Data Protection</h3>
<p>The ability to use mobile payment methods is a significant convenience. Maximizing that convenience entails the use of the consumer’s financial data in the payment app. That data, along with the user’s personalized security credentials, requires protection. The PSP must provide that protection.</p>
<p>Developers can take a variety of approaches to protect mobile apps and user data. For example, one of the mitigating measures PSD2 outlines is “the use of separated secure execution environments through the software installed inside the multi-purpose device.”<sup>3</sup> Another approach could be to use a RASP solution. These methods aim to protect the app and the data the app contains, but are of limited value if the device on which the app resides is compromised.</p>
<h3>Zimperium Enables PSD2 Compliance for Mobile</h3>
<p>Fundamentally, if you build mobile apps, particularly apps that process the data of EU citizens, you want to make sure you’re ready to adapt to the latest PSD2 requirements. To comply with PSD2, you will need to establish stringent mobile app security standards.</p>
<p>The good news is that Zimperium can help.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/zdefend/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zimperium’s zDefend</a> enables mobile app developers to meet requirements for device and software integrity, secure communication, and data protection. Further, with the solution, you can address PSD2’s strong customer authentication requirements, which are vital in mitigating the risk posed by failures elsewhere in the security ecosystem.</p>
<p>Zimperium provides a software development kit (SDK) that makes it fast and easy for developers to embed Zimperium’s machine learning-based detection engine, z9, directly inside any mobile app. With the engine embedded, mobile apps can immediately determine if a multi-use device is compromised, if any network attacks are occurring, and if malicious apps are installed. Moreover, developers can specify local remediation actions to mitigate risk when a threat is detected. In short, zDefend is a single solution to meet a host of PSD2 requirements.</p>
<p>Contact us today for help complying with PSD2. Be sure to review the <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/zdefend">zDefend documentation</a> or view our <a href="https://youtu.be/AK32p_S5Hw8">summary video on what PSD2</a> means for your mobile app.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><sup><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/?utm_medium=Blog-CTA-Banner&amp;utm_campaign=WeSecureMobile&amp;utm_content=Contact-Us-Banner"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9958" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="180" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px.jpg 720w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px-300x75.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a></sup></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><sup>[1] EU, “Commission Delegated Regulation (EU) 2018/389 of 27 November 2017,” Article 9. Independence of the elements. Section 2 and Section 3 (b), (c). https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2018.069.01.0023.01.ENG&amp;toc=OJ:L:2018:069:TOC</sup></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><sup>[2] EU, “Commission Delegated Regulation (EU) 2018/389 of 27 November 2017,” Paragraph 26. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2018.069.01.0023.01.ENG&amp;toc=OJ:L:2018:069:TOC</sup></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><sup>[3] EU, “Commission Delegated Regulation (EU) 2018/389 of 27 November 2017,” Article 9. Independence of the elements. Section 3 (a). https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2018.069.01.0023.01.ENG&amp;toc=OJ:L:2018:069:TOC</sup></span></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/psd2-compliance-mobile-devices-banks-need-know/">Upcoming PSD2 Deadlines and What They Mean for Mobile App Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimperium is Proud to Sponsor Professional Race Car Driver Josh Green with Turn 3 Motorsport</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-to-sponsor-race-car-driver-josh-green-with-turn-3-motorsport/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[JT Keating]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 18:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[sponsorship]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10029</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Acceleration can be defined as ‘the increase in the rate or speed of something.’ In 2021, Zimperium established superiority in mobile security. In 2022, Zimperium has embraced the theme of acceleration and is incorporating this theme in the center of our business structure. We are stepping on the gas and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-to-sponsor-race-car-driver-josh-green-with-turn-3-motorsport/">Zimperium is Proud to Sponsor Professional Race Car Driver Josh Green with Turn 3 Motorsport</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>Acceleration can be defined as ‘<em>the increase in the rate or speed of something.</em>’ In 2021, Zimperium established superiority in mobile security. In 2022, Zimperium has embraced the theme of acceleration and is incorporating this theme in the center of our business structure. We are stepping on the gas and only striving for first place. Although 2021 brought on many challenges, we came out stronger by gaining new partnerships, onboarding new team members, gaining new customers and innovating new product features. None of this would be attainable without the grit, determination, passion, and accelerating mentality that the Zimperium team has embraced.</p>
<h3>Zimperium To Sponsor Josh Green with Turn 3 Motorsport</h3>
<p>With the theme of acceleration in mind, Zimperium is thrilled to announce the sponsorship of <a href="https://www.joshgreenracing.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Professional Race Car Driver, Josh Green</a>, in his pursuit to win the Indy Pro 2000 Championship Presented by Cooper Tires with Turn 3 Motorsport. Josh started his racing career in 2015 and like Zimperium, has dedicated the last years to perfecting his craft to be a leader in the space. Since 2015 he has accomplished so much including advancing to the Indy Pro 2000 Championship, multiple wins, podiums, and top 5 and 10 finishes. There is so much to learn from Josh&#8217;s story and Zimperium is proud to be a sponsor in his journey to success.</p>
<p>Think of a race car driver participating in a huge championship race. There are hours of preparation, planning, practice, mental and physical tools, and a fully equipped team needed to contribute to the success of each event. Josh Green said:</p>
<blockquote><p>It’s not just the driver. It takes a team to win on race day. My team consists of so many different job types varying from engineering to manufacturing, partnerships to sponsorships, operations to analytics all of which are synonymous with the Zimperium team ranging from Sales, Customer Success, Product Management, Marketing, Legal, HR &amp; Finance. As a team, we are each held accountable to make our contributions to manifest a win on race day.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.joshgreenracing.com/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-10030 size-large" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ad_Racing_1a_1280x720px-1-1024x576.png" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ad_Racing_1a_1280x720px-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ad_Racing_1a_1280x720px-1-300x169.png 300w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ad_Racing_1a_1280x720px-1-768x432.png 768w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ad_Racing_1a_1280x720px-1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>Zimperium is looking forward to this upcoming race season and is proud to partner with Josh Green with Turn 3 Motorsport. Josh Green’s Zimperium-branded race car embodies our theme of acceleration. Zimperium is dedicated to accelerating growth and remaining the global leader in mobile device and app security, offering real-time, on-device protection against both known and unknown threats. Green stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>Elite drivers carry an elite mindset. You must be confident in your abilities and hungry for success at all times. Every successful driver has a strong mental framework behind them whether that be in a race car or on a sales team. I’d like to thank Zimperium for your contributions to me as a driver and I look forward to seeing you guys accelerate on the track.</p></blockquote>
<p>To learn more about Josh Green’s journey to success, please visit <a href="https://www.joshgreenracing.com/">https://www.joshgreenracing.com/</a>.</p>
<h3>About Zimperium</h3>
<p>Zimperium provides the only mobile security platform purpose-built for enterprise environments. With machine learning-based protection, Zimperium is the only solution to provide on-device mobile threat defense to protect growing and evolving mobile environments. For more information or to schedule a demo, <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/">contact us</a> today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/?utm_medium=Blog-CTA-Banner&amp;utm_campaign=WeSecureMobile&amp;utm_content=Contact-Us-Banner"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9958" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="180" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px.jpg 720w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_ContactUs_1a_720x180px-300x75.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-to-sponsor-race-car-driver-josh-green-with-turn-3-motorsport/">Zimperium is Proud to Sponsor Professional Race Car Driver Josh Green with Turn 3 Motorsport</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimperium Joins NIST Project on Zero Trust Architectures</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-joins-nist-project-on-zero-trust-architectures/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Kovach]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Threat Defense]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[zero trust]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile threat defense]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MTD]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[zIPS]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=10022</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Zimperium has been working closely with the National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence (NCCoE) at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). The NCCoE is a collaborative hub in which industry organizations, government agencies, and academic institutions work together to address businesses’ most pressing cybersecurity challenges. Through these engagements, we [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-joins-nist-project-on-zero-trust-architectures/">Zimperium Joins NIST Project on Zero Trust Architectures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><p>Zimperium has been working closely with the <a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence</a> (NCCoE) at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). The NCCoE is a collaborative hub in which industry organizations, government agencies, and academic institutions work together to address businesses’ most pressing cybersecurity challenges.</p>
<p>Through these engagements, we are contributing to the advancement of approaches that ultimately improve the security of organizations across industries and around the world. In recent months, we’ve worked to support the development of another NCCoE project dedicated to improving <a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/nists-guidelines-to-improving-byod-mobile-device-security-and-privacy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BYOD mobile device security and privacy.</a></p>
<h3>Zimperium’s Participation in the NIST Zero Trust Cybersecurity Project</h3>
<p>Last month, Zimperium was approved to participate in the NIST ‘Zero Trust Cybersecurity: Implementing a Zero Trust Architecture Building Block Consortium.’ As NIST explains, the intent of this project is to “develop practical, interoperable cybersecurity approaches that address the real-world needs of complex information technology (IT) systems.”</p>
<p>Zimperium is working diligently with the NCCoE to develop approaches to design and build zero trust architectures that align with the tenets and principles documented in <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-207.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NIST SP 800-207, Zero Trust Architecture</a>. The proposed example solution(s) will integrate commercial and open source products together that leverage cybersecurity standards and recommended practices to showcase the robust security features of a zero trust architecture applied to several common enterprise IT use cases.</p>
<p>To learn more about the consortium and its work on zero trust architectures, be sure to visit  <a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/zerotrust" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.nccoe.nist.gov/zerotrust</a>.</p>
<p><i>*NIST does not evaluate commercial products under this consortium and does not endorse any product or service used.*</i></p>
<h3>About the National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence</h3>
<p>The NCCoE, a part of NIST, enables the creation of practical cybersecurity solutions for specific industries, as well as for broad, cross-sector technology challenges. Through consortia under CRADAs, including technology partners including Zimperium, the NCCoE applies standards and best practices to develop modular, easily adaptable example cybersecurity solutions by using commercially available technology. The NCCoE documents these example solutions in the NIST Special Publication 1800 series, which maps capabilities to the NIST Cybersecurity Framework and details the steps needed for another entity to re-create the example solution. The NCCoE was established in 2012 by NIST and more information can be found at <a href="https://www.nccoe.nist.gov">https://www.nccoe.nist.gov</a>.</p>
<h3>About Zimperium</h3>
<p>Zimperium zIPS is an advanced mobile threat defense solution for enterprises, providing persistent, on-device protection to both corporate-owned and BYOD devices. Zimperium zIPS’ on-device security gives agencies the mobile device integrity attestation necessary for a complete approach to zero trust. By design, zIPS protects end-user privacy, ensuring that Federal agencies comply with Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA) and privacy mandates. For more information or to schedule a demo, <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/">contact us</a> today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/?utm_medium=Blog-CTA-Banner&amp;utm_campaign=WeSecureMobile&amp;utm_content=Request-Demo-Banner"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9956" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="180" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px.jpg 720w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px-300x75.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/zimperium-joins-nist-project-on-zero-trust-architectures/">Zimperium Joins NIST Project on Zero Trust Architectures</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Threat Defense for OMB Memorandum M-22-09</title>
      <link>https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-defense-for-omb-m-22-09/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Kovach]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 21:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Security]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Mobile Threat Defense]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[mobile threat defense]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[zero trust]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.zimperium.com/?p=9954</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>OMB Memorandum M-22-09: Moving the U.S. Government Toward Zero Trust Cybersecurity Principles. On January 26, 2022, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) published M-22-09 Moving the U.S. Government Toward Zero Trust Cybersecurity Principles. M-22-09 sets out activities that agencies need to undertake to meet the requirements under Executive Order [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-defense-for-omb-m-22-09/">Mobile Threat Defense for OMB Memorandum M-22-09</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="bsf_rt_marker"><h4></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><i>OMB Memorandum M-22-09: </i></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><i>Moving the U.S. Government Toward Zero Trust Cybersecurity Principles</i>.</strong></p>
<p>On January 26, 2022, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) published <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/M-22-09.pdf">M-22-09</a> <i>Moving the U.S. Government Toward Zero Trust Cybersecurity Principles</i>.</p>
<p>M-22-09 sets out activities that agencies need to undertake to meet the requirements under <a href="https://blog.zimperium.com/the-presidents-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-is-a-massive-shift-for-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Executive Order (EO) 14028 <i>Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity</i></a>. Under M-22-09, agencies need to achieve specific cybersecurity standards and objectives by the end of Fiscal Year (FY) 2024.</p>
<p>Understanding where mobile threat defense (MTD) completes the <a href="https://go.zimperium.com/completing-the-zero-trust-framework-with-mobile-threat-defense" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zero trust framework requirements</a> under the  OMB Memorandum provides insight into how agencies can establish robust security.</p>
<h3>The Key Zero Trust Framework Pillars</h3>
<p>M-22-09 aligns with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) maturity model. Of the five pillars listed, MTD fills in the gaps around mobile device security under three key areas.</p>
<p>At a high level, M-22-09 defines the following three pillars where MTD provides the security needed to ensure a robust approach to zero trust security by incorporating mobile devices:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Devices:</strong> The Federal Government has a complete inventory of every device it operates and authorizes for Government use, and can prevent, detect, and respond to incidents on those devices.</li>
<li><strong>Applications and Workloads:</strong> Agencies treat all applications as internet-connected, routinely subject their applications to rigorous empirical testing, and welcome external vulnerability reports.</li>
<li><strong>Data:</strong> Agencies take advantage of cloud security services and tools to discover, classify, and protect their sensitive data, and have implemented enterprise-wide logging and information sharing.</li>
</ul>
<p>As Federal Civilian Executive Branch (FCEB) agencies continue to support remote work, more workforce members will be using their mobile devices. CISA’s draft <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/CISA%20Zero%20Trust%20Maturity%20Model_Draft.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zero Trust Maturity Model (ZTMM)</a> highlights mobile devices and bring-your-own-device (<a href="https://get.zimperium.com/government-it-leaders-guide-to-securing-byod/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BYOD)</a> as assets under the Devices pillar.</p>
<p>For mobile devices, many of the current solutions lack the ability to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure appropriate attestation and security</li>
<li>Secure mobile applications</li>
<li>Automate security responses</li>
</ul>
<p>MTD fills these gaps, augmenting current security tools so that FCEB agencies can achieve the goals set forth in M-22-09.</p>
<h3>Government-wide endpoint detection and response</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/mobile-edr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Endpoint detection and response (EDR)</a> is fundamental to a successful zero trust framework implementation. M-22-09 touches on the need for EDR tools. However, going into detail would be repetitive within this Memorandum. Therefore, M-22-09 references the October 2021 <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/M-22-01.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M-22-01</a> <i>Improving Detection of Cybersecurity Vulnerabilities and Incidents on Federal Government Systems Through Endpoint Detection and Response.</i></p>
<p>M-22-01 states:</p>
<blockquote><p>EDR combines real-time continuous monitoring and collection of endpoint data (for example, networked computing devices such as workstations, mobile phones, servers) with rules-based automated response and analysis capabilities…EDR provides the increased visibility necessary to respond to advanced forms of cybersecurity threats, such as polymorphic malware, advanced persistent threats (APTs), and phishing. Moreover, EDR is an essential component for transitioning to zero trust architecture, because every device that connects to a network is a potential attack vector for cyber threats.</p></blockquote>
<p>As FCEB agencies look to meet these EDR requirements, they need to consider solutions that address any networked computing devices. M-22-01 specifies mobile phones. However, it’s important to remember that any device with a mobile operating system must fall into this category.</p>
<p>Additionally, M-22-09 highlights that FCEB agencies need to maintain a diversity of different EDR tools. Under this directive, OMB appears to recognize that traditional EDR technologies, including mobile device management (MDM), may need to be augmented to ensure continuous mobile device security.</p>
<h4>What EDR and MDM do for meeting OMB requirements</h4>
<p>EDR and MDM provide several benefits as FCEB agencies. EDR monitors device activity, automates responses, and prevents risky devices from connecting to networks. MDM tracks location, access, and device security.</p>
<p>At the same time, they also leave gaps when <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/zerotrust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">moving to a zero trust security model</a> as required by the OMB memo.</p>
<p>EDR solutions lack the ability to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Provide visibility around locked down kernels in mobile OS’s</li>
<li>Detect risky or malicious networks</li>
<li>Detect disabled cloud-based detection by network attackers</li>
<li>Assess privacy and security risks in legitimate (non-malicious) mobile apps</li>
<li>Address end-user privacy concerns on owned devices</li>
</ul>
<p>On the other hand, MDM tools are unable to detect and resolve issues associated with:</p>
<ul>
<li>Advanced threats</li>
<li>Mobile phishing attacks</li>
<li>Device health, particularly in real-time</li>
<li>Cloud application security</li>
<li>Malicious applications downloaded from untrusted sources</li>
</ul>
<h4>Getting MTD into the Zero Trust Framework mix</h4>
<p>MTD is often referred to as “Mobile EDR” and meets the spirit of EDR recommendations from NIST, CISA, and OMB.</p>
<p>With MTD, agencies achieve the necessary mobile device integrity attestation necessary for a complete approach to zero trust. The <a href="https://go.zimperium.com/zips-mobile-threat-defense-data-sheet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zIPS intrusion prevention system</a> agent deploys to a device then:</p>
<ul>
<li>Scans for known malware</li>
<li>Verifies device configurations comply with policy</li>
<li>Inventories applications for malicious apps or side-loaded apps</li>
<li>Provides data to security tools via API</li>
</ul>
<p>Creating a complete endpoint security technology stack should incorporate MTD to ensure that the unique risks arising from mobile devices are addressed as part of a zero trust framework.</p>
<h3>Application security testing</h3>
<p>M-22-09 also incorporates <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/zscan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">application security testing</a> as part of achieving a successful zero trust framework implementation.</p>
<p>The Memorandum notes:</p>
<blockquote><p>For Federal applications to withstand sophisticated probing and attack, agencies need to go beyond implementing and documenting security controls. To gain confidence in the security of their systems, agencies must analyze their software and its deployed functionality with a comprehensive and rigorous approach, whether their software is built internally or by a contracted vendor.</p></blockquote>
<p>Although not specified, mobile applications should be considered part of the implementation. Using an MDM tool offers some capabilities. However, for a complete implementation, agencies also need to consider where MTD fits.</p>
<h4>Where MDM fits into application security testing</h4>
<p>With MDM, users download an agent to their devices then the MDM server updates configurations, applications, and policies over the internet. MDM lacks the ability to separate user and agency data, creating privacy risks for agencies using it to secure mobile devices.</p>
<p>Additionally, MDM offers rudimentary device-trust assessments against known threat approaches like jailbreaks and outdated operating systems. However, it lacks the rigorous approach required by M-22-09 because it fails to detect and resolve issues associated with <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/support-advancedthreatinsights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">advanced threats</a>, mobile phishing attacks, device health, particularly in real-time, cloud application security, and malicious applications downloaded from untrusted sources.</p>
<h4>How MTD fills out the OMB application security testing requirements</h4>
<p>Mobile Threat Defense solves these problems, giving agencies a way to ensure appropriate security and user privacy.</p>
<p>MTD runs locally on mobile devices to ensure end-user privacy. MTD provides the following security and privacy capabilities:</p>
<ul>
<li>No need to collect or process personally identifiable information (PII)</li>
<li>Recognize standard baselines configurations for operating systems and apps</li>
<li>Recognize regular web traffic activity</li>
</ul>
<p>MTD enables the rigorous app testing required by monitoring all applications, including those downloaded by users that would remain unmanaged otherwise.</p>
<p>When deploying MTD in combination with other app security technologies, agencies gain the comprehensive application risk and vulnerability monitoring needed for a comprehensive zero trust framework implementation.</p>
<h3>Automating security responses</h3>
<p>Every zero trust framework best practice suggests that agencies need to incorporate artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) technologies as part of their zero trust framework strategies.</p>
<p>M-22-09 is no different. The Memorandum states:</p>
<blockquote><p>Agencies should strive to employ heuristics rooted in machine learning to categorize the data they gather, and to deploy processes that offer early warning or detection of anomalous behavior in as close to real-time as possible throughout their enterprise.</p></blockquote>
<p>Using automated solutions provides the real-time threat detection and response capabilities needed to ensure a successful zero trust framework implementation.</p>
<h3>How do EDR and MDM automate security responses?</h3>
<p>EDR automates detection and response capabilities, but it primarily focuses on traditional devices, like workstations.</p>
<p>EDR uses AI/ML to identify threats and protect from having them execute on endpoints. However, they still fail to protect from threats:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hidden in locked down kernels in mobile OS’s</li>
<li>Privacy and security risks in legitimate (non-malicious) mobile apps</li>
</ul>
<p>Meanwhile, MDM often fails to provide the real-time visibility needed.</p>
<h4>The MDM visibility and automation needed to meet OMB requirements</h4>
<p>Where EDR and MDM create security gaps, MTD offers the AI/ML capabilities for a complete zero trust security framework deployment. MTD provides:</p>
<ul>
<li>On-device, machine learning-based detection against the latest mobile threats, including zero-day malware</li>
<li>Send users alerts when detecting abnormal activities on devices</li>
<li>Block activities, like preventing a phishing link from loading</li>
<li>On-device remediation and UEM driven compliance actions</li>
<li>Ability to protect from threat actors disconnecting or redirecting traffic when connected to a cellular tower</li>
</ul>
<h3>Zimperium Mobile Threat Defense for a Zero Trust Framework</h3>
<p>FCEB agencies need to meet the OMB’s goals by the end of FY 2024, but a zero trust framework requires multiple, integrated solutions across all five pillars that CISA outlines.</p>
<p>MTD is critical to securing mobile devices, providing the visibility into threat and risk postures that impact overall user and device attestation necessary for successfully implementing ZTA. Zimperium augments an agency’s IDM, EMM/MDM, and CASB, integrating critical data collection and advanced mobile endpoint security.</p>
<p>Zimperium is a trusted solution across the Federal landscape. Zimperium was the first <a href="https://www.zimperium.com/mtd-maturity-model/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mobile threat defense (MTD) provider</a> to be granted an Authority to Operate (ATO) status from the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP). Further, the U.S. Department of Defense (DoD), through its Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA) and Defense Innovation Unit (DIU), selected Zimperium to deliver comprehensive Mobile Endpoint Protection (MEP) to service members around the world. Zimperium’s MTD solutions will protect DoD mobile endpoints against phishing, malicious/risky apps, OS exploits, and network attacks.</p>
<p>Zimperium’s advanced mobile threat defense solutions provide mobile endpoint security to enterprises and governments around the world. Built with advanced threat security in mind, Zimperium zIPS meets the mobile security needs of enterprises and governments around the world.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.zimperium.com/contact-us/?&amp;utm_medium=Blog-CTA-Banner&amp;utm_campaign=WeSecureMobile&amp;utm_content=Request-Demo-Banner"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-9956 size-full" src="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="180" srcset="https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px.jpg 720w, https://blog.zimperium.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/blogCTA_WSM_Demo_1a_720x180px-300x75.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a></strong></p>
</div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com/mobile-threat-defense-for-omb-m-22-09/">Mobile Threat Defense for OMB Memorandum M-22-09</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://blog.zimperium.com">Zimperium Mobile Security Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>