<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Net Security</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com</link>
    <description>Daily information security news with a focus on enterprise security.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 12:47:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.3</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://img.helpnetsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/09093400/cropped-hns2-32x32.png</url>
      <title>Help Net Security</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Observability 8.2 provides fine-grain control over data collection and storage</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/elastic-observability-8-2/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 01:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Elastic]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227550</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Elastic announced new features and enhancements across the Elastic Observability solution to support modern cloud-native environments, including smarter tail-based sampling for application performance monitoring (APM) and enhanced visibility across AWS cloud services. Eliminating blind spots with Elastic tail-based sampling Tail-based sampling can help DevOps and site reliability engineering (SRE) teams eliminate application performance blind spots by providing finer-grain control over trace sampling conditions in high-volume systems with millions of transactions. While common head-based sampling that &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/elastic-observability-8-2/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/elastic-observability-8-2/">Elastic Observability 8.2 provides fine-grain control over data collection and storage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syniti Migrate optimizes data migration for enterprise customers</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/syniti-migrate/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 01:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Syniti]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227538</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Syniti announced the first of multiple updates to its Syniti Knowledge Platform this year. Building on the platform’s history of success in complex enterprise data migrations, the company is introducing the fully cloud-based version of Syniti Advanced Data Migration, now called Syniti Migrate. With Syniti Migrate, customers will have greater control of their data in a faster, more secure offering – from any source to any target – helping to ensure a Boring Go Live &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/syniti-migrate/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/syniti-migrate/">Syniti Migrate optimizes data migration for enterprise customers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Votiro partners with Thales to strengthen zero trust security for enterprises</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/votiro-thales/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 23:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Thales]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Votiro]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227506</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Votiro announced the extension of its collaboration with Thales with a joint solution combining Votiro’s Zero Trust CDR solution, Votiro Cloud, with the Thales CipherTrust Data Security Platform to deliver enhanced zero trust security and protect the full lifecycle of inbound, outbound, and at-rest data. The Thales CipherTrust Data Security Platform unifies data discovery, classification, data protection, and unprecedented granular access controls with centralized key management – all on a single platform. When used with &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/votiro-thales/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/votiro-thales/">Votiro partners with Thales to strengthen zero trust security for enterprises</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binarly collaborates with immune to secure modern computer infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/binarly-immune/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 23:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Binarly]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[immune]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227542</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Binarly and immune have entered into a strategic partnership to deliver the most comprehensive device security solution to protect customers against hardware, firmware and software supply chain weaknesses. The partnership, which integrates Binarly’s AI-powered SaaS analysis platform with immune’s supply chain protection and device attestation, brings together decades of expertise to provide a joint solution performing in-depth inspection of firmware and hardware to ensure the device isn’t tampered with before an endpoint security solution is &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/binarly-immune/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/binarly-immune/">Binarly collaborates with immune to secure modern computer infrastructure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atos partners with VMware to help organizations drive value from data</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/atos-vmware/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 23:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Atos]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VMware]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227554</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Atos and VMware announced an extension of the companies’ strategic partnership by working to deliver an integrated set of capabilities to help speed up the development of “Data Spaces”. Data Spaces are platforms that allow for greater exchange, collaboration, and monetization of data between organizations or industries, independently of the underlying infrastructure, whilst enabling data sovereignty and interoperability. With the VMware and Atos collaboration effort on Data Space development, the companies plan to deliver an &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/atos-vmware/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/atos-vmware/">Atos partners with VMware to help organizations drive value from data</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megaport and Bechtle join forces to accelerate digital and network transformation for companies</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/megaport-bechtle/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 23:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Bechtle]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Megaport]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227558</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Megaport announced it has entered into a distribution agreement with Bechtle. The agreement will make Megaport’s global, private Software Defined Network (SDN) platform available through Bechtle to companies looking to modernise their networks and accelerate digital transformation. “Bringing Megaport’s leading NaaS platform into the Bechtle portfolio makes it easier for customers to modernise their network connectivity and connect quickly to leading cloud service providers,” said Rodney Foreman, Chief Revenue Officer at Megaport. “Whether customers are &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/megaport-bechtle/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/megaport-bechtle/">Megaport and Bechtle join forces to accelerate digital and network transformation for companies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brian Stone joins NetAbstraction as CRO</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/netabstraction-brian-stone/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 22:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[NetAbstraction]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227512</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>NetAbstraction announced the appointment of Brian Stone as Chief Revenue Officer (CRO). Brian will oversee all business functions across sales, field operations, marketing, channel and customer success. “Brian is a proven sales leader with a strong track record for building emerging technology vendors into successful brands,” said Gordon Lawson, CEO of NetAbstraction. “We’ve achieved significant early market adoption for our intelligence-grade cloud and network concealment technology, and Brian’s team building and management skills will help &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/netabstraction-brian-stone/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/netabstraction-brian-stone/">Brian Stone joins NetAbstraction as CRO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetrate appoints Paul Machle as CFO</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/tetrate-paul-machle/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 22:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tetrate]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227514</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Tetrate announced the appointment of Paul Machle as Chief Financial Officer (CFO). A finance veteran, Machle brings over 20 years of experience on senior leadership teams for both private and public high-growth software companies. “As we ramp up to meet the universal need for enterprises to modernize and secure infrastructure, Paul will help us expand our vision to make zero trust architecture a worldwide standard,” said Tetrate co-founder Varun Talwar. “Our whole team is delighted &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/tetrate-paul-machle/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/tetrate-paul-machle/">Tetrate appoints Paul Machle as CFO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Island appoints Jennifer Park as CPO</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/island-jennifer-park/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 22:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Island]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227519</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Island announced the appointment of Jennifer Park as its first Chief People Officer (CPO). Park joins Island’s senior leadership team with over 20 years’ experience fostering rich, innovative and diverse work environments. Her appointment reflects Island’s commitment to creating a culture that fully empowers its employees and attracts top-level global talent. With a proven track record at leading companies like Google, American Express and, most recently, D2iQ, Park joins Island to architect an authentic company &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/island-jennifer-park/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/island-jennifer-park/">Island appoints Jennifer Park as CPO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DocuSign hires Steve Shute as President of Worldwide Field Operations</title>
      <link>https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/docusign-steve-shute/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Industry News]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 22:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Industry news]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[DocuSign]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/?p=227517</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>As it continues to digitally transform how agreements are prepared, signed, acted-upon and managed around the world, DocuSign announced the appointment of Steve Shute as its new President of Worldwide Field Operations. &#8220;DocuSign has more than doubled its business over the past two years and is well on the path to becoming a $5 billion organization. To scale to even greater levels of success, last quarter we decided to unify our sales and success organizations &#8230; <a href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/docusign-steve-shute/" rel="nofollow">More <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com/2022/05/05/docusign-steve-shute/">DocuSign hires Steve Shute as President of Worldwide Field Operations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.helpnetsecurity.com">Help Net Security</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>